<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B1-2</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p> Miss Lois Hull accompanied Miss
            Josephine Sechler, of Sechlerville, to
            Waverly, Florida, last November, and
            has been spending the winter there.
            She recently returned to Waverly af-
            ter spending a week in Havana, Cuba,
            with Miss Janet Lowrie, and a week
            in Miami with the latter?s mother,
            Mrs. Walter A. Lowrie. Mrs. Lowrie
            is a niece of Miss Hull?s mother, Mrs.
            Merlin Hull. Miss Lowrie has had a |
            position with the American Consulate [
            in Havana for the past four years.
            She and her mother visited at the
            Hull home here about six years ago
            She drives her own car in Cuba, and ?
            was able to show Miss Hull over a I
            lot of territory. While she was there |
            Washington?s birthday was celebrated
            on Wednesday as a legal holiday, and j
            Friday of that week was a Cuban le- j
            gal holiday so they had a good share |
            of the week for sight-seeing. Miss
            Lowrie speaks Spanish like a native, |
            which is a decided asset in that sec-
            tion. Miss Hull saw Mr. and Mrs.
            Herman Gebhardt in Miami. They
            were having a grand time, and had
            also been to Havana.
            Mr. and Mrs. Albert Mierow were
            visitors Friday and Saturday at the
            home of Mrs. Mierow?s niece, Mrs.
            Price Moe, and left during the after-
            noon Saturday for their home in Khe-
            dive, Saskatchewan, Canada. Mrs.
            Mierow came from Khedive last Nov-
            ember and stayed in Melrose caring
            for her sister, the late Mrs. Milton
            Young, who passed away last Sunday.
            Mr. Mierow joined her in January
            and spent a few months here. They
            have been able to make only brief
            visits among their many friends and
            relatives in this section, who regret
            that their time with them could not
            have been longer.
            Friends will be interested to learn
            of the marriage of Harold Oakes, son
            of Mr. and Mrs. Harley Oakes, of
            West Salem, to Miss Kathryn Kinney,
            of Omaha, Nebraska. The ceremony
            was performed at Hebron, Nebraska,
            February 24, 1939. Both Mr. and
            Mrs. Oakes are instructors in Hast-
            ings college at Hastings, Nebraska.
            Mrs. Oakes is instructor of voice in
            the college conservatory, and Mr.
            Oakes is athletic coach. He is a grad-
            uate of the West Salem high school,
            La Crosse state teachers college, and
            received his master?s degree from the
            University of Iowa.
            C. A. Kuhn and Dr. Carl Pflanz
            left Sunday evening for Hot Springs,
            Arkansas, where they will enjoy about
            a week?s visit and bring home Mrs.
            Kuhn, who has spent the past month
            there. Just to show again how small
            the world is. Mrs. Kuhn met Robert
            and Gile TlifT at the faces at Hot
            Springs one day last week. They
            were visiting friends there on their
            way home and with all the crowds
            at the races they met Mrs. Kuhn. Mr.
            Kuhn and Dr. Pflanz will enjoy what
            Hot Springs has to offer this week,
            and arrive home next Sunday night.
            Mr. and Mrs. John A. Olson and
            son Edward, of York, were visitors
            in town one day last week. Mr. Olson
            spent the afternoon visiting with B.
            P. Lanning, and they had a fine time.
            It was the first time he had been in
            town for two years. They also called
            on Hans K. Hanson, at the court
            house. Their son Edward spends the
            summers in Columbia county raising
            tobacco but returns for the winters
            with his parents at York.
            Mrs. Rose McDonald entertained
            the London bridge club at her home
            last Thursday evening. Refreshments
            were served at Lloyd?s cafe, and there
            was a beautiful birthday cake to com-
            memorate the 11th anniversary of the
            organization of the club. Mrs. Carl
            Cadby was prize winner for the evening.'
            Miss Lotta Bright received a card j
            from Miss Marion Cheney last week,
            mailed from San Antonio. Texas.
            Miss Cheney left here early in the
            year and has been spending some time j
            in Chicago. She is going from Texas
            to Mexico, where she made an extend-
            ed visit last year, and enjoyed it very
            much.
            Miss Man- Jedney returned to Baraboo Sunday evening, accompanied 
            by Miss Marian Trondson who is a 
            guest of Miss Man- this week. Mr. 
            and Mrs. Bob Peck came here with
            her Saturday afternoon, for a week
            end visit at the home of Mrs. Peck?s
            parents, Mr. and Mrs. Henrv E. Olson.</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
