<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B1-5</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>Miss Dorothy Hanson, R. N., left
            Monday to return to her home in Au-
            rora, 111., where she has employment
            in a hospital, after spending a couple
            of weeks here caring for Mrs. Ber-
            thilde Johnson. Miss Hanson, daugh-
            ter of Mr. and Mrs. Si Hanson, left
            Aurora for California early in Feb-
            ruary to care for Mrs. Hanson, who
            underwent a major operation in a Los
            Angeles hospital. We are pleased to
            learn that she is much improved and
            again at home. Miss Hanson came
            directly here on her return from
            California to care for Mrs. Johnson,
            who is slowly recovering from her re-
            cent illness. Mrs. Phil Johnson and
            Mrs. Elizabeth Benson are looking af-
            ter her since Miss Hanson left, both
            of them are registered nurses, so
            Mrs. Johnson is assured of good care.
            Her friends are pleased to know she
            is progressing toward recovery.
            Mrs. Harold Turner went to Milwaukee last Saturday where she is (
            a guest at the home of Mr. and Mrs. i
            Oscar Sprague. She is also attending I
            home display week which is being
            held there. Mrs. Sprague has not ,
            been too well since an injury she re-
            ceived on returning to her home af-
            ter being called to Merrillan by the
            illness of the late Mrs. Frank Sprague.
            The taxi in which she was going to I
            her home from the station was in a
            collision, and she was severely jolted 
            and suffered an injury to her spine.
            Friends hope she may soon be better 
            and suffer no ill effects from her accident.
            Margaret, little daughter of Hu- 
            bert Johnson, who has spent the first
            month of her life at the hospital. 
            was taken home Sunday. Mr. Johnson?s mother is caring for her, and his
            sister. Miss Dorothy, who has employment at the telephone office,
            spent several days at home, returning
            to work today. Little Margaret is 
            thriving nicely.
            Dr. Hendrickson of Fairchild. 
            brought Miss Violet Rice to the hospital Monday for an emergency appendectomy.</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
