<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B3-1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>The ORIOLE STAFF BETTY THOMAS—Editor-in-Chief WILMA DUNN—News Editor
            Reporters: Kieth Allison. Betty Arndt. Faye Bowen, Mary Rose Boyer,
            Vilah Dob- son, Erva Loomis, Virginia McCormick, Gertrude Peterson,
            Donna Quackenbush. Marian Scafe. Allan Siemers, Kathleen Olson,
            Peter Olson, Wayne Glennie, Kathleen Horswill, lone Haralson, Jean
            Haralson, Pauline Meek, Arlene Ibinger. LA VON HAUG and—Desk Editor
            Donna Burge NORMAN MARTINSON—Sports Editor David Noble, Stanley
            Gilbertson FLORA HARPEN—Feature Editor Marie Melichar, Lucille
            Bowman, Marion Inderbo, Irene Laughnan. Marcella Nan- st, Rosli
            Zwahlen. LOTTIE RUTH FRYER Exchange Editor GWEN BUNCE—Humor Editor.
            Gwen Wensel, Nellie Mae Wyss, Margaret Olson. Ruth Anderson, Dorothy
            Staves MERLE HALVERSON—Music Editor Jeanette Lee DOROTHY STAVES—Head
            Typists Frances Potter, Irene Laughnan, Elva Faulkner MARCELLA
            NANSTAD—Distribution Mavis Davis, Marguerite Eggen SECOND SEMESTER
            HONOR ROLL FIRST SIX WEEKS High Honor Roll: Seniors—Vivian Anderson,
            Mary Rose Boyer, Donna Burge, Verland Olson, Betty Thomas
            Juniors—Kathleen Olson, Leslie Thomas Sophomores—None Freshmen—Berle
            Barkley, Dorothy Burge, Lucille Gonia, Jeanette Lee, Peter Olson,
            Donna Quackenbush Eighth grade—Dean Allison, Ar- thur Johnson,
            Arlene Thompson Seventh grade—Mary Ellen Bich- ler, Pearl Brewer,
            Virginia Davis, William Frei, Mary Joyce Gilbertson, Alice Ibinger,
            Norma Thiele, Iris Thomas, Edna Uhlberg, Carmen W right Honor Roll:
            Seniors—Dorothy Brinker, Wayne Glennie, Joseph Marousek, Agnes
            Prochaska, Mary Rice, Marion Thomp son, Nellie Mae Wyss, Rosli
            Zwahlen Juniors—Stanley Gilbertson, Verna Gilbertson, Eleanor Olson,
            Don Per- ry, Bessie Prochaska Sophomores—Monica Bielinski, Lu- cille
            Bowman, Thelma Cain, Emmett Kampen, Lucille Schneider, Gene- vieve
            Stein, Joyce Strozewski, James Theile, Garth Wensel Freshmen—Keith
            Allison, Betty Arndt, Harold Dunn, Margie Hagen, Evelyn Harmon,
            Kathleen Horswill, Merle Jacoby, Milton Larson, Erwin Peterson,
            Marie Reichenbach, Frank Snowdon, Lucille Thiele, James Thornton
            Eighth grade—D o n aid Larson, Grace Nanstad, Marjorie Roberts
            Seventh Grade—Allan Danielson, Donald Johnson, Maxine Wiley BAND
            NEWS The next band concert will be held the latter part of April.
            The contest numbers will be played then. These include “Jolly
            Robbers” and “New Colonial”. The latter is being me- morized for
            marching. The tourna- ment is in La Crosse and to be held the last
            of April or the first of May. A new Glockenspiel has just arriv- ed
            for use in the band and orchestra. It has a reversible stand so it
            can be used in marching. It really is a beautiful affair.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
