<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B3-2</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>“SO LONG AGO!” I’ll bet some of you know that Black River had a
            school paper, namely “The Breee”, as far back as 11 years ago, 1928.
            We still have the Breeze. It is now our annual, but the school paper
            has a different name (Pm sure you’ve all read the “Oriole”.) But I’m
            not supposed to be telling you about the “Oriole”. It’s well- known,
            and I feel safe in saying well lived, in our school. But let’s turn
            time back to 1928 and talk about “The Breeze.” First of all, there
            was an organiz- ation called “The Ink Spots”, made up largely of
            girls. The club sponsor- ed a leap year party, this particular year,
            and the invitations were artis- tically printed by hand by Miss
            Carol Kinley. The party was a gay one, for every one dressed like a
            child. Each guest was to come to the party in appropriate costume
            and be pre- pared to recite some rhyme of his or her childhood.
            After the dinner each “child” recited his “piece” or sang a song. A
            prize was given to “little Tommy Mills” for the best recitation,
            even though he broke down and wept for “Mama” when he couldn’t
            remember his lines. The best-dressed child, “little Carol Kinley”,
            also car- ried off a prize. After awarding the prizes, the “little
            folks” were allow- ed to dance in the spacious hall or the Junior
            High building, and promptly at 9 o’clock all were sent home. I think
            this sort of party would go over “big” in our school. How about it,
            Mr. Johnson? Some other interesting features of the 1928 Breeze were
            original poems written by some of the students. One poem, “Lincoln”,
            by Norma Bersing, particularly appealed to me. It was
            after*Lincoln’s death. There was also a short review of the class
            play of that year. Mr. Sin- delar was included in the cast. He took
            the part of John Sedgwick, an old flame of Miss Day (Marjorie Ov-
            erlien). Wonder if he still remem- bers it. The Commercial
            department was giving typing medals then. too. And if a student
            typed 25 wQjds a minute for 15 minutes without more than 10 errors,
            he received a proficiency cer- tificate. Pins, or medals, were given
            the same as they are today. Jokes were also printed in “The Breeze”,
            some of which are reproduc- ed in this issue of the “Oriole”, with a
            change of characters. Did you know that our High school printed a
            monthly magazine called The Black River Breeze” as far back as 1909?
            No? I didn’t either until I read the “Breeze of ’28.” There were
            also short articles about the G. A. A.- Girl Scouts and the Hi-Y
            club. I thoroughly enjoyed reading the paper, and if I haven’t given
            you enough information here. I’m sure Miss Bailey would let you “see
            for yourself.” Get in line! I </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
