<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B5-6</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>MERRILLAN MIXTURE
            Editor ..........Geneva Rhoades	BOY	SCOUT	NEWS
            Assistant Editor--John Jarolimek On Tuesday, March 7, the Merril-
            Sports ..............  Dale	Austin	]an Boy Scouts were called to the
            dass . ............. Frances Larson First Air O’ree at Black River Falls.
            Esther Buttke, Virginia Christian- Gibson Gile took five Scouts to Black
            son, Vivian Ransom, Minnie Sorlie, Rjver. They were Goodwin Zinn,
            June Meyers	Claire Van Sickle, Elwood Austin,
            nil roinruir	Frances Rogers and Floyd Fulling-
            FLU EPIDEMIC	ton. Claire Van Sickle was captain
            Mr. Olson, Mr. Schultz, and Miss on the group.
            Fobes were absent from school be- Troop No. 58 of the east side won
            cause of flu. Mr. Schultz was sick 1st place. Merrillan was third. This
            longest being out of school four days. meet was entirely different from what
            During their absence, students took we baVe in the Boy Scout handbood.
            charge of classes and, with the co- We would have to think out our own
            operation of every one, school was remedies for the patient. We all had
            run as smoothly as ever.	two problems to work on. When the |
            i ai muFNCir roNTFST two Problems were worked the troop
            night, March 17. From the contest- , e	rewarded with a shield
            ants in this contest four students will having First Aid Oree 1939 print-
            be chosen to represent Merrillan High	ln	letters on the front. It
            school at the league forensics contest IS ver>' nice. Next time we hope for
            at Fall Creek.	more of an honor.
            Dramatic Declamatory—Shi rley .	w.ere Scouts atthe meet-
            Austir. Margaret Shultz, Caroline 01- mg Thursday, MarchJh They were
            son	as follows:	Duane Franks, Elwood
            Humorous Declamatory—Vivian Austin, Floyd Fullington. Frances
            Ransom, Josephine Erickson	Rogers, Goodwin Zinn, Harold But-
            Oratory—Virginia Erickson, James terfield, Jack Van Sickle, Claire Van
            Larson	Sickle, Thomas Kearney, Robert
            Extemporaneous Reading—Eva 01- Kearney,
            son, Frances Larson	Bob	Wilkins	will	be	our	assistant
            -----	Scout Master.
            Ruben, Rachel, is a favorite piece Harold Butterfield passed his first
            for group singing Monday morning, aid in the second class rank.
            Mr. Olson always wears a broad smile Duane Franks passed his judging,
            after the last line—“and I’ll split handicraft, bank account in the first
            with you my money every pay-day of class rank
            my life.”	Goodwin	Zinn	and	Clair	Van	Sickle
            . passed their Firemanship Merit Badge
            in the Star rank,
            i No parents visited this week. Re-
            member, “Everybody is welcome.”
            CAMP FIRE GIRLS
            The Camp Fire girls, with Miss
            Smith as their guardian, have ac-
            complished much this year.
            At Christmas time they repaired
            old toys and sent them to orphanages.
            The girls have had two cookie
            sales. The proceeds are to be used
            to camp as a girls’ summer camp this
            summer.
            Their headbands are well under
            way.
            A SOCIAL SUCCESS
            The Puff-Pant Prom came off Fri-
            day night as a social success. All of
            the gentlemen and ladies were on
            their best hehavior and dances were
            exchanged just as at any other kind
            of prom.
            The “fellows” called for their girl
            friends, took them to the dance and
            acted all evening just as they wish
            their escorts would. With only a few
            mistakes, everything went off well
            and the fellows admirably took their
            part.
            The gymnasium was decorated in
            St. Patrick’s style with shamrock,
            pipes and hats. Seats were placed on
            the balcony for the spectators and all
            in all it looked very nice.
            This was the first prom of this sort
            that the Merrillan girls have had and
            here’s hoping we can have some more
            life it that will be as big a success.
            SENIORS
            Well, the debate finally came off.
            The Social Problems class debated on
            the abolition of capital punishment.
            The affirmative side consisted of Vi-
            vian Erickson, Dale Austin and Fred-
            erick Breheim. The negative side had
            Frances Larson, Dale Rhoades and
            Harold Simonson. John Jarolimek was
            chairman. Mr. Schultz and Mr. Ol-
            son were judges and the decision
            went to the affirmative while the neg
            ative sat with long, sad faces and still
            think they were right. However, the
            judges decision could not be changed.
            The annual staff has been working
            hard this past week and have several
            pages ready for the dummy copy
            which wi'l be used as a means of ad-
            vertising. This week the staff will
            be working nights in order that more
            work can be accomplished. This no
            doubt will be quite sad news for some
            of the seniors, to have to come to
            the school at night!
            The Freshman class was very glad
            to welcome a new student to the
            class. Evelyn Jones.
            The old man Flu came to visit Mr.
            Schultz and Mr. Olson but didn’t stay
            long with Mr. Olson, for he only re-
            mained at home a half day. Shirley
            Austin took Mr. Schultz’ place in
            Science class Tuesday. But then old
            man Flu decided to visit Shirley so
            Howard Mathews played teacher until
            Friday, when Mr. Schultz returned.
            We will soon have new books in
            Social Science. Mr. Schultz has been
            on the sick list all week. The high
            school pupils could teach their own
            classes but Junior High pupils could
            not so we have had no class in Gen-
            eral Science.
            We have been having some good
            debates on the World war, in Social
            Science.
            3RD AND 4TH GRADES
            Mr. Frost made a writing desk for
            our librarian. It is painted green to
            match the other furniture in our
            room. We extend our thanks to Mr.
            Frost for making it.
            Esther Kubecka has been appoint-
            ed librarian to act in place of Irene
            Burlingame, beginning this Monday.
            Sidney Gearing has moved to Al-
            ma Center. He is in the 4th grade.
            Ira Bennet was taken to the hos-
            pital last Monday night and under-
            went an appendectomy Tuesday. He
            is getting along very well.
            POETRY CORNER
            Flu when it strikes you, is a horrible
            thing,
            It makes your throat sore, and makes
            your head ring.
            You get the chills, your feet are cold.
            It makes you feel weak, and sort of
            old.
            You miss all the fun, your mother
            gets mad,
            And scolds and frets as tho you had
            The measles or something else as bad.
            I know because I’ve had it too—
            But be thankful that it’s just the flu.
            —Suzanne Helbling
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
