<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B5-7</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>HUMBIRD	
            coming here from Neillsville.	week into part of the house of hei
            Frank Moore returned from his Madge Flynn, a senior in high son, Bert Hart. She will make hei
            work in Madison, Friday.	school, was operated Friday at the home here. Francis Dudlev, whore
            The Excelsior club met at the home Krohn clinic for appendicitis.	she has been caring for, came wit!
            of Anna Brandstedter Tuesday.	There	are	a few cases of whooping her to stay a few weeks
            „ Harold Anderson left Friday for cough here. The homes of Lee Ter- The Study club met at the home ol
            Fedeka, Minn to vis.t friends.	rell and Angus Flood are under quar- Mrs. Morris Rretchmer Wednesdaj
            . Mlss E's'e Lind" has gone to Mad- antine.	.	afternoon. Mrs. Clarence Olson wa:
            ison, where she has employment.	The	men	of the Methodist church tv,P lPaHer and p-rvo an interestino
            Miss Ometh, first and second grade are planning on having a St. Patrick’s LD;C “Around the World with the
            teacher, spent the week end in St. day supper next Friday. Irish stew mL on the Street”, as seen by the
            aMrs. Wm. Duchow and Mrs. Clar- “ The ladi^of'the village have been ^ author and ^lobe-trotter, tfranli
            ence Olson were at B. R. Falls, Fri- enjoying themselves going on “gal- _ .'
            day.	loping parties” and incidently raising , Friends here were very sorry tc
            Mrs. Rose Russell, who is staying money for the Methodist Aid Soci-	°* death of George Hart, ol
            in Eau Claire, was a caller in town ety.	Colfax. Mr. Hart and family had re
            Tuesday	'n,	a	j	a	...	sided ln Humbird the major portior
            Mr and Mrs Mike Mathews and r " .if	met	Wl	\	AJ-1Ce	of his life as he was owner of the
            family sDent Sunday at Mrs Myrtle ~°,,Rr T ursday aHernoon. A fine Red £ White store here many years
            RTl L’ fn Hakvon	ad a"°i er ,a-ge They moved to Colfax a couple ol
            \i ^ a \a ro	r»i	a	rr0V*i! ^atbered there in the evening months ago. Mr. and Mrs. Harrj
            Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Olson and for the weekly Lenten service.	Hart, Mrs. Charlev and Ed Noyes
            Russell O’Leary made a business trip Word was received here last Fri- H. h’. Nibby and Buddy Kelsh attend
            to Eau Claire, Monday.	day of the death of Aaron Huyck, ed the funeral.
            Miss Edna Peterson, 7th and 8th of Duluth. He was a brother-in-law	_____________
            grade teacher, was called to her home of B. J. and Henry Stallard, and re-	card of thanks
            in Ashland because of the death of sided in Humbird many years ago.	w* wi.h to thank our friend. who »tund
            her father. Mrs. Mae Hohn is teach- Henry Stallard left Saturday to at- ed our weddin*
dance for their *ift an
            ing in her place.	tend the funeral.	*or the money they gave us. W« are prate
            Will McMellon and son Roy have Mrs. Lawn Cook moved her house-	all r*celTed and for the klnd
            moved into the Tillie Murry house, hold goods here from Neillsville last MR. and MRS. henry valence</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
