<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B6-1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>B6-1 MERLIN HULL’S WEEKLY LETTER The bill for reorganization of the
            executive and independent depart- ments is again up for
            consideration. It is considerably changed from the Theasure proposed
            last session, but the issue of congressional control still is there.
            Some 19 years have elapsed since the issue arose in the Harding
            administration, and it has been be- fore almost every Congress
            since. A law was passed in the closing days of the Hoover
            administration. Al- though President Hoover had de- manded the law,
            he made no use of it. The powers of the law were ex- tended into
            this administration when it came in, but they were permit- ted to
            lapse without action. In the last session, a new bill was defeated
            by a narrow vote. The present measure has been drawn to eliminate
            some of the opposition of a year ago. In that direction, it provides
            that at least 16 boards and commissions shall not be included in the
            re-organization. This probably will result in less inter-department
            opposition to the bill, and also less opposition of some of the
            large group organizations which help- ed stir up sentiment against
            the proposal when the former bill was under consideration. While
            from the press the impression might be gained that the matter is a
            fight between the President and Congress, that is only partly the
            case. Striking out so many boards and commissions from the
            jurisdiction of the measure is a con- cession that the contest
            involves a division of sentiment within administration circles. The
            year 1939 will be a record breaking year in the construction of new
            war vessels. At the present rate qf progress, 73 new naval vessels
            will be launched this year. They will range from battleships of
            40,000 tons, the cost of each of which will be $70,000,000 or more,
            down to the submarines, torpedo boats, and other smaller vessels.
            This addition to the Navy will make it second to no other nation in
            the number of warships, and possibly excelled only by that of Great
            Britain in the way of tonnage. That record may not be held long, as
            Great Britain has a building program even more extens- ive than our
            own. Next year, and for the ensuing three or four years, naval
            expansion will continue upon even a larger scale; particularly in
            the way of battleships and large cruisers. Millions more will be
            spent upon the additional thousands of air- planes. An attempt will
            be made to obtain an investigation of illegal alien im- migration
            into this country The sub- ject is not new, but disclosures in
            recent months would seem to indicate that the number of aliens
            coming by stealth and conspiracy may be equal if not larger than
            those who come legally and with proper visas under our immigration
            laws. The same in- vestigation if authorized may ascer- tain the
            reason for the great decline in the deportation of aliens who have
            come here surreptitiously. That num- ber has dropped from 37,000
            deport- ations annually to about 8,000. It is known that the number
            who have come here contrary to law and re- mained notwithstanding
            the law runs into hundreds of thousands. The Im- migration
            Department has lacked funds to make much headway in the matter. The
            scandal arising from the smug- gling in and wrongful entrance of
            aliens has been growing in the larger seaport cities, and the recent
            orders forbidding employment of aliens on WPA are aiding in forcing
            attention to the problem. Among the most in- sistent violations of
            the law are said to be those of large ship lines on the Atlantic,
            which are said to profit handsomely through the traffic. Ships which
            carry a crew of 700 on the outward voyage are charged with em-
            ploying 900 or more on their return. Once in the country by such
            methods, the aliens are safe until they can be rounded up by federal
            agents and taken into court. By the time an order of deportation has
            been issued in a single case, dozens of newcomers arrive by the same
            method. It is charged that some lines have a regu- lar charge of
            from $50 to $100 each for thus aiding men from foreign countries to
            come to our ports. There are, of course, other agencies engag- ed in
            the illegal traffic, and boats coming from Cuba and other Carri-
            bean islands are frequently captured with from a dozen to 100 aliens
            on board. The huge profits of such a voyage make alien smuggling a
            regu- lar business which the government finds difficult to stamp
            out. When the Economy Act was pass- ed, several years ago, a few
            millions were stricken out of the appropria- tion for border guards
            on the borders between our country and Canada and Mexico. The
            smugglers who had for- merly found fortunes in running in foreign
            booze were not slow in tak- ing advantage of the new opportun- :
            ity. In a single night they are able to transport aliens from the
            border- ing country to one of our large ' cities, and the fares are
            said to be many times the rates paid by others on Pullman cars. How
            many thous- ands of aliens who are being dis- charged from W’PA came
            in by either the sea or the land routes is not i known. This illegal
            flow of aliens makes uncertain the exact status of immigration under
            our laws. Those who came from abroad honestly and openly upon visas
            issued by our consular service abroad are less numerous than for
            years. From 1931 to 1938 there were 4,260,081 who came mainly from
            Europe. In that same period, aside from those deported by the
            government, 4,487,085 returned to their native lands over seas. Last
            year, the number departing was 50,000 more than those who came in.
            The situation in Europe and the possibility of war between some
            countries now is increasing the number of applicants for visas. The
            quota of visas permissible annually for Germany is about 27,000, but
            applications have been filed by ten times that number. From Census
            Bureau estimates the distribution of racial stocks in this country
            is about 37 per cent English and Welsh, 8 per cent Scotch, 11
            percent Irish and 17 per cent German, the percentage from other
            nations is about 4 per cent each for Frances, Poland and Italy. 2
            per cent for Sweden and about the same for Norway, other countries
            are represented by a smailer percentage. MERLIN HULL</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
