<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B6-4</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>STATE EMPLOYMENT SERVICE With the question of unemploy- ment
            occupying the center of interest more than any other problem, the
            Eau Claire office of the Wisconsin State Employment Service has set
            aside this week as the beginning of a more concerted effort to bring
            to the attention of employers and em- ployees the service which is
            available. The purpose of the Employment Service is to put the right
            man in the right job by referring only qualified applicants to fill
            the openings which the office is asked to handle. Soon there will be
            a need for farm workers and the Employment Service urges all those
            seeking this type of work to register now. Farmers who wish to
            secure workers should noti- fy the office in advance. Equal
            opportunities are afforded all residents of the district even tho
            they live at points a long distance from the Eau Claire office.
            Itinerant interviewers, bringing the employ- ment service to all
            main points in the district, may be contacted by employ- ers and
            employees at the city halls or other public buildings. The
            Employment Service is open to the public at all times, but during
            this week, a special invitation is ex- tended to every one to visit
            the of- fice. Their service is your service, and a trained staff
            headed by H. J. Younberg, is ready and glad to serve you.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
