<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B6-8</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>B6-8 TRIBUTE TO CADY FOWLER “Well done, thou good and faithful j
            servant. Enter thou into the joy of the Lord”. How fitting these
            words to the life of Mr. Fowler, a much loved and respected citizen
            of our community. Good and faithful! Not only was he a good man but
            a good Christian man. How much like the Master, when we can say of
            him, he went about doing good. Always ready to go the second mile,
            to do a bit more than was required of him, al- ways ready and
            willing to be of ser- vice to all. When a neighbor or friend was
            sick or in trouble he was the first to be there to encourage and
            cheer, bringing in a basket of good things or flowers. He had
            expressed the wish that when his time came to go he might just say
            good night here and awake and say good morning Over There, and so it
            was. He retired at night as usual, bidding his family good night,
            and while he was sleeping a Pres- ence came, awakened him gently and
            said “Come”, and his spirit depart- ed. While our hearts were
            saddened how great must have been his joy as he met his Master Whom
            he faith- fully served all his life and saw again the faces of his
            loved ones and friends who had gone on before. Faithful! For 24
            years he had charge of the O.and N. lumber yard here and when he
            retired in 1926 he received a fine testimonial from the owners of
            the yard for many years of faithful service. He was a faith- ful
            member of the Masonic lodge and served as treasurer for many years.
            Always interested in the community he served several years as clerk
            of the school board. For the major portion of his long and useful
            life he was a devoted and faithful member of the Methodist church,
            serving as Sunday school su- perintendent for many years and also as
            treasurer, which office he held at the time of his death. Here again
            he evidenced his faithfulness, look- ing after all the little
            details that the less thoughtful forget. The most out- standing
            evidence of his faithfulness was shown by the loyalty of his church
            attendance. Altho for the last two or three years he could not hear
            any of the sermon on account of im- paired hearing, every Sunday
            morn- ing found him in his place at the church service. His life is
            an inspiration and a challenge to all who knew him, and to have
            known him was to love him. May his picture never fade from me-
            mory’s wall. Truly he was Thy ser- vant and how precious in the
            sight of the Lord is the death of His saints! We cannot say that he
            is dead. Spirits like his do not die. He is still with us in
            fellowship, in pur- pose and in spirit. He is not dead, just a
            little farther on. A FRIEND</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
