<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B7-4</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>NOTICE
            The Taylor Creamery Association
            will offer at public sale at the cream-
            ery, Tuesday, March 21st, at 2:00 o’-
            clock p. m., the entire output to one
            party or separate days churnings to
            different parties of the buttermilk
            from the creamery from May 1, 1939
            to May 1, 1940. Board reserves the
            right to reject any or all bids,
            lw	SAM	KELLY,	Sec.
            NOTICE OF APPLICATION FOR PROBATE
            OF WILL AND NOTICE TO CREDITORS
            STATE OF WISCONSIN. COUNTY COURT.
            Jackson County
            In the Matter of the Estate of Hans H.
            Iverson, deceased.
            Notice is hereby given that at a terns of
            said court to be held on Tuesday, the 4th
            day of April, 1939, at 10 o’clock in the
            forenoon of said day, at the court house in
            the city of Black River Falls, in said county,
            there will be heard and considered:
            The application of Anna Iverson for the
            probate of the will of Han? H. Iverson, de-
            ceased, and for the appointment of an ex-
            ecutor or administrator with the will annex-
            ed of the estate of said Hans H. Iverson,
            deceased, late of tire City of Black River
            Falls, in said County;
            Notice is further given that all claims
            against the said Hans H. Iverson, deceased,
            late of the Village of Taylor, in Jackson
            county. Wisconsin, must be presented to
            said County Court at Black River Falls, in
            said county, on or before the 7th day of
            August. 1939, or be barred; and that all
            such claims and demands will be examined
            and adjusted at a term of said court to be
            held at the court house in the city of Black
            River Falls, in said county, on Tuesday, the
            8th day of August. 1939, at 10 o’clock in
            the forenoen of said day.
            Dated March 4. 1939.
            By Order of the Court,
            HARRY M. PERRY. Judge
            D. M. PERRY, Attorney.
            March 8-22</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
