<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B9-12</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>SUMMONS STATE OF WISCONSIN, CIRCUIT COURT. Jackson County The
            Federal Land Bank of Saint Paul, a body Corporate, Plaintiff, vs
            Joseph Rachenske; Julia Rachenske. his wife; John Merschdorf; Mrs.
            John Merschdorf, wife of above named John Merschdorf; Kenneth D.
            Mickelberry; Mrs. Kenneth D. Mickelberry, wife of above named
            Kenneth D. Mickelberry; Federal Farm Mortgage Corporation, a
            Corporation; and the First Jackson Coun- ty National Farm Loan
            Association, a Corporation, Defendants. The State of Wisconsin, To
            the Said De- fendants. You, and each of you are hereby sum- moned to
            appear within twenty days after the service of this summons,
            exclusive of the day of service and defend the above entitled action
            in the court aforesaid; and in case of your failure so to do
            judgment will be rendered against you according to the demand of the
            complaint, of which a copy is herewith served upon you. DONOVAN,
            GLEISS and GOODMAN. Planitiff’s Attorneys Post Office Address: Sparta,
            Monroe coun- ty, Wisconsin. The original Summons and Complaint is on
            file in the office of the Clerk of the Circuit Court, Jackson
            County, Wisconsin. This is an action to foreclose a mort- gage on
            the lands described, as follows: The southeast quarter of the
            southwest quarter (SE*4 SW ^4) ; also the south half of the
            southeast quarter (S% SE Vi) of Section nineteen (19); also the
            south half of the southwest quarter (S% SW*4) of Section twenty (20)
            ; also the north half of the northwest quarter (NVfc NW^) of Section
            twenty-nine (29) ; also the north half of the northeast quarter
            (N^fc NE\4) and the northeast quarter of northwest quarter (NE*4
            NW*4) of Section thirty (SO), all in Township twenty-one (21) North
            of Range five (5) west, containing four-hundred (400) acres, more or
            less, ac- cording to the Government survey thereof, Jackson County.
            Wisconsin. March 15-29 NOTICE OF HEARING ON FINAL SET- TLEMENT AND
            DETERMINATING OF INHERITANCE TAX STATE OF WISCONSIN. COUNTY COURT.
            Jackson County In the Matter of the Estate of Herman Johnson,
            deceased. Notice is hereby given that at a term of said court to be
            held on Tuesday, the 11th day of April, 1939, at 10 o'clock in the
            forenoon of said day, at the court house in the city of Black River
            Falls, in said county, there will be heard and considered: The
            application of Edna Johnson, admin- istratrix of the estate of
            Herman Johnson, deceased, late of the town of Franklin, in said
            county, for the examination and al- lowance of her final account,
            which account is now on file in said court, and for the allowance of
            debts or claims paid in good faith without filing or allowance as
            re- quired by law, and for the assignment of the residue of the
            estate of said deceased to such persons as are by law entitled
            thereto; and for the determination and adjudication of the
            inheritance tax, if any. payable in said estate. Dated March 7,
            1939. By Order of the Court, HARRY M. PERRY, Judge March 8-22 NOTICE
            OF HEARING ON FINAL SETTLEMENT STATE OF WISCONSIN. COUNTY COURT.
            Jackson County In the Matter of the Estate of John Olson, deceased
            Notice is hereby given that at a term of said court to be held on
            Tuesday, the 4th day of April, 1939, at 10 o’clock in the forenoon
            of said day, at the court house in the city of Black River Falls, in
            said county, there will be heard and considered: The application of
            Emil G. Gilbertson, ad- ministrator of the estate of John Olson, de-
            ceased. late of the City of Black River Falls, in said county, for
            the examination and al- lowance of his final account, which account
            is now on file in said court, and for the allowance of debts or
            claims paid in good faith without filing or allowance as requir- ed
            by law, and for the assignment of the residue of the estate of said
            deceased to such persons as are by law entitled thereto. Dated March
            6. 1939. By Order of the Court, HARRY M. PERRY. Judge D. M. PERRY,
            Attorney March 8-22 SUMMONS STATE OF WISCONSIN. CIRCUIT COURT.
            Jackson County Federal Farm Mortgage Corporation, a body Corporate.
            Plaintiff, J. E. Garaghan, an Administrator of the Estate of John
            Fenney, deceased; James Nichols, single; William Nichols; Lola
            Nichols, hris wife; George Nichols, also known as George Tucker:
            Hilda Nichols, also known as Hilda Tucker, his wife; Hazel Morse;
            Edith Morse; Gertrude Morse; David Morse, single; Donald Morse,
            single; Dayton Morse, single; Soren Fenney, single, also known as
            So- ren Johnson; Olea Fenney; EfTie Ander- son; Olga Schure; Milton
            Fenney; Mrs. Milton Fenney. his wife; Raymond Fen- ney; Mrs. Raymond
            Fenney. his wife; Menford Fenney; Mrs. Menford Fenney, his wife;
            Lillian Fenney; Goodwin Fen- ney, single; Adolph Fenney. single;
            Nor- man Fenney. single; Tilford Fenney, sin- gle; Edward Fenney.
            single; Clara Fen- ney; Mabel Helbling; Gladys Bailey; Verna Fenney;
            Jul*’a Fenney; Norma Fenney: Julia Anderson; Minnie Chris- tianson;
            Joseph Anderson; Agnes An- derson. his wife: Theodore Anderson;
            Marge Anderson, his wife; Agnes An- derson ; Violet Anderson; Doris
            Ander- son; Lois Anderson; Charles Anderson, single; Anna Fenney;
            Thelma Fenney; Meba Fenney; George Fenney; Mrs. George Fenney, hris
            wife; Curtis Fenney; Mrs. Curtis Fenney. his wife; and all the
            unknown heirs of John Fenney, deceased, and the unknown owners of
            all or any part of or interest in the lands described in this action
            and all whom it may con- cern. Defendants. THE STATE OF WISCONSIN.
            To the Said Defendants. You and each of you are hereby sum- moned to
            appear within twenty days after the service of this summons,
            exclusive of the day of service and defend the above entitled action
            in the court aforesaid; and in case of your failure so to do
            judgment will be rendered against you according to the demand of the
            complaint, of which a eopy is herewith served upon you. DONOVAN.
            GLEISS A GOODMAN. Plaintiffs Attorneys Post Office Address: Sparta.
            Monroe Coun- ty, Wisconsin. The original Summons and Complaint is on
            file in the office of the Clerk of the Cir- cuit Court, Jackson
            County, Wisconsin. March 8-April 12</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
