<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B9-10</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>NOTICE OF JUDICIAL ELECTION
            April 4, 1939
            STATE OF WISCONSIN. COUNTY OF
            Jackson—ss
            Notice Is Hereby Given that at an election
            to be held in the several towns, wards, vil-
            lages and election precincts on the first
            Tuesday of April, A. D. 1939. being the
            Fourth day of said month, the following
            officers are to be elected:
            A Justice of the Supreme Court, for the
            term of ten years, to succeed Marvin B.
            Rosenberry, whose term will expire on the
            first Monday of January, A. D. 1940.
            ^ A Circuit Judge for the Seventeenth Judi-
            cial Circuit comprised of the counties of
            Clark, Jackson and Juneau, for the term of
            six years, to succeed Emery W. Crosby,
            whose term will expire on the first Monday
            of January, A. D. 1940.
            Given under my hand and official seal, at
            the Court House in the City of Black River
            Falls, this 10th day of March. A. D. 1939.
            HANS K. HANSON, County Clerk
            (SEAL)	Jackson County. Wisconsin
            March 15-29
            ELECTION NOTICE
            Notice U hereby given that the annual
            Municipal Election for the City of Black
            River Falls, Jackson County. Wisconsin,
            will be held on the first Tuesday of April,
            1939 (being the 4th day of April A. D.
            1939) at which time the following officers
            are to be elected.
            A City Marshal for a term of one year
            to fill vacancy, term of office expires on
            the 1st day of May, 1939.
            Two Justices of Peace to fill vacancies.
            Two Constables to be elected from the
            City at large.
            A Supervisor in and for the First Ward
            of the City of Black River Falls, to succeed
            I. S. Hollenbeck, whose term of office ex-
            pires on the first day of May, 1939.
            An Alderman in and for the First Ward
            in the city of Black River Falls to succeed
            Lawrence E. Jones whose term of office ex-
            pires on the third Tuesday in April. 1939.
            A Supervisor in and for the Second Ward
            of the City of Black River Falls, to succeed
            Emil G. Gilbertson whose term of office
            expires on the first day of May. 1939.
            An Alderman in and for the Second Ward
            in the City of Black River Falls to succeed
            Joe Widmar whose term of office expires
            on the third Tuesday in April. 1939.
            A Supervisor in and for the Third Ward
            in the City of Black River Falls, to succeed
            Phillip Gebhardt, whose term of office ex-
            pires on the first day of May, 1939.
            An Alderman in and for the Third Ward
            in the City of Black River Falls, to succeed
            David L. Hilts whose term of office expires
            on the third Tuesday in April, 1939.
            An Alderman (for a term of one year)
            in and for the Third Ward, City of Black
            River Falls, to succeed Lawrence Larkin
            whose term of office expires on the third
            Tuesday in April. 1939.
            A Supervisor in and for the Fourth Ward
            in the City of Black River Falls, to succeed
            Burnham Tanner whose term of office ex-
            pires on the first day of May. 1939.
            An Alderman in and for the Fourth Ward
            in the City of Black River Falls to succeed
            O. J. Tollack whose term of office expires
            on the third Tuesday of April. 1939.
            Said election will be held at the City
            Hall in the City of Black River Falls, and
            the polls will be open at nine o'clock in
            the forenoon and close at five-thirty o’clock
            in the afternoon of that day.
            Dated March 8. 1939.
            ll-4w EILERT M. HAGEN. City Clera</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
