<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>T39M03D16P1B1FC1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Fred Sam come from Wittenberg at Indian hospital for eye
            trouble and come on purpose to see Dr. Winter. Dr. Winter help lots of people with eye
            trouble and make some get better. Everybody laugh when Indian reporter tell about want
            cupota on In Indian school building when tear down house and want big barn for coop for
            10 hens and rooster to exercise in winter time. Indian reporter think white man
            government pretty crazy when want to tear down nice school when Indian children learn
            how white man farm to make living and have to know or can’t do things but hunt and trap
            and can’t make living Indian school built for Indian farms and tell them Indians don’t
            want to live in brick house on Indian school farm. Another thing maybe give land to
            Indians and then put on big tax for everything and take away from them like did
            Winnebagoes when agent tell all Indians to buy land one time and tell use trust money
            from government to buy land Indian reporter pay $416.06 1914 for farm and in little
            while county clerk and clerk of court big shot white fellows at court house tell because
            don’t five them more than make from farm for tax that have to get off farm and give to
            them to sell to other so can put big tax on hum and take away again. Indian reporter had
            to go Madison in big court state trial and tell all about how buy farm with trust money
            and that Compton say if stay on land can’t take away. Judge tell stand up and raise hand
            and tell just truth. Indian reporter only went to school three months and judge say lots
            of things don’t know understand and tell judge never went to school and don’t know bug
            words like he use and everybody talk loud and tell that have to give farm away because
            don’t pay tax. Then everybody don’t talk and let reporter tell how Compton say don’t
            have to pay tax if live on farm and can’t take away. Christie Indian Agent say same
            thing. Only two Indians keep farm me and another fellow and all others lose farm and
            county clerk and clerk of court make them get out. They five farm back to white man and
            trust money all gone and Indians get nothing. Charley Low Cloud has been at Indian
            hospital pretty sick for long time now. Charley bad cold and flu and been pretty sick
            but get better. Get letters from Michigan and Minnesota about people like Indian News
            and want picture of Indian reporter. Maybe have some good pictures not like picture in
            paper like Dr. Cunningham take and send to people. People that like Indian news and want
            picture of reporter want to send stamp or can’t send picture and send letter to Indian
            reporter at Tomah Journal and Monitor-Herald. </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
