<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M2TM</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>Some time in the latter part of January, the Wisconsin Winnebago Claim committee, of which the writer is president, 
received a letter from their tribal attorney in Washington, stating that Senator “ Bob” La Follette had introduced the Winnebago 
Jurisdictional bill on the 16th of that month, in Congress.  This bill, if it passes Congress, will open the doors of the Court of Claims 
to the Winnebago tribe that they may present what claims they may have against the U. S. Government. 
Proving claims against Uncle Sam is what we would call a task colossal. This Winnebago claim committee, representing the Winnebago tribe, 
of Wisconsin, is represented in Washington by the tribal attorney Ralph H. Case. The committee is also working in conjunction with the state’s 
attorney general’s office. A law was passed about four years ago in the state legislature conferring on the state the authority to secure or 
work out some means o f securing satisfactory recompense for the Indians of Wisconsin from the U. S. government, for long neglected benefits 
from unfulfilled treaties. Providing that this jurisdictional bill introduced in Congress by Senator La Follette should pass and the Winnebagoes 
receive a favorable decision from the Court of Claims and the Indians receive satisfactory adjustments from Uncle Sam, 
the state will have benefitted by having the living standards of its Indians greatly lifted and will have benefitted largely also from the monetary viewpoint. </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
