<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>T39M03D16P8B3</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>Cutler
            Mr. and Mrs. Art Woggan were at Sparta Sunday visiting at the Charles Parrot home. 
            Mr. George Greeno received the sad news of the death of his father who passed away at his home near Sparta. Mr. and Mrs. Greeno went to Sparta Monday to help make arrangements for the funeral.
            Mr. and Mrs. Charles Mark of Camp Douglas were Sunday visitors at the A. Georganson and James Neustader homes. 
            Mr. and Mrs. C. C. Hanson and sons, Roland and Harvey, spent Sunday at the Clarence Hanson home.
            Mr. and Mrs. H. T. Hanson and daughters, Irene and Florence, and son Raymond spent Sunday at Martin Hanson’s home in Adams.
            The White Hill Homemakers club met at the home of Mrs. Wilkenson Wednesday, March 15. 
            Miss Dorothy Belcher returned to Milwaukee Friday after spending the past month with her parents, Mr. and Mrs. Harry Belcher.
            Tomah callers Saturday were Mr. and Mrs. Ed Crips and daughter, and Mrs. H. T. Hanson and son Raymond.
            Mr. August Garbrecht accompanied Mr. and Mrs. Frank Schmeckel to Sparta Thursday when they took their son Gilbert to the hospital. On Monday they took Gilbert to a hospital in Madison. Mr. Garbrecht accompanied them to Madison. 
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
