<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>T39M03D16P8T2</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>West Warrens
            Mr. Carl Calloway and Marvelene and Pauline were guests Sunday at the Ike Parker home.
            Irving Blowers was a caller at the T. E. McNamer home Wednesday forenoon. 
            Callers Wednesday evening at the R. Garber home were Archie Calloway and Mr. and Mrs. Gesner Garber of Tomah.
            We are sorry to know that the Loy White children have the measles and have to be absent from school.
            Leonard Crawford was a caller Thursday at the Irving Blower home. 
            Dewitt McNamer was a caller Sunday at the home of his parents, Mr. and Mrs. T. E. McNamer. 
            
            
            East Wyeville
            Mr. and Mrs. Victor Anderson called at Chris Wind’s Sunday evening. 
            Miss Ethel Anderson and Florence Pederson attended Y. P. meeting at Carl Christensen’s on Friday evening. 
            Friends in this community were sorry to hear of the illness of Gilbert Schmeckel. We all hope he will soon be well again. 
            Herman Rutlin is having his barn shingled. Ingolf Rutlin is doing the work. 
            Florence Pederson was home last week to help her mother who was on the sick list.
            Mr. and Mrs. Albin Rutlin called at Nels Nelson’s Wednesday evening.
            Misses Vida and Viola Hansen visited at the Leo Zimmerman home Sunday evening. 
            The white of an egg will remove chewing gum from the hands or the hair. 
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
