<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>T39M03D16P8T3</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>Local Happenings
            Mr. and Mrs. Weishapple spent the weekend in Durand. 
            Miss Elsie Heppe spent the week end in Madison.
            Mr. and Mrs. Artz of Mauston were Tomah visitors Thursday.
            Miss Mary Harris is spending a few days of this week in Madison.
            Dr. and Mrs. R. I. Peck and Attorney Lawrence Clark spent Saturday in La Crosse. 
            A daughter was born to Mr. and Mrs. Howard Kuehl on Friday, March 10.
            Leonard McGinnis of Warrens spent the week end with his brother at the Harry Porter home.
            Many friends of Mrs. Reynolds attended her funeral which was held at the Methodist church.
            Mr. Frederick Elmer spent the week end at the home of his parents, MR. and Mrs. Fred Elmer.
            Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Vandercrt and daughter were Saturday evening visitors at Robert Clay’s. 
            Ten local bowlers will play in the state tournament in Janesville Saturday and Sunday.
            Mr. Dickinson and daughter, Miss Mary, of Sparta, called on Tomah friends Sunday afternoon.
            Mr. and Mrs. Lundgren of Madison called on Tomah friends on Thusday. 
            Mrs. Begelow was a dinner guest Sunday of Mr. and Mrs. Bruce Daniels. 
            Mr. and Mrs. Luen Densmore and Mrs. Emma Wilde were Saturday evening visitors at the La Vern Wilde home.
            Miss Glayds Wick of Sparta spent Sunday at the home of her mother, Mrs. Laura Wick.
            Mrs. Harry Sweet was hostess to her card club at her home on Monday afternoon.
            Mrs. Ralph Taft visited one evening at the Henry Kieger home.
            MR. Ed Can Wie and Miss Marian Van Wie, La Crosse, were callers in Tomah on Sunday.
            The ladies of St. Mary’s Catholic church will serve a desert luncheon in the church basement on Friday, March 18, at 1 p.m. The luncheon will be followed by cards. The charge will be 25 cents. Everyone is invited. Adv.
            Mr. L. J. Harper returned from St. Mary’s hospital, Sparta, on Saturday, after an illness of several weeks.
            About 35 Girl Scouts and their troop committee were guests of the Evangelical church at their service on Sunday morning.
            Mr. Robert Woodliff and Mr. Fred Giesler attended a meeting of I. G. A. dealers in La Cross Sunday.
            Mr. and Mrs. Walter Ellis of Sparta visited at the home of Mr. and Mrs. Robert W. Henry on Thursday. 
            Mr. and Mrs. Eugene Reekie visited Sunday with the latter’s mother, Mrs. Christine Gnewikow at Wilton.
            Mrs. Fred Purdy, Mrs. Vera Wildes and Leonard Wilde spent Saturday evening at the Eari Greeno home in Pine Grove. 
            A daughter, Diann Lea, was born to Mr. and Mrs. I. B. Bell Friday, March 10, at the St. Mary’s hospital, Sparta.
            Mr. and Mrs. Walter Ward and little daughter of near Clifton visited their home folks in Tomah Monday.
            Mrs. Gertrude Linehan who has been visiting at the home of her sister Miss Anna Costello, left for her home in Chicago Sunday. 
            Mrs. Ed Wilson was called to Leon last week by the serious illness and death of her father, Wm. Bell.
            Mrs. Hanson, accompanied by her son Harold Hanson of Alma Center, drove to Milwaukee Sunday to visit at the Malcolm Bin home. 
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
