<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>T39M03D16P6T5-8</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>Out In the Country with Charley
            By Chas. H. Hall
            Interesting government figures on 1938 farm incomes show that federal benefit checks sent out to farmers amounted to $196,000,000 more than in 1937/ In spite of this fact 1938 farm income was$942,000,000 less than for 1937. Still it is predicted that 1939 will be better than 1937 was. Now, butter prices have dropped two cents, to a new low of 23 cents. We all hope the new prediction comes true, but just can’t help but wonder.  
            Friday dawned with a real spring-time atmosphere. I piled into the car and started out- this time up old county “O”. I got within a stone’s throw of Arnim Gilner’s and came to the end of the trace where some woodchoppers turned into the timber. I got stuck turning around but Charles Bowers and his partner drove up just in time to give me a push. I would have been o.k. then but stopped to thank them. They gave me another push and I let them believe I was thankful that time and kept on going and soon got to Gilner’s from the opposite direction. I found Mrs. Gilner home but Arnim was over at Louis Schoot’s. Mrs. Gilner said she had not been reading this column til yesterday (Thursday). She had been over to call on Mrs. Schoot who is ill. She asked her to read the paper to her. I spent a few minutes at the barn- one of the No. 1 barns of the community. They are taking good care of about 20 or 25 head of cows and young stock, all tested and Bangs-free, besides three horses and three or four feeder pigs. There was a small flock of busy hens, just about family size, I should say. The farm is owned by Mrs. Sarah Lamb and her interests there are taken care of by her son, Eber. There is some good pine timber on the place and Mr. Gilner is getting out a few saw logs for needed repairs about the buildings and for gates. The buildings are in good shape and apparently they don’t believe in letting them run down. 
            It’s but a few steps across the field from Gilner’s over to Schoot’s so I walked ocer there instead of driving around the road. Mr. Shoot had recently tested for Bangs and with Mr. Gilner’s help was making required repairs and changes in his barn. This farm is owned by Mrs. Cars. Lea. Before I left, Mr. Gilner subscrived for the paper so they could read the news without going to the neighbors. Louis says he has read the Journal for 25 years or more. There is plenty of good pine on this farm and Louis thinks some of getting out a few logs too. 
            I got up to Ern. Snider’s just as he finished with hauling out the manure from the barn. He put the team in and unharnessed them. While he did that I looked the barn over. It’s a fine comfortable one for his 15 or more head of cattle and horses. He had two horses and says he wants to buy another. The poultry-a nice flock- he has in one corner of the barn. Only the hogs are outside. Ern. Is a canary-grass-hybrid-corn fan. He says he believes after the grass gets started that one can easily pasture three cows on an acre of it instead of having to use two to three acres for one cow, that is required of most other pasture seedings. If it works out “that’s something” for canary and marshes. For hybrid corn, he’s 100%. He said when the ears on his corn were ripe the fodder was green as grass. Also when corn was blown down so badly all around that they were cutting by hand his hybrid stood up so he cut it all with the binder. He showed me his crib of corn, and his fodder, both of which would justify his confidence in his hybrid. 
            After dinner I drove over to Ed Dams. Mrs. Dams was in bed with flu. The two girls were up, just getting over it and Ed was getting his own dinner and caring for Mrs. Dams between acts. In his poultry house he has a homemade mash feeder that he says he prefers to the commercial feeder that stands beside it. It is a long trough with a removable cover which has wire arches arranged about two inches apart for the chickens to eat through. The flock, he says, has produced about 50 % this winter. The barn isn’t a new one but is in good shape and will arranged. About 45 head of cows and young cattle furnished plenty of chores for Ed. And his hired man. Mr. Dan Sullivan. For milking they use a Surge power milker with two single units and Ed surely wouldn’t have any other kind. The farm is composed of about 195 acres rich bottom land with the crop land divided into three equal fields of about 30 acres each on which the crops are rotated-grain, corn, hay. Few farms, around here, have fields as large as this. There is more land to break up, which Mr. Dams expects to have under cultivation soon. Then he says he will arrange four large fields. Council Creek flows through the place so there is a good water supply and also city electric lighting. 
            Henry Vehmeier, who owns the place across the road, says that he has found be keeping his silage a little lower around the outside it doesn’t freeze so bad. This year, however, he says it hasn’t worked so well as the center spoiled a little when it was left high. He has a neat, comfortable place with city electric lights and water. In spite of the fact that he has but 40 acres in his farm, Mr. Vehmeier has 14 head of cattle and two horses, all in fine shape. Of course some outside land is necessary so he rents the old sawmill site from the city for pasture during the summer. 
            After getting acquainted with Mr. Vehmeier. I drove over to Ernie Schuman’s. He has a farm about a quarter of a mile off the highway at the northeast corner of the Dam’s farm. They haven’t been there but a few years and are building up as present farm prices permit. Mrs. Schuman and the youngsters were home and said they all had been having colds and the rest of the winter ills. She also said if they subscribed for any more papers they wanted the Journal. Ernest was away brushing so I didn’t get a chance to talk to him.
            I noticed farm buildings further back that I suspected to be Herman Hubert’s but as I had trouble getting to Schuman’s, thought I hadn’t better try to go further that way so turned around and got back on the main road. 
            From there I started down highway 21 toward Wyeville and stopped at Linder’s, but Mr. Linder had gone to the Co-op. Oil Association meeting in Tomah, I passed the time of day with Mrs. Linder and went on. They have a nice level farm with good buildings. 
            The next place was Mrs. Mee’s. She just went out for an armful of wood when I stopped there. She said they have lived there 23 years and managed to keep going. And thinks, although conditions are bad, it could be worse, so it we all look at that side we will get along alright. 
            Just as I approached Antone Uischner’s the kids came boiling out of the school house that is just across the road. I was a little bit late to get a chance to kid them as they were pretty well spread out when I got there. I did get a chance at one youngster later on though. He came dragging on, rather late, so I said, “Uh, ha, had to stay after school didn’t cha?” He said “Ah, I have to stay lots a times.” I picked him up and gave him a ride to the next place I stopped. 
            I caught Anton Uischner hauling manure. He was putting on the last load for the day. I hadn’t met him before and am glad I have met him now. We round during our brief conversation, that some of our opinions held quite a lot in common. He has a good level farm and good buildings. His barn is arranged handy, and houses 11 head of cattle and his horses. There’s plenty of room for them and some more. 
            I went down to Chris Linenburg’s . I’ve known Chris about as long as I have known anybody. He lives on the Wm. Puttkammer farm, renting on shares. I did not see Chris as he was away cutting wood. But the boys came to my rescue. We went to the barn where things looked good. They have 21 head of cattle and two horses, in which the oldest boy showed considerable interest. Besides these there were cats and four puppies in which the interest of the younger lad seemed to center. He offered me a pup and when I picked one, he told me that was the one he was going to keep so that deal didn’t go through. 
            I stopped at the Allingham farm next, where I found the two of them, Hugh and son Leslie, doing chores. The y have a new barn, built in 1936, after a fire that took the barn with some of the stock in it. They have a nice herd coming along again. I almost forgot that I met toward Robert Allingham, too. At least that’s what he called himself when I asked him his name. He also has some puppies. When I asked him where he got all of them he said, “Oh, we get a lot of ‘em every year.”
            On the way home I stopped at Max Neuman’s, but they were eating supper and I went home, but first argued myself into a chance to see his pigeons some other time. 
            This is about as much as the readers can stand this week, so I might as well lay low until next week. 
            Charley. 
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
