<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>T39M03D16P5T5</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>School Notes
            First Grade
            The following first graders were neither absent nor lady this last six weeks. Donald Benjamin, Anne Dickinson, Charles Henning, Grace Laudon, Arthur Sarney, Darlene Vandervort and Danny Schultz. 
            We are discussing health secrets in our language classes. We want to help each other to grow strong and healthy. 
            The fifth grade presented their play, “Hansel and Gretel” for us on Wednesday. We enjoyed it very much.
            Third Grade, Miller School
            These people have not been tardy nor absent this six weeks. Eugene Burnstad, Joann Ridgeway, John Schedler, Mary Lou Shackley, Marjorie Mae Hansen, Margaret Whisler.
            Mary Lou Shackley has not been tardy nor absent since school started. 
            We are making health posters and charts in our social studies and art classes. 
            Fourth Grade
            Wednesday, March 22, the third and fourth grades will have a tea to which all the parents are invited. The theme of the fourth grade program will be Life in Holland. 
            We were very sorry that one of our girls, Rosella Fredrickson, lost her mother this week.
            In social studies we are furnishing a doll house. 
            Fifth Grade
            Helen Muhlethaler and Winifred Taft received “Honorable Mention: cards from the Let’s Draw Radio Program.
            We have had fun getting the play, “Hansel and Gretel” ready for the P.T. A. program. Everyone in our room will help in the play. 
            Sixth Grade
            WE were very happy to hear Roger Starkey’s name announced over radio station WHA today. His drawing was among the best sent to the “Let’s Draw” program in Madison. 
            Friday, in geography class, we had “Surprise Day.” Many very interesting articles and talks were presented. 
            In reading we are enjoying the story of “The King of The Golden River” by John Ruskin. 
            We are so glad the boys and girls who were absent a part of last week are now able to be present in school.
            Seventh Grade
            In geography class we made graphs of the consumption and the production of the United States.
            In language every spring bird we see we are going to draw pictures of it and tell something about it. Robert John Maxwell reported a Cardinal yesterday.
            This six weeks we got the flag “For Punctuality and Attendance.” We are very proud of it.
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
