<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W1-1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>State Capitol Letter Wisconsin Press Association Progressive
            Filibuster Voting strictly on party lines, the senate Friday morning
            advanced to final passage the Budlong repeal hill abolishing the
            LaFollette created Wisconsin Development Authority by a vote of 20
            to 11, The senate is ex pected to complete its action of con
            eurrence with the assembly bill this week Advancing the repeal bill
            to passage, however, did not come until after senators had spent a
            full night in session. Beginning at 7:30 p. m. Thursday evening, it
            was not until 7:46 a. m. Friday morning that the vote was taken.
            Progressives who have been forced to sit by and witness the repeal
            of much of the legislation which was en acted*by the 1937
            legislature and the I9$f special session, engaged in ah futile
            12-hour filibuster against the repeal of the WDA. Although the long
            delay on the vote did not garner them a single additional vote, they
            did is a measure gain a brief respite in that! after the all night
            vigil, the majority party, Republican and Democrat coalition, agreed
            not to place the bill oni final passage, and thus the WDA lives
            another week Michael F. K resky, Green Bay Progressive, chief
            filibuster, made legislative history when he talked continuously for
            five hours and eight minutes The only time Kresky stopped talking
            was when he sipped a drink of water or when Progressive colleagues
            interrupted to Kresky’s voice a rest and to give him by way of
            questions, additional subject matter to discuss. The Green Bay
            senator's feat was acclaimed by observers to be all the more
            remarkable because he never deviated from the subject before the
            house. His voice was just as strong at 6:00 a. m. friday morning as
            it was when he began five hours earlier. Nelson Derides Governor
            Interested spectator at the senate’s all night session was Governor
            Julius Heil and several members of bit executive staff. Noting the
            Governor presence, and that he chatted with senators in the
            corridors and senate parlors. Senator Phil Nelson, Maple
            Progressive, accused the chief executive of “Huey tong tactics. “In
            all my 14 years as legislator never before witnessed the spectacle
            of a governor coming right into the legislative halls while
            Important leglslation was being discussed. That’s the way Huey Long
            used to operate In Louisiana. The governor of our state be very much
            interested in the repeal of the WDA which is doing so much to
            promote electrification for our farmers and cooperatives in
            Wisconsin* That why he's calling out senators and telling them how
            to vote,” Nelson shouted. Ironically enough, while Nelson was making
            hi* charges. Governor Julius was talking to Progressive Senator Rush
            of Neillsville. Reports have it that the senator and governor were
            exchanging farm experiences, as both were once farm boys, The
            governor left at StOO a. nt. He visited an evening session of the
            as- sembly two weeks ago, and assembly- men too wondered why he was
            there. Those close to the governor, however, point out that the
            governor is new in politics, and has never before held any political
            office, and that his visits to the legislative chambers and hearing
            rooms ate mad# because of bis interest In bis job as chief
            executive. None of the senators with whom the governor chatted
            during the evening accused the governor of trying to influence his
            vote. Short, Hectic Life If, at is expected, the senate eon- WDA,
            the Wisconsin Development Authority will Have completed a very short
            but hectic career. Designed to advise and assist municipal power
            plants and rural cooperative plants, the Wisconsin Development
            Authority, a non-profit, semi- public corporation received a $60,006
            only after a long, hard fight in the 1137 Progressive-controlled
            Legislature The all night session of last week Democrats and
            Republicans, then the minority, during the 1937 session which gave
            the WDA its first life. the gag rule in stopping debate on the
            measure. They returned to the chambers later and the measure was
            passed I I Passage of the bill and Governor La Follette’s signature
            did not mean all that was hoped for WDA. Its first vouchers for
            payment by the secretary of state were contested and finally ended
            in the supreme court where the court declared it unconstitutional.
            At a hearing by the state*s highest tribunal, WDA found life again
            as the court reversed its first decision, but restricted most of the
            activity of the department to rural electrification The second
            supreme court decision! came during the middle of June, 1938, and
            now, less than nine months later the WDA again faces death and this
            time it appears most certain and final. Arguments against the repeal
            of the! WDA in the senate were similar to those heard by assemblymen
            when they voted to repeal it weeks ago. Those for the WDA claim that
            rural electrification will suffer. Opponents of WDA say that other
            states received just as much rural electrification work (Continued
            on Page 4.)</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
