<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W2-3</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>National Affairs Reviewed by Carter Field 
            Too much build-up is turning Harry Hopkins oratorical efforts into a dud…Cutting federal expenses and balancing the budget is seen a virtual impossibility…new Deal will fell the loss of Jospeh B. Keenan's political sagacity. 
            
            WASHINGTON.—Whatever else
            may be said of Harry L. Hopkins’
            "appeasement" speech, intended to
            start the wheels of prosperity turn-
            ing again in this country and to
            pave the way to his own nomination
            and election next year, very little
            poker strategy was shown. The
            build-up was wrong. The timing
            was calculated badly. And finally,
            it became evident that Hopkins sim-
            ply does not have the golden radio
            voice of his chief.
            On this last point, one wonders If
            Mr. Roosevelt is really doing his
            Ebest by this, his second candidate to succeed him in the
            White House—whether Hopkins, like
            Robert H. Jackson,
            is not being "given
            like a candidate at a presidential convention. For
            it would seem to the casual student
            of mike oratory that
            Harry “-p-1- the President must
            have known that
            Harry was not big time so far as
            broadcasting is concerned, and that
            he could be improved quite considerably by a little training.
            Moat people, for instance, figure
            that Herbert Hoover would like an-
            other try for the White House brass
            ring, but nevertheless he did advise
            Thomas E. Dewey, just before
            Dewey entered the New York gubernatorial race, that his oratory sim-
            ply must be improved. And no one
            should know better than Hoover,
            who as secretary of commerce and
            as President was one of the worst
            ever known—until Alf M. Landon—
            but who turned himself, in the opinion of many observers, into the best
            orator the Republican party has by
            the time he had been out of the
            White House for four years.
            Promised His Head Off;
            Final Effort Became Dud
            Coming back to Hopkins strategy,
            or lack of it, it is possible that he
            could not avoid one big mistake.
            Looking at the whole affair coldly,
            it is probably that if Hopkins had
            made that same speech three
            months earlier it would have been a
            wow. The whole country would
            have talked of nothing else for
            weeks. Business would have been
            electrified. Everybody knowing
            bow close he was to the President,
            it would have marked a dramatic
            and spectacular milestone.
            What had happened in that three
            months to make it seem an anti-
            climax? To have made it, frankly,
            a disappointment to business as well
            as to Hopkins’ boosters?
            The answer is simple. There had
            been too much build-up. The trouble was that Hopkins meantime had
            been nominated for secretary of
            commerce, and had to get himself
            confirmed. Not only that, he bad
            to go far enough in his campaign
            to get confirmed to avoid any serious fight over his confirmation. Any-
            thing else might have thrown him
            off what seemed like a clear track
            leading to the White House before
            he could get steam up.
            So he promised his head off, not
            in one interview but In dozens. He
            had half a dozen "spokesmen” on
            the conservative side in the senate
            telling their colleagues, and news-
            paper men, and business men back
            home, just how safe and sane Harry
            was going to be. He was specific
            in his pledges, left nothing to the 
            imagination.	
            In fact, he said so much, and it I
            was relayed so widely, that it is no
            wonder his final public effort was a
            dud.
            Balancing the Budget Is
            Seen Virtual Impossibility
            The virtual impossibility of cut-
            ting federal expenditures and balancing the budget is clearly demonstrated in the recent senate vote
            on the proposal to cut $4,262,000
            from the TVA appropriation. It is
            significant because this was the
            most logical place for congress to
            cut this particular bill if it were to
            be cut at ail.
            The point ia that the house, in
            cutting more than four times that
            amount from the TVA appropriation, had included in the projects to
            be discontinued toe Gilbertsville
            dam, on which the government has
            already expended some millions of
            dollars, and which in addition is
            recognized by alt engineers as Important not only to toe navigation
            and flood control of the Tennessee
            river, but to toe lower Ohio and
            Mississippi rivers as well.
            In short, it is easy to see that the
            most determined man to cut appropriations in all congress might easily have been swayed to vote for
            the Gilbertsville dam money. On
            this particular point there was no
            roll call. It was approved by a
            voice vote.
            
            But the the four-million-dollar appropriation there was no such argument calculated to Appeal to toil who want to federal government
            into to bill—to go on spending—
            waa 49 to 31. A* tour additional
            Mentor* were paired In favor of
            too appropriation, toe total strength
            far It was actually 3, four more
            than a majority of too entire body.
            
            Really  Fart and Parcel
            Of Old Pork-Barrel System
            The really discouraging phase of
            the whole matter to those who see
            to* necessity of budget balancing
            has nothing to do with the merit*
            of this particular appropriation. In
            fact, it is not unfair to say that most
            of toe senators who voted for it
            were not primarily voting on its
            merits at all. Some of them were
            voting for the additional dam be-
            cause they believe in toe government going further into the electrical business. Some of them did
            so because they knew the White
            House wanted it. Some of them
            want to round out the TVA project.
            For example, had Arthur E. Morgan been a member of the senate
            when this vote was taken, he would
            of course have voted for the appropriation, despite his bitter criticisms of David E. Lilienthal, and, inferentially, of President Roosevelt, in the conduct of TVA affairs.
            But the really discouraging point
            is that it is part and parcel of the
            old pork-barrel system. It will be
            noted that the senators from many
            of the states which hope for more
            federal spending on dams and river
            control projects went along with
            the majority.
            What so many people who hope
            for economy from congress do not
            think about in their wishful talking
            is that it is good business for poli-
            ticians to spend public moneys. In
            fact, that is how politicians live.
            Sometimes it is crude, as in toe
            case of local contracts, with atten-
            dant graft. Sometimes it is more
            difficult to trace, as in toe pork-
            barrel type of federal spending.
            There toe objective ia not graft, but
            “bringing home the bacon."
            JV«c Deal Feels Loss of
            Keenan's Political Wisdom
            The stepping out of the New Deal
            circle of Joseph B. Keenan, who
            has been assistant attorney general,
            leaves really no one on the inside,
            so to speak, whose knowledge of
            practical politics and political intelligence commands very much respect on Capitol Hill, with the notable exception, of course, of the
            President himself.
            It has frequently been a matter of
            comment that Mr. Roosevelt, from
            the day he yielded to Alfred E.
            Smith's urging that he run for governor of New York in 1928, did not
            make a single serious political mis-
            take until he had entered on his
            second presidential term. It is also
            frequently pointed out that a great
            many positive actions, which were
            of the highest order of political
            sagacity, contributed to his success
            in the period a little short of seven
            years which is included in this span.
            His first political mistake, accord-
            ing to the consensus on Capitol Hill,
            was his proposal for the enlargement of toe Supreme court, made
            in January, 1937. Then followed
            the purge, and a long list of actions
            which approach the definition of an
            old-time political leader that "It
            was worse than a crime, It was a
            blunder."
            Many critics Insist that it is not
            merely a coincidence that during
            the brilliant—always measuring by
            the test of pure political Judgment,
            and not by whether the actions were
            otherwise sound or unsound—period
            Mr. Roosevelt had the advantage of
            the advice of loyal Louis McHenry
            Howe, and that the period since,
            when blunders hove been frequent,
            came after Howe's death.
            Farley Definitely Excluded
            Fram Political Councils
            Be that as it may, the administration is recognized as having definitely excluded James A. Farley
            from its political councils almost
            ever since the 1936 election.
            The President actively entered
            three of the purge contests himself.
            In one case, Mary-
            land, Farley is
            known to have
            hoped that Senator
            Millard E. Tydings
            would be defeated,
            though his judgment
            was that it could not
            be done. In fact, he
            is known to have
            told dose friends.
            during the Mary-
            primary, to bet
            Senator on Tydlngs. In the
            Tydiags other two cases
            where the President
            personalty spoke his wishes to the
            voters, South Carolina and Georgia,
            Farley not only thought the purge
            could not succeed but did not agree
            with it. In short he would have
            opposed fighting Walter F. George
            and Cotton Ed  Smith even
            it he had been sure he could beat
            them.
            Considering the whole picture
            after Howe died, and when Farley’s
            political judgment was being ignored, Joe Keenan, who was the
            ace politician of the New Deal, so
            to speak, did not make a very favorable record. But Keenan is not
            blamed for this. He did not make
            the big decisions. He simply tried
            to carry out the orders once they,
            had been given.
            Farley is not apt to regain his
            political leadership. The New Dealers regard him as a candidate for
            the presidency himself.</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
