<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W3-1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>THe Life of the Party by Elizabeth Jordan
CHAPTER Vl—Continued	
— 17—	
"I suppose," Hate went on slowly, 
"that ethically we have a duty to 
the community. We ought to show 
you up. That would mean publicity for us as well as for you, Craig. I ll 
make you a proposition. I ll give
you a week to close up your American interests and go abroad. I 
don t care where you go, or what 
you do. I’ll have a full statement  
at this Kneeland affair written out  
and signed by those whose names  
I ve given you. If you ever try to 
practice in America again, and I  
hear of your doing it. I’ll hand out  
this statement to the Grievance ;
Committee. I’m not justified in fore 
tog you on Europe, but I’ll take a
chance and Europe must take one,
too. Possibly you have learned
something by this experience. Mich
el knows ail about you and will keep
an eye on you over there, so far
as he can. He’ll keep his wise old
mouth shut unless you start some
thing. You won’t have an easy time
financially. Youll have to slave at
odd jobs to keep yourself going,
and odd jobs are not numerous in I
Vienna. You’ll be cold and hungry
many a time. When you are, took
on that experience as part of the
price you’re paying for this episode
—and thank God that you re being
let off so lightly. Now, Craig, which
is it to be? New York and exposure, or Vienna and another
chance?”
I have intended to sail for Vienna the fourteenth of July,” Craig
said stiffly. “I see no reason to
change my plans.”
“All right. I accept the amend
ment. Just to make sure I ll come
and see you off. What’s your ship?"
’’The Triest, damn you.”
"AH right,” Hale said. “Auf wie
dersehn. I ll see you on the Triest
on the fourteenth. You needn't say
goodby to Bert. He has lost  in
terest in your amenities. By the
way, there’s one more point to be
covered before you go. You say
you didn t put that dead cat in my
room. Just as a matter of curiosity
I’d tike to know whether you have
been tossing anonymous notes and
sketches in here, and poisoning the
water to my thermos bottle.”
Craig gave him a black look.
"I haven’t,” he said. "I m de
lighted to infer that someone else
has done that, f hope whoever it
is will end by wringing your neck.”
The door closed behind him.
The news of Doctor Craig’s un
explained departure from Halcyon
Camp depressed no one, nor did it
sretn to surprise his companions
there. They were, as Hale re
marked, a selfcentered lot. How
ever, they immediately observed
the amazing change in young Knee
land. Following Hale s advice, Bert
passed Wednesday in bed—supposedly nursing a cold, but in reality
enjoying nine hours of sleep. He
was dressed and downstairs in the
evening. He did not shake Hale’s
prestige as the Camp s social lead
er, but he was certainly more nor
mal and companionable than he had
been heretofore. Also his eyes had
new look, which even the least
observant of them noted.
Hale went to New York again
Thursday. He had to report the
Craig affair to Kneeland. He also
wished to get his additional finger
print reports and to learn the results of the analysis of the dregs in
hit water glass. Concerning these,
if they were important, he wanted
a chat with Doctor Dewar. All these
little matters he attended to in the
afternoon. He received some surprises in the process. He preceded
his evening report to Kneeland with
an invitation to dine with him at
the Engineers’ Club, where he gave
him a carefully selected meal. The
attention and the food pleased his
employer. It was not until they
were back In the study of the town
house that the new secretary got
down to what Kneeland called
“brass tacks.” He made his report
very seriously and In full, even re
peating all the conversations that
had taken place as accurately as
ha could.
Kneeland s reaction was about
what he had expected it to be. The
older man had been first incredulous and explosive, then amazed
and explosive, rest convinced and
appalled and at the end deeply affected, and genuinely grateful to
Hale.
“And now, Uncle Cass,” Rex said
when Kneeland had finished thank
ing him, “we’U take up your case.
In my present mood of achievement
I feel equal to anything. It isn t
quite fair that I should have to dig
for my employer s trouble as well
as for the remedy. You understand
the situation. Tell me what Ains
worth has at you. I think I can
handle him. You say it isn t black
mail, but to me it looks like Its twin
brother."
Kneeland nodded again.
“Iff about that,” he said. “I
suppose I might as well spill it to
you. It s one of those things a man j
isn’t exactly ashamed of, nor yet
proud of. It’s—well, it s just au 
man. I ll tell you the whole yam, I
since you found the other skeleton i
to the closet, I’ve got a good business reputation. I made it and Ive
got it and Ive always been proud 
of it. Perhaps I’ve bragged and i
swaggered e little. I realize that 
now, as I look back. I hadn t real 
ized it before.   give you my word
it never occurred to me that—well,
that I had a vulnerable spot like
Achilles or whatever his name was.
I’d have stood up anywhere and
asked anyone to took into my record. Yet I know now that that
pup Ainsworth could go into a court
of law and make me look like antograte and perhaps like a thief.
Sooner or later he ll do it, and I
may have to spend a small fortune
to defend myself. In the meantime,
I was fool enough to ask him to
the Camp late last summer end
again this year. He behaved himself pretty well last year. I hoped
we could get on good terms, you
see, and come to a friendly agreement. It hasn t worked out. John
Phelps, my lawyer, tells me my cue
is to ignore him till he gets tired
baiting me and settles down to money talk. Well, I m trying to do it.
But that young skunk is taking his
time.”
“Suppose you tell me what he’s
got on you,” Hale suggested patiently.
"Well—”
Kneeland had no liking for the
recital. His red face grew almost
purple as he proceeded with the
details. Hale leaned back, clasped
his hands behind his red head, and
listened to the monologue that followed. It was long and halting. It
wandered off into sidepaths of explanation and reminiscence and
selfdefense. At the end Rex nodded.
"Then it all boils down to this,”
he summed up. "Soon after you
started in Chicago to manufacture
one of your early Inventions you
met a man named George Morse.
He was by way of being an inventor, too, but his ideas were not
practical. He had patented dozens
of gadgets, none of them worth a
cent. He was likable though, and
you and he became friends. He
talked his head off about his patents. One of them and only one,
seemed to you to have possibilities.
You worked over it with him. It
wasnt yet practical but you made
it so between you and the patent
was taken out to your name end
his. You didnt make much on it—
only a few hundred. It wasnt any
thing in itself. But it really held the
germ that finally led to the development at your big success, the
Kneeland Safety Clutch. You
worked that out alone, but you told
Morse about It and showed him the
drawings. He was Interested end
enthusiastic and made a helpful suggestion or two. He was financially
down and out at the time. You paid
him cash for his suggestions, not be
cause they were worth much but
because he was broke and you liked
him. You told him that if the clutch
was a big success you would give
him a stake in It. You didn’t mention any amount or make any writ
ten promises. But he sat down that
night and wrote an exuberant let
ter quoting your verbal promise to
his only relative, a widowed sister
with a small son, who lived back
East. He also said he had helped
to work up the clutch. In his excitement and optimism—he was the
Micawber type—he claimed to have done more for it than he had done.
When he quoted your promise he
added that as he was s bachelor,
and had no notion of marrying, he
would be able to do a lot for his
sister when his ship came in. She
must have been used to his big talk,
for he was the sort that was always
seeing a fortune just around the
corner. But she needed money bad.
ly. She was sufficiently impressed
by the letter to keep it with some
others he had written her. All right
to far?”
“Absolutely. Guess I ll have you
argue the case when it comes
up,” Kneeland grinned. His deep
flush had faded and Hale was relieved to see that he was becoming
relaxed and normal again. He went
on.
“A few months after the patent
was taken out—to your own name,
of course—Morse died suddenly of
pneumonia. He was sick only four
days and doomed from the first.
You weren't allowed to see him
while he was sick, but you went to
his funeral. During his sickness
you had made sure that he lacked
nothing. He had just enough money
left to pay his doctor, but you paid
the funeral bill. Morse had left no
addresses of friends or foe He
had mentioned his sister once
or twice, but you didnt	
married name or where she lived
except that it was somewhere to
New York state. You officiated as
his friend. You saw that his grave
was marked.
“That same year your Safety
Clutch began to catch on. Things
moved fast and you had to move
with them. You moved to New
York. You made a fortune with
your clutch. You never heard of
Morse again, and you hadn’t thought
of him for years till Frederick Ains
worth walked into your office one
day last summer. He told you he
was Morse’s nephew. He said his
mother, who had died when he was
still a boy, had been Morse s only
relative. He said that in looking
ever some papers in his old family
home on the Hudson, just before his
call on you, he had found Morse s
letter to his mother, to a forgotten
drawer in her desk. He announced
himself as his uncle s heir and
claimed half the accumulated earn
ings of the Kneeland Safety Clutch.
That s the whole story, isnt it?
“Just about.”
“Well, Uncle Cass.” Hale ended,
“I’m no lawyer. But surely you
see that the fellow hasnt a legal
leg to stand on. His claim would be
thrown out of any court.”
Kneeland blinked.
“Legally," he said, “he may not
have a case. But he could easily
make an impression on a sentimental jury with his yarn, and there’s  
many a business rival of mine who ,
would be glad to believe that t did 
the Morses out of their just dues. 
And wouldnt the newspapers love
to play the thing up? Ainsworths 
got quite a social position, you 
know, even if he hasnt a cent to
bless himself with. That gives him  
some influence. What   dread most
and what he’s threatening ail the
time—is the loss of my business 
reputation. Boy, it s driving me
crazy!"
"What would you pay him to close |
up the case and clear out for good
right now?"
"He won’t do It.”
"I think he will. Will you authorize me to act For you. as you did to
the case of Craig?"
“That worked out pretty well—as
far as   can tee now.”
Hale grinned. Kneeland was al
ready on the way to the comforta
ble theory he had predicted. That
was all right. Hale himself, and
Wallace Craig and, so far at least,
young Herbert Kneeland, knew what
the boy had escaped.
“Will you leave the Ainsworth afair in my hands?" he insisted. "I'm
getting to like this nosey, busy
body stuff. How much have you offered him?"
“We never got down to figures."
“How much are you ready to give
him and may I act for you?"
"Oh, all right. But I’m not betting on you this time. We re deal
ing with a dirty customer."
“Not as dirty as the customer w«
dealt with last night. How much
can I offer him?" Hale repeated.
Kneeland hesitated "Twentyfive
thousand," he suggested without
hope.
“Twentyfive thousand a year?"
“Heavens no!" Kneeland fairly
yelped the words, "Do you want to
ruin me?” Then, discovering that
his young friend was grinning again,
he subsided, looking annoyed. Mrs.
Nash had been right Casper Knee
land was close. But no man would
have felt generous in his situation.
“Fifty thousand, maybe," Kneeland
muttered, at last.
*T don t think he’d consider it.
You admit that he can put a crimp
in your business reputation by
starting a auit and working up a
lot of undesirable publicity. I m go |
tog to ask you a leading question
How much is the Safety Clutch ■
bringing you every year in clear
profits?"
“  Bout a hundred thousand,"
Kneeland muttered.
“All right. Why not give him a
year s income and be rid of him?
I fancy he might take it."
“I should think he would!”
"What does Mr. Phelps advise?"
Rex asked
"Oh, he says we d better pay up
and forget It. He thtnks break
under the damned thing if it goes
on."
Kneeland was still trying to digest
the unpalatable suggestion of a hun
dred thousand.
“Would he take it in stock?” he
asked at last.
“I’ll put that up to him."
“It would bring him six thousand
a year. I ll guarantee that. Our 
stocks on the Curb, and it s way
above par. It wouldnt be so bad if
you could put iliat through."
 I think i can. Anyway, i ll try."
(TO to continued)
</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
