<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W4-1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>State Capitol Letter (con)
            
            and federal assistance as Wisconsin 
            did, without a 60,000 a year corporation.
            
            Teacher's Tenure Survives
            Wisconsin school teachers retained the tenure granted them by the 1937
            legislature when the state assembly
            voted 49 to 45 to kilt a hill which
            would have repealed the law.
            The tenure law provides that teachers who have served a five-year probationary period cannot be fired except
            for incompetence and inefficiency, and
            can demand a public hearing before
            the discharge is effective.
            The bill repealing the law which the
            assembly refused to engross was introduced by Glenn James. Republican.
            Defending his hill in the 31? hour de-
            bate preceding the vote on the bill.
            James charged that teachers were
            fired before their probationary period
            ended to avoid keeping them on permanently, and said “the present law
            seems to defeat its own purpose.” Defending the law. Paul Alfonsi, Progressive, said that “teachers tenure
            has given those in the profession the
            right to become spirited citizens, an
            integral part of their community.”
            There still remains, however, a bill
            which exempts one-room school teachers in rural districts from tenure. The
            bill, authored by Herbert Schenk, Progressive, had been previously killed,
            but was revived and engrossed by the
            assembly. Most of the opposition to
            tenure has come from the rural school
            districts.
            Leaves State Employment
            Wilbur G. Carlson, for the past year
            director of the Wisconsin Agricultural
            Authority, and before that director of
            the state department of agriculture
            and markets advertising and publicity
            bureaus since 1932, will leave his state
            job to take over the position of executive secretary of the Corn Canncrs
            
            Service Bureau in Chicago.
            In his new position Carlson will still
            be working for many of the state interests with whom he was associated
            as director of the WAA, because practically all of the corn canners of this
            state are members of the new organisation which he will direct. The Corn
            Cannein Service Bureau represents
            some 300 corn canneries in the United
            States.
            The WAA is another of the bureau?
            originating under the La Follette 1937 special session and its repeal is asked
            in a hill now before the senate. No
            action on the repeal has been taken as
            yet. Carlson will continue to devote
            a day or more n week to the WAA to
            complete projects now under way such
            as the diamond jubilee cheese sale, a
            sauerkraut sale and a poultry products
            sale
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
