<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W4-6</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>Notice to Farmers
            The farmers of Shawano County,
            who are in need of. one of the feed or
            crop production loans offered by the
            Emergency Crop end Peed Loan Office
            cf the Farm Credit Administration,
            may apply for such at the Court House
            in the city of Shawano on Friday of
            each week from 8 a. m. to 4 p, m.
            The Field Supervisor, Paul A. Thateher. of Waupaca, will be present at
            the time stated above to receive appiicants.
            Married applicants must bring their
            mate as both must sign the loan forms.
            They should also bring their land description, soil conservation acreage
            allotment card for 1939, and a complete description of their livestock,
            showing breed or color, age, and ear
            tag numbers or name.
            The loans will he made as in the;
            past, only to farmers whose cash requirements are small and who cannot
            obtain credit from any other source.
            The money loaned will he limited to
            the farmer's immediate and actual
            cash needs for growing his 1939 crops
            or for the purchase- of feed for live-
            stock.
            Farmers who can obtain the funds
            they need from an individual, production credit association, bank, or other
            concern are not eligible for crop and
            feed loans from the Emergency Crop
            and Feed Loan Section of the Farm
            Credit Administration. The loans will
            not be made to standard rehabilitation
            clients whose current needs are provided for by the Farm Security Administration, formerly known as the
            Resettlement Administration.
            As in the past, farmers who obtain
            emergency crop and feed loans will
            give as security a first lien on the
            crop financed, or‘a first lien on the
            livestock to be fed if the money borrowed is to be used1 to produce or purchase feed for livestock.
            Where loans are made to tenants,
            the landlords, or others having an interest in the crops financed or the live-
            stock to be fed, are required to waive
            their claims in favor of a lien to the
            Governor of the Farm Credit Administration until the loan is repaid.
            Checks in payment of approved
            loans will be mailed from the Regional
            Emergency Crop and Feed loan Office
            at St. Paul, Minnesota.
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
