<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W5-1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Local News Notes Robert and Lorry Olson mode o trip to Marinette
            Saturday. Pool Hempel, of Bimamwood, was a Saturday visitor at Bent.
            Victor Stenaon was a caller at the Con Verpoorten home Tuesday.
            Henry Janmteeh la attending an in- surance meeting in ClintonviUe
            today. Mr. and Mrs. R. Oeatreich and daughter a pent Saturday at
            Marsh- field. Dorr Hickok, of Chicago, was a visitor in the Chfts.
            Schwertfeger home last Friday. Mr. and Mrs. Ed. Meeh, of
            Clintonville, were Sunday visitors in the Blum home. Mrs. Herbert
            Haufe went to Marion Friday for a visit with relatives over the
            week-end. Mrs. George Dexter has returned here after spending the
            winter in Oshkosh and Theresa. Mrs. William Schwitake, of
            Blrnamwood, is receiving treatment at the Bimamwood hospital. Miss
            Sara Schaar is spending several days with her sister, Mrs. Herths
            Murdock, in Shawano. Avery Vose. manager of the Kraft-Phenix plant,
            made a business trip to Stevens Point Monday afternoon. Mr. and Mrs.
            Joe Thorson and child- ren, of Morris, were Saturday afternoon
            visitors in the Verpoorten home. Mr. and Mrs. Martin Stelter and
            children, Martin and Judith, of Milwaukee, are visiting In the Rev.
            Fierke home. Mr. and Mrs. Ed. Btoecher and Mr. and Mrs. Don Seefeldt
            visited at the Ed. Younk home in Green Bay on Sunday. Mr. and Mrs,
            August Bens and son Carlton and Mrs. Lorena. Hempel and Norman were
            at Antigo Wednesday afternoon. Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Wendler and
            daughters, Lucille, Ardel and Viola, and Mrs. Ed. Guerin spent
            Saturday in Antigo. Mr. and Mrs. Henry Luepke, of Bonduel.and Chas.
            Matzke and son, of Underhill, were visitors Saturday afternoon at
            the Benz home. Mrs, J. C. Johnson was a visitor in Wausau on
            Saturday, being accompanied home in the evening by her daughter,
            Aneta, who spent Sunday here. We hear that Dr. Truman Gordon, of
            Madison, will be guest speaker at the next meeting of the local
            Lions club, on the subject of the Townsend question. We are informed
            that the local Townsend club is sponsoring a full page ad to be run
            in the next issue of The Enterprise. Mr. and Mrs. Keith Dies and
            children visited lit Bowler on Sunday. Mr. and Mrs. Letand Bloecher
            and Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Bates were visitors in the Alfred Sehrank
            home In Gresham on Sunday. Miss Cerda Jacobson, a teacher in the
            ClintonviUe public schools, spent the week-end at the home of her
            mother, Mrs. Nels Jacobson, in the town of Etdcron. Mrs. Elizabeth
            Pletser. Mrs. John Barta and son John and Miss Ludwig, of Appleton,
            were Sunday visitors in the home of the former's son, Joseph
            Plesser, and family. William Arnold, who is a student at Marquette
            university In Milwaukee, arrived in town today to spend the week-end
            at the home of his parents, Mr. and Mrs. W, L, Arnold, Cleve Guerin
            made a business trip to Rhinelander on Monday. He represented the
            county board at the meet- ing held there to discuss relief matters
            in northern Wisconsin. Harold, Robert, Lyle and Larry 0lsen, Kathryn
            Guerin and Carl Olson spent Sunday at Three Lakes. Larry, who Is
            employed at a resort near . Three Lakes, remained up there. George
            Overen returned to hit home in Bimamwood on Saturday from the :
            Veterans' hospital at Wood, after spending the past three and
            one-half months there recovering from a serious operation. As we go
            to press we learn that William Schoepke passed away at his home in
            Crandon on Sunday. He was 73 years of age and the oldest brother of
            Henry and Ed. Schoepke, of this community. Quite a number of
            relatives left today to attend the funeral. We expect to run the
            decedent’s obituary next week. Mr. and Mrs. Jack Krohn and son ' of
            Crandon, were Sunday visitors with ' her parents, Mr. and Mrs. Frank
            Hdlstrom. Mr. Krohn, who operates the Crandon Ben Franklin store,
            plans to erect a new brick and tile building, 33x25, in that village
            in the spring. Mr. Krohn is president of the local Badger Theatre
            Inc. The board of directors of the Homme Home for the Aged held a
            regular quarterly meeting on Tuesday at the office of the manager,
            Rev. H. M. Mason. The following directors, Rev. O. O. Sovde,
            chairman, of Scandinavia, Arne Johnson, secretary. Rev. W. A.
            Johnson of Rosholt, A. W. Miller, of Sturgeon Bay, and John Englund,
            were present and transacted routine business. Mrs. Sovde and Mrs.
            Englund accompanied their husbands as guests at the institution.
            Miss Gladys Lunde and Miss Eva Drew, who have both been employed at
            Homme Orphan Home, discontinued their positions March . They spent
            about ten days at the Otto Lunde home near Elderon and then left
            last Saturday via bus for St. Paul, Minn. Miss Lunde has been at the
            Home for five years and seven month. Her work there consisted of
            baking bread, etc., for all the children and employ- ees,
            supervision of the dining room and laundry, and she was assistant
            cook, substituting in the regular cook’s (dace during her time off.
            Miss Drew was employed as secretary and stenographer in the office.
            8he is well known in this community, having attended High School in
            Wittenberg. Both young ladies were members of the Luther League and
            L, D. R. of First Lutheran Church. We received the following
            communication from Mrs. Nels Jensen, of Chicago, concerning her
            granddaughter: "On February 26th, Joan Carol Chapman, age 4, sang
            and named 40 popular numbers after hearing a few bars on the piano.
            She sang “You’re a Sweet Little Headache” on Rubin’s Hour of
            Opportunity radio program, winning first prize. She received a
            professional engagement on Rubin’s “Stars of Tomorrow” broadcast on
            March 6, at 7:6 in the evening over WCFL. She also received a
            beautiful Benrus gold watch. She can name over a hundred popular
            numbers when just a few notes are played. 8he also sings many of
            them. Many who have heard her predict a future in the world of music
            for Joan Carol. She also sang on Morris B. Sack’s radio program on
            August 28. She is the daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Russell Chapman, of
            Chicago.” </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
