<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W5-2</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Dr. Srolle was a supper guest at the I Indian Mission Thursday
            evening. Mr, and Mrs. Conrad Verpoorten attended a birthday party at
            Surland Thorton’s Saturday night The Lutheran Social Club met this
            afternoon with Mrs. Rine Brehmer. Mrs. Henry Wolff received the
            prise. A number of friends gave Robert Olsen a surprise party
            Saturday eve- ning, the occasion being his birthday, Mr. and Mrs. R.
            G. Peterson and daughter Priscilla were supper guests of Rev. and
            Mrs. E. W. Sihkr Friday evening. Mrs. Earl Gates entertained her
            bridge club Thursday night. Prizes went to Mrs. Rudolph Hanson, Miss
            Leona Schwertfeger and Mrs. Carl Hanson. Mrs. Henry Wolff
            entertained her bunco club Thursday night. Prises went to Mrs.
            Edward Bloecher, Mrs. Albert Gunderson, Mrs. Paul Kusserow and Mrs.
            Rine Brehmer. The Tuesday Afternoon Bridge Club met this week with
            Mrs. Walter Netsel. Prizes were won by Mrs. H. E. Kersten and Mrs.
            Rudolph Hanson. Mrs. Harry Hoppe received a guest prize. Mrs. Palmer
            Wahl was pleasantly. surprised Saturday afternoon on her birthday
            anniversary by a large group of ladies from the Morris community, A
            gift was presented and lunch was served by the ladies. Mr. and Mrs.
            Reuben Balke, Mr. and Mrs. Asa Balke, Reinert Laude and Miss Anita
            Westphal, of Pella, and Mr. and Mrs. Louis Gerret and Louis and
            William Balke, of Embarrass, visited in the Roland Jesse home on
            Saturday, the occasion being hit birthday anniversary. A number of
            Wittenberg players attended tKe card party in the Community Hall In
            Shawano Tuesday eve- ning. Forty five tables of bridge, skat and
            schafskopf were in play. Mrs. Ed. Rosenow, of Shawano, won the
            five-tube radio, the grand prize. Among the other dozens of winners
            were Mrs. Walter Netzel, of this village. The proceeds will be used
            to further the conservation program in Shawano county. The Bethany
            Indian Mission Circle met with Miss Anna Mathison Tues- day
            afternoon. Members worked on pictures for the Indian homes and
            hemmed handkerchiefs for the school children. The following program
            was given: Hymn; devotions by Mrs. C. C. Petersons piano solo. Ruby
            Sundet reading, Mrs. P. A. Wahl; piano duet. Ruby Sundet and Janet
            Vollmcr; piano solo, Janet Vollmer; closing hymn. In the absence of
            the president, Miss Anna Mathison took charge of the program and
            brief business meeting. Mrs. Art Lai son read two very interesting
            letters which recently arrived from Miss Helen Frost, missionary in
            igloo, Alaska. Miss Frost reports a very severe winter with
            considerable illness among the natives. The Mission Circle decided
            to send Miss Frost an Easter greeting and will perhaps send gifts to
            Alaska for the natives in igloo for next Christmas. The next meeting
            of the Mission Circle will be held April in the home of Mrs. Val
            Meckes. </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
