<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W5-5</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>FOREST VIEW Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Schaar and eons visited the Albert
            Kutchenriter’s Friday evening. Mr. and Mrs. Chris. Kading and sons.
            Oscar and Lawrence, visited at the August Schumacher home Sunday
            evening. Mr. and Mrs. Charles Carlson and children visited at the
            Gust Carlson home Sunday evening. Leilia Carlson spent Saturday at
            the Gust Norrbom home at Elderon. Mr. and Mrs. Otto Wendler and
            daughters, Margaret and Alvina, and Mr. and Mrs. Melvin Fuhrman were
            dinner guests st the Clarence Wendler home on Sunday. Mr. and Mrs.
            Stanley Westgor and daughter Betty visited at ths Fred Hansen home
            in Morris Sunday after- noon and evening. Mr. and Mrs, Cleve Guerin
            and family and Mrs. Ed. Guerin and son Edward visited in the
            Clarence Wendler home Sunday evening. Mrs. Gust Carlson and son
            Everett visited Mrs. Charles Carlson on Friday. Doretta Guerin
            visited school on Tuesday afterboon. Lecss than fifty per cent of
            our school enrollment wet present on Tuesdsy due to the unfavorable
            weather. HELLO. WORLD! Born to Mr. and Mrs. Earl Oim, Bimamwood, on
            March 6, a daughter. Bora to Mr. and Mrs. Robert Klitska, town of
            Hutchins, on March 2, a ton.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
