<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W5-6</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>WAYSIDE SCHOOL Mr. and Mrs, Art Schaar and sons visited at the Jake
            Bernards home Sunday evening. Art Schaar and Earl Nelson Jr. visited
            Bernard Carlson Saturday after- noon. Theodore 8chear was at
            Tigerton Saturday with John Hellstrom. Earl Nelson and children
            visited at the Art Aanonsen home Sunday after- noon. Mr. and Mrs.
            Tom Swenson and Laura Rasmusaon were Sunday after- noon visitors at
            the Homme Orphan Home. Mr. and Mrs. Rudolph Schoepke and family were
            callers at the Ed. Schoepke home Sunday afternoon and eve- ning, Mr.
            and Mrs. Art Grimstad and daughter Betty called st the Heldtborne
            Sunday evening. Margerle and Carol Kaufman were Sunday afternoon
            visitors at the Clarence Simonson home. Mr. and Mrs. Fred Dahlen of
            Rosholt visited at the Art Arnonsen home Sunday afternoon. The
            school board met at the A. R. Aggen home Friday evening. Mr. and
            Mrs. A. R. Aggen and daughter Arvtlls were Antigo callers Saturday.
            Mrs. John Liesch visited with Mrs. Bradendick at the Aggen home.
            Esther and Earl Anderson and Lawrence Buck visited at the Ed.
            Kaufman home Thursday evening. Mrs. Lawrence Buck and daughter Diana
            returned to the home of Eugene Buck. Mr, and Mrs. Ed, Kaufman and
            Patsy, Phyllis and Peter, and Art Carlson were at the Eugene Buck
            home Saturday.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
