<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W5-7</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>BUNGALOW SCHOOL Mrs. Mary E. Day has returned from White Lake where
            she visited for several weeks At the home of her daughter, Mrs.
            Peter Metelski. Mr. and Mrs. Joe Stoltz and daugh- ter of Ringle
            called at the Gust Hanke home Thursday. Mr. and Mrs. Julius Nevinskl
            and children were Wednesday evening vis- itors at tho L. H. Brehmer
            home. Ray Fenske has returned from a visit at Waupun. Mr. and Mrs.
            Lester Kasson and children of ClintonviUe spent the week- end at the
            Gust Hanke home. On Sun- day Mr. and Mrs. Kasson and Mr. and Mrs.
            Marlyn Hanke visited at Antigo. Mr. and Mrs. Ed. Ullenbrauck of
            Ringle also called at the Hanke home on Sunday. Mr. and Mrs. Julius
            Nevinski called at the Max Ssews home Saturday eve- ning. Neighbors
            gathered at the Fred Fenske home Sunday evening. Cards were played,
            after which lunch was served. Last Saturday evening {he gathering
            was held at the Gust Hanke home. Arthur Petersen, Alfred Hegewaid,
            Ray Vanderkooy, Elroy Peterson and Billie Burnett visited at the
            Harry Vanderkooy and Vernon Petersen homes at Menasha Sunday.
            Rupert, Ernest and Lorraine Stews. Ethel and Leonard Brehmer and
            Joyce Jacobsen attended a program at the Elderon State Graded School
            Monday evening. </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
