<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W7-1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>Floyd Gibbon' Adventurers' Club
            headlines from the lives of people like yourself!
            "Fanged Death"
            Hello, everybody:
            Distinguished Adventurer Graham Babcock of Paterson,
            N. J., takes the Adventurers' club rostrum today, and Graham
            wins ten bucks because he wouldn’t take another fellow’s advice.
            If he’d done what that fellow told him to he'd have had no story j
            to tell us today. But Graham paid no attention to that fellow,
            and the result is one of the most thrilling, blood-curdling adventure yarns I’ve seen in a coon's age.
            It was in August, 1913. Graham was just seventeen years
            old, lived in Suffern, N. Y., and spent his spare time hunting in j
            the Ramapo mountains, in season and out. At the time, hunting |
            was out of season, so Graham carried his rifle in a gun case and
            took along a fishing basket, just in case he happened to meet up
            with a game warden. Game wardens can put you in the jug
            for hunting In August, but there's no law against fishing for
            minnies at that time of year.
            Graham started out up the tracks of the Erie railroad and walked
            as far as the Ramapo crossing. From there he planned to cut into the
            mountains, but the crossing tender, an old friend of his and an old-timer
            in that section tried to dissuade him. ‘‘There's a rattlesnake den just
            up the side of that gully,” he said, "and rattlers are mean at this time
            of year. Belter go in up the track a ways.”
            Graham Unknowingly Walks Into Nest of Snakes.
            But Graham had seen rattlers before and he wasn't afraid of them.
            Whenever he'd come on them they had always wriggled out of sight
            as fast as they could. He forgot, though, that a nest of rattlers in the t
            late summer season might actually be LOOKING for trouble.
            Graham climbed up the side of the hill and walked along a ridge
            until he came to a place where a big boulder jutted out over the edge |
            of a small cliff. There wasn't a rattler in sight, and he began to think I
            he must have passed the nest the crossing tender had spoken of. He j
            saw some berry bushes a few yards away and set his gun and fishing i
            basket down on the boulder while he climbed up to pick a few berries.
            But Graham never picked so much as a single berry. The minute he
            reached for them, things began to happen.
            As he stooped down to part the leaves of the first bosh, a
            rattler shot oat from beneath It and landed almost at his feet.
            Graham leaped back. As he did, the shirring ruffle of another
            rattler sounded from a niche in the rock just over his head.
            Then, all at once, that sound wee repeated from a dozen directions. From the right. From the left. From behind him! The
            sound swelled Into a low, ominous hum.
            Graham realised, then, that he was right In the middle of that
            nest of vipers. Be took a quick step forward—and stopped dead
            In his tracks. “A big one lay right in my path," he says,
            "coiled and ready to strike, its whole body swelling and deflating
            with anger, as If it were being blown up by a bellows. Its tall
            sounded its threatening war-note end Ha bead was Battened and
            drawn back far the kill. I tried to back up, and right behind me
            near a rotted tree trunk another one reared its head and rattled
            and hissed.
            “Talk about things flashing through your mind! In a split second
            I remembered everything I had ever heard about rattlers. I remembered
            my grandfather telling that this was the worst time of year to be bitten,
            for in late August when the rattler is about to seek his winter quarters
            his venom is twice as poisonous as it is at other times. And I remembered hearing that the speed with which the venom takes effect depends
            on where you are bitten. My uncle once told me of a woman bitten in
            the breast who lived just 17 minutes.”
            Those thoughts went through Graham's mind in just the smallest
            fraction of a second, and they stirred him into action. Over his head
            was a tree limb. He leaped for it, caught it, and swung out from be-
            tween the snakes that hod him cornered. He landed in an open space,
            grabbed up a stick and began flailing the bushes to right and left. “I
            made for the boulder where I had left my gun and fishing basket,”
            he says, “still beating frantically with my slick. Another snake struck
            at the stick, and I threw it away as hard as 1 could and tore through
            the bushes like a madman.”
            Suddenly He Heard Another Low-Pitched,'Ominous Hum. .
            Graham reached the boulder where be bad left his gun, out
            of breath and shaking like a leaf. He had hart his knee In his
            mad scramble through lira brush and now, believing himself out
            of danger he sat down to look it over. And then, suddenly, he
            heard another low pitched, ominous hum.
            Says he: “I looked	back	over	myshoulder just in time to see
            another big rattler leap at me. How I ever did it I'll never know, but
            from a sitting position, without getting to my feet, I actually jumped
            three feet to one side, and the snake missed me by a foot. It knocked i
            over the basket and landed coiled right on my gun case. I ran to the ;
            left edge of the boulder and broke a limb from a green sapling as if i
            It were a pipe-stem. I saw the infuriated snake make ready for another 
            strike and I knew it wouldn’t miss this time.
            "Behind me was the Cliff. In front of me was Hie snake, and
            I couldn't get off the boulder without getting In range of its strike.
            Then I saw two other rattlers edging up to Join in the attack,
            and although it was a terrible Jump I preferred the cliff to death
            by snake-bite. I hesitated only an Instant, hoped for the best,
            and leaped into apace."
            The top of a cedar tree broke Graham's fall. He landed in a bed
            of pine needles below it and he says he fairly bounced as he landed.
            "Luck was with me," he says, "and the only injuries I suffered were
            the terrible scratches on my body, arms and face. I went home leaving
            my gun and basket right where they were, and I didn't go bock
            for them until after cold weather set in and the snakes were all holed
            up In their winter quarters."</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
