<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W7-5</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>What to eat and Why
            C. Houston Goudiss Reveals Several Reasons Why Food Sometimes Disagrees; Warns against eating when tired or worried
            C Houston Goudiss
            A GREAT many people have the unfortunate habit of
            warning friends and acquaintances against this or that
            food, on the ground that it is "difficult to digest,” or “is
            almost sure to cause digestive distress, especially if eaten at
            the wrong time of day or in combination with the wrong
            foods." Indeed, to hear some men and women recount the
            various dishes that are
            left alone, is to wonder how
            they manage to find anything
            to eat at all, in view of the
            many good foods they consider taboo!
            Certainly there is no objection to
            food as the topic of conversation.
            It is so basic to
            good health that it
            should be upper-
            most in the mind
            of every individual
            who desires to pro-
            mote physical and
            mental efficiency.
            And it is also natural for n person to
            be guided by past
            experience in determining what he
            should eat, and
            What it may be advisable for him
            to avoid.
            But It is a grave mistake for
            Me person to wars another
            against any food or combination
            of foods on the ground that it will cause digestive distress. For the
            truth of the matter it that under
            proper conditions, a normal,
            healthy person should have no difficulty in digesting almost any
            food that has a place to the well-
            balanced diet.
            Food Dislikes Often Unfounded
            1 once met a woman who told
            me that her contented-looking husband could, and did, eat most everything except horseshoes. Menu
            planning was simple for her! And
            how different from the problems
            of the home-maker who must try
            to reconcile her menus, both with
            the food dislikes of various members of the family, and with the
            foods that they declare they can't
            eat, for fear of digestive distress.
            It is true, of course, that individuals differ greatly, and occasionally a food that can and should
            be eaten regularly by most people, will cause distress in on individual case But that is no indication that the food will have
            the same effect on another per-
            son. and it is misleading either to
            proffer or accept advice of this nature from friends.
            It may be that the victim has
            an allergy to the food in question
            —that he reacts to it differently
            than the majority of people. But
            there is also the possibility that
            the prejudice exists because of
            some previous distress, caused,
            not by the food itself, but by the
            circumstances under which it was
            eaten.
            Perhaps a dearer understand-
            ing of some of the mental and
            physiological factors Influencing
            digestion would dispel many of
            the bugaboos that cause people to
            avoid various, wholesome foods
            and food combinations, and to
            warn others against them.
            Emotions Influence Digestion
            Scientists have established that
            the stomach is capable of reacting
            to almost every emotion and sensation that is experienced by men
            and women. Thus, how you eat
            becomes quite as important as
            what you eat. And any food or
            combination of foods consumed
            when you are tired, worried or
            angry, may cause acute distress,
            whereas the same food, when eaten at another time, may be digested without Ute slightest disturbance.
            This indicates the folly of jump-
            ing to the conclusion that you
            can't eat this or that, and shows
            that one is scarcely justified in
            warning friends or relatives to
            avoid certain articles of diet.
            There is a large amount of evidence that fear, anger or anxiety
            have the effect of diminishing the
            gastric secretions, and further, of
            arresting or slowing down the
            movement of the intestines.
            If food is eaten under these conditions, it may remain stagnant
            in the alimentary canal, with the subsequent formation of gases and
            decomposition products. But instead of recognizing the true cause of the trouble, many people erroneously blame the food itself!
            I Medical men have frequently
            noticed that people often develop
            gastric disturbances when they
            suffer financial reverses, and continue to suffer from them until
            their financial condition improves
            a striking demonstration of the
            importance of banishing fear and
            worry
            Never Eat When Tired
            Almost any food may cause dis-
            tress when one is suffering from
            fatigue. So it la unwise to sit down
            to a large meal when exhausted
            from too much physical or mental
            work. A brief rest before eating
            will put the body in much better
            shape to receive and assimilate
            the food.
            Then. If the meal Is served In
            pleasant surroundings, and if the
            food is flavorful and well cooked,
            the chances are that It will be digested satisfactorily by all normal
            individuals.
            Be Tranquil at Mealtimes
            In view of the fact that tranquillity af mind is essentia! to the
            proper utilisation at feed, hememakers should remember never
            to discuss unpleasant subjects at
            meal times. Don’t nag  children about eating, or choose that
            time to discuss their lapses from
            discipline. Don’t talk about
            finances or lake up real or fancied
            grievances with your husband. Let
            such matters wait until the meal
            hat been digested.
            If these suggestions were more
            generally followed, it Is almost
            certain that we would hear much
            less conversation about foods that
            cause distress, much more whole-
            some talk about the pleasures of
            the table.
            Questions Answered
            Mrs. G. M, B.—Perhaps the
            most important single improvement that could be made in our
            dietaries would be to include more
            calcium-rich foods. So many of
            our staple foods are poor in calcium that a diet may be abundant
            and varied, and stiff lack this bone
            and tooth-building substance. In
            general, milk is the best source
            of calcium and should be the cornerstone of the diet. Fruits, vegetables and eggs also help to in-
            crease the supply of this mineral
            which has such a far-reaching effect upon health,
            Mrs. J. H. L
            It is a fallacy to
            believe that hot foods supply much
            more heat to the body than chilled
            foods. In cold weather, we may
            prefer hot foods because they give
            an immediate sensation of
            warmth. But the temperature at
            which food is eaten has little bearing upon the heat or energy value
            it contributes to the body. The
            I most ‘'heating” foods are those
            that contribute the most caloric
            value. Fat takes the lead in this
            respect, because it is the most
            concentrated form of body fuel
         </p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
