<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_minimal.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_minimal.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B39M02D22</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>VOL. LXXXIII
m n t v 'l n v m l
KN IG H TS H A V E SUCCESSFUL
OPEN HOUSE
There was a fine attendance last
Thursday night at the open house
held by Knights o f Pythias members
for the organization and friends.
There were over 70 in attendance.
The occasion marked the 75th anniversary
o f the organization o f the
lodge. The meeting was to have been
called at 8 p. m. and previous to that
games o f Chinese checkers, cribbage
and 500 were enjoyed by the guests.
A fine lunch was served by a committee
composed o f Lloyd Helbling,
Arthur Hortum and E. J. Manthe.
The main speaker o f the evening
was Rev. Gee, o f Sparta, who delivered
one o f his inspirational talks, this
time on Pythiasm. Horace Sherwin
officiated as master o f ceremonies,
and others on whom he called were
who responded with short talks were
Archie Haralson, Charles J. Bowlen
and Milton Hauge. The latter, by
the way, has never missed a meeting
o f the lodge since he joined about two
and a half years ago. Horace Sherwin
and C. W. Helbling were the
members o f the general committee in
charge o f the meeting. Mr. Helbling
gave a short talk on his trip to the
Rathbone memorial in upper Michigan
at the time it was dedicated in
1930. He had gone as a representative
o f the local lodge.
Rev. Gee was accompanied here by
Chancellor Commander Hotvedt, o f
Sparta, who was called on for a
short talk and also invited the local
lodge to Sparta Tuesday o f next week
to put on the rank o f knight work.
BLACK RIVER FALLS, WISCONSIN, FEBRUARY 22, 1939
MRS. GEORGE HORNE D EATH OF BR YA N J. CASTLE
Mrs. George Horne, widow o f the i A T AG E OF 90 Y EARS
late Dr. George Horne who practiced j Bryan J. Castle, for many years a
medicine here for a number o f years, | resident o f Black River Falls, died at
died at the home of her only son, C. ' his home in Madison, Friday, Febru-
E. Horne, o f Lancaster, Sunday, ary 17, 1939, after about a month’s
February 19, 1939. She has been j illness. He had reached the age o f
failing in health for some little time 90 years July 15th last, at which
but with great courage refused to time considerable publicity was given
NUMBER 8.
MR. AN D MRS. DAN LAU GH NAN
CE LE B R A TE GOLDEN W EDDING
Mr. and Mrs. Daniel E. Laughnan,
o f Irving, celebrated their golden
wedding anniversary Surday, February
19, 1939, at their home in the
town o f Irving. The standing they
have in the affections o f their friends
was shown by the fact that in spite
o f the fact that the roads were almost
impassable on account o f ice, and
that it was a very cold day, 38
friends came to help them make a
gala occasion o f the day.
Miss Caroline Overlien made a
beautiful wedding Miss Julia Clausen, who has been cake and wa--s- --i-n
a guest for nearly two weeks at the I frla e ° the table, which was beauhome
o f Misses Mary and Jane Spaul- t»fully decorated with the cake for a
ding, returned to her home in Chicago,
yesterday. She has been a guest
at a number o f affairs while here,
centerpiece. Nothing is too much
work for Miss Overlien if she thinks
she is doing something for somebody
given in honor o f her approaching ? un a7 was undoubtedly another
marriage, which will take place April
15th. Mesdames E. E. Ringrose and
Philip Mills were hostesses Thursday
at a dessert luncheon for her, followed
by contract bridge. Miss Jane
Spaulding was high lady in bridge,
Miss Claussen received the second
prize and also a guest prize. She was
a dinner guest Thursday at the home
o f Mr. and Mrs. Duane Hoffman. Friday
Mrs. Richard W olff gave a tea in
her honor. Saturday Mrs. M. C. Neeley
gave a dessert luncheon, followed
by bridge. Miss Julia Bright was the
winner o f the prize for high score,
Miss Mary Spaulding received consolation.
Miss Claussen was presented
with a guest prize. Saturday night
Mesdames D. M. Perry and Mahlon
o f those days. We have no doubt
but what her contribution added
greatly to Mr. and Mrs. Laughnan’s
pleasure in the day.
Mr. and Mrs. Laughnan were married
February 19, 1899, by Father
Flock, o f Sparta, in St. Patrick’s
church in that city. For a time they
lived with Mr. Laughnan’s parents
and then moved to the farm they
have since occupied. Mr. Laughnan
has been an active farmer until recent
years. He is 79 years old and
is enjoying the best o f health. He
has an interesting hobby, that of
raising strawberries.
Mrs. Laughnan has not been so
well of past years, having suffered of
high blood pressure which makes her
a partial invalid but does not stop
her from her chosen pastime o f makink
quilts.
There are eight children in their
fine family. Willie and Leo operate
the farm ; Dannie, o f Melrose; Grace
of Milwaukee: Mrs. Ruth Loper, o f
West Allis: Mrs. Florence Fela, of
Washington, D. C .; Thressa and Ed
na at home. They have four grandchildren.
Their daughters from away
were not with them Sunday, but a
long distance telephone call from
Miss Grace and Mrs. Loper pleased
them very much.
Mr. and Mrs. Laughnan received
some fine gifts from relatives and
friends and a purse o f money from
their neighbors, for which they were
very grateful. They wish to thank
one and all for their very happy day
and especially Miss Overlien and her
helpers. Many friends who were unable
to be with them Sunday on account
o f the roads, join heartily in
a wish for many happy returns o f the
day to this worthy and highly respected
couple.
Mrs. A. J. Roiseland is nursing a
broken right arm, as the result o f a
fall on the steps o f her east porch
about a week or so ago. The top
step was covered with ice, with a
, , . , r x little snow on it, and although she
Richards entertained at dinner at the was exercising the usual care, she
Perry home, followed by contract
bridge. Miss Claussen, who thought
she was attending a bridge club meeting,
was very much surprised and delighted
by a shower o f bathroom
gifts. Miss Jane Spaulding was the
winner o f prize for high score for the
evening. She was entertained at dinner
Sunday at the home o f Mr. and
Mrs. John H. Mills, where 17 sat
down to dinner. Miss Claussen is
marrying Clyde I. Bowman and will
make her home in Portland, Oregon.
Albert Knutson, who has been a
patient at the Grand View hospital
in La Crosse for the past seven weeks,
was able to return home last Thursday.
E. S. Jedney drove to La
Crosse for him and took him to the
home o f his brother in the town of
Springfield, where he will convalesce
for a week or so before returning to
town. Mr. Knutson enjoys an acquaintance
throughout the county
since serving as county treasurer for
numerous terms and his many friends
are glad to learn that he is improved
enough to return home again and
trust that he wil! have no further
recurrence o f his illness. Mr. Knutson
makes his headquarters at the
Freeman hotel while in town.
Mrs. Carl Danielson is slowly improving
following a serious illness
last week, in which she suffered a
slight attack o f pneumonia complicated
by bronchitis. Her daughter,
Mrs. Herbert Koenig, o f Menominee,
Michigan, who had Tjeen spending a
couple o f weeks in Illinois with ner
husband, arrived here Thursday and
remained to take care o f her mother.
Mrs. Jack Adams and son Bud, o f La
Crosse, were up Wednesday night to
see her.
slipped and fell, striking her hip but
fortunately not breaking any bones
except in her arm. Both bones were
fractured near the wrist. It is rather
hard to learn to get along without
your right hand, especially when living
alone, but Mrs. Roiseland is doing
pretty well with a little help. Her
friends are glad that she was not hurt
more seriously.
Mrs. Sadie Castle, o f Chicago, attended
the funeral service o f the late
Bryan J. Castle in Madison Sunday,
and accompanied the funeral party
here Monday for the service at Riverside.
The others o f the party returned
to Madison that afternoon but
Mrs. Castle remained at the home of
her sisters, Misses Mary and Jane
Spaulding until Tuesday noon when
she returned home by train with Miss
Julia Clausen, who had been a guest
at the Spaulding home for the past
couple o f weeks.
Mr. and Mrs. J. K. Van Etta are
arriving home today from Emporia,
Pennsylvania, where Mrs. Van Etta
has spent the past month with her
parents, Mr. and Mrs. J. L. Lingle.
Mr. Van Etta went east a week ago
Monday in response to a message
from Mrs. Van Etta stating that her
mother was seriously ill. Later reports
are that her mother is improving
and Mr. and Mrs. Van Etta are
expected to reach home today.
George Dettinger and Douglas
Curran were visitors in Madison on
Thursday o f last week. The former
visited his daughter, Miss Dolores,
and also spent a little time 1 stening
in at a session o f the legislature. He
met his cousin, Will Dettinger, also
visiting the legislature that day. Mr.
Curran attended a meeting o f the
state fair board directors which was
held there that day.
Mrs. Ward Waterman went to Milwaukee
Monday to spend a little time.
She had been in Milwaukee before ______________
for rest and treatment, as she was j Mrs A len MacVeyj formerly Miss
not at all well and as l n£ as she | gerena Hess, was guest o f honor at
stayed home insisted on overdoing. a party last night, given at the Friends are pleased to learn that she Rr£hn 'h i t a nurses- home by Mrs.
is feeling ever so much better and | Marjorie Meyers and Missec Hazel
hope that she will soon be home again olson and XHe,ma Larson. It was a
taenrdm afene. liwnhgo qhuaidte shucehr seal fl ongM rs.e nWouas- oenf Jjo yae bNleo aaf faci,ru ba nwd erteh e pumeesmts-.
illness, is also feeling much better. acV ey was presented with a
Miss Marion Printz came from | £ ft as a remembrance o f the
Madison Friday and returned Sunday, | occasion. _____________
after a visit in Melrose at the home | Jud and Mrs Harrv M Perrv 
aonfdJ hbr ro t*hTe°rt,h wW arrernS.‘ She lh as; com-’ | KEmerim, itG HGailnbseornts, (mM. rfsr.o mC ahrle rCe,a dabnvd.
pleted her course in nursing but is | Robert Hamilton, o f Merrillan, went
continuing to add to her training and ------
work for a degree at the University
o f Wisconsin. She hopes to complete
the work in a couple o f years more.
She was a visitor in town Saturday
afternoon.
Monday was Katy McCallum’s
birthday. She celebrated the day by
entertaining eight little friends at an
after-school party at her home. Her
guests brought lovely gifts, most o f
which will keep a little 7-year-old
girl busy for a long time. Present
at the party were Carol Jean W oodford.
Carol Wang, Sylvia Moen. Mary
Lou Davidson, Hope Widmar. Jackie
Jones, Marilyn Hagen and Ramona
Holmgreen.
Downs Castle o f Cleveland, Ohio,
was in Madison Sunday to attend the
funeral services o f his uncle, the late
Bryan J. Castle. He desired to remain
over and come here for the
interment service Monday but was
obliged to return to Cleveland as soon
as possible. Mrs. Castle’ s mother has
been very seriously ill, and her condition
still is critical.
Will Marsh came from Neillsville
Friday, and Saturday he and John
F. Marsh went to Eau Claire to visit
their brother. Judge A. J. Marsh.
Will Marsh returned here to assist in
the final preparations for the opening
o f Biggar’ s store this week.
Mr. and Mrs. E. E. Homstad were
in Milwaukee last week attending a
lumbermen’s meeting, held there.
to Whitehall Friday to attend a regional
pension meeting arranged by
the Wisconsin Public W elfare department.
Mr. and Mrs. Nick Kocum. o f
Melrose, were visitors in town Saturday.
Their daughter and son-in-law,
who have been farming with them
are moving the first o f March to the
Louis Grinde farm in 'the town of
Franklin, and Mr. and Mrs. Kocum
are thinking o f selling their farm.
Mr. and Mrs. Stanley Lund stoptied
off Wednesday to see Mr. and
Mrs. Ralph Lund and their little son.
David Ralph. They continued their
iournev to their home in Minneapolis,
Thursday morning. They Tiad spent
about three weeks, and enjoyed a trip
to Mexico City.
Mr. and Mrs. Louis Gardipee and
little daughter are attending a Gamble
store convention being held in
Oshkosh. They went over Saturday
and returned last night. Their baby
daughter. Joan, was a guest o f Mrs.
George Ness during their absence.
Miss Lucile Olson, o f Galesville.
has been eiven the position in the
rural rehabilitation office. left vacant
bv the resignation o f Mrs. Lloyd Gilbertson
recently. Miss 01'on was
formerly employed in the R. A. o ffices.
Miss Evelyn Snowden left Monday
for Chetek. where she will be a
guest o f Miss Jeanette Konkol.
GOM ER-HEINE
Miss Evelyn Gomer, daughter of
Mr. and Mrs. Albert Gomer, o f this
city, was united in marriage February
3, 1939, at Sullivan, Wisconsin,
to Walter Heine, o f that place.
The bride was bom and grew up in
Pine Hill, and came here with her parents
when they moved to the city.
She graduated from high school here
a few years ago. Last spring she
went to Oconomowoc, where she has
since had employment. Mr. Heine has
employment in Sullivan, and his home
is near there. He and his bride will
make their home in Sullivan.
Mrs. Heine, accompanied by
friend, came here and spent a week
at the home o f her parents. Last
Wednesday afternoon a shower was
given in her honor at the home o f her
parents, which was attended by many
of the old friends from Pine Hill.
There were 42 present and a fine
kensington dinner enjoyed. In the
evening friends again dropped in to
present her with shower gifts. She
and Miss Wagner left on the bus that
night to return to their homes.
Friends here join in wishing Mr.
and Mrs. Heine happiness.
M ARE K -V ALEN C E
Miss Rose Carol Marek, daughter
o f Mr. and Mrs. Charles Marek, and
Henry Valence, son o f M r and Mrs.
Joe Valence, o f this city, were united
in marriage February 20, 1939, at
Decorah, Iowa.
There was a family gathering in
their honor at the Cliarles Marek
home in Hatfield Tuesday evening,
just before the opening o f Lent.
The groom is engaged in trucking
in B. R. Falls, foreman o f the Wausau
Sand Gravel Company. He and
his bride will make their home in
Wausau. The young people have a
wide circle o f friends who join in
wishing them happiness.
KAM PEN-BU E
Miss Adeline Kampen o f Disco, and
Winifred Bue were united in marriage
at Winona, Minnesota, February
11, 1939. The service was performed
by Rev. Wine, o f the Lutheran
church. They were accompanied
there by the bride’s mother, Percy
Kampen, and cousin, Miss Irene Kersting.
The bride is a daughter o f Mr. and
Mrs. Nick Kampen, o f Disco, and Mr.
and Mrs. Bue are making their home
there for the present. They were
given a charivari by their friends at
the Kampen home Monday night.
Friends join in wishing them happiness.
PRE STO N -BA LL
Dorothy Preston, daughter o f Mr.
and Mrs. Roy Preston, o f Hixton, and
Ross Ball, son o f Mr. and Mrs. Arthur
Ball, o f this city, were united in
marriage February 6, 1939, at Waukon,
Iowa, by Rev. Lee Davies o f the
First M. E. church. A wedding dance
was held Wednesday evening to which
a nice crowd attended. They are living
in this city, where Mr. Ball is employed.
Congratulations are extended for a
a long and happy future.
An application for a marriage license
was made Friday at the office
o f County Clerk Hans K. Hanson,
by Miss Sylvia A. Thompson, daughter
o f Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Thompson,
o f this city, and Walter La Fave,
son o f Fred La Fave, o f Iron Mountain,
Michigan.
Mr. and Mrs. Einar Skar and little
daughter, Jean Karen, o f Birchwood.
were house guests over the week end
at the home o f Mrs. O. E. Wang.
They were en route to Chicago for a
week’s visit with relatives and friends
there. Mr. Skar is a brother o f Mrs.
Wang.
Mrs. Lloyd Gilbertson, who recently
returned home from the hospital
following an operation for acute appendicitis,
has been confined to her
bed for several days bv an attack of
pleurisy. She is improving at this
time.
MRS. H UBERT JOHNSON
There was shock and sorrow among
the family and friends o f Mrs. Hubert
Johnson, o f Disco, formerly Miss
Margaret Johnson, o f this city, when
it was learned Thursday morning,
February 16, 1939, that she had died
following the birth o f a little daughter
at 11 o’clock the previous night.
give up to her illness. Mr. and Mrs. to the occasion and to his unusual I The baby is being cared for at 'the
HH norrnn oe rc»as»mm ea ttno LI-aa (C,rrnosssspe , wwhhoerroe schlieo j IhtAenall+tVh. and activity -ffo__r_ __o_n__e o. rf hi• s - _____1 _ i i , . .
had been staying at the home o f Mrs. years. His brilliant mind functioned
J. R. Ogden and Miss Grace for the | as actively as it had when he was
past year or so, and took her to Lan- much younger.
caster about a month ago. She had | Funeral services were held at 2 o ’-
since been confined to her bed, and clock Sunda at the Masonic temple
nothing could be done for her. ! in Madison, Arthur W. Quan conduct-
A funeral service was held at 10 ing the "Masonic service for Madison
o’clock Tuesday morning at the Hos- j Lodge No. 5, o f which Mr. Castle was
kins Funeral Home in Lancaster, and a member. He had been a Mason
the remains were brought to the j for 57 years.
Keefe Ness Funeral Home here ! The remains were brought here by
where a service was held at 3 p .m . car, Monday, and a commitment ser-
Rev. H. A. Allison was a charge o f | vice, under the auspices o f the local
the religious service and the Eastern | Masonic lodge, was held at Riverside
Star service was given by members I cemetery. Rev. H. A. Allison was
o f the order here. There were two | in charge o f the religious service and
lovely duets_by Mrs. H.. H. Richards j Lawrence E. Jones o f the Masonic.
hospital, where she was born, and is
doing nicely.
and Rufus Dimmick, with Mrs. Jennie
White at the piano. Many friends
from here were in attendance. Those
who came from away were Mr. and
Mrs. C. E. Horne and daughter, Beverly,
o f Lancaster; Mr. and Mrs. R.
J. Beranek, Mrs. Anna J. Farnham
and Mrs. Mary Bleadsa, o f La Crosse;
Mr. and Mrs. A. J. Farnham, of
Portage.
Emma Carson was born November
13, 1865, in Danport, Maine. She
was married March 3, 1887, to
George Horne, at Auburn, Maine. In |
1908 they moved to Wisconsin, where j
Dr. Horne practiced medicine for a j
time at Milwaukee, later at Durand I
for a year and at Owen for a time,
moving to Black River Falls in 1913
and continuing to practice here until
his death, November 28, 1920.
One son survives this marriage;
Clarence E. Horne, who for the past
20 years has been living in Lancaster
where he is connected with the highway
department. She also leaves
three grandchildren, Beverly, Donald
and Robert. Since Dr. Horne’s death
Mrs. Horne has divided her time between
La Crosse and Lancaster. Last
summer she visited her old home in
Maine. During the Christmas holidays
she was a guest at the home of
Mr. and Mrs. E. S. Jedney, o f this
city, and has visited here at intervals
during the years since she moved
away. JShe was held in fondest affection
by all who knew her and had
made many close friends in La Crosse
and Lancaster, where her personality
had won for her the same lasting
friendships she leaves here. The sympathy
o f all goes to her son and his
family as they mourn her loss.
BOY SCOUTS TO RECEIVE
EAGLE BADGES
Eighteen Boy Scouts o f Gateway
Area Council will receive their Eagle
badges at the annual banquet Monday
evening, Feb. £ 7 , at La Cros6e.
About 400 are expected for the banquet.
Judge M#rv£i B. Rosenbfcrry,
o f Madison, Chief Justice o f the state
supreme court, is to be the speaker.
Four Scoutmasters’ keys will be
awarded. No awards to our county
this time.
Following are the boys winning
their Eagle badges: Robert Stuckey,
Arnold Sorenson, Henry Stephenson
and Richard Lofgren, Arvid
Olson, John Gueltzow, Perry Anderson
and William Krismer, all o f
La Crosse; John Bates, William Dorval,
Caledonia; Robert MacCornack
and Ardell Paulson, Whitehall; Robert
Sweeney, Scoutmaster, and Kenneth
Doans, Sparta; Reid Perry,
Mondovi; Jack Lake and George
Michel, Prairie du Chien.
Interment was made at one o’clock.
Mr. Castle’s only daughter, Miss
Mildred A. Castle; Mrs. Sadie Castle
o f Chicago, and Mrs. Kennedy, of
Madison, were the members o f the
family who came here for the service.
Others o f the family who attended
the service in Madison Sunday were
Mr. and Mrs. Spaulding Castle, of
Chicago; Miss Margaret Castle, of
Champaign, Illinois; Downs Castle,
of Cleveland, Ohio; and Dr. R. W.
Baldwin, o f Viroqua. Miss Castle
and Mrs. Kennedy returned to Madison
Monday afternoon. Mrs. Sadie
Castle remained until the next day at
the Spaulding home.
Mr. Castle came to Jackson county
as principal o f the Merrillan schools
more than 65 years ago, and soon
afterward established the Merrillan
Leader there. A few years later he
came to Black River Falls as owner
and publisher o f the Wisconsin Independent.
From here he went to
Madison as chief clerk in the state
land office, returning in 1901 to engage
in the practice o f law, first as _
a partner with George E. Waldo as i town o f Alma, and her last school
Funeral services were held Sunday
afternoon at the home in Disco, and
at the Little Norway church. In spite
of the fact that it was a cold day and
the roads were sheets o f ice, there
was an attendance o f friends which
filled the church, the social rooms
in the basement and overflowed the
outside. Even bad roads did not prevent
friends from paying their last
tribute o f respect to Mrs. Johnson.
Rev. A. M. Romstad conducted the
service and preached an eloquent sermon.
The song service was given by
Mrs. M. H. Moen, who sang “ Face
to Face” and “ In the Garden” , and
Rev. Romstad sang “ God Will Take
Care o f You.” Mrs. Esther Peterson
played the accompaniments. Lawrence
and Arthur Nelson, Richard Weckwerth,
Philip Monsos, Osborne Johnson
and Norman Larkin officiated as
pall bearers. The many beautiful
flowers were in charge o f Mrs. Hazel
Wold Fields, Mrs. Helen Larkin
W oelffer, Misses Ruby Stamstad and
Florence Gullickson. Miss Gullickson
came from Menomonie and Mrs.
Woelffer from Sparta for the service.
Interment was made in Little Norway
cemetery.
Margaret I. Johnson, daughter of
the late Hans A. and Berthilde Johnson,
was born in Black River Falls,
July 25, 1909. She attended school
here, graduated with the class of
192T and after completing the course
in teachers’ training taught school
very successfully in Jackson county
for ten years. She taught in the
Sunnybrook, Valley View and Tindahl
schools, all in the town o f Cleveland,
the Houghtonburg school in the
FIRST COUNTY 4-H CLUB
LEADERS M EETING
The first county 4-8 Club leaders
meeting for 1939 wil be hed at the
court house on Salturday, March 4th,
at 10:00 a. m. W. McNeel, assistant
state club leader, will be here to discuss
club work and any changes in
the projects for 1939.
All adult and junior leaders are
invited to attend and to bring any
older club members whom they think
might be interested in the meeting.
Since older club members often serve
as assistant leaders during the year
we should give them every opportunity
to learn more about the club program
through our leaders meetings.
Arrangements are being made for
group dinner at 12:00 m. followed
by a short program of 4-H club
moving pictures or a talk by Mr. McNeel.
It is hoped that all leaders will attend
this meeting in order that we
may set up a definite organization
for our 1939 club program.
Castle Waldo, and later with his
late son, Sydney H., as Castle Castle.
He continued to practice here
until 1908 when he moved to Madison
to accept a position in the state service,
in which he continued until recent
years.
Mrs. Castle died November 6, 1923.
He is survived by one daughter, Miss
Mildred A. Castle, who lived with
him. She has the sympathy o f her
friends here, who share in her feeling
of thankfulness that she had a long
life with such a fine father.
The following story from the “ Wisconsin
Public Employee” gives a very
complete picture o f Mr. Castle’s long,
interesting and busy life.
Many persons enter the public service
for a short time; some men devote
an entire lifetime to such a career.
An outstanding example o f a
career within the state service here in
Wisconsin is that o f Bryan J. Castle,
former member o f the Wisconsin
Civil Service Commission. Mr. Castle
when he retired from active duty on
the commission in 1931 had been in
the state service for 33 years. He
served 19 years in the Department of
Public Lands under two appointments
(1882 to 1890 and 1899 to 1918);
two years in the Adjutant General’s
office during the World W ar; and
12 years as a member o f the state
Civil Service Commission (1919 to
1931).
Besides these appointments, Mr.
Castle also served on numerous special
commissions, the most important
one relating to the Swampland Grant
under Governor Davidson. Mr. Castle
REPUBLICAN R A LLY
FR ID A Y N IG H T ______
Attention is again called to the also taught for seven years in rural Fairchild.
Republican rally, to be held Friday j schools o f the state, beginning his
was the Disco graded school, where
she was teaching at the time o f her
marriage. She was fondly regarded
among all who knew her in the various
districts.
She was united in marriage December
26, 1937, at the Lutheran parsonage
in this city, to Hubert Johnson,
o f Disco, who survives and is
deeply affected by his loss. She also
leaves her little daughter, Margaret
Ruth Ann, her mother, Mrs. Berth ilde
Johnson, sister, Miss Jeanette,
and brothers, Philip J. Johnson and
Oswald H. Johnson, all o f this city.
The sympathy o f the many friends
o f the family has been doubly extended
for Mrs. Johnson has been
prostrated by the death o f her daughter
and has since been confined to
her bed with every care and attention
being exercised in her behalf.
Margaret will be sadly missed.
She was a lovable character, quiet
and unassuming. The strong bond
existing in her home continued after
her marriage, and her plans and happiness
in her new home were shared
by her family. She was a devoted
wife, a loving daughter and sist?r.
She was a member o f the Lutheran
church.
The heartfelt sympathy of all goes
to her bereaved husband and baby,
her mother, sister and brothers.
Among those o f whom we have
learned from away who attended the
funeral were Mr. and Mrs. Theodore
Bloss, o f La Crosse; Mr. and Mrs.
Henry Halverson, o f Mineral Point;
Mr. and Mrs. Mike Bowler, o f Sparta:
and Mr. and Mrs. William Radatz
and Mr. and Mrs. Beckett, of
night of this week at the New Free- first term at the age o f 17 after passman
hotel, where a banquet will be ing the customary teacher’s exammserved
at 7 o ’clock. Tickets for the 1 ation in Richland county. Altogether
his years as a public employee number
more than forty.
banquet are $ 1.00, with half of the
proceeds going to the county fund.
Carl Taylor, a Democrat, from Mil- Wa a Pioneer New.paperman
waukee, will give a talk at the meet- .
ing following dinner. He is said to! between his appoint
be a very fine speaker. If the crowd ; ment.s 1.n„ theJ ate Caf tle
warrants the lecture will be held at ! sP?nt
the. Falls theatre, otherwise it will
take place at the hotel.
All who are interested are given a
cordial invitation to be present.
Mr. and Mrs. Duane Hoffman and
daughter Janet, and Mrs. J. O. Nordin
went to Madison early Tuesday
morning and spent the day.
in various journalistic enter-
His first connection with this
profession came in his early youth
when he worked for a few months at
a job printing office in Cincinnati.
This job he gave up to accompany a
F R E A K CA LF BORN IN IRVING southern group o f Union refugees
A freak calf was bom last Friday , into the turbulent South o f the Civil
on the Charles Posvic farm in the j War days. He attempted a journal
town o f Irving. We have heard o f o f his own in 1869 when he set up
freak calves before, but never o f one the Lawler (Iow a) Gazette.
quite so unusual as this. bought an interest
Later he
in the De Sota
The calf had one head and one 1 Leader here in Wisconsin. He was
tail and eight legs. It apparently was
not premature but was fully developed.
Its four regular legs were normal
size but the extra set were
slightly smaller. It is difficult to
describe, but apparently there was a
Siamese twins effeet and they had
grown in much the form o f a pair
o f gloves clasped with the palms together.
The head o f one calf was out
o f sight in the chest cavity o f the
other calf. They did not live.
also associated at one time with the
Prairie du Chien Union and is the
founder o f the Merrillan Leader,
which he started over fifty years
ago. At the beginning o f the century
during the gubernatorial campaign,
and first term in office o f “ Bob” La
Follette as governor, Mr. Castle was
part owner o f the famous old Madison
newspaper “ The State” , a Republican
weekly. At one time he also
owned a half interest in the Wisconsin
Journal o f Education, and he has
edited for a short time both the Wisconsin
Independent and the Algoma
(Iow a) Times.
A good many persons in Madison
Mrs. Lewis Hobbs, o f Fairchild,
was able to return home following an
operation at the hospital for removal
o f a goitre. She had stayed at the _ ____
hospital for several days before the know "Mr. Castle aYieast by sight. He
operation, to get rested for it. s a tall man, slightly stooped, with a
Mrs. Mildred Burckhardt spent ° P ur! " j ” * - ........ — - ~ ~ r " V ------------ v "
several days last week at her home Hill for the past couple o f years, has
in Boscobel, attending prenuptial par- j whlte eyebrows frame his clear blue been m o f pneumonia, but is getting
ties and wedding o f a friend. | (Continued on page 4 ) I along nicely toward recovery.
HANS H. IVERSON
Hans. H. Iverson, o f Taylor, died
list night, February 21, 1939, at the
hospital where he was under treatment
for a serious heart trouble.
Members o f his family were called
here yesterday by his critical condition.
Funeral services will be held at 2
p. m. Saturday, at the Taylor Lutheran
church.
V E R Y COLD AND ICY HERE
For the past week there has been
a sheet o f ice over everything, and
travel has been so difficult that it is
a wonder there are not more accidents.
Apparently the ice sheet extends
as far north as Augusta and as
far south as below Tomah.
Saturday, February 11th, it was 16
degrees below, and a maximum o f 8
that day. The temperature slid up to
18 above the next day or so, but was
11 below on the 15th, and 16 below
on Thursday and Friday o f last week.
Saturday it was again 18 above, and
Sunday 25 above. Monday was two
below again, yesterday 7 below and
this morning it was 8 below at the
Ranger station. This should interest
our citizens who are spending the
winter in a warmer clime.
Mr. and Mrs. Robert Mills, accompanied
by Misses Phyllis Pongratz,
Ethel Gilbertson, Mildred Linder and
Gladys Olson spent last Wednesday
evening in Baraboo, guests at the
home o f Mr. and Mrs. Bob Peck.
Charles Annis, who has been staying
at the Alex Vance home in Pine
W O M A N ’S CLUB PRESENTS
COLORFUL P A G E A N T
T1?e ®rama department o f the
Black River Falls Woman’s club presented
“ In An Antique Shop” Monday
night at the high school auditorium.
Proceeds o f the entertainment
will go toward the health program
being sponsored by the club. Mrs.
Bert F. Johnson was the director o f
an may well feel satisfied
with the results o f her work. It was
a beautiful production. The setting
consisted o f a collection o f antique
furniture and bric-a-brac collected
from Black River Fals holmes.
It was a cold night and the streets
were covered with ice. In spite o f
these two disturbing facts there were
over 250 in the audience that night.
It was a star audience so far as attention
was concerned for seldom has
a program been given the close attention
that was accorded this one.
All and all it was a lovely entertainment.
The program opened with three
songs from the Schubert club, under
the direction o f Rufus Dimmick. They
sang Schubert’s “ Serenade” , Krone’s
“ Hiking Song” and Speaks’ “ Morning.”
It was their usual finished and
pleasing performance. Miss Vem a
Carlson was their accompanist and
she also played a violin accompaniment
during the music furnished by
the Woman’s club chorus, which sang
under the direction o f Mrs. Irwin
Krohn with Mrs. Esther Peterson as
accompanist. There were two numbers
by the trio, composed o f Mesdames
Thomas Mills, Irwin Krohn
and Duane Hoffman, and a solo by
Mrs. Thomas Mills during the program.
The music contributed a great
deal to the effect o f the program. It
had been arranged by Miss Verna
Keefe. The chorus was out o f sight
o f the audience.
Miss Ruth Ann Bailey, cast as a
modern girl in a shop o f antique furniture,
carried the theme o f the
pageant. At the close o f each episode
she told o f each antique that
inspired the reverie about which the
theme was woven. Her performance
was particularly good. The same may
well be said o f those taking part in
the 13 episodes, each o f which made
a beautiful picture.
The general committee in charge
o f the program was: Mrs. Adolph
Borufka, Mrs. P. W. Dickey, Mrs.
Mason Werner, and Mrs. Erwin Homstad.
Mrs. Jack Sypulski was chairman
o f properties and Mrs. I. S. Hollenbeck
o f tickets.
The Woman’s club wishes to thank
all who loaned costumes, and stage
properties, Mrs. Johnson for her successful
directing, the school for the
use o f the auditorium and for mimeographing
the programs, the Schubert
club for its songs, and all who contributed
to the evening’s program.
LEW IS JOHNSON LOSES
HOME BY FIRE
Lewis Johnson has his good home
entirely destroyed by fire Monday
morning. He lives near the Pole
Grove school house in the town o f
Hixton, about a half mile from the
Lien Hatchery.
The fire started about 8 o ’clock in
the morning from an oyerheated
chimney. Neighbors gathered to do
what they could toward getting it under
control and although the Hixton
and Alma Center fire trucks were on
the job it was impossible to save the
house. However, most o f the contents,
and even some o f the doors
and windows were salvaged.
Mr. Johnson had remodeled his
house within recent years, and it was
a comfortable and attractive home.
It is a real loss at this time o f the
year especially, and he has the sympathy
o f his many friends.
TW O HOMES BURNED
The Matysek home, six miles south
o f Fairchild, burned Saturday and
not very much was saved. John Matysek
was away at the time and his
son and wife, Mr. and Mrs. Ed Matysek,
had gone to the Watson home.
There had been a fire in the chimney
the day before and it is thought that
it must have been left defective.
The Earl Bemis home at Humbird,
located on the southeast edge o f town
burned about ten o ’clock Monday
morning. A few clothes were saved
and some o f the contents o f the basement.
There had been a chimney fire
there on Friday.
This is a very cold time to be left
without a home, and their friends extend
sympathy to the families who
lost theirs.
CO-OP. PEOPLE PRESENT
“ THE SPIDER W E B ”
“ The Epider W eb” , a three-act
plav will be presented Wednesday
night o f this week at the Falls theatre
and Saturday night at the York Community
hall at the meeting o f the
Farmers Union, and Friday night at
Alma Center high school gymnasium.
The play is being directed by Mrs.
Tom Stodola and Mrs. Richard Faldet.
A complete list o f characters
will be found on the special Co-op
pages this week. It promises to be
an interesting entertainment.
SUNDAY EVENIN G PROGRAM
There will be a program in the
Lutheran church Sunday evening at
8 o’clock. Rev. A. J. Bringle, of
Taylor, will be the speaker. In addition
to this there will be a hymn sing
and other special numbers. You are
cordially invited to attend this service.
MERLIN H O RSW ILL MOVING
BARBER SHOP
Merlin Horswill, who has had his
barber shop located in the Avalon
block for some years past, will move
the first of March to quarters in the
lower floor o f the Freeman hotel,
with entrance on the west side.
A fine time was had at the V. F.
W. Auxiliary “ 500” party. Bert Sanford
was high for men and Oswald
Young low. For the ladies, Mrs.
Francis Hagen was high and Mrs.
Nellie Tester low. An excellent lunch
was served by the committee.
Dudley W. Jones has been confined
to his home for the past week or so,
quite seriously ill o f an attack o f
erysipelas. His many friends will be
pleased to learn that he is responding
to treatment and is on the road to
recovery.
Miss Blanche Overlien and Miss
Alice Myhrom came from Rochester
to spend Saturday and Sunday at the
form er’s home iiT Irving.
PAGE NO. 2 THE BANNER-JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin W ednesday, February 22, 1939
JULIUS DIETRICH DIES
IN W ASH ING TO N
Julius Dietrich, a son ot the late
Henry and Mrs. Susie Dietrich, residents
for many years o f the town of
Albion, dropped dead on a train in
Washington, D. C., on February 1st,
1939. He was 67 years old. Interment
was made in Fort Lincoln
cemetery, Washington.
News o f his death was received by
a message to his niece, Mrs. William
Rozmenoski. Mr. Dietrich has stopped
off to spend a little time with
them on many occasions recently and
her little daughter had received a
long letter from him from Washington
about the time the message announcing
his death was received.
Mr. Dietrich was born in the county,
his family living for many years
in Cloverdale and the home farm is
now occupied by his brother, John.
He was one o f six sons. He is survived
by his widow, one son, Richard.
His mother, Mrs. Susie Dietrich,
lived in Richmond, Washington,
with her son, Louis. Two other brothers
survive— William, o f Owen, and
Samuel, o f Los Angeles. His brother
John is now in the west, visiting his
mother and brother Louis, and will
go from there to Los Angeles to see
Samuel.
Mr. Dietrich was president o f the
Dietrich Dry Milk Company, o f Sheboygan,
where he made his home.
He had perfected a milk drying process
which he was putting into use in
steadily advancing quantities. He had
installed a plant in New York and
was engaged in installing one at
Washington at the time o f his sudden
death as the result o f a heart attack.
MOTION M ADE FOR
NEW DIETRICH T R IA L
Judge Emory W. Crosby, o f Neillsville,
held circuit court here for motion
day last Wednesday. He took
under advisement a motion for a new
trial in the case o f Mrs. Clara Dietrich
vs H. G. Kilstofte, Winona, which
was presented that day.
A motion for change o f venue to
Milwaukee county in the case o f
Schultz vs R. C. Hartmann was denied.
Out o f town attorneys present were
Charles Gorman and Leroy Michel, of
Milwaukee; Thomas Holland, Eau
Claire; Harold Wilke, Madison;
Lawrence Brody, La Crosse; Charles
P. Curran and Henry Rowen, Mauston.
The annual guest day party o f the
Clio club was held last Wednesday
evening at the Freeman hotel, and
was attended by 97 o f the members
and their guests. Dinner was served
at 7 o’clock. The table committee
had used a valentine motif in their
plan o f table decorations with red
roses and white sweet peas for centerpieces.
Following the first course
there were two fine solos by Joe
Johnson, young Winnebago baritone,
who has a peculiarly pleasing voice.
He was accompanied by Miss Verna
Carlson, who also played the accompaniment
for two xylophine solos
played during the last course by Miss
Betty Trimm. They were both fine
numbers, very well rendered, and
very much enjoyed by the audience.
After a social half hour during which
the dining room was prepared for
cards, the remainder o f the evening
was spent at bridge and Chinese
checkers. Mrs. C. L. McDonald was
high and Mrs. Jay Jorgensen low at
auction bridge, and Dr. A. S. Trondson
high and John Bolger low for the
men. Mrs. Duane Hoffman was high
and Miss Harriet Bright low for the
ladies playing cantract, and Robert
Sechler was high and Dr. Robert
Krohn lew for the men. Mr. and
Mrs. Robert Iliff captured the honors
for Chinese checkers. Mrs. R. M.
Matteson was chairman of the general
committee in charsre o f the party,
which was a very pleasant affair.
SINGER Sales Service
by Representative H. E. Kaun
Hancock Hardware Co.
Complete Service on Singer and e t h e r
Makes. Also Used Machines fo r Sale.
A T T O R N E Y VIC TO R STOLTS
VIC TIM OF H EA RT A T T A C K
There was general regret among
his many friends here when news of
the sudden death of Attorney Victor
Stolts, a former resident o f the county,
was received. He is a son o f Mrs.
Rose Stolts, o f Sechlerville.
Funeral services were held in Eau
Claire Tuesday and the remains were
brought to his home at Sechlerville,
where services are being held today.
Members o f the American Legion
from the Eau Claire, Taylor, Alma
Center, Hixton and Black River Falls
posts will be in attendance. Bishop
Wilson, o f F v t Claire, officiated at
the service tnere and is also officiating
at Sechlerville today.
He is survived by his mother, sister,
Mrs. Erwin Bills, o f Sechlerville,
uncle, Charles Stolts, also o f Sechlerville,
and three nephews, Wendelll
Ashton, o f Ypsilanti, Michigan and
Donald and Millard Bills, o f Sechlerville.
The following is taken from the
Sunday Milwaukee Journal.
Victor M. Stolts, 47, widely known
Eau Claire lawyer and American Legionnaire,
died late Saturday o f heart
disease at a Wausau hospital.
Stolts was taken ill Friday while
on his way to Wausau. He recovered
but suffered a relapse Saturday
morning.
Stolts was tenth district commander
o f the legion and a form er Eau
Claire county and post commander.
When the state legion convention was
held in 1935, Stolts was chairman.
In the World war, Stolts was regimental
sergeant-major in the judge
advocate general’s department at
Camp Grant, 111., after enlisting at
Madison.
Stolts was active in the Republican
party. He served three terms as district
attorney, starting in 1920. He
was the party’s candidate for congress
in 1928. In 1934, he won the
Republican nomination, for attorney
general, but was defeated in the general
election. He also had served as
Republican county chairman.
Stolts was unmarried. He is survived
by his mother, Mrs. Rose Stolts,
o f Hixton.
BO Y SCOUT TRO O P 58
Boy Scout Troop No. 58 met in the
basement o f the Methodist church on
Feb. 15, 1939. The meeting was
opened by saying the scout oath and
pledge o f allegiance to the flag. Mr.
Richards then led us in song. Mr.
Mac Vey then took over the business
meeting. The plan o f each scout
bringing 5 cents a week was brought
up. This was voted upon and carried.
The patrol leaders were then elected.
They are as follows: David Noble,
Bob Squires and Ronald Anderson.
Each leader got four boys. David Noble
got Lyle Strausberg, Dean Allison,
Allan Danielson and Bob Bright.
Ronald Anderson got John Noble,
Frederic Field, Clifford Manthe and
Don Holder. Bob Squires got Billy
Squires, Keith Allison, Hugh Trask
and Harold Dunn. Mr. Pratt then led
us in games. The meeting was then
closed by singing taps.
NOTICE TO T A X PA Y E R S
OF BLA CK RIV ER FALLS
The tax roll is in my hands for
collection. During tax collection time
I will be at the city clerk’s office the
first ten days o f each month and
every Saturday.
ROSE MCDONALD,
2-7w City Treas.
TO IRVIN G T A X P A Y E R S
The tax roll for the Town o f Irving
is in my hands for collection. I
will be at the Black River Falls Implement
Co., in Black River Falls,
every Saturday anl the last two Tuesdays
in the month o f February.
PALMER MIDTLIEN,
4-5w Treas. Town o f Irving
NOTICE O F SEALED BIDS
Sealed bids will be received on my
property in Taylor, Wis., consisting
o f house, garage, barn and lots.
The bids will be open until Feb,
28, 1938. The owner has the right
to accept or reject-any or all bids.
Mail bids to owner,
O. O. LOVAAS,
6-3w Litchville, North Dakota
MRS. MITCHELL TALKS
ON TRAVEL
Mrs. Nellie Nelson Mitchell has
been interesting numerous audiences
in the county with her interesting
Travel Talk, which is a result o f three
years she spent in Europe. The title
o f her talk is “ Three "iears in Europe
on Three Hundred Dollars” , and
opens up avenues o f thought. She
tells interestingly o f her experiences.
Mrs. Mitchell talked to a group of
club women at the circuit court room
in the court house, Monday afternoon
at 2 o ’clock. That evening she addressed
a large group at the regular
meeting o f the D9rcas society. On
Tuesday she went to Melrose where
she spoke at the high school, including
adult visitors as well as students. Friday
afternoon she spoke to Mrs. Olson’s
history classes at high school
here.
While here Mrs. Mitchell was a
guest o f her cousins, Mr. and Mrs.
Olaf Nelson and also visited her cousin,
Mrs. Fay Button and Mrs. Theo.
Bullock, at Melrose. Accompanied by
Mrs. Nelson she went from here to
Taylor where they visited Mrs. Anton
Prestlyken and Mrs. Rena Odemark.
She will return to Minneapolis,
and from there goes to North and
South Dakota to fill engagements
with her Travel Talk. She has almost
finished writing a book on her
three years travel in 15 different
European countries which she plans
to publish in the fall.
Misses Rena and Othilda Olson, o f
whom she was a schoolmate, entertained
for her Friday afternoon, and
Friday evening Mrs. Matt Christianson
entertained in her honor.
COMMON SENSE CO N SERVATIO N
(B y L. H. Kingston)
Right now our “ conservation frontier”
is at Madison where the legislature
is in session. One o f the bills
that have been introduced would, if
enacted, shake our conservation structure
to its very foundation— I refer
to Mr. Berquist’s proposal for a one
man conservation commission. Then
there are proposals that are very desirable
such as the bill for a universal
fishing license and the public
shooting grounds bill. Will the bad
bills be killed and the good bills be
enacted, that is the question.
Our legislators are not all
hunters and fishermen, neither is
every one o f them familiar with conservation
problems but they certainly
all realize the importance o f conservation
to Wisconsin. Each one o f
them will tell you that he welcomes
advice from well informed sportsmen
in his precinct on these conservation
issues. It is the truth— and I wish
to emphasize this— that one letter favoring
a good bill or opposing a bad
bill written to your state senator or
assemblyman may be o f far more
benefit than all the other conservation
work you do the rest o f the
year all put together. This column
will continue to keep its readers informed
on all the more important
bills being introduced, the hope being
that sportsmen will take proper
action to protect their own interests.
Assemblyman Budlong o f Marinete
has come forward with a bill that
says “ A licensee shall immediately a fter
killing and taking a deer, attach
his deer tag thereto, and thereafter
shall not hunt for the remainder o f
the open season for hunting deer.”
Judging this bill from a strictly
conservation standpoint one must admit
that it would limit the kill o f
bucks to some extent and thus be
o f benefit to our deer herd. This column
has always maintained that the
welfare o f our deer should be considered
first, hunters second; so perhaps
we should support this bill.
But we are not in favor o f Mr.
Budlong:s bill and we have just one
reason. Deer hunting has always been
the choice recreation o f a large group
o f citizens; farmers especially are
strong for it because it comes at the
only time o f the year when they can
get away from the farm. If a hunter
gets his buck the first o f second day
o f the season from then on he helps
his companions fill their tags. Should
you then ask him what he’s doing,
he will tell you he’s bear hunting” .
Everybody stays with the group helping
the last man o f the party get his
deer and they all have a grand time
together.
Perhaps this last man helped drive
out the deer that made the other
hunters successful— would it be fair
to make them all go home and leave
this last man to hunt alone? That
is just what Mr. Budlong’s bill would
do.
There is no place quite so lonesome
as a deserted hunting camp and
even one or two o f the boys pulling
out for home early spoils the fun for
those remaining. They lose their enthusiasm,
spirits are dampened and
vacations are spoiled. We learned
long ago that the deer hunters who
have the fun are the groups that stick
together.
If it is necessary to further limit
the kill o f deer let’s find some other
scheme by which to do it. Cut one or
two days off our deer season or even
make us go back to a closed season
in odd numbered years but don’t spoil
our little deer hunt.
R O Y A L NEIGHBORS
Will meet second and fourth Saturday
afternoons each month, at 2 :80
o’clock, at Marsh’s hall.
ROBERT TAYLOR and WALLACE BEERY in “ STAND
UP AND FIGHT” which opens at the AVALON THEATRE
SUNDAY, FEBRUARY 26.
A Suggestion from the Tender Krust Baker*
SERVE A VARIETY OF BREADS AND TOAST
An econom ical and simple way to add extra interest to each meal
T-K Rye L oaf— Light Am erican Rye Bread
T-K Milwaukee Rye----A heavier rye loaf.
T-K W hole W heat----W ith that nutty whole wheat flavor.
T-K Kracked W heat— Nutritious; supplies healthful roughage
T-K Graham— Fine Textured and Tasty.
T-K Raisin White----(W ed n esd ays)— A real treat.
T-K Vienna L oaf— (T h ursdays)— A Hearth-Baked bread.
T-K Date-Nut Bread— (F rid a y s)— Dates and Chopped Walnuts.
Your Toaster Will Tell You the Quality Story
Tender-Krust Baking Co.
Eau Claire, Wisconsin
SHIP VIA
BRIGGS
TRANSFER
CO.
Daily Refrigerated
Service
To and From
Chicago and
Twin Cities
Experienced Household
Goods Moving
Phone 435
BLACK RIVER FALLS
THREE PRIZE WINNERS IN
RECIPE CONTEST
Jackson county winners in the recent
Wisconsin butter recipe contest,
sponsored by state radio stations
WHA and WLBL in cooperation with
the Wisconsin Agricultural Authority,
have just been announced.
A set o f four colored mixing bowls
goes to Mrs. Francis Gonia o f Taylor,
for the best recipe sent in from
this county. Mrs. Ralph Sieg, o f Osseo,
will receive an ice box dish for
holding butter as the second award;
and Mrs. William Curran, o f Taylor,
is to get an aluminum frying pan
for placing third. All others in the
county who took part in the contest
will receive wooden butter molds for
making fancy butter patties for table
use.M ore than 2,300 Wisconsin women
and girls sent in their favorite recipes
for this contest. They have shown
that using butter in meats, vegetables
and desserts gives these foods a rich
and pleasing flavor. The recipes also
showed that the women o f the state
have worked out many ideas for unusual
foods, with butter as an essential
ingredient. As part o f this statewide
butter campaign, scientists and
nutrition specialists o f the state also
emphasized the fact that butter is important
to make a well balanced diet.
Of the 200 recipes in the various
counties, which are worthy o f awards,
the judges have selected these two as
being particularly outstanding:
Honey-Butter Upside-Down Cake
Core 3 or 4 unpeeled apples. Cut
them crosswise in ring slices Vt to 
inches thick, preparing enough slices
to cover the bottom o f a medium-sized
iron skillet. Put M cup honey
and *4 cup butter in this skillet.
Melt, add the apple rings and simmer
until apples are partially cooked,
turning once. Place a maraschino
cherry in the center o f each apple
and nut meat halves in the spaces
around the apple slices. Pour the
following batter over this hot mixture
:
Vi cup butter
 cup honey
1 egg
M cup milk
1 cups flour
1 teaspoon baking powder
XA teaspoon soda
 4 teaspoon nutmeg
Vi teaspoon cinnamon
Vi teaspoon ginger
Cream together the softened butter
and honey. Add egg and beat till
smooth. Add milk alternately with
the sifted dry ingredients.
Bake at 350 F. (moderate oven)
30 to 35 minutes. Turn upside down
on a large plate. This may be served
hot or cold with a spoonful o f this
sauce on each serving:
h cup butter and M cup honey
creamed together. This sauce, which
may be used in other ways, may be
stored in a cool place.
Waldorf Eggs
2 ounces dried beef
1 cup canned tomatoes
'A cup grated cheese
Vi teaspoon finely chopped onion
Dash pepper
Dash cinnamon
3 eggs well beaten
M cup butter
Chop beef fine, add tomatoes,
cheese, onion, cinnamon and pepper.
Melt butter, add mixture. When
heated add beaten eggs, scramble like
scrambled eggs. Prepare:
5-6 slices toasted bread
1-3 cup melted butter
Dip one side o f toast in melted
butter, then coved the hot toast with
the egg mixture.
Note: Ring bologna may be used
in place o f dried beef.
JACKSON COUNTY’S SHARE
OF LIQUOR TAX
John M. Smith, State Treasurer,
has announced that the Jackson county
municipalities’ share o f the state
liquor tax for the last six months o f
1938 was $9,784.84. This amount was
apportioned among the cities, towns,
and villages o f Jackson county.
Under the law, revenue derived
from the liquor tax, minus the cost
of collection, is distributed every six
months to cities, towns, and villages
o f the state in proportion to population
in the last federal census to help
reduce the tax on general property.
Following is the first 1939 apportionment
o f the cities, towns, and villages
o f Jackson county, based on
revenue derived during the last six
months o f 1938:
Population
Amount
Albion T .................... 1,495 $ 888.29
Alma T...................... 821 487.82
Alma Center Vil. . . 383 227.57
Bear B luff T............ 128 76.05
Black River Falls C. 1,950 1,158.64
Brockway T .............. 479 284.61
City Point T.............. 368 218.66
Cleveland T .............. 763 453.35
Curran T................... 627 372.55
Franklin T ................. 739 439.09
Garden Valley T. .. 710 421.86
Garfield T................. 611 363.04
Hixton T .................... 654 388.59
Hixton Vil................. 270 160.43
Irving T..................... 798 474.15
Knapp T ..................... 178 105.76
Komensky T.............. 436 259.06
Manchester T ............ 493 292.93
Melrose T .................. 499 296.49
Melrose V il............... 480 285.20
Merrillan Vil............. 554 329.17
Millston T .................. 281 166.96
North Bend T .......... 620 368.39
Northfield T .............1,039 617.35
Springfield T ............ 753 447.41
Taylor Vil................. 339 201.42
16,468 $9,784.84
The apportionment is based on a
total state population o f 2,936,513 in
the last census.
LEGISLATURE NEWS LETTER
The greatest attraction in the Legislature
during the past week was
that o f committee hearings, particularly
the hearings on pensions for old
people.
Another hearing which filled the
Capitol to its capacity was that on the
Labor Relations Board bill. An attempt
was made in the House to revive
the Wisconsin Development Authority
Bill by a motion to reconsider.
However, the move to reconsider was
defeated by a vote o f about 41 to 50.
Another bill o f interest is Bill 9A,
which appropriates a larger sum to
towns, cities, villages and counties
for highway purposes. This bill was
engrossed by a vote o f 54 to 40 but
action for final passage was blocked
by a vote o f 46 to 45 and the bill
was then sent to the committee on
Finance. It may prove very difficult
to get this bill out o f the Finance
committee for final passage and
many o f the legislators believe- that
the sending o f the bill to the Finance
committee will eventually mean the
defeat o f the bill.
PETER A. HEMMY,
Assemblyman. Jackgson County
NOTICE
American Lesrion Auxiliary meets
first and third Wednesday o f month.
BOWLING NEWS
The Chaimson Maytags went into
sole possession o f first place by taking
all three from Camp Irving while
the Hagen Clothiers who were tied
for first were being drubbed in all
three by Bert Jones’ Creams. By taking
one from Jackson Box, the Moe
Clothing team climbed into a second
place tie as did the Tollack Coals
by taking one from S. C. S. The
week’s best bowling in an otherwise
mediocre week was turned in by the
Larkin Hardwares in trimming Coca
Cola three times. B. A. E. climbed
back into the thick o f the race by
taking all three from the Millis Contractors
shoving the Millis team into
sixth place five games behind the
leaders.
Scores were unusually low for the
week, with Si Knudsen’s 561 set the
only one worthy o f mention.
The week’s best scores:
Individual:
Single— Si Knudsen 219
Set— Si Knudsen 561
Team:
Single— Larkin Hardwares, 904
Set— Larkin Hardwares, 2625.
The standings:
Team Won Lost Pins
Chaimson Maytags ___ 32 19 847
Hagen Clothiers ...........29 22 860
Moe Clothing Co.............29 22 846
Tollack C o a ls ................. 29 22 787
B. A. E............................. 28 23 834
Millis Contractors ___ 27 24 818
S. C. S............................... 26 25 737
Coca C o la .......................25 26 768
Jones Creams ............... 24 27 783
Larkin Hardwares ___ 22 39 785
Camp Irv in g ................... 19 32 734
Jackson Box Co.............. 16 35 637
The Big Ten:
Fr. Peters, Moes, 190; O. Kleven,
Hagens, 179; M. Davis, Chaimsons,
177; H. Cole, Chaimsons, 176; C.
Lipinski, Millis, 175; H. Kleven, Hagens,
175; A. Haralson, Hagens, 175;
S. Knudsen, B. A. E., 174; W. Boehm
Moes, 173; C. Pflanz, Larkins, 173.
In a pair o f matches here over the
week end the Travellers trimmed an
Eau Claire team Friday night 2430 to
2302. Hank Kleven’s 565 led both
teams, being the only set out o f ten
that bettered 500.
Sunday night one o f the best teams
in Wisconsin, the Heileman Old
Style Lagers o f La Crosse appeared
against an All-Star team here. The
Old Styles had bowled at Eau Claire
in the afternoon and notwithstanding
the extremely bad traveling conditions
arrived here about an hour late
for their match.
Altho the bowling was bad on both
sides the local All-Stars won out by a
margin o f 21 pins, 2477 to 2456. Si
Knudsen led the All Stars with 529
and Pete Wais topped the Old Styles
with 537.
Feb. 14
J ackson B ox Co.—
1st 2nd 3rd T otal
H. L eicht ____ _______ ____ 158 140 151 449
G. Bauer ....... ........................ 117 123 118 358
E. G ardner ......................... 107 90 112 309
S. Johnson ________ ______ 123 95 112 330
C. N anstad ............................ 135 153 114 402
193 193 193 579
Total .................................834 794 9002 227
M oe C lothing Co.—
E. N em ec ...............................210 121 166 497
O. Mee .....................................119 156 178 397
H. P op p ................. ...............180 171 178 529
W . Boehm ..... ...................... 188 149 142 479
Fr. Peters ...............................184 175 159 518
 13 13 13 39
T otal .................................884 785 782 2451
Feb. 14
Larkin H ardw ares—
1st 2nd 3rd T otal
M. H aralson ________ _____ 198 165 139 302
N. Larkin .............................. 1S3 167 156 446
D. N anstad ............................145 175 182 502
Osborne Johnson _______ 177 138 171 486
C. P fla n z ...._______________ 197 170 160 527
54 54 54 527
T otal ..................... .......... 904 859 962 2625
C oca Cola—
G. Sullivan _______________ 157 115 136 428
R. K rohn .................................176 127 182 483
H . Galston _______________ 137 148 133 418
E R ingrose ......................... 140 134 167 441
T. Mills ................................... 137 134 110 381
71 71 71 213
T otal ................. ............... 818 729 819 2366
Feb. 15
T ollack Coals—
1st 2nd 3rd T otal
A . H agen ..... ...........................175 151 176 502
H. H. R ichards .................. 133 156 167 456
D. P erry __________________125 165 170 450
O. T ollack ............................136 132 140 428
M. Richards ..........................145 177 182 604
58 58 58 174
T otal ______________ s c s — ___792 839 893 2524
E. Quick ........... .......... ..........148 164 159 462
R. Rasm ussen .....................161 141 117 419
G. Schultz ................. ............ 123 171 138 452
W . Bean __________________155 143 160 453
J. Zellinger ...................... _...174 142 139 445
87 87 87 261
T ota l ................. ............... 848 848 831 2527
Feb. 15
Chaim son M aytags—
1st 2nd 3rd T otal
J. Sypulski _______________ 166 139 188 493
H. Cole ................................... 151 138 193 502
O. Iserloth ................. ..........194 129 170 493
R. Lund ...................................156 187 169 512
M. D avis ______________ ___ 156 165 168 489
13 13 13 39
T otal ...... ..........................836 791 901 2528
Cam p Irvin g—
G. Allen _______________ __ 141 146 145 432
J. Dundas ..............................102 122 153 377
H. G utgesell ..........................127 135 167 429
V . Schrroeder _____________181 106 138 425
H. Zw eifel ............................134 140 165 459
97 97 97 291
T ota l .................................802 746 865 2413
Feb. 16
H agen Clothiers—
1st 2nd 3rd T otal
E. Rudolph ............ ...............166 137 153 456
A. H aralson ______________144 164 138 446
O. Kleven ..............................135 172 171 478
M. H aug ...................... ..........128 167 143 438
H. K leven ........................ — .165 165 186 516
T otal .................................758 805 791 2334
Jones Cream S tation —
Lud Gilbertson ........- ........155 156 151 462
B ert Jones ............................188 139 169 494
H om er R ichards ........- ........163 155 143 463
P rice Peterson ___________ 154 153 145 452
Don Carish ..... ...................... 153 191 159 503
H andicap .............................. 64 64 64 192
T otal __________________877 856 833 2566
Feb. 16
Millis C ontractors—
1st 2nd 3rd T otal
W . Jones .......... ...................... 132 158 147 439
R. M illis ................................ 157 133 170 460
M. Stenulson ...................... 162 147 164 473
C. G o m e r ...... ..........................157 108 92 357
C. Lipinski ................. .......... 170 149 212 531
31 31 31 93
T otal ................................ 807 726 818 2351
B. A. E.—
M. N em ec ................. ..........170 150 160 480
J. Kasik ................................ 192 172 141 505
J. N andory .......... ................. 166 164 190 420
R. Stai ...................................154 171 142 467
S. Knudson ............................161 181 219 561
24 24 24 72
T otal __________________ 867 862 876 2605
B lack R iv er Falls—
1st 2nd 3rd T otal
H . K leven _______________ 201 192 172 565
H . Cole ______________ ____ 145 181 162 488
M. R ichards .........................160 179 108 447
M. D avis .................................171 139 135 445
O. K leven ________________ 160 159 168 435
T otal ................................ 837 847 745 2430
Eau Claire—
Phillips __________________ 146 168 177 491
R aderson ________________ 155 137 160 492
Tim bers ...................... ..........124 170 157 451
C l e a s b y ..... .......................... 153 181 140 474
T iller ...... ....................... „...144 124 146 414
T ota l ________ ______ ___722 800 780 2302
Feb. 19
A ll Stars—
1st 2nd 3rd T otal
O. K leven _________________135 140 190 465
C. Lipinski ...................... ..... 178 166 181 525
S. K nudsen ______ _________181 177 171 529
M. Davia .................................169 172 133 494
Fr. Peters _____ _________ 165 164 145 474
T otal .................................828 819 840 2477
Old Style Lagers—
L. K oblitz .............................. 156 157 178 491
A . Gilles __________________ 146 142 201 489
J. Fuchs ................. ...............181 159 138 468
H. W itten b erg _____ ____- 1 3 5 166 170 471
P. W ais ............ ....................149 198 190 537
T ota l ..... .......................... 7*7 822 897 2456
NOTICE
The American Legion Auxiliary
will meet Wednesday evening, March
1st, with Mrs. Mabel Moe.
SafetY
W ith o u t
Question
THRU FEDERAL DEPOSIT INSURANCE
Ho question of safety need ever arise in
your mind when you deposit money in
an account in this bank. Every dollar
up to $5,000 is insured by the Federal
Deposit Insurance Corporation as extra
protection in addition to the strength of
the bank itself, and its sound management.
There are very few other investments
in the world today which can compare
for safety with an insured bank account.
Jackson County Bank
Black River Falls, Wis.
With Stations at Taylor, Hixton, Alma Center and Merriliaa
NOTICE TO ALBION T A X P A Y E R S
The tax roll is in my hands for
collection. I will be at the Albion
town hall every Friday and Saturday
during February for the purpose o f
collecting taxes.
51-tf A. C. SANDEERG, Treas.
NOTICE
American Legion meets second and
fourth Tuesdays o f each month.
NOTICE OF AN N U AL M EETING
Notice Is Hereby Given that the
annual meeting o f the Disco Creamery
Association o f Disco, Wis., will
be held at the Disco hall, Thursday,
March 2nd, 1939, at 1 :30 o’clock in
the afternoon. All patrons and stockholders
o f the creamery are invited
to attend.
GILBERT GULLICKSON, Pres.
HUBERT JOHNSON, Sec.
Huebsch
Laundry Co.
OF EAU CLAIRE, WIS.
WILL SERVICE THIS COMMUNITY ON
MONDAY and THURSDAY
OF EACH WEEK
in Laundry - Dry Cleaning and
Linen Supply Service
FOR QUALITY AND SERVICE TRY
HUEBSCH LAUNDRY AND DRY
CLEANING CO.
EAU CLAIRE, WISCONSIN
Telephone 121 - Black River Falls
A m W r£ sM 0 8 u ? 
A C A R A D A Y O t V E N A W A Y
E V E R Y D A Y N M A R C H
I N O L D S M O B L E 'S N A T IO N W I D E
P R I Z E C O N T E S T ?
So that you may get to know the new Olds Sixty better, Oldsmobile
is staging a great nationwide prize contest. Enter today
and you may win an Oldsmobile free. W h at you do is take a
trial drive, fill out an Official Kntry Blank and mail it to Oldsmobile
at Lansing, Mich. Your entry will then be considered
for the day’s prize corresponding to the date of its postmark.
b g " s x r v ' s - D o o n s e d a n s
ara the prizes, rem em ber—one for every day of the month.
You have nothing to buy and you incur no obligation.
Y ou sim ply d rive — and w rite d ow n the things that
impressed you most about Am erica’s n ew est low-priced car.
W A fT W R A f O I A f c o j u w n F O R
COMPLETE RULES £ ENTRY B L A N K !
„Y 0| f t i C O M T K S T S T AWR T S A,M* A H C fM 
HARDY CHEVROLET CO.
Black River Falls, Wis.
THE BANNER-JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin PAGE NO. 3
ALMA CENTER NEWS
MR. GEORGE LINNELL
CE LEBR ATES 85th B IR T H D A Y
Eighty-five years ago, February 14,
a Valentine baby was born, and Tuesday,
February 14 , thirty relatives, in
honor o f the occasion, met at the
home o f Mr. and Mrs. C. Stroup to
help celebrate Grandpa Linnell’s 85th
birthday. They ail came with loaded
baskets o f good things to eat and a
beautiful decorated Birthday Cake,
made by his two daughters, Mrs.
Blanche Schnick and Mrs. Cora Enerson.
it contained 86 green and
white candles. A bountiful supper was
served at seven-thirty. A fter supper
was over the evening was spent playing
500 and Chinese checkers.
It was a lovely ending to a perfect
day for from friends and neighbors
coming in bringing gifts and best
wishes he also enjoyed hearing his
name announced over Eau Claire’s
W £ Al).
iUr. Linnell was given a purse of
moiiiey in honor of the happy day.
Yve wish him many more happy birthdays.
Mrs. John Murphy shopped in Winona
Saturday.
Airs. Lester Duxbury spent last
week with her parents in i? ail Coulie.
-Ur. and Mrs. Martin o f uowanda,
•New lorK, were recent visitors here.
Joseph and Peter Held attended a
funeral o f a relative at Siinger recently.
Ueorge Kunzelman came from Eau
Claire Friday to spend the week end
at his home here.
The rather 6i Sons Banquet held
at the M. E. Aid parlors, was a success
in every way.
Mr. and xvlrs. Bruce Van Gorden
called on Mrs. Jennie Hall at Alma
Center Friday night.
ih e Birthday oiub met at the home
o f Mrs. Vvm. Hall Saturday for supper.
A very pleasant time was had
by all.
Mrs. Harold Sprester came up
from La Crosse Saturday and expects
to be here to help celebrate her mother’s
birthday.
Wm. Rubenbauer took his wife to
Sparta where they consulted Dr.
Scantleton in regard to Mrs. Rubenbauer’g
health.
Mrs. Bert Winters o f Minneapolis,
spent the week end here with Mrs.
Anna Hall and other friends. She
will leave this week for a visit in
California.
Mr. and Mrs. Harold Bartholomew
attended a masked ball at Onalaska
Saturday night. They were guests at
the home o f Mr. and Mrs. Semb of
La Crosse.
Mrs. Wm. Ball and Donna Rose
spent several days at the home o f C.
A. Stroup. While here she attended
the West End Whist Club held at
Harold Hanson’s and also Grandpa
Linnell’s birthday party.
Don’t forget the Co-op. movie and
speech at the high school gym, Friday
night, February 24th, at 8 p. m. to
be sponsored by the Jackson County
Co-op. Advancement Association and
shown by the county agent. A real
picture and no admission charges, all
free. Everybody welcome.
NOTICE
This week being Co-op. Week we
are going to show a Co-op. movie at
the Alma Center high school gym,
Friday night, February 24th, at 8
p. m. We understand this is a very
interesting picture and we also intend
to have a good speaker there. Everybody
come out and spend another
friendly evening with us. No admission
charges.
WM. RUBENBAUER,
E. J. RANDELS, Com.
G RACE LU TH E RAN CHURCH
Sunday school 9 :45 a. m.
Services 10:30 a. m.
Lenten services are being held every
Thursday evening at 8 p. m.
The next Lenten service is on Mar.
2nd. E. A. KLEMP, Pastor.
Y O R K
Mr. and Mrs. Charley Iverson and
sons, Carl and Thomas, were Sunday
guests at the home o f their daughter
and sister, Mrs. Sam Knutson, near
Blair.
A son was born to Mr. and Mrs.
Neil Johnson at the home o f his parents
Mr. and Mrs. Martin Johnson
on Sunday night, Feb. 19th. Dr. Leasum
and Mrs. Neal Humphrey, R. N.,
were in attendance.
A deal wa.- made at York last week
when Henry Hanson bought the house
now occupied by Martin Johnson,
from Mrs. Martin Hanson. Mr. and
Mrs. Lester Moe will move into the
house the middle o f March. It will
be handy as the oil station which
Lester runs is right near by.
The Jackson County Advancement
Society are putting on a program on
Thursday night, Feb. 23, which will
consist o f moving pictures and speakers.
It is sponsored by the creamery
ladies and are asked to bring
cake or sandwiches as they will serve
lunch. They are looking forward to
a nice sociable time. This is Co-Op.
week.
The Farmers Union social meeting
fill be held next Saturday night, Feb.
25th. The program will consist o f a
play entitled “ Spider W eb” put on
| by members o f the Co-op Oil Co. of
B. R. Falls. Geo. Dettinger is one o f
the characters. There will also be
other numbers. Lunch and dancing
after the program. Come and enj'oy
a pleasant evening.
The annual creamery meeting was
held on Thursday, Feb. 16th. The
morning was devoted to the reading
o f reports o f the treasurer and secretary.
Archie Brovold o f Ettrick, and
Fritz Holtzman o f Minneapolis, vice
president and fieldman o f District 24
o f Land o’ Lakes were present, and
each gave talks. Dinner was served
by the creamery. The afternoon was
spent in election o f officers and most
important was the decision o f installing
an accounting system for the
purpose o f simplifying the bookkeeping
whereby one man can take care
o f both the secretary and treasurer
job, saving one man’s salary. The directors
elected were Edwin Thomley,
Olger Mickelson, Geo. Humphrey,
Theo. O. Thompson, Arthur Johnson.
The new creamery was started in operation
the same day. There will
probably be a more complete account
o f the meeting in a separate item.
CHEESE
LONG HORN
per lb...... 1 7 s
16 OZ. Can Silvalaska
Pink Salmon
2 cans tor 2 § S
Fancy Rice
4 lbs Jor 2 1 g
Salad Dressing
I.G.A. E X T R A W H IPPE D
quart jar 3 3 c
48 OZ. PKG. IGA
L en ten
Foods
7 oz. pkgs. Macaroni or
SPAGHETTI
4 1 7 c
Ginger Snaps
3 lbs. for 2 5 C
M ACARO N I or
Spaghetti
2 lbs. bulk 1 2 c
Candy Bars
3 *cr 10c
1 lb. pkg. Blue G
Coffee
2 pkgs for 4 9 c
Dishes FREE
Oatmeal
17c
EGG NOODLES 8 oz. pkg....... 7 c
Meat Department
A rm our’s Star
Lard
2 lbs. for 1 5 c
W ith Meat Order
L EA N DRY
Salt Pork
2 lbs. for 2 7 c
ITS A R M O U R’ S BE TTER
Bologna
2 lbs. for 2 5 c
ST E A K OR RO AST
Pork Shoulder
per lb...... 19c
Fresh Fish of All Kinds
Anderson Food Market
Phone No. 1 We Deliver
THE INDIAN NEW S
We had cold spell last few days,
Quite a few people had bad cold.
Belle Stack and John Dixon went
back to Wisconsin Rapids this week
and they have been here visit Indian
Mission and to see the relative and
friends.
Tom Kings wan and A. Johnson
were gone to iom ah Indian hospital
last week end, and both are having
oad cold.
The Indians some have poor house
to live in winter, that what is cause
to have aad cold and some flu, and
once government promised build
houses last year, never done anything
yet. All we got is “ promised".
Our teacher, Mrs. Emma Olson, report
this week, some of our pupils
are havicg the flu, but they are Detter
at this writing. But not only
school pupils, some old people too.
Our forelady, Miss Matilda Stacy
sewing project, report that two white
ladies working on the sewing project
at Indian Mission, as following names
— Mrs. id ith Wood work Sept. 1st,
1938, and Mary Kidrick ie b . 10,
1939.
The Indian reporter had a letter
from a man, his address E. J. Nichols
o f 1852 Howe St., Chicago, 111., Jan.
15, 1939. He says, he was born here
Black River on 18o7.and he mention
some Indian names, Mary Crane,
Doctor Big Nose and Winneshieck.
We all know these Indians but young
people they don't know anythings at
ail, and Mr. Nichois’ father lived at
Robinson Creek, where Fallhall Glen
is now. During that time the old Indians
they used to live anywhere they
want to live in winter, or anywhere
they think a good place for any kind
game or plenty game, but now they
can not do that any more. White
immigrants made too many laws and
the Indians they getting use horns
made laws, and always put some kind
scared crow to them. “ Old Dandy’ "
he told them before hand, that his
own tribe, at present time where we
are now, and still some more coming
too.Mr. George Johnson o f La Crosse
was here today. Mr. Johnson is exstudent
o f Carlisle Indian school witli
the Indian reported the time o f 1893
to 1898.
The Indian reporter had a letter
from his old teacher, Mr. fYed Sacia
of Galesville, Wis. Indian reported
never been school before that time
he is learning a. b. c. from this man.
This is letter from him.
Galesville, Wis., 2-15-39
Dear Mr. Low Cloud:
I am glad that Mr. Gipple o f the
Galesville Republican prints your
“ Indian News” every week.
I am not only interested in the
doings o f your people, but in you too.
Do you remember back 47 years ago
when you were the pupil and I the
teacher in the little school between
North Bend and Stevenstown? You
were an interesting letter writer even
at that time and I am not surprised
that you have become very useful.
I will tell you why I think you are
a good reporter: When you tell of
death and bad luck your readers feel
sorry, when you tell about your
church, your schools, o f the new babies
and o f the getting together o f
families and friends, we are glad.
When you tell about the little things
that happen, we are interested. What
reporter could do more. I congratulate
you. Yours very truly,
FRED SACIA
NOTICE
The German Hill Sewing club will
meet at the home o f Mrs. Harry
Pierce on Wednesday, March 1st.
Those serving are Mrs. Arthur Ball
and Mrs. Harry Pierce. Remember
to bring your thread for waxing.
CARD OF TH A N K S
The children and grandchildren o f Mrs.
M artha H alvorson wish to express their sincere
thanks to their friends and neighbors
fo r the kindness and sym pathy shown us
during her illness and death. W e especially
want to thank R ev. B ringle fo r fris com fortin
g w ords, the singers, and Mr. Gibson
fo r his services, and also those w ho sent
flow ers and m em orial w reaths.
IN MEMORIAM
In m em ory o f ou r beloved husband and
father, H arry Stevens, w h o passed away on
February 17, 1938.
W hat is hom e w ithout him.
N o one know s the b itter pain
W e have felt since he le ft us.
L ife has never been the same.
W e have been so lonely
W ith ou t seeing his dear fa ce.
F or all o f us, he did his best.
D ear God gran t his Eternal rest.
Sadly m issed by his w ife, Mrs. Ida Stevens
and sons, R alph and Russell. lw
- Falls Theatre -
BLACK RIV ER FALLS, W IS.
T H U R SD AY , F R ID A Y , SAT.
FEB. 23, 24, 25
DOUBLE FEATU RE
Tom Keene in
“ PAINTED
TRAIL”
with
Eleanore Stewart
also
Preston Foster in
“ The Lady in
the Morgue”
with
Patricia Ellis and
Frank Jenks
Tw o free candy bars with each
paid adm. Saturday matinee at
2 :0 0 Adm. 10 and 15c
SUN., MON., TUES., W ED.
FEB. 26, 27, 28, 29
Constance Bennett
in
“ SERVICE
DE LUXE”
with
Vincent Price, Charlie
Ruggles, Helen Broderick
and Mischa Auer
Matinee Sunday at 2:00
Adm. 10 and 20c
BR O A D C AST S FOR
C O -O P E R A T IV E W EEK
Madison— When cooperators cooperate,
it’s Cooperative Week in Wisconsin.
Through the cooperation o f radio
stations in all parts o f the state and
two out-of-the-state stations more
than 80 broadcasts will ‘air’ the news
and views o f the cooperative movement
from many angles during the
week February 20 to 25, proclaimed
by Governor Heil as Wisconsin’s second
annual cooperative week, the department
o f agriculture and markets
announced today.
Tying in with the special radio
programs cooperatives are urged to
arrange various educational activities
for the week, organize membership
drives, and present aggressive streamline
programs to their members for
1939.
“ No problem is o f greater importance
to the farmers o f Wisconsin
than that of marketing their products”
, Ralph E. Ammon, director of
the state department declares. “ The
Cooperative Week program prepared
by the cooperative organizations o f
Wisconsin, the department o f agriculture
and markets, and the College of
Agriculture should be o f immeasurable
value to the prosperity o f the
state, and merits the attention o f all
citizens, young and old” .
Men, women, and youth representing
the leading cooperative groups of
Wisconsin and the Middle West wi.l
take part in the broadcasts.
Cooperating radio stations giving
free time to the observance o f Cooperative
Week are: WHA, Madison,
and WLBL, Stevens Point, the two
state owjied stations; WTMJ and
WISN, Milwaukee; WIBA Madison,
W1BU, Madison and Poynette; WFIZ
Fond du Lac; WHGY, Green Bay;
WSAU, Wausau; WEAU, Eau Claire,
WKBH, La Crosse; WCLO, Janesville;
WRJN, Racine; WHBI, Sheboygan;
WOMT, Manitowoc; WCCO,
Minneapolis, and WLS, Chicago.
The schedule of broadcasts for the
last three days o f the week follow s:
Thursday, February 23
WHA and WLBL, 12:45 — Milo
Swantan, “ Cooperative Incidents” .
1:15 - 1:20— Prof. Barton, “ Vision
Necessary in Cooperative Building.”
WIBU, KFIZ, WHBY and WHBL,
7:15-7:30— Lee Yorkon, Dairy Industries,
Inc., “ Presenting the New Program
of Dairy Industries, Inc.”
WIBA, 6:15-6:30— Marvin Smithback,
Cambridge, Dane County Farmers
Union Co-op. Oil, “ A Farmer
Business.”
WSAU,— Chris Holzen, Marathon
Co-op. Dairy Association, “ How We
Can Succeed Cooperatively.”
WOMT, 8:00-8:15— A. L. McMahon,
Calumet county agent, “ What
Value Cooperatives.”
1:00-1:15— K. T. Wiegand, Cleveland,
“ Value o f Cooperation in Spraying
Operations.”
WCLO, 1 :00-l :15— A1 Stoldt, Monroe,
“ Purpose o f Swiss and Limburger
Cheese Cooperative.”
WRJN, 12:00-12:15— Frank Van
Alstine, Kenosha Milk Producers Association,
“ Working with the Farmer,
Dealer and Consumer.”
WCCO, 1 :00-l :07— E. A. Syftestad
Farmers Union Exchange, “ Development
o f our Northwest Cooperatives.”
1:07-1:14— Glenn Thompson, Midland
Wholesale, “ Why Consumers Cooperate.”
WKBH, 9:30-9:45 p. m. — Fred
Rogers, Viroqua, Vernon County Live
Stock Shipping Association, “ Selling
Live Stock Cooperatively Through
both Local and Terminal Market
Channels.”
WEAU, 12:00-12:10— C. J. Ritland,
Chippewa Falls, “ Interesting
Points in Marketing Wool Cooperatively.”
WEBC, 1:00-1:15— Round Table
discussion on Electric Cooperatives
conducted by George Halonen, Sr.,
Superior, representing Head o f the
Lakes, Electric Co-op. Association.
Friday, February 24
WHA and WLBL, 12:30-1:00 —
L. F. Roherty, Wisconsin Farm Bureau;
Herman ldhe, Wisconsin State
Grange; Warren Nelson, Wisconsin
Farmers Equity Union. Interviews by
Wilbur L. Wittee, chief division of
markets, department o f agriculture 
markets, “ General Farm Organization
Discussion.”
11:45-11:55— A representative of
the Grange.
WIBU, KFIZ, WHBY and WHBL,
7:15-7:30— Art Staple, Fox River
Valley Wholesale Co-op., “ A Wisconsin
Wholesale.”
WIBA, 6:00-6:15— Jack Wilson,
Wisconsin Rural Electric Cooperative
“ Development o f Electric Cooperatives
in Wisconsin.”
WSAU, — Chas. Simmons, Marathon
County Co-op. Breeders’ Association,
“ For Economy and Breed
Improvement.”
WOMT, 8:00-8:15— Frank Kowa-
Ichyk, Maplewood, “ Advantages of
a Local Cooperative Oil Association.”
1 :00-l:15-— Mr. Schulz, Two Rivers
“ Cooperative Warehousing.”
WCLO, 1:00-1:15— Hugh Hemingway,
Janesville, “ I arm Bureau Activities
in Rock County.”
WRJN, 12:00-12:15 — Herbert
Katt, Racine Consumers’ Cooperative
“ A Business Owned by its Custom-
WISN, 4 :00-4:05— Grace Catherine
Dineen, Cedarburg, “ Going Forward
with the Milwaukee Milk Producers
Association.”
WKBH, 9:000-9:15 p. m. — Geo.
Nygaard, Chaseburg, president Northern
Wisconsin Tobacco Pool, “ Sunlight
Appearing through the Clouds.”
WEAU, 12:00-12:10 — C. H. Almena,
“ Success in a Town Mutual
Insurance Association.”
WEBC, 6:30-6:45 — A. J. Hayes,
Central Wholesale, “ Relationship o f
Wholesale Cooperatives to the Cooperative
Movement.”
Saturday, February 25th
WTMJ, 12:30-12:40 — R. C. Swanson,
Milwaukee County agent, “ Milwaukee
Fluid Milk Cooperatives.”
CH RISTIAN SCIENCE SOCIETY
Services Sunday, 11 a. m.
Sunday school 10:15 a. m.
“ Christ Jesus” will be the subject
o f the Lesson-Sermon read in all
Churches o f Christ, Scientist, on Sunday,
February 26.
The Golden Text is taken from
Colossians 3:16, 17:
“ Let the w ord o f Christ dwell in you
richly in all w isd om ; .. .. And w hatsoever
ye do in word o r deed, do all in the
nam e o f the L ord Jesus, giv in g thanks to
God and the Father by him.’*
NOTICE
There will be an hour o f prayer
service at the Methodist church FViday
afternoon at 2 o’clock. Every
one interested is invited to attend.
ST. JOHN’ S LUTH. CHURCH
E. A. Klemp, Pastor
Instead o f the bi-weekly service
there will be a weekly Lenten service
held each Wednesday evening at 8,
beginning with March 1st. The topic
for these services will be the Passion
history o f our Lord and Savior Jesus
Christ.
BlGGAR’S (Formerly Marsh’s)
extend a cordial invitation to you to attend the
opening of their new store
FRIDAY, FEBRUARY 24th, 1939
C o a t s —
Plenty of Style in our New Coats — Swaggers that flare
from shoulder to hem — Reefers with young
square shoulders — Flaring Skirts — Bright
Fleeces — Checked Tweeds mixtures
-------- Special Prices for Our Opening----------
$7 95 to $ I 2 95
STUNNING SPRING STYLES
m
vsSS#. ; 
W a sk Frocks
PRINTS and SPUN RAYON
SPECIAL
88c $1.79 $2.79
H ats—
PARIS COPIES
Straws — Felts — Fabrics —
With Flowers, Bows, feather
and drifting in yards of
veiling
$1.95 to $2.95
Rayon Satin
Slips
Gleaming, lustrous slips with
guaranteed seams and adjustable
straps. Tearose only —
sizes 34 to 44— SPECIA L A T
6 6 c and 8 8 c
BURST OF COLOR IN
YOUR SPRING
Handbags
Classic top handle and pouch
styles! Smooth Calf, Shining Patent!
Doeskin and MeloSuede
Cloth! New Sun Tones — —
Chartreuse, Dusty Pink, Gold—
Japanica, Cranberry, Teal Blue
$1.00 to $2-95
SWEATERS
Cardigans ----
Zephyr Knit ----
Brushed Knit —
Chenilles —
Pastel Shades —
SP ECIA L AT
8 8 c - $ 1 . 7 9
Tweed Jackets
W ide array o f Plaids, checks,
flecks! M an-tailored with broad
Shoulders. Sizes 12 to 20
SPECIAL PRICES
$2-79 to $g.39
Perfect for Spring ----
M AN -TAILORED
SUITS
All W ool W orsteds — Coverts,
Hairline Stripes, Tweeds ----
Sizes 12 to 20
$7.95 to $9.95
" blo u ses
Everything new in Blouses to
liven up your suit and give you
a real spring feeling. Plaids —
Checks and plain colors — ----
Washable
8 8 c - $ 1 .7 9
FU LL GOSPEL T AB ERN ACLE
Paul J. Bicket, Pastor
Men may judge us by the success
of our efforts but Cod looks at the
efforts themselves. Of what value are
your efforts to God and for righteousness?
Will you reap benefits in
eternity thru the efforts you are putting
forth? Today is the time to consider
such and make every effort and
every day count for God.
You are invited to the house o f
worship where you may find real relaxation
from worries and cares of
life. Our services are as follows:
Sunday school 10 a. m.
Morning worship 11 a. m.
Evangelistic service 8 p. m.
Bible Study (Thursday) 8 p. m.
“ The Book o f Acts”
E V A N G E L IC A L LUTH ERAN
PARISH
A. M. Romstad, Pastor
Confirmation class Saturday morning
at 10 o’clock.
Black River Falls:
Thursday, 2:30, The Ladies Aid
will be entertained by Mrs. A. M.
Romstad, Mrs. J. H. Harmer and Mrs.
Ole Hagen. Topic— “ The Christian
and his Church work.” Leader— Mrs.
A. M. Rockney
Thursday, 3:30 Children’s choir;
7 :00 Junior choir.
Sunday, 9:30, Sunday school
Sunday, 10:45, Divine worship.
Sermon, “ Prosperity and Possession” ,
the seventh o f a series on the Commandments.
Monday, 8:00, The Dorcas Society
will be entertained by Selma Christianson,
Merle Waidum and Lucile
Pugh.
Little N orway:
The Irving Ladies Aid will have a
kensington Wednesday, March 1, at
the home o f Mrs. Anna Haugstad.
Squaw Creek:
Divine worship Sunday afternoon
nf O nVlnrlf
The first o f a series o f five midweek
Lenten services will be Thursday
evening, March 2, at 8 o’clock.
The series will be based on the general
theme: “ Five Great Experiences
in the Life of Jesus” . The first sermon:
“ The Decisive Start” . These
services have been remarkably well
attended in past years. The public is
cordially invited. Begin with the first
service and attend them all.
There will be a special service in
the town church Sunday evening at 8
o ’clock. Rev. A. J. Bringle, of Taylor,
will be the speaker. Other special
numbers.
CATH OLIC SERVICES
Sunday—
6 : iu -Slabs at Roaring Creek
10:30 Mass at BlacK Kiver Falls
V :3U p. m. Eucharistic stations
Wednesday 7 :30, Way ol tne Cross
Also every Alonuay and r nday evening
at 8:U0 there will De a lecture
on tue uamoiic religion, ihis course
will be an explanation ol Catholic
teaching and practice.
Any one interested in the Catholic
church is welcome to attend this series
which begins this coming rriday
evening (Feb. 24th), at 8 o clock in
the basement ol the church.
This series is an opportunity of examining
the claims of the Catholic
church. Many people have perhaps a
distorted idea ot her teachings, were
is a chance to get an authoritative
statement o f her doctrine.
You place yourself under no obligation
by coming.
and to the mid-week services.
T rout Run:
Sunday school and church service
at 2 :00 p. m. Feb. 26th.
TH E M ETHODIST CHURCH
Harold A. Allison, Pastor
Black River Falls:
Thursday, Feb. 23, Choir rehearsals
: J unior choir after school, Intermediate
choir at 7 p. m .; Adult choir
at 7 :45 p. m.
Friday, Feb. 24th— World Day of
Prayer Service at 2 :30 p. m. at the
church. All are invited to attend this
service, the first o f the Lenten Observances.
Similar services are being
held in churches of all denominations
all over the world on this day.
This service is sponsored by the W omen’s
Home Missionary Society.
Sunday, Feb. 26, Church school at
9 :45 a. m. All Reds and Blues are
urged to be present to boost your side
in attendance.
Morning worship at 10:45. The Intermediate
choir will sing. The special
music by the junior choir was
much appreciated last Sunday.
Junior League at 6:30 p. m.
Epworth League at 7 :30 p. m.
Monday, March 27 the postponed
meeting of the Marthas at the church
at 7 :30 p. m.
Wednesday, March 1, the 5th and
6th grades in the Week Day School
o f Religion at 1 0 :30 a. m.
Boy Scout meeting at 7 :30 p. m.
Regular Lenten Mediations are being
planned for each Thursday evening
from 8 until 9 p. m. during the
Lenten season beginning March 2nd.
Every one is cordially invited to participate
in and profit by these special
services during Lent. Take time to
Worship. Go to church each Sunday
Wisconsin
Certified R.O.P.
Sired Chicks
Lay Best — Pay Best
Make no mistake and buy W isconsin
certified chicks, which
are R. O. P. (R ecord o f Perform
ance) male mated chicks.
National average R. O. P. hens
lay three times the average
o f eggs laid by ordinary farm
hens. Certified chicks have better
than 50 per cent R. O. P.
blood and will give you some
mighty nice strong pullets for
the laying house next fall. Stock
produced under state supervised
trap nesting method. Priced
right to make you profits.
Buy Certified —
Be Satisfied
Iliff’s Hatchery
Phone 273
BLACK RIVER FALLS, WIS.
PAGE NO THE BANNER-JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin W ednesday, February 22, 193'|
® )c S a n n e r 'J o ttr n a i
Subscription price $2.00 j«r y«ar.
E ntered at the postoffice at Black Biver
Falls as second-class matter.
MEKLIN H U LL. Publisher.
H A R R IE T TH OM AS NOBLE. Local Editor.
H ENRY E. OLSON. Business Manager.
J. H. W ID M A R . Job and Ad Department.
C LA R A B. OLSON, M achine Operator
HELEN M A E W A L T E R S, Bookkeeper
M ERLIN H ULL’S LETTE R
While the Senate committee continues
to probe monopolies, uncovering
about the usual number o f o ffcolor
practices, when the affairs o f
large financial or business instiutions
are put under the spot-light, the Supreme
Court also continues to point
out what can be done with conspiracies
set up for restraining trade.
Thus far, in our history, such conspiracies
are about the only kind
which may be entered into without
danger o f indictment and prosecution.
In this very recent case the Supreme
Court permanently enjoined a
lot o f Texas movie magnates from
continuing a “ gentlemen’s agreement”
which controlled the handling
o f movie films in a monopolistic manner,
and at the same time fixed theatre
admission prices even o f theatres
in which they had no direct or financial
interest. How long the agreement
had been in full operation to the
profit o f those engaged in it and to
the detriment o f those not included,
as well as to that o f the public, is
not stated. Probably a couple o f years
or more, as that much time generally
is required to get a case into the Supreme
Court, and have a decision rendered.
In that period the conspiracy
may have yielded a few millions in
profits. Under the decision, it can no
longer carry on. But there was nothing
before the court which would have
enabled it to command restitution o f
the gains made or even the payment
o f damages to those more greatly injured.
The court went as far as it
could go in dissolving the monopoly.
There is still the anti-trust law, which
could be invoked by the Justice department
for the more drastic applications
o f its penalties, but somehow,
after 49 years and 8 months since the
law was enacted, drastic application
to the point of fines and imprisonment
has not been made.
That there are laws in plenty to
be applied to monopolies is evident
from the manner in which the Supreme
court has continued to uphold
their provisions from time to time.
Delay, compromise, avoidance and
general inefficiency have characterized
enforcement o f anti-trust laws
from the start, and they continue to
impede justice just as the monopolies
continue to impede national porgress
by oppression and intimidation o f independent
concerns. Three years ago
the Trade Commission pointed out
the monopolization o f the dairy supply
in many larger cities .Six months
ago, indictments were brought in by
a Chicago grand-jury against 96 people,
public officials as well as those
of the conspiring corporations, for
monopolizing Chicago’s supply o f
fresh milk. When, if ever, the cases
may be brought to trial, nobody seems
to know. In the meantime, the benefits
o f organized control continue to
cost farmers and consumers alike
many thousands o f dollars daily.
The Senate’s comimttee investigating
monopolies seems to be plodding
along in a way “ not to scare big business”
. It has mot reached the point
o f investigating the history o f inefficient
law enforcement which enables
monopolistic conspiracies to thrive
and pile up millions in profits notwithstanding
the decisions o f the
courts as to what is and what is not
a conspiracy in restraint o f trade.
The Senators now are studying the
business methods o f the big life insurance
companies to discover whether
or not they are using their immense
resources toward control o f industry
and commerce. It is not believed
that any o f the corporations
are exercising such control for their
own benefit. There are many big interests,
however, represented in the
management o f such companies, and
how far such interests are able to
utilize the power o f the corporations
for their own special purposes is more
the province o f the investigations.
Not all large business concerns are
engaged in practices which seem at
least peculiar when the light is turned
upon them, but from the investigations
o f the last twenty years it seems
that all too often there are officials
who are willing to resort to financial
or managerial jugglery when an honest
and conscientious compliance with
law would be a greater advantage and
an assurance against public reproach.
In its investigations o f the life insurance
company methods, one o f the
first revelations made was that certain
officials and agents o f one of
the largest corporations had engaged
in forgery o f proxies which were used
at annual meetings o f one o f the
largest o f the insurance companies.
Higher officials o f the same company
declared their ignorance and their
condemnation o f i.he practice very
promptly, but the notoriety brought
to their institution cannot be explained
upon a plea o f ignorance o f
those in higher places.
More than thirty years have elapsed
since the present Chief Justice
Hughes startled the nation and the
financial centers o f the world by exposing
conditions in some o f the big
eastern companies. New laws were
passed and under closer supervision
the corporations have been better
managed and far more successful. In
that 30-year period they have added
twenty billions o f dollars to their resources.
The present financial standing
o f the companies is unquestioned.
Life insurance continues to be one of
the best and safest forms o f investment
as well as protection. Even so,
the Senate committee may discover
methods which are beneficial to neither
the policy holders nor the country.
It is certain that forged proxies will
never again be permitted by any of
them.
BLA CK R IV E R FA L L S CO-OP
PRESEN TS “ THE SPIDER W E B ”
A Co-operative Play in three acts
by Ellis Cowling.
Act 1— The Dixon Home. A Summer
Night in 1935.
Act. 2— The Co-operative Manager’s
Office. The Next Day.
Act 3.— The Dixon Home. A Summer
Night One Yveek Later.
Characters, in order o f their appearance.
Mary Ellen Dixon, seventeen, Ruth
Dunlap.
Mrs. James Dixon, her mother,
Mrs. Grant Grebei.
Kuth Klein, eighteen and something
o f a flapper, Dorothy McNulty.
Jack Armer, a lively young man,
Grant Grebei.
Kenneth Orr, a young man, a bit
bashful, Ellsworth Sharp.
Mr. James Dixon, a middle-aged
farmer, George Dettinger.
Vem Orr, a farmer who sticks to
farming, Douglas Curran.
Robert Hail, A Co-operative Manager,
Kay Huriburt.
Joe Stein, a Co-operative service
man, middle aged, Richard Faldet.
Ralph Mitchell, a Co-operative service
man, middle aged, Robert Nortman,
Jr.
Cecil Jones, a Co-operative service
man, about thirty, Leonard Drescher.
Max Abrams, a Co-operative service
man, about thirty, George Martin.
Miss Smith, a stenagrapher, Alma
Kay.
Directed by Mrs. Richard Faldet
and Mrs. Thomas Stodola.
Stage Property Manager, Mr. Ray
Huriburt.
To be presented at the Falls Theatre,
Wednesday, February 22nd.
lo rk Community Hall, Saturday,
February 25th.
TU E SD A Y CLUB NEW S
The next meeting o f the Tuesday
club will be held Wednesday, March
1st at the home o f Mrs. Jack Sypulski,
who will be assisted as hostess by
Mrs. C. L. McDonald. The program
will be in charge o f Mrs. A. M. Komstad.
The last meeting o f the club was
held at the home o f Mrs. Otto Flugstad,
with Mrs. Inga Gulbrandsen as
assistant hostess. The program was
given by A. P. Jones, who gave a very
interesting talk on petroglyphs and
historical facts o f Jackson county. His
talk was very much enjoyed by the
club members.
PERSO NALS
The House passed the air-plane
bill,, part o f the emergency national
defense program. It authorizes the
construction o f 3,000 new war planes
in the next three years. This is a
policy bill, and not an appropriation.
The total authorization is $376,000,-
000. How much will be appropriated
for each year o f the authorization remains
for further consideration. The
bill also carries the authorization of
funds for fortifying and other protection
to the Panama canal. This is
the first measure o f the program, but
other measures are likely to bring on
more o f a division, this bill passing
Hans Bates o f MerrilU-n, underwent
an appendectomy at the hospital,
Monday.
Miss Mary Spaulding and Miss Julia
Claussen were visitors in La
Crosse one day last week.
Miss Ruth Dunlap went to La
Crosse Saturday to take a civil service
examination which was held
there.
Eugene O’Brien broke a bone in
his ankle, Sunday, when he slipped
and fell at the oil station where he
works.
Hon. P. A. Hemmy was in town
Monday, on his way to Madison after
spending the week end at his home
in Humbird.
Corrine Stanley, daughter of Chester
Stanley, o f Humbird, is a patient
at the hospital following an appendectomy,
Monday.
Miss Pearl Marie Bowman and
Miss Alice Heller, who is visiting
here from Duluth, were shoppers in
La Crosse, Thursday.
Mrs. George Howson o f Aberdeen,
South Dakota, arrived last week and
is visiting at the home o f her mother,
Mrs. H. P. Jensen.
Rugus Dimmick was a business visitor
in La Crosse Friday afternoon.
He was accompanied by his father,
James Dimmick, and Henry Sprester.
Mr. and Mrs. Horace Anderson, of
Marshfield, were visitors in town on
Monday. Mrs. Anderson called on
Mrs. Ray Biggar and Mrs. Gladys Mc-
Manners.
Mrs. Christina Gunderson, o f Melrose,
is a patient at the hospital following
an operation last Friday for
ruptured appendix. She is getting
along pretty well.
Mrs. Louis Davenport, o f Irving,
was admitted to the hospital Tuesday
of last week, seriously ill o f an infection
in her hand and arm following
a felon on her finger.
Mr. and Mrs. Henry Halverson,
daughter Margaret, and son Kingsley,
drove up from Mineral Point,
Sunday, to attend the funeral o f the
late Mrs. Hubert Johnson.
E. E. Homstad and Ralph Boehlke
left Tuesday afternoon for Milwaukee
where they will attend an oil
meeting. They drove to Sparta and
went by train from there.
Mrs. Esther Peterson was appointed
as investigator for the W PA review
for Clark and Jackson counties
and has taken up her new work. She
spent Tuesday in Dorchester.
Mr. and Mrs. Henry E. Olson went
to Baraboo Saturday afternoon and
were guests at the Bob Peck home
until Sunday evening. They went
to help Janis celebrate her birthday
anniversary.
R. A. Jones, and Dr. and Mrs. Irwin
Krohn, o f this city, and Mr. and
Mrs. Frederick Barber, o f Warrens,
attended a meeeting o f the Union
Cranberry Company held at Minneapolis,
Saturday.
Mrs. C. A. Kuhn left Friday for
Hot Springs, Arkansas, where she
will spend about a month at the home
of her parents. Mr. Kuhn plans to
drive there and bring her back, after
spending a few days there.
Miss Lucile Monroe, o f Boscobel,
who attends the University o f Wisconsin,
came Monday to see her
grandfather, H. H. Iverson, o f Taylor,
who is a patient at the hospital.
She returned Monday night.
B E A V E R S
March 1st is our next meeting
night. Be there and have a good time
with us. Lunch and entertainment.
NOTICE
Play Chinese checkers a tthe American
Legion hall, Friday, Feb. 24th.
Lunch will be served and prizes given.
Everybody come.
by a vote o f 367 to 15. Included in
the measure are provisions for training
army flyers to the possible number
o f 21.000. Other defense measures
pending, aside from the regular
Army and Navy appropriations, are
those for air-bases at an estimated
cost o f $65,000,000, and a further
increase in officers and men in the
Army and Navy. Added to the battleship
and other naval and military authorizations,
the total appropriations
asked for preparedness purposes,
and maintenance o f the present defense.
may be close to two billions o f
dollars, or about 20 per cent o f national
expenditures, estimated at ten
billions for the coming vear.
MERLIN HULL.
GETS FULL PARDON
The story o f the full pardon o f a
man convicted 42 years ago will bring
back memories o f a tragedy that
darkened the home o f a worthy North
Bend couple. The case was tried
before Hon. W. F. Bailey, and George
M. Popham served as district attorney
at that time.
The following story appeared in
Saturday’s Madison State Journal.
Gov. Heil today wiped out the shadow
o f prison and parole that for 42
years has dogged the steps o f George
T. Palmer, convicted in 1897 o f the
murder o f a four-year-old Jackson
county girl.
By granting Palmer, now 59, an
absolute pardon, the governor took
the last step needed to set him completely
free for the first time since
he entered Waupun prison as a 17-
year-old youth.
Canadian bom Palmer was brought
to Marathon county by his parents
when he was three years old. At 15
he was adopted by a Jackson county
farmer. One day he struck the latter’s
4-year-old daughters with an axe
and killed her. His subsequent attempt
at suicide failed.
Jackson county court records, taken
at the trial in 1897, show in their
yellowing pages that Palmer claimed
his foster father had persecuted him,
and that in a fit o f insanity he had
stmck and killed the child.
Sentenced to Waupun for life, the
youth became a young man there,
passed his 30s and 40s. In 1931, already
51, Palmer was paroled from
Waupun. He returned to prison voluntarily.
He was paroled again in
1932, and o f his own will returned
once more to the penitentiary— his
home the greater part o f his life.
Paroled a third time on June 19,
1934, he went to work on a farm.
This time he did not return, worked
steadily and used several hundred dollars
o f his earnings to care for his
88-year-old mother.
Former Gov. La Follette on March
9, 1937, granted him a conditional
pardon. The state board o f control
on Feb. 7 o f this year recommended
that he be released from supervision.
Heil’s pardon carried out the recommendation
o f the board.
Palmer is free now, but both the
district attorney who prosecuted him
and the judge who sentenced him,
have died.
MRS. M A R T H A H ALVERSON
Mrs. Martha Halverson passed
away at her farm home south o f Taylor,
Tuesday night, Feb. 14, 1939, at
the age o f 81 years, six months and
18 days.
She was born at Slen, Voee, Norway,
July 26, 1867, a daughter o f
Joseph and Ragna (Peterson) Johnson.
She came to America with her
parents when she was seven years old
and the family settled in Walwort
county, Wisconsin. Two years lated
Mrs. Halvorson and her parents
came by stage coach to Sparta, and
then drove to Jackson county, where
they settled on a farm in the community
which was her home for many
years.
She left her home in Vosse Coulie
following her marriage to Sever H.
Halvorson on June 24, 1886, and
went to Skutley Coulie, now called
Rose Hill. She lived on the family
farm since the death o f her husband
on October 25, 1918, and although
somewhat incapacitated by failing
eyesight she did her household duties
with the aid o f her three sons
until recently. To this union six
children were born, and all survive.
They are: Alfred, Mrs. Regina Johnson,
Ernest, (Gena) Mrs. Bennie
Knutson, Bennie, and Sedwin, all of
Taylor.
Mrs. Halvorson is also survived by
seven grandchildren: Shirley, Arlene
and Alvira Halvorson, Shirley
and Lillian Johnson, Mrs. Gladys Harmes
and Maurice Knutson, and one
great-grandchild, Laurna Mae Harmes,
a half-brother, Bennie Thompson
was killed by a horse on a farm
in Curran Valley 42 years ago.
Mrs. Halvorson walked from eight
to ten miles from her home across
the bluffs to church to prepare herself
for confirmation and was a member
o f the first Evangelical Lutheran
church o f Trempealeau Valley. A
reunion o f the remaining charter
members was attended by Mrs. Halvorson
a few years ago. Although
unable to attend church in her later
years, she always listened to church
programs on her radio.
Funeral services were held Saturday
at 1 o’clock at the Gibson Funeral
Home, at Taylor, and at 1 :30
at the Taylor Lutheran church, conducted
by Rev. A. J. Bringle who
paid a fine tribute to the life o f this
pioneer woman. Three sons and three
grandsons acted as pall bearers. A
song, “ Jesus Lover o f My Soul” was
sung by Mr. and Mrs. Henry Huseboe,
Selma Huseboe and George Lind
with Selma Huseboe as organist. Mrs.
Huseboe also sang a lovely Norwegian
hymn, “ Mor” . Burial was made
at Trump Coulie cemetery beside her
husband.
She will be missed not only by her
children and grandchildren but by a
host o f other relatives and friends.
Those from away to attend the funeral
were Mrs. Leroy Harmes and
Mrs. Norman Thompson o f Black
Ricer Falls; Miss Juliette Halvorson
o f La Crosse; Mr. and Mrs. Fred
Higley and children o f Eau Claire.
M ARTH A SO CIETY
The postponed Martha meeting will
be held Wednesday evening, Feb. 22,
at the church parlors. Serving committee—
Mrs. A. P. Jones, Mrs. L. D.
Anderson, Mrs. Pearl Rose and Miss
Mary Upton.
BIRTHS
A son was born at the hospital,
February 21, 1939, to Mr. and Mrs.
Joseph Church, o f Melrose.
A son was born February 21, 1939,
to Mr. and Mrs. La Verne Peterson,
o f this city.
A daughter, Janice Marie, was
born February 19, 1939, to Mr. and
Mrs. George Dickey, o f this city.
A daughter was born at the hospital,
February 17, 1939, to Mr. and
Mrs. Charles Moutour, o f this city.
A son, Roy Hugh, was born February
15, 1939, to Mr. and Mrs. Hugh
Washburn, o f the town o f Brockway.
A son, James Anton, was bom on
February 15, 1939, to Mr. and Mrs.
James Blazek, o f Hatfield.
A son, James Robert, was born at
the hospital, February 13, 1939, to
Mr. and Mrs. James Vodicka, o f this
city.
A little daughter, Margaret Ruth
Ann, was bora at the hospital, Wednesday
night, February 15, 1939, to
Mr. and Mrs. Hubert Johnson, o f
Disco. The mother was Miss Margaret
Johnson, o f this city.
D EATH OF BR YA N J. CA STLE
A T TH E A G E OF 90 YEAR S
(C ontinued fro m page 1)
eyes only slightly dimmed by the
years. His neatly trimmed white
beard recalls the early days o f the
century, as do his stiff wing collar,
black string necktie, and shiny pointed
shoes.
Favors a Merit System
Mr. Castle will be 88 years old in
July. He is still extremely active for
that age in spite o f recent ill health.
He likes to travel, especially through
the South, reads a great deal, and
takes an active interest in state affairs,
particularly as regards the extension
o f the merit system o f hiring
government employees, a project to
which he has devoted much o f his
time and influence.
Born in Ireland in July, 1848, Mr.
Castle came to the United States in
early infancy. The family settled in
New Work for a time, but in 1861
came west, stopping in Madison for a
short while, then moving on to Crawford
county. At the age o f 15, two
years later, young Castle returned to
Madison. He worked for a time on a
farm below the state fair grounds.
The land on which he worked is now
owned by the Castle family. He also
worked for a time in Thomas Hagen’s
blacksmith shop in the sixth ward,
just long enough to put aside a little
money.
With these small savings, young
Bryan went to Cincinnati, where he
enrolled in the Polytechnic College,
a pretentious name, he says, for a
small school. To help pay his expenses
he worked in a job printing
office.
It was in this period that he met
Colonel J. C. Murphy and his band
o f Union refugees from East Tennessee
who had come North to purchase
supplies for their Southern store. The
kindly Colonel was attracted to the
serious Irish youth in the print shop
and offered him a job in the South
at much higher wages than he wTas
then receiving. Adventure called to
Bryan Castle and he accepted Colonel
Murphy’s offer.
Remembers Clearly Lincoln's
Assassination
In the early laii alter oniy a few
months at ivnoxviile, nearby military
movements caused Mr. Castle, then
lb years of age to leave Tennessee.
He walked up tnrougn Powell Valley,
crossed tne Cumberland mountains
and entered Kentucky where,
during the winter, he helped care for
some government mules near Camp
Nelson. In April, 180o, he wandered
back to Chattanooga and there entered
in the federal service as a civilian
in the quartermaster’s department.
His work was freighting government
supplies by mule train between Atlanta
and Chattanooga along the
route made famous by Sheridan and
his men. He was in Chattanooga,
April 14, when the news o f Lincoln’s
assassination was received. He remembers
the event clearly— the horror
and despair of the people, the
hope that the war was ended.
In the fall o f 1865 Mr. Castle returned
to Wisconsin, worked in the
harvest, and after that work was finished
took an examination for a
teacher’s certificate at old Middleton
Station. He passed, but upon deciding
to return to Richland county
where he had relatives it was necessary
for him to take a second examination
before he could be certified
to teach there. After this formality
he secured his first public position.
It was in 1881, after he had been
first a teacher, later an editor, that
he secured an appointment as committee
clerk to the Wisconsin Assembly
committee on Lumber and
Manufactures. This was the beginning
o f his career as a state employee
The following year he received the
first of his two appointments as clerk
in the Department o f Public Lands.
Mr. Castle attended the Law School
at the University of Wisconsin, graduating
with the class o f 1890. He was
first admitted to practice law in Prairie
du Chien where he was then employed
as principal o f the fourth
ward school. He later edited the
Prairie du Chien Union.
Since his retirement Mr. Castle has
spent his winters traveling. Recently
he visited Norris Dam, Lincoln Memorial
University at Harrowgate,
Tenn., and the territory in Kentucky
and Tennessee where he worked 72
years ago. He is biding his time now
until he gets back enough strength to
visit some o f the interesting spots in
the Ozark mountains o f southern
Missouri and northern Arkansas.
Collects Valuable Reference Books
Mr. Castle’s hobby has been the
collection o f valuable reference books
and he has over 3000 volumes o f this
sort besides his law books. Many of
them concern political science ; some
are historical, others biographical. He
has 30 volumes on Lincoln, the man
whom Mr. Castle considers the greatest
o f all personalities. He reveres
Lincoln because o f his honesty, great
mind and love o f simplicity. Mr. Castle
believes that the people must be
governed by reason and honesty. It
is for this reason that he is such an
earnest advocate o f civil service.
During his travels through the
South Mr. Castle is often asked to
speak before special groups there, lie
usually talks on his favorite subject,
Lincoln, and he finds that audiences
there are really interested in hearing
a simple, honest discussion o f this
great man. Mr. Castle also enjoys
talking about Edison and Benjamin
Franklin, because these great men illustrate
Mr. Castle’s own simple philosophy
o f life that the little things
are the things that matter; that the
great man is the simple man.
Although in political circles Mr.
Castle has long been known as a Stalwart
Republican his real political religion
is not rooted in a party but in
a desire to see a job for every man
able and willing to work at a compensation
to afford that man and his
family a comfortable living.
Mr. Castle’s daughter, Miss Mildred
Castle, is also making the public service
her career. She is employed in
the office o f the Secretary o f State.
CLE VELA N D
Miss Thelma Holman spent the
week end at home.
Herman Johnson and family were
B. R. Falls visitors Friday.
A son was bom to Mr. and Mrs.
Leonard Watson, Saturday.
Leonard Hobbs and Mr. and Mrs.
Aaron Johnson were Fairchild visitors
Friday afternoon.
Miss Ellen Larson entertained the
school children and their mothers
with a valentine party Wednesday.
Mrs. Chas. Holman and daughters
Thelma and Lucille spent Saturday
with Mrs. Morris Faldet, near Hixton.
John Matysik’s house was completely
destroyed by fire Saturday. It is
thought it started from a chimney
fire.
ST A T E OF COUNTY TRU NK
PATROLM EN HIRED
State trunk patrolmen were hired
in the forenoon and county trunk
patrolmen in tne atternoon at a meeting
held Tuesday o f last week in the
mgnway ottice ox the court house.
G. N. Growt and T. Al. Reynolds,
o f the La Crosse division highway o ffice,
were here for the meeting which
was attended by Sam Amundson, of
Melrose; Peter Bever, o f Fairchild,
members o f the highway committee.
Charles M. Olson, member o f the
committee from Northfield, was ill
and could not attend. Commissioner
O. H. Overlien and Dan Clark assisted
in the work.
Following are the patrolmen, their
work, and length o f their patrol.
State Trunk Patrolmen:
All Truck Sec.
Sec. 1, U. S. No. 12, Henry Arndt,
32.08 miles
Sec. 2 S. T. 54, H. L. Schilling,
16.93 miles
Sec. 3 S. T. 54-71-108 James Clark,
14.43 miles.
Sec. 4 S. T. No. 27, W. H. Duerkop,
18.51 miles
Sec. 5 S. T. No. 95, Ernest Galster,
23.26 miles
Sec. 6 S. T. No. 10-27, B. J. Larson,
17.95 miles
Sec. 7 S. T. No. 27-54, Joe Weiduch,
21.58 miles
Sec. 8 S. T. No. 54, Frank Smagacz,
21.22 miles
County Trunk Patrolmen:
Sec. 1 C. T. “ B” Albert Holman
Team Sec., 8.0 miles
Sec. 2 C. T. “ B-T” Louis Jacobson,
Team, 8.7 miles
Sec. 3 C. T. “ G-U” Edwin Moe,
Team, 9.0 miles
Sec. 4 C. T. “ A -F ” Ray Duxbury,
Motor Patrol, 20.0 miles
Sec. 5 C. T. “ K” Frank Bohac,
Team, 7.0 miles
Sec. 6 C. T. “ P” Gang help, truck
Sec., 15.1 miles
Sec. 7 C. T. “ C” John Sampson,
Motor-patrol, 16.0 miles
Sec. 8 C. T. “ N” Edwin Peterson,
Motor Patrol, 16.0 miles
Sec. 9 C. T. “ D” Edgar Olson,
Team, 8.5 miles
Sec. 10 C. T. “ H” Arthur L. Overlien,
team, 8.0 miles
Sec. 11 C. T. “ O-HH” George Rudolph,
team, 14.0 miles
Sec. 12 C. T. “ Z ” Tom Hanutke,
team, 6.0 miles
Sec. 13 C. T. “ V -w ” John H. Johnson,
team, 7.0 miles
Sec. 14 C. T. “ P” Peter O. Anderson,
team, 7.0 miles
Sec. 15 C. T. “ H” Dan Danielson,
team, 6.0 miles
Sec. 16 C. T. “ X ” Peter Hoagenson,
team, 6.8 miles
Sec. 17 C. T. “ X ” Mandenus Peterson,
team, 8.6 miles
Sec. 18 C. T. “ J” Irvine Baird,
team, 6.5 miles
Sec. 19 C. T. “ O-S” Extra gang,
Motor Patrol, 9.5 miles
Sec. 20 C. T. “ U” Spencer Hanson,
team, 11.5 miles.
B-J SM OKE SIGNALS
By Red Cloud
In these days o f relief some have
slumped down so far that they can’t
catch cold for themselves.
And again there’s the fellow who
is so ignorant he thinks he knows
everything. That’s what we would
call ignorantly intellectual.
Sunday the 19th was the birth o f
a new moon. Indians call it the raccoon
courting moon. Raccoons come
out o f hibernating and commence
traveling up and down streams and
rivers looking for mates. During
this moon the weather is very much
changeable. Mornings may be warm
and thawing but in the afternoon the
temperature may drop way below
zero. Many many hunters and travelers
have been known to freeze to
death because o f inadequate clothing.
Again it could be just the reverse.
A blizzard blowing in the morning
and spring-like weather in the afternoon.
This moon is considered by the
Indians as not a winter month nor a
spring month but a sort o f pariah
among the many moons o f the year.
Next month will be the Winnebago’s
calendar moon of fish-courting. These
animals and fishes do not wait for
the month o f June for any love making.
W
hatever Old Chief Dandy, last
o f the great Winnebago prophets prophesied
and was right, and whatever
old Mother Shipton prophesied and
turned out to be true, yet these two
never mentioned the long range forecasting
o f weather that we are about
to have. The farmer will have come
into his own when this have come to
pass. Close study o f air movements
by scientists have brought to light
many startling discoveries which will
be used as a basis o f weather forecasting.
From now on until well into April
there will be bustling activities in the
sugarbush camps o f farmers and Indians
who make it a practice each
year to make maple syrup and maple
sugar. There will be hustling preparation
for the tapping of trees for sap
when that sweet life-blood o f trees
begins to run. Boiling vessels will be
scoured, sap sprouts will be cleaned
and firewood will be gotten up too.
Lots and lots o f work but when the
sap has been boiled down to a light
conistency when a person can take a
large spoon or a wooden paddle and
skim off the froth and harden it by a
quick dip in cold water all drudgery
is forgotten. Skimming off the foam
is just a prelude to having pure unadulterated
maple syrup on nice piping
hot pancakes. Eating o f maple
sugar comes later in the season. Some
Indians still use home made birch
bark vessels to catch the sap but
many have switched over to using of
pails or gallon cans. But whatever
is used the result is the same. It’s
yum yum and more yum yum.
PAPO O SE CREEK
Morris Olson was a caller at Mrs.
Sophia Mason’s at Spring Creek, last
Friday.
Blanche Olson spent a couple of
days here with her grandmother, Mrs.
Anna Olson.
Martin Tjorstad o f Taylor, was a
business caller at Morris Olson’s one
day last week.
Archie Emerson was entertained at
Henry Johnsons’ and at Andy Harmer’s,
last Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Gaylord Emerson
were visiting her parents, Mr. and
Mrs. Iver Olson, Sunday.
Mrs. Herman Reschke and son
Donald, o f Warrens, visited recently
with her mother, Mrs. O. Halverson
and family.
Mrs. Forrest Loasching o f Sechlerville,
visited one day last week
with her mother and brother, the
Ha versons.
Ford Harmer and Floyd Baker
were hauling wood for Will Gonia
from the Emil Torkelson farm south
o f Disco, last Monday.
Mrs. Mollie Emerson and two sons
visited one day ast week with Miss
Caroline and Henry Johnson. Wayne
remained to help his uncle Henry
with some o f his work.
IT’S FUN
WHEN YOU
HAVE NO
RENT TO
PAY
When you buy or build a home on our
plan, your future “ rent-money” pays
for it. After a fewT years, you’ll have
no more payments and no more rent .
the home will be yours.
With our home-financing
plan your interest cost decreases
as the loan is paid
off.
Tk
t r JACKSON COUNTY 
IF e d e r a l S a v i n g s
AN D L O A N A S S O C IA T IO N
R U F U S D I M M I C K . S E C R E T A R Y
B L A C K R I V E R F A L L S . W I S C O N S I N
'X jS lfc f These new Phoenix Personality
shades have a way of glamour•
hing your legs. The tones will
grow on you . . . and glow
on youl See INTRIGUE — an
unusual toasted tan, and ELAT
IO N — a stunning copper
bright.
PHOENIX
o m n .
HOSIERY
Special Prices
$1.09 Hose..... 2 Pr- f°r $1.85
79c H ose....... 2 Pr- f°r $1.45
59c H ose....... 2 P r-f°r $ 1 . 9 0
BlGG VR’S
(F O R M E R L Y M ARSH ’ S)
Black River Falls Wisconsin
V--
Young folks, old folks, everyone join the FERDINAND coloring
contest. All you do to enter is clip the above picture from
the paper and color it to the best of your ability. Then be
sure to leave it at the AVALON THEATRE BOX OFFICE
no later than SUNDAY, MARCH 5. THREE prizes will be
awarded to the best picture. First prize 5 FREE admission
tickets — 2nd Prize 3 FREE Admissions, 3rd Prize 2 FREE
Admissions.
NORTH BRANCH
Mr. and Mrs. Archie Burnett were
Eau Claire callers Monday.
Mr. and Mrs. Will Koehler entertained
company Sunday.
Mrs. Archie Burnett attended the
Civic club at Hixtc n, Tuesday.
Basil Burnett and family spent
Tuesday evening at Louie Janke’s.
Nygaards and Melbye entertained
the Upper Pigeon Ladies Aid, Friday.
L. H. Krueger and son Harvey
made a business trip to Dodgeville,
Friday.
Lyndahl Melbye and John and Casper
Nygaard spent Friday evening at
Ralph Sheffer’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Harvey Carpenter attended
community club at the Burton
school house Friday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Lester Shimmings
and three children o f Warrens, spent
Saturday night and Sunday with Mr.
and Mrs. Harvey Carpenter.
A number o f the mothers helped
Mrs. Christianson and pupils enjoy a
valentine party and short program
and nice lunch, Tuesday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Roger Hoonsbeen,
Mr. and Mrs. Anton Varklick and
daughter Betty Rose, also Mr. and
Mrs. Claire Enerson and son9, Dick
and Kenny were entertained at Enoch
Enerson’s Sunday.
CARD OF T H A N K S
W e wish to thank ou r friends fo r their
expressions o f sym p ath y upon the death of
our beloved m other and gran dm other, Mrs.
George Horne. W e are particularly gra teful
to Mr. and Mrs. E. S. Jedney fo r their
kindness, the pall bearers, those -who fu rnished
cars, and the Eastern Star fo r its
beautiful service.
MR. A N D MRS. C. E. H ORN E
AN D FA M ILY
IN M EM ORIAM
In lovin g m em ory o f o u r dear m other,
Mrs. Ole H. P eterson, w ho passed aw ay
fiv e years a go tod a y , February 22, 1934.
lw p TH E C H ILD R EN
THE BANNER-JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin PAGE NO. 5
:: MERRILLAN LEADER NEWS ::
MRS. OLIVER SPENCER
Word was received here Monday o f
the death o f Mrs. Oliver Spencer, nee
Theo Judkins o f Great Falls, Mont.,
and a sister o f Mrs. Clarence Johnson.
Death was caused from cancer
o f the liver. Mrs. Spencer went thru
the clinic at Rochester, Minn., last
November, just before Thanksgiving,
coming here afterwards for a day’s
visit on her way back home. Shortly
after arriving there she took to her
bed and gradually failed until death
took her at 10:45 Monday morning.
Mrs. Spencer, a daughter o f Mr.
and Mrs. Seba Judkins, attended the
Merrillan High school and then the
Hyde Park High school at Chicago,
graduating from there. She then
graduated from the Stout Home Economics
school at Menomonie, later
becoming employed at various places
until her marriage to Mr. Spencer.
She leaves her husband and one son,
William.
Mrs. Clarence Johnson left here
Tuesday morning for Great Falls, to
attend the funeral, and will probably
be gone a month or so.
The members o f the local cribbage
club met with Mrs. J. H. Stiehl last
Tuesday evening. Mrs. Stiehl served
another o f those suppers that men
like. The score o f the members was
as follows: C. J. Johnson 189, Eric
Erickson 176, Joe Stiehl 158, Fred
Helbling 142, Oscar Erickson 135,
Oscar Rickard 129, C. A. Nolop 123,
Bob Hamilton 115, O. F. Peterson
98, Nels Erickson 88, Hi Hendrix 61
and Ed Persson 59.
The Men’s supper at the M. E.
church last Wednesday was fairly
well patronized in spite o f the awful
weather. And they all say the supper
was good, with its roast beef, etc.
The net proceeds were nearly $15.
Phone 90
We will call for and deliver
Laundry and Dry Cleaning ---
We wash on Mondays, Wednesdays
and Thursdays.
Keller’s Laundry
BLACK RIVER FALLS, W l£
A T H L E T I C C L U B W I N F R O M
H I X T O N 39 t o 25
L e d b y C h r i s t y w h o d u n k e d 11
c o u n t s v i a f i v e f i e l d e r s a n d a f r e e
c a s t t h e A . C . b a s k e t t e a m w o n a n
e a s y v i c t o r y f r o m a s m a l l e r b u t f a s t
a n d s c r a p p y H i x t o n s q u a d h e r e l a s t
T u e s d a y e v e n i n g . T h e l o s e r s s p a r k
p l u g w a s S k a a r e w h o c a g e d t w o f i e l d
b u c k e t s a n d a h a l f d o z e n o f t h e f r e e
v a r i e t y o f c o u n t s . N e x t i n l i n e in
t a l l y i n g w a s F r o s t , o f M e r r i l l a n , w h o
s u n k f o u r 2 - p o i n t e r s , f o l l o w e d b y
S k u t l e y o f H i x t o n , w h o b r a c k e t e d
t h r e e d o u b le s a n d a o n e c o u n t e r .
T h r o u g h o u t t h e g a m e w a s f a s t a n d
f u r i o u s b u t c l e a n , d e s p it e 28 p e r s o n a l
o f f e n s e s , d iv i d e d w i t h 16 f o r t h e A .
C . ’ s a n d 12 a g a i n s t t h e g u e s t s . T h e
p a r a d e t o t h e f r e e m a r k w a s d u e
m o s t l y t o t h e s p e e d o f t h e b a l l g a m e
r a t h e r t h a n in t e n d e d m a y h e w .
T h e e n e m y g a v e a n u n u s u a l l y g o o d
a c c o u n t o f t h e m s e l v e s c o n s i d e r i n g
t h a t i t w a s o n l y t h e i r t h i r d g a m e o f
t h e y e a r .
T h e s c o re :
H ix t o n — F G F T P T P
H a g e n , F ............................................... X 0 1 2
H a n s o n , F ............................ ...................2 0 0 4
S k a a re , C ---- --------------------- 2 6 1 10
S k a a r , G ................................................0 1 2 1
N o rth ru p , G ..........................................0 0 0 0
S k u tle y , F .............................................3 1 5 7
R e ia in g e r, G — ------------------0 0 1 0
M itc h e ll. C .............................................0 2 1 2
R h e in e c k . G ............................ - .......... 0 0 1 0
T o t a ls ............. ..................................8 9 12 25
A . C .’ s—
C h r is t y , F ........................................— .5 1 0 11
N ic h o ls, F ________________________1 1 3 3
H a y d e n . C ...................... - ...................1 0 1 2
M a ta a ls , G ...............................................2 1 3 5
F r o s t . G ..................................................4 0 4 8
P o rt e r, G ........... .............— ................1 1 2 3
B e n so n . F ............................ ................1 0 1 2
B a r r it t , F _________________________ 0 0 0 0
K o lb r a c . C .............................................2 1 2 5
T o t a ls ..........................................17 5 16 39
H ix t o n ........................................... .......4 0 12 9 25
M . A . C .............................. ............ .........6 14 12 7 39
M i s s L o r r a i n e D u n n o f S p a r t a , i n
c o m p a n y w i t h a g i r l f r i e n d , v i s i t e d
h e r e l a s t S a t u r d a y f o r a s h o r t t i m e
w i t h h e r p a r e n t s , M r . a n d M r s . L e s l
i e D u n n .
H e n r y C o l l u m h a s p u r c h a s e d t h e
o ld E i d b u i l d i n g o n M a in s t r e e t f r o m
O s c a r S k a a r a n d i t i s r e p o r t e d t h a t
h e w i l l m o v e i t o v e r t o h i s l o t s o n
N o . 1 2 .
L a f e O n s t a d i s o f f e r i n g m u c h o f
h i s h o u s e h o ld g o o d s f o r s a l e S a t u r d
a y a f t e r n o o n c o m m e n c in g a t 1 o ’c
l o c k , a t t h e h o u s e .
O s c a r S p r a g u e c a m e f r o m M i l w a u k
e e l a s t S u n d a y f o r a s h o r t v i s i t w i t h
h i s m o t h e r , w h o i s q u i t e i l l .
Mrs. Anna Erickson is still quite
ill. f
A V A L O N
M O TIO N PICTURES ARE Y O U R BEST E N TE RT A INM EN T1
FRI., SAT.
MIRACLE RACKET
EXPOSED!
FEB. 24, 25
Anil M ilU r
M m K regar
Feature 2 I The 3
Mesquiteers
SUN.. MON. FEB. 26, 27
PLUS
“LINCOLN in the
WHITE HOUSE”
Continuous Showing Sunday
Starting at 1 p. m.
TUESDAY FEB. 28
120 120 120 120
WED., THURSDAY, FRIDAY
MARCH 1, 2, 3
W IN N IN G the W O R LD
in n w o m a n ’s h e a rtl
GARY COOPER
Adventures
JSiarco Poll
«•-(* B A S IL R A T H 30NE V.
Ernest Trutx • G«orv« 3arbi«r
Alan Hale • Binnie ilarnet
D irected by A R C H IE t * A Y O
Released tkru United A -fists j l » I
j* rM W ii*SIG RID G U R K
New ecreen discovery from .Norway £
Feature 2
Raw drama!...
Three against
th e r a g in g
in cp.a1
BARRIE
ALAN HALE
BARRY FTT7 GERALD
' K O RADIO ficMt.
D irected b y I E W L A N D E R S . Produced by
R O I I R T SISK . Ser..n hov b , Johfl Twi*
STARTING SATURDAY, MARCH 4TH
LO R ET TA R IC H A R D
YOUNG-GREENE
WALTER BRENNAN
DOUGLAS DUMBRILIE
KAREN MORLEY ,
MORONI OLSEN
WINONA LAGERS EASY FOR
MERRILLAN CLUB 42 TO 21
Very little difficulty was experienced
by the Athletic club in a game recently
in which they outclassed the
alleged high class Winona Lagers by
a margin that widened to 42 to 21
when the going was over. Hayden
and Christy were the big shots in the
Merrillan offensive with a total of
22 points divided 12 to 10, Christy
getting the larger portion. A guy
named Davis was high for the visitors
with 2 fielders and 3 charities for 7.
The Locals started off gertly by
gaining a 7 to 4 mark in the curtain
raising division- o f the ball game.
Nine counts were rolled thru the
drapes in the 2d period, and the half
ended at 10 to 7. The insertion o f
the " B ” squad only served to shift
the score even more on the Merrillan
side, until the third period ended at
30 to 14. Twelve more counters were
registered by the Athletics in the
final round as compared with 7 by
the Minnesotans.
Tho the game from a scoring standpoint
was dull generally there were
a number o f fast plays by the home
towners that fairly sparkled with brilliance
and served to demonstrate the
fact that Merrillan has one o f the
greatest semi pro teams in the state.
May we pause to make note that the
Blair Merchants and the Neillsville
squad may also be placed in this class
o f ball teams. They being the only
teams, except Osseo, who were capable
o f giving the A. C. regulars anything
like a ballgame to date.
W in o n a L a g e r s : F G F T P T P
F . K a e h le r, .............................................1 0 3 2
H a rd e rs f .................................. ............o 1 2 1
B e rg , c ......................................................o 0 1 0
J . K a e h le r g ..........................................2 2 2 6
W e im e r, g ...................... ........ ................2 1 2 5
D a v is , f ......................................................2 3 2 7
G o rlo w s k i, g ..........................................0 0 1 0
T o t a ls ................................................7 7 13 21
M e rrilla n A . C .—
C h r is t y , f ........... . . ................... .............5 1 1 12
N ic h o ls, f ................ ...............................2 2 0 6
H a y d e n , c .................................. .. ..........5 0 2 10
F r o s t , g ............................ ........................ 1 0 1 2
M a ta la s , g ................................................3 1 2 7
B e n so n , £ ................................................0 0 2 0
P o r t e r , g ...................................................1 1 0 3
B a r r it t , f ............................ ........ V —0 0 0 0
K o lb ra c . g ................................................1 0 0 2
T o ta ls .................. ..........................18 6 8 42
W in o n a L a g e r s ..........................................4 7 14 21
M e rr illa n A . C ............................................7 16 30 42
METHODIST CHURCH
F. A. Fahlgren, Pastor
Sunday, Feb. 26.
Humbird:
9 :30 Public worship
10:40 Sunday school
Alma Center: - —-
10:00 Sunday school
11:00 Public worship
7 :00 Epworth League
Merrillan:
10:00 Sunday school
7 :30 Public worship
6 :45 Epworth League
Sermon topic is “ A Prayer for a
New Heart.”
What is Church For—
The work o f a church may be
broadly construed as having to do
with every department o f human life ;
but it has to do with this wide range
from the center o f the regenerated
personality. Good sanitation, material
prosperity and education are the
fruitage o f religion; they are not the
causes o f spiritual life. The business
o f the church is to promote these interests
o f the community by imparting
spiritual life to individuals, and
by having her own organization permeated
with spiritual forces. It is
our business to maintain the church.
Why not accept the invitation and
Come to Church Next Sunday?
Mrs. Anna Larson Staples has moved
into the Roy Comstock house.
Miss Cora Johnson and Horance
Hilts o f B. R. Falls were last Sunday
guests o f Mr. and Mrs. Lynn
Loomis.
Mr. and Mrs. Eric Erickson and
family were dinner and afternoon
guests o f Mr. and Mrs. Art Epting at
Neillsville, last Sunday.
Dr. L. M. Boxer moved part of
his household goods and medical
equipment here the first o f the week
and by the time this" issue reaches the
readers, Mr. and Mrs. Boxer will be
in Merrillan and the doctor ready for
business.
Mrs. M. E. Winters o f Minneapolis
was a caller in the village Saturday.
In a short time she, in company with
Mrs. La Breck, a friend, will start
west for a six weeks trip. They will
visit friends in Wyoming, Los Angeles
and San Francisco.
Mr. and Mrs. Harlow Rickard came
from Milwaukee last week and visited
several days here with friends and
relatives. They are moving to La
Crosse where Harlow will be employed
by some Milwaukee firm, with several
counties as his territory.
Mr. and Mrs. George Purnell and
family visited recently with Mr. and
Mrs. Chris Anderson o f Ladysmith,
and found the family all well. On
their return they slid in the ditch
once and had to be pulled out, an
experience that many motorists have
just now. No damage was done.
This office received an interesting
letter from our old friend, Selah
Cannon, now located at Seattle,
Wash., the other day. In it he states I
that he reads the B-J every week and
sends in a remittance so as to keep
“ the home news” still coming. He
reports having a visit from Ben Melby
several years ago, also one from
Clarence Whitney, o f Burlingame,
Cal., both former Merrillan boys. He
just recently had a visit from Albert
J. Heath o f Bellingham, Wash., where
he visited recently. States that Al-
| bert is the same old Albert, and he
(Selah) states that he is the only
person he has seen from the old
home town since leaving there in
f893. What a visit they must have
had. Selah lives just next door to
Jessie Beck Adams, and no doubt
they have many good visits. They
both join in sending greetings to old
friends and state that should any
Merrillanites come out that way to
be sure and look them up. Selah
keeps track o f the cribbage games
here and hopes that some o f the boys
will have better scores soon.
MERRILLAN MIXTURE
Editor ...................... Geneva Rhoades
Assistant Editor ....J o h n Jarolimek
Humor ............................Who Knows?
Class— Frances Larson, Esther Buttke,
Virginia Christianson, Shirley
Austin, Minnie Sorlie, June Meyers
Band Concert
We were all very proud o f our
music department after the musical
concert FViday evening, Feb. 17. The
concert was opened by several selections
by our school band, Mr. Davidson
directing.
Instrumental solos were rendered
by Mr. Davidson, Dale Austin and
John Jarolimek. Marcella Heath and
Dorothy Nash played a clarinet duet.
Two o f the faculty members, Miss
Schoengarth and Mr. Davidson, gave
us a fine violin duet. Mr. Schultz
and John Jarolimek gave us a trumpet
arrangement that was practically
triple tongueing.
The vocal was no less represented
than our instrumental talent. Our
glee club sang quite a few selections.
Virginia Erickson and Vivian Ransom
entertained with “ When Paw
was Courtin’ Maw” . They dressed
the part too. Shirley Austin, Suzanne
Helbling, and Violet Bouchard
sang as a trio, and Margaret Schultz,
Violet Bouchard, Virginia Bates, and
Vivian Ransom formed a fine quartet.
It would be hard to pick out any
part o f the program as outstanding,
for all o f it was. We may merely say
“ orchids” to our music department
and its director.
The program is as follows:
1. Marches by Bennett— Band
2. Cornet duets— Mr. Schultz and
John Jarolimek
3. Vocal— Girls glee club
4. Violin solos— Mr. Davidson
5. Bass solo— Dale Austin
6. Vocal duet— Vivian Ransom and
Virginia Erickson
8. Clarinet duet— Marcella Heath
and Dorothy Nash
9. Vocal trio— Violet Bouchard,
Virginia Bates, Margaret Shultz.
10. Vocal— Girls glee club
11. Violin duets— Miss Schoengarth
and Mr. Davidson
12. Vocal— Girls glee club
13. Concertina solos— John Jarolimek
14. Vocal duets— Shirley Austin,
Suzanne Helbling.
1’5. Band
Annuals o f Seniors
The staff o f the Annual is as follows
:
Editor-in-Chief— John Jarolimek
Assistant Editor— Douglass Fullington
Business Manager— Carroll Olson
Assistant Manager— Burdette Erickson
Production Manager— Frances Larson
Social-Literary— Vivian Erickson
Art— Dale Austin
Sports— Dale Rhoades
We are publishing an alumni list
in the Annual and would like to have
some help with the names o f graduates
from 1923 on. If any one has
any information on this please get
in touch with the seniors. Some o f
the material for our annuals arrived
last week and we are busy with plans
fo rmaking a dummy copy to use as
a guide for our annuals and as a
means o f advertising.
Health Talk
Miss Baker, o f the Child Welfare
division o f the State Board o f Health,
talked to the high school girls on
“ baby care” , Monday. She illustrated
her talk with a 2-reel movie, “ Judy’s
Diary” , tracing an average baby’s life
from six to 18 months.
Puff-Pant-Prom
The boys are all keeping spare hats
and suits, ties, socks, and overcoats
under cover, for the pals and sisters
who have eyes on being Romeos the
night o f March 10th are “ hot on their
trails” to borrow. We are expecting
many surprises when we have a
chance to view the couples at the
Puff-Pant Prom. Rumors have it that
some o f our faculty members are going
to make handsome escorts.
Forensics
The people out for Forensics are:
Dramatic— Caroline Olson, Shirley
Austin, Margaret Shultz
Humorous— Vivian Ransom, Josephine
Erickson
Extemporaneous Reading— Eva Olson,
Burdette Erickson, Frances Larn
Oratory— Virginia Erickson, James
Larson.Alma Center vs Merrillan
The Merrillan team were victims
o f another sad defeat last Thursday
Vance Bates was operated on at
the Krohn hospital the first o f the
week for appendicitis, and is getting
along nicely.
Mrs. Ray Gile will entertain the
members o f the S. B. Society Wednesday,
March 1st.
The Card and Thimble club will
meet Tuesday, Feb. 28, with Mrs. Edward
Persson.
The Priscillas will meet Tuesday
evening. Feb. 28, at the home o f Mrs.
Gibson Gile.
- - S E K 0 V - -
THE PROVEN
METHOD FOR
WEIGHT
REDUCTION
SEKO V is a modern scientific
form ula, consisting o f herbs,
tonics and glandular extracts. It
is based upon a combination of
herbs and tonics that H AVE
D EFIN IT ELY PRO VEN in laboratory
research to be o f great
value in NORM ALIZIN G and
TONING up the system in general.
SE K O V is used and endorsed
by reliable physicians as a
healthful and corrective method
o f W EIG H T REDUCTION.
MISS ROSE BENESH
SEKOV REDUCING
STUDIO
122 So. Barstow Street
EAU CLAIRE, WISCONSIN
Dial 3936 for Appointment
night. It looked as if the boys wouldn’t
have more than one point until
the 4th quarter when Kenny Kolbrak
made a field goal, the only one of
the game for Merrillan. The other
point was made on a free throw by
Harold Simonson.
The first quarter passed without
much excitement except that Alma
Center had several free throws which
they missed. In the second quarter
things began to get exciting. C. Olson
was taken out and Simonson was
called to the field o f battle. Alma
Center got a field goal and Olson
went back in. Shortly Alma Center
got another field goal and during the
mixup C. Johnson got a bloody nose.
A foul was called on Olson and he
was sent to the showers.
During the first quarter o f the 2d
half Alma Center made 9 points and
at the beginning o f the 4th quarter
the score was 16-1. The last quarter
opened up with a field goal by Merrillan.
Simonson made a basket but
it wasn’t counted. During the rest
o f the game, there were several substitutions
and nothing very exciting
happened. The final score was 19-3
Alma Center winning.
Washington Program
Mr. Shultz was chosen to take
charge o f the Washington Birthday
program. The program will be as
follow s:
Band selection, “ America.”
Life o f Washington— Francis Larson
Washington and Religion— Rev.
Fahlgren
Band selection, “ Star Spangled
Banner”Monday Night League
A fter practicing all year, two times
a week, Mr. Frost's Monday Night
Leaguers have been rewarded with
two victories. Both o f their victories
were over Alma Center. One game
here, one over there. Mr. Frost is
now trying to get two games with
Humbird. The score o f the last game
was 19-12 in favor o f Merrillan.
Juniors
The two members o f our class that
dropped a few months ago have started
again. We are proud o f the facts
that our class is not the very smallest.
The Seniors rate lowest in size.
Sophomores
The Sophs sold popcorn at the basket
ball game Friday night. The
money will be used for buying some
biology equipment.
Rogene Olson and Lottie Pasek
have been absent from school for the
past week.
7th Grade
We won the bulletin board contest
the last few times and we hope to
have a party in our honor soon.
5th and 6th Grade
We had our valentine party Tuesday
night. Prizes were given to the
prettiest baskets. Those who won
were Patrick Fullington and Corinne
Dean.
3rd and 5th Grades
We had our valentine party last
Tuesday afternoon. The 4th grade
boys and girls made the boy like a
little house. The house was white
with a green roof. The windows,
doors, and walk leading to the door
were o f hearts.
1st And 2nd Grades
We had our valentine party Tuesday
afternoon. We took turns being
mailman and helping to pass out the
valentines. Some o f us received over
25 valentines.
Feed Bargains
SHELLED CORN per ton $18.00
O A T S ............ per ton $20.00
Grd. Oats and Corn.. ton $ 2 0 . 0 0
— 16 per cent Protein Dairy Feed —
Made of Whole Grains — contains no Screenings or Filler.
We mix and sell a complete line of feeds. Get our
prices before Buying Elsewhere.
CHARTER OAK MILLS
Phone 199-R-3 Black River Falls
HORSE SALE
FRIDAY, FEB. 24
AT 1:00 P. M.
1 2 miles west o f County Trunk P,
5 2 miles east o f Tomah, on the place
known as the old Batchelor Farm
Carload of Heavy Type
Farm Horses
These horses are sold under an absolute
guarantee. 
Horses to Suit every class of j
Buyer
These sales will be held every two
weeks on the same farm with the
same owner.
Terms — AH sums o f $15 or under
Cash; over that amount cash, balance
6 months time on monthly payments
with interest at 6 per cent per
annum. L. E. Jones, Owner
Norton Christensen, Auctioneers,
Camp Douglas
Thorp Finance Corporation, clerk
Auction Sale
An unusual opportunity to purchase
High Class Furniture and Household
GOODS at the ONSTAD RESIDENCE in the VILLAGE
of MERRILLAN, W ISM
at 1:30P.M . SATURDAY, FEB. 25
The Residence has been SOLD, we must vacate, W e are moving away
and everything advertised will BE SOLD Regardless o f price or value.
This Furniture is All practically NEW, in excellent condition and o f
quality that will be appreciated by the most discriminating buyer.
LISTEN — Beautiful Dinette Set consisting o f Solid Oak B uffet,
Table and Six Chairs to Match. Y ou’ ll want it. Breakfast Set, Table
and Four Chairs to Match. It will brighten up your home. One Davenport
and Chair. Something to be proud of. One Bed Spring and
Innerspring Mattress. Sleep on it and you will never want to get up.
An occasional table and an occasional rocker. Very nice for occasi©nal
company. One Cream and Green Ice Box. Keep Cool this winter.
One Speed Queen W ashing Machine as good as NEW. Speed Up
your Queen and wash your clothes in a HURRY. You will have more
time to talk politics and relief. One Cream and Green Perfection
Oil Stove. Saves Coal and W ood. One Oil Stove with two burners,
one for ordinary cooking, the other for Ludefisk. Oven also for baking
slapjacks.
O n e C re a m an d G r e e n C o o k in g R a n g e w ith H o t W a te r F r o s t , o n ly
t w o y e a r s o ld , lo o k s lik e b ra n d N E W . B e o n h a n d a n d see th e b id d
e rs fig h t it o u t. O n e A ir T ig h t H e a le r, w ill k e e p y o u r H o u se W a r m
a n d c o m fo r t a b le .
Axminister Rug, 9x12, Bigelow weave. One Sandura Linoleum Rug
9x12, Sandura Linoleum 6x9. These rugs are all NEW and in perfect
condition. A pride and ornament to your home.
Several kinds o f Curtains. Some Nice Dishes. Ironing Board. Wash
Board. Tubs. Bed Springs. Two Stove Boards. Floor Lamp. Radio
Stand. Some small tools, and many other articles too numerous to
mention.
TERMS — CASH — Come prepared to buy and to settle for this
fine furniture and household goods. Be here aa 1:30 p. m. all set,
Rearing to Go, and Ready to BUY everything that comes up at your
own price. BO W M AN will put it over in a clean sweep, Cut loose
SALE.
LAFE ONSTAD, Owner
Col. F. J. Bowman, Black River Falls, Auctioneer.
Service that satisfies and a square deal for ALL. Write or wire for
DATES.
s*’" A BIG CAR AT A SMALL PRICE
1 9 3 9 F o r d V - «
C o u p e , wi t h 6 0 -
horsepower engine
. . . delivered at
Detroit, taxes extra,
V-» EN G IN ES-r
8 5 h p . tor e x t r a
u r t h o l e * -
oupre rfcormance!
ns no. »wr r
60 bp. tor extra economy
Mrs. Claude Winson was on
sick list the first o f the week.
the
August fflattauu
fou r IFunpral Sirrrtor
Ambulance Service
Nearly a Quarter Century of
Service
BLACK RIVER FALLS, WIS.
HYDRAULIC B R A K E S - S m . . 
f a r t , e a s y - a c t ," ? . * '
fo r d sta n d a r d * of safety
TRIPLE-CUSHIONED COMFORT
T R ' P L E e ; , . a t , . - e . l b e . p r l , , . .
big h y d r a u l i c
. Softer
f o u r
absorbers.
k o c k
SCIEN TIFIC SOUNDPROOFING
r E E . » « » .-. *ibro+io; rd
u c e d by careful reseorek.
T h e r e are good reasons why
so many folks are talking about
the 1939 Ford V -8!
One obvious reason is the
fact that it provides so much
car for so little money. Actually,
it costs less than a Ford
car o f the same size and
power sold for last year! And
its low price includes many
items of desirable equipment.
The Ford V -8 has all the
room and all the basic features
of the De Luxe Ford. Some of
them are listed at the left!
But riding is better than
reading. Out on the road, you’ll
soon understand America’s enthusiasm
for the car that is big
in everything but price!
FORD V-8 FOR 1939
Ford Cars and Trucks . Tdephon' N° ’
are SOLD and SERVICED by The Riverside Motor Co
PAGE NO. 6 THE BANNER-JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin W ednesday, February 22,1939
JACKSON COUNTY CO-OPERATIVES
Governor Heil Proclaims
Cooperative Week
Governor Julius P. Heil on January 20 issued the following
proclamation:
“Co-operation is the art of working together. From our federation
of 48 states down to the townships, we have a living example
of mutual self-help. Whether to build a bridge, sell farm products
or provide for the national defense, people co-operate for the
common good.
“ In an economic sense, people work together to develop conveniences
and extend services. In rural communities particularly,
we find farmers working through co-operative producers’ associations
for the purpose of gaining a fairer share of the consumers’
dollar which is paid for their products.
“Because Wisconsin farmers particularly have made progress
in solving their own problems by co-operation, and because there
is need for reflection and analysis of the true aims and possibilities
of the Co-operative movement,
NOW, THEREFORE, I, Julius P. Heil, Governor of the State
of Wisconsin, do hereby designate the week of February 20-24 inclusive
as
WISCONSIN CO-OPERATIVE WEEK
and urge the citizens of this state to avail themselves of the opportunity
provided during these five days by special radio programs,
newspaper articles, and otherwise, to learn more of the
spirit and principle, as well as the aims and accomplishments, of
co-operation.”
HISTORY OF TH E JACKSON
ELECTRIC C O -O P E R A T IV E
As is usual in such an undertaking
the organization o f the Jackson Electric
Cooperative was not without its
difficulties. However, its organizers
knew what they wanted, stuck together
until they got it and now may enjoy
the fruits o f their labor.
The Jackson Electric Cooperative
is the youngest cooperative in Jackson
County, but it is a healthy youngster
and should enjoy a rapid growth.
Officially this cooperative was incorporated
under the laws of'the state
o f Wisconsin on October 11, 1937,
and boasted only o f 23 members. The
actual beginning dates back much further
than that, but the story is too
long for our limted space.
The first annual meeting o f the
members was held on March 9, 1938,
and 59 members were in attendance.
On that day the Construction Loan
Contract between the Cooperative and
the United States in the amount of
$160,000.00 was approved by the
members present and signed by the
authorized officers.
The Attorney for the project, Mr.
Norris E. Maloney, had been previously
appointed, and incidentally, Mr.
Maloney was elected District Attorney
o f Dane County, Wisconsin, in
the last fall election. The Project Engineer
was designated by the Wisconsin
Electric Cooperative Association,
o f Madison, Wisconsin, and Mr.
Harold M. Durnin was appointed as
Resident Engineer. Mr. M. J. Smith,
o f Hillsboro, Assistant Engineer at
the time has since been promoted to
the position o f Project Superintendent,
having taken over the duties of
that office on October 15, 1938.
The construction contract was
awarded to Snyder Johnson, Inc.,
o f Humboldt, Iowa, on June 15, 1938.
Actual construction began approximately
two months later. The final
amount of the contract was $111,-
$69.55. Construction was completed
December 5, 1938.
Without a great deal o f fanfare or
publicity the first, or north section
of the project was energized on December
1st and the energization o f
the second, or south section began on
December 8, 1938. At the present
time 148.5 miles are energized and
electricity is being served to 235
families and business establishments
as this is being written.
Power is purchased from the Wisconsin
Power Cooperative whose plant
is located at Eagle Point, North of
Chippewa Falls, Wisconsin. This
wholesale power is metered at a substation
located 4 miles west o f Hixton
and one mile north o f highway
95.
As this is being written, we have
information from an unofficial, but
nevertheless reliable source that extensions
to the present Jackson County
Project have been approved and
that funds will be allotted very shortly.
For the benefit o f posterity a record
o f the names o f the present o fficers,
directors, and employees o f
the organization might not be amiss.
The officers and directors are those
originally chosen to serve in that capacity
and are as follows:
Roy H. Kunzelman. president.
George J. Johnson, vice president.
Archie O. Burnett, secretary and
treasurer.
Other directors:
Frank C. Bright.
Charles Nordstrom.
Gust Kohnert.
Competition:
Competition is a selfish
and hostile struggle for
wealth and power.
Competition arises out
of conflicting interests
and desires.
The purpose of competition
is personal gain or
private profit.
Competition is selfish 
indifferent.
Competition leads to hatred,
conflict and war.
Competition concentrates
wealth and income
in the hands of a few.
Competition leads to
plutocracy, the reign 
rule of the rich.
Competition destroys
human values, wastes
natural resources and
leaves equipment and
man-power idle in its
quest for profits.
Competitive business
takes a slice of everything
that is sold or
bought.
Competition offers you
one chance in a million
to make a fortune for
yourself.
CO -O PERA TIO N THE
AM ER ICAN W A Y
Co-operation retains the traditional
high standards originally set up by
our American forefathers. It gives us
equality o f rights in business, one
man one vote regardless o f the amount
o f money invested by that individual
and no one individual can
gain a monopoly control.
The ideals o f Co-operation guide
the business toward more and more
efficiency within itself as regards
bookkeeping, quality o f merchandise,
mass purchasing power, high standards
o f improvement and also a just
and fair distribution o f over charge,
or net earnings o f the business.
The Co-operative distributes its net
earnings to those who made the .net
earnings possible, namely to the patron
member, on the basis o f his patronage.
Thus the Co-operative way
is a continuation o f the high ideals
and policies set forth by our American
forefathers. It retains equality of
right, open and free opportunity for
all, and above all a square deal for
the average American citizen.
The Co-operative way in America
is one o f the few opportunities yet
left to our youth through which they
can express their individuality and
develop their high motives in life of
service to mankind.
AR E YOU A C O O P E R A T O R ?
If so, then you are willing to cast
your lot with your fellowmen; then
you are willing to substitute mutual
benefit for personal gain, altruism for
selfishness, and friendly cooperation
for hostile struggle.
You believe that cooperation is superior
to competition in every field
of human activity? If so, are you
willing to cooperate with your own
family in your own home, with your
neighbors and with men and women
who differ with you as to religion
and politics?
Do you earnestly and sincerely
practice what you believe— by being
a loyal and faithful member o f your
cooperative, by encouraging the doubters
and pessimists, by pulling the
slackers with you, and by preparing
yourself to meet the challenge of
those who try to undermine and destroy
the cooperative movement?
You and I are a part o f a great
movement; we are working hand in
hand for a noble cause, that o f making
America into a happy home o f a
happy people. Security, prosperity
and happiness for all the people —
that is our goal. The more faithful
and loyal we are the closer we come
to that goal and the sooner shall we
reach it.
Let us be missionaries preaching
ajnd practicing the ?ospel o f cooperation.
Let us show in words and deeds
what it means to believe in the brotherhood
o f m an: let us be COOPERATORS
for what we can give and
contribute to the economic and social
salvation o f this and future generations.
COOPERATOR.
Delbert Nortman.
George O. Humphrey.
Martin Lund.
Maintenance and office personnel:
M. J. Smith, Project Superintendent.
Lawrence F. Crowley, Maintenance
man.
Donald H. Stromberg, Bookkeeper.
The office o f the organization was
established July 1st, 1938, and at
present is located over the post office
in the city o f Black River Falls, Wisconsin.
Cooperation:
Cooperation is a friendly
working together for
the welfare of all.
Cooperation is based on
common interests.
The purpose of cooperation
is mutual benefit.
Cooperation is mindful
of the wants and interests
of others.
Cooperation makes for
harmony and peace.
Cooperation tends toward
a fair and even
distribution of the fruits
of labor.
Cooperation is the extension
of democratic
principles to every field
of human activity, economic
as well as political.
Co operation reduces
waste, eliminates unnecessary
expense, conserves
and utilizes material
and spiritual values
for the satisfaction
of human needs.
Cooperative business
eliminates the exploitation
of consumer and
producer.
Cooperation offers everybody
an opportunity
to make a decent living
in a decent way.
JACK SO N COUNTY CO-OP. A D VA
N CE M EN T A SSO C IA TIO N
by Earl Horswill, President
In order to bring before the people
o f Jackson County the important
role which the cooperatives are playing
in our everyday life, we take this
opportunity, “ Cooperative Week” of
informing them o f the volume o f
business actually done by cooperatives
and farmer owned organizations
o f our county.
The publication o f the amount of
business done by each cooperative is
not for comparative purposes but
rather to show the gross amount o f
business transacted during the year
1938. Some o f our smallest cooperatives
are very efficient, well organized
and managed; they compare very
favorably with the larger ones.
Through the efforts o f the Cooperative
Advancement Association, the
cooperatives o f the county and The
Banner-Journal, these co-op pages
have been made possible.
The people o f Jackson County can
feel justly proud o f the splendid
group o f cooperatives that we have,
and we take this opportunity during
cooperative week to honor them and
the men who worked and sacrificed to
make them a success.
In connection with the above attention
is called to the following story
from the February 18th issue o f The
Cooperative Builder, o f Superior. It
will be o f interest to readers to know
that their movement in the county is
receiving this publicity.
Cooperation Am ong Co-ops.
‘Co-op Advancem ent Association’ is
Most A ctive County Council
Furthest developed o f the county
co-operative councils in Wisconsin is
the Jackson County Cooperative Advancement
Association, according to
W. L. Witte, o f the state department
o f agriculture and markets. How this
association was formed and what its
program is was told by its president
Earl Horswill, o f Black River Falls, in
a recent letter to the Builder.
The association grew out o f Wisconsin’s
Co-operative Week last year.
Previously there was a community
club in Black River Falls which held
“ Neighborhood Nights", consisting of
an entertainment and educational
program. Last year Horswill was appointed
program chairman; so in
racking his brain for a program he
suggested that the county hold an all
co-op meeting and discuss mutual
problems.
All A re Invited
Invitations went out to the directors
o f all co-ops in the county— and
there are 7 co-op creameries, three
livestock shipping associations, 2
cheese factories, 2 oil co-ops, one
electric co-op, a credit union, and a
strawberry shippers’ association. The
date was February 16, in the middle
o f Co-op Week.
A good turn out came, some coming
even from the western border of
the county 15 to 20 miles away on
slippery roads.
“ It was the first time in the history
o f this county,” says Horswill,
“ when the presidents, directors, their
wives and families o f the various coop
enterprises were assembled together
in one meeting, all thinking and
talking Co-operation.”
It was suggested that an association
be formed, made up o f one representative
o f each o f the co-op enterprises,
whose sole purpos eshould be
to extend the field o f the various coops—
to try and teach more people
to see the light o f co-op dealing in
buying and selling.
An organization meeting was called
for March 31 at Hixton. R. E. Fisher,
o f the state department o f agriculture,
attended and the association was j
incorporated.
Hold Picnic Institute
Since that date the organization I
has held a county-wide co-op picnic
at Hixton park June 16 with a b ou t!
' 1,500 attendance, arranged a co-op
parade at the county fair, and held
a one-day co-op institute at the court
house in December. Other activities
are planned.
Congressman Merlin Hull, who publishes
The Banner-Journal at Black
River Falls, gave space for a co-operative
news column, and in this space
the association has published co-op
news o f the county, state and nation.
Recently, Tom Stodola, well known
co-operator, wrot« up an article on
the new Co-op tire. Another article,
by Horswill, discussed _tfie Co-operative
Health Assaciatu i(being formed
at Superiors, ‘ .{ » ( « v
The officers oi the Association, in
addition to President Horswill, are
Roy Kunzelman, vice president; F. C.
Bright, secretary Jmd treasurer; Chas.
Olson, Gust Kohnert, Cornell Rogness
and Harry Ifflan , directors.
Oil Co-ops Have Good Record
Exact figures on the total co-op
business done in Jackson county are
not on hand. However, the two oil
co-ops— the Farmers Oil Company, at
Hixton, founded 10 years ago, and the
Federation Co-op. Oil Company at B.
R. Falls, 9 years old, have paid to
their members over $100,000 in patronage
refunds and interest since
their start. An electrical appliance
store, run in connection with the Federation
Oil, did $2,000 worth o f
business in December, and it has been
going only a few months.
Other county co-op councils have
been formed in Brown, Barron, and
Walworth counties, and probably will
be formed in still other counties as
the movement for “ more co-operation
between co-operatives” goes forward.
The Biennial Congress o f the Coopt
rative League meeting in Kansas
City, Oct. 12, 13, and 14 reported its
membership as 965,000 as against
704,000 at the time o f the Congress
in 1936. From the Congress grow proposals
for a Co-operative financial
agency to free the Co-operative from
dependence on outside financial sources
and to mobilize Co-op funds for
more rapid expansion o f Co-operative
distribution and production. The
Congress moved to strengthen the relations
o f organized consumers with
organized labor and agriculture.
NEW YORK, N. Y.— Two summer
tours for co-operators were announced
by Rev. J. Henry Carpenter, tour
director o f the Co-operative League.
One will visit co-ops in northern Europe,
leaving New York July 1 and
returning September 3. The other will
go to Nova Scotia, August 21 to Sept.
2, viewing co-operatives there.
Nineteen thirty-eight will go down
in Co-op history as a year o f growth
and co-operation. While private profit
business went through another “ recession”
and hit the lowest level since
1933, American consumers Co-ops can
describe the year with one word —
Progress.
i FED ER ATIO N C O -O P E R A T IV E
OIL CO M PANY
Organized in July 23, 1929, at
Galesville, Wisconsin.
Bought an independent Oil Jobber
at Black River Falls in 1931.
Offices (main) moved to Black River
Falls November 23, 1933.
Bought an independent Oil Jobber
at Fall Creek, in April, 1933.
Capitalization $50,000.00, o f which
$42,000.00 is in Common Stock and
$8,000.00 in Preferred Stock.
Total outstanding stock at present
is: Common Stock, $17,025.00, and
Preferred Stock $3,150.00.
Total Stock Credits $5,189.30.
Number o f Stockholders at present
800.
Volume o f business for 1938,
$132,704.00.
Officers and directors :
James P. Bullock, president.
Henry Graff, vice president.
Edward Rau, secretary and treasurer.
Bert C. Congdon, James Haug,
Harvey Gilbertson, William Ruebenbauer.
In 1935 the Federation Co-operative
became a member o f Midland
Co-operative Wholesale.
W hat is M idland?
Midland Co-operative Wholesale is
a central organization o f almost 200
retail consumer cooperative associations,
most o f which are in Minnesota
and Wisconsin, with a few scattered
associations in North and South Dakota,
Iowa and Michigan.
The home office and the original
compounding plant is located at 739
Johnson Street, N. E., Minneapolis,
Minn. In 1936 a new compounding
plant, office and warehouse was opened
at 5070 No. 35th Street, Milwaukee,
Wisconsin. The Milwaukee
branch serves all o f the associations
in the Milwaukee trade area.
Midland is owned and controlled
by the local cooperative associations
which patronize it. It is organized and
operated on the Rochdale cooperative
plan under the laws o f the State o f
Minnesota.
In order to give proper representation
in the wholesale to the local
cooperatives, the entire area served
by Midland is divided into ten districts
each o f which has a director on
Midland’s board o f directors. The districts
hold quarterly meetings where
problems o f policy and business practice
are discussed, and decisions and
recommendations are made relative to
the operation o f the central organization
as well as o f the local associations.
The Federation Co-operative of
Black River Falls, with branches at
Galesville and Fall Creek is a member
o f Midland in the 8th District,
and therefore has an equal voice with
all other member co-ops in the control
o f Midland.
Although Midland is comparatively
young, having recently celebrated its
tenth anniversary, its volume o f business
has grown to significant proportions.
Whereas sales for the first year
o f 1927, amounted to $269,862.78,
the volume for 1938 amounted to $3,-
650,000. The local member associations
had a business volume in 1938
amounting to approximately twelve
million dollars. Their savings or net
income on this volume was nearly
three-quarters o f a million dollars.
The local associations belonging to
CONSUM ERS’ CO -O PERATION
America is beginning to use the
words “ consumer” and “ co-ooeration”
. But Americans generally do
not yet know what these words really
mean when joined together to describe
the new economic system —
Consumers’ Co-operation— which is
being built to replace competitive
Middleman Monopoly.
We read many articles and hear
many addresses discussing the three
alternatives o f Capitalism, Communism
and Corporatism (Fascism). Yet
there is a fourth alternative being developed
on a large scale in over forty
countries in the world. Its results are
particularly evident in such countries
as Great Britain, Scandinavia, Switzerland
and other European countries
which are demonstrating that there’s
another way out— through voluntary
democratic Consumers’ Co-operation
— without violence or dictatorship,
but by gradual evolution.
In Consumers’ Co-operation the
principle o f open membership will
give us economic brotherhood. Its
principle o f “ one person, one vote”
will give us economic democracy. Its
principle o f “ minimum interest on
shares” will give us security instead
o f speculation. Its principle o f “ distributing
the surplus savings as dividends
on the basis o f patronage” will
give us just distribution o f wealth.
These are the four corners o f a Cooperative
Economic Society.
Consumers’ Cooperation recovers
the ownership o f the means o f production
and distribution for the people.
We, the people, have largely lost
the ownership o f the country in which
we live. The way to regain ownership
is through Consumers’ Cooperation. It
is not only the democratic economic
system for the future but it can be
put in practice at once by any group
which wishes to cooperate and buy together.
It pays as it goes in both material
and more benefits to its members.
Consumers’ Cooperation starts
right in your own home neighborhood.
Local associations then join together
and form a wholesale. This is
the way to “ start clearing your own
little corner o f creation” . Everyone
has his or her part to do in building
the new cooperative economic order
that will constantly increase productioij 
and justly distribute it.
First Cannibal— “ Is I late for dinner.”
Second Cannibal— “ You is. Everybody’s
eaten.” — Ex.
Midland have made savings each year
through their patronage o f their
wholesale. In 1927 these savings
amounted to $3,436.29; in 1938 they
amounted to more than $85,000.00.
The local associations have wisely
kept these savings in the central organization
rather than taken them out
in cash. As a result Midland has
grown from year to year in proportion
to the benefits derived by the
local associations, and the local associations
in turn have received the advantages
o f -the increased purchasing
power o f the wholesale and improved
and increased services which the
wholesale has been able to render.
Together they have grown in financial
strength, business efficiency and cooperative
understanding.
Dr. Ottar Tinglum,
Midland Educational Fieldman.
THE YOUNGEST CO-OPERATIVE
IN JACKSON COUNTY
But we believe it to be one of the most welcome.
Under the guidance of the Rural Electrification Administration,
now making electricity available to
hundreds, formerly denied its benefits.
M AY W E SERVE YOU?
Jackson Electric Co-operative
BLACK RIVER FALLS, WIS.
TEN YEARS OF PROGRESS
In Merchandising Co-op Products
GASOLINE, KEROSENE, OILS
DISTILLATE and GREASES
$40,000.00 Returned in Stock and Patronage
Dividends
FARMERS CO-OPERATIVE OIL
COMPANY
HIXTON, WISCONSIN
Make Your Choice
Specials for Co-op Week
FEB. 20th to FEB. 25th
Goodrich Chieftain Tubes (all s iz e s )................$1.00
Goodrich Silvertown Tubes 5:50x17 to
7:50x16 ................................................................ $2.00
Goodrich Tires (all sizes ) ....................$5.00 and up
We are closing out our stock of Goodrich Tires-tubes
All CO-OP. Tires and Tubes 10 per cent off during
CO-OP. Week. 5:50x17, first line, regular
price $12.20, for this sale only .................... $11.00
CO-OP OILS
Pool Oil Price Guaranteed until March 15th
CO-OP FLY SPRAY
Buy Your Summer Needs Now
CO-OP APPLIANCE STORE
SPECIAL — Combination Phonograph and
Radio ...................................................................$19.95
CO-OP. Food Mixer, Special for one week . . . .$9.95
CO-OP LABEL IS YOUR
GUARANTEE of QUALITY
CO-OP Gas. CO-OP. Kerosene. CO-OP. Penn
Co-op. Oils, CO-OP Tires, CO-OP Tubes, CO-OP
Light Tubes, CO-OP Greases, CO-OP Steel Products,
CO-OP Fly Spray, CO-OP Spark Plugs, CO-OP Fan
Belts.
APPLIANCES — CO-OP Separators, CO-OP Electric
Irons, CO-OP Electric Stoves, CO-OP radios,
CO-OP Washing Machines, CO-OP Vacuum Sweepers,
CO-OP Pump Jacks, CO-OP Electric Ranges,
CO-OP Refrigerators, CO-OP Radio Tubes, CO-OP
Fixtures. CO-OP Toasters, CO-OP Waffle Irons,
CO-OP. Electric Motors, CO-OP. Paints, CO-OP.
Water Systems, CO-OP. Water Heaters.
FEDERATION CO-OPERATIVE
OIL COMPANY
THE BANNER-JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin PAGE NO. 7
OBSERVE WISCONSIN CO-OP. WEEK
C O -O P E R A T IV E BU SINESS
IN JACK SO N CO UNTY
There are many people in our county
who think that the volume o f business
done by cooperative organizations
does not amount to much, that
it is hardly worth mentioning, and
still it runs up into some impressive
figures.
The volume o f business o f coop
and farmer owned enterprises in
Jackson county for 1938 amounted to
$1,178,020.67 according to a survey
just completed on the occasion of
"Cooperative Week.”
A million dollars is a lot o f money.
It takes a great deal o f imagination
to visualize what it means to this
county as a whole and to the individuals
who are members o f these cooperatives.
One thing is certain, and
that is— cooperative business has
proved its soundness and its ability
to serve the average man whether he
be classified as producer or as consumer.
Nationally
Agricultural cooperation has never
been in a more fundamentally sound
position than it is today. Over a period
o f years agricultural marketing
and purchasing associations have
d eafly demonstrated that they can
perform important services for the
farmer. The significance o f agricultural
cooperation today is indicated
by the fact that about one-half of
the farmers o f the nation participate
in some form o f agricultural cooperative
activity, and that the total business
o f agricultural cooperative associations
amounts to over 2 billions
dollars annually.
The principles o f cooperation, in
their simplest form, are as old as the
world itself. But it remained for the
American farmer, beset by a multitude
o f woes, to apply these principles
to the selling o f his crops and live
stock and to the purchasing o f supplies
essential to production and the
maintenance o f his property, so well
that today organized farm cooperation
aggregates a business considerably
over the tidy sum o f 2 billion
dollars a year.
The Co-op Credit Union
The Co-op Credit Union o f which
Walter Bean is president and Dick
Faldet treasurer is the first credit
union in Jackson county. It was organized
July 1st, 1938, with 58 members
an amount o f paid in share capital
o f $82.00, total shares to date
amount to over $1000 and the number
o f stockholders at present is 75,
number o f borrowers 12. The office
o f the treasurer o f the credit union
is in the office o f the Federation Cooperative
Oil Company. The Co-op.
credit union is a member o f the state
credit union league in the National
Association o f Credit Unions.
W A R R E N CO-OP FRU IT
G RO W ERS ASSO CIA TIO N
Located at Warrens, Wisconsin.
The above is a strawberry growers
co-operative with a branch at Alma
Center doing a total volume last year
o f over $50,000.00. Half o f the volume
came out o f Jackson county.
The directors from Jackson county
are as follows:
Erwin Duxbury, Will Nemitz, Will
Onstad, Erwin Bowen, Alvin Relyea
and Earl Randles, manager o f Alma
Center Branch.
NORTH BEND
C O O P E R A T IV E CR EAM ER Y
Organized as the North Bend Separative
Cooperative Creamery Company
January 27, 1896.
When the new Cooperative law was
enacted in Wisconsin the word, “ Cooperative”
was dropped from the
name at a special Stockholders meeting
January 13, 1922, and the organization
came under the general Corporation
law as the North Bend Creamery
Company.
The Creamery was reorganized
with 49 stockholders June 30, 1938,
under the Cooperative law and the
name was changed to North Bend Cooperative
Creamery. On January 1,
1939, the Creamery had 104 stockholders.
*
The Creamery owns a beautiful mo'
dern equipped brick building located
at North Bend on the banks o f the
Black River. It has operated continuously
for over 43 years, now in the
44th year.
Mr. George Manser has been the
buttermaker for over 41 years, starting
his 42nd year as buttermaker. We
believe that to be a record in our
state, 41 years o f continuous service
as a buttermaker for the same Cooperative
Creamery.
The Creamery’s volume o f business
for 1938 amounted to $129,256.07.
The officers and directors are as follows:
John A. Baird, president.
James P. Bullock, vice president.
James A. Ristow, secretary and
treasurer.
Alfred Ravnum.
Gile Patterson.
Bernard Ramsey.
Charles Nordstrom.
George Manser, buttermaker.
M ELROSE CR EAM ER Y CO M PAN Y
Organized January 3, 1910.
Number o f stockholders, 98.
Number o f shares, 320.
Volume o f business for 1938,
$150,617.78.
Officers and Directors:
Merlin Olson, president.
A. G. Stern, secretary and treasurer.
H. B. Grinde, vice president.
Paul Spars, E. O. Paulson, Joe
Mayer, Will Potter, Pete Olson, N.
E. Nelson.
Irvine Rohnert, buttermaker.
BROOKSIDE CH EESE CO M PAN Y
By accident notes on the organization
and output o f the Brookside
Cheese Company were lost but we
are publishing herewith the officers
of the thriving organization.
R. Aesch iacher, president.
Charles Dunlap, vice president.
Harry Iffland, treasurer.
Harmon Van Horn, secretary.
Directors: Tony Statz, Joe Forstena,
Leo Link.
Arnold Beyer, cheesemaker.
T A Y L O R CR EAM ER Y
ASSO CIA TIO N
Organized 1912.
Stockholders, 50. (Paid $5.00).
Volume o f business for 1938, $44,-
575.00.
Officers and directors:
Elwood Relyea, B. R. Matson, Theo’
Strande, Sam Kelly, C. M. Halverson,
Manford Forness, Fred Curran, Erick
Brynildson.
Buttermaker, Homer Hilton.
NORTH BEND C O -O P E R A T IV E CR EAM ER Y
FARM ERS CO-OP.
C R E A M E R Y ASSO CIA TIO N
At Black River Falls, Wisconsin.
Organized in 1909.
Stockholders 473.
Stock outstanding $18,922.50.
Volume o f business for 1938, $87,-
059.25.
O fficers:
C. S. Ristow, president.
John Wyss, vice president.
Helge Rustad, secretary-treasurer.
Directors:
Frank C. Bright.
Theodore Hauge.
Roy Kunzelman.
Fred Krome.
Frank Brauner.
Herman Rosenbaum.
SILV E R MOUND
C R E A M E R Y ASSO CIA TIO N
Organized March 28, 1905.
Number o f shareholders, 71, own
153 shares. ($10.00).
Total receipts in 1938, $50,763.49.
Officers and Directors:
John A. Thompson, president.
Charles Dorrance, vice president.
R. E. Mortiboy, secretary.
Phillip Merrill, treasurer.
Lewis Peterson, manager.
Charles Newell, Simon Amundson
Operator, Forrest W. Loasching.
DISCO CR EAM ER Y
ASSO CIA TIO N
Organized 1908.
Volume o f business for 1938, $55,-
579.49.
Officers and directors:
Gilbert Gullickson, president.
Carl Klein, vice president.
Hubert Johnson, secretary.
Henry Wyss, manager.
John Rendig, Helmer Jacobson, A lbert
Hoem, Emil Lien, Edgar Gilbertson,
Adolph Peterson.
Buttermaker, Arthur Rogness.
A L M A CENTER
C R E A M E R Y CO M PANY
Organized 1908.
Stockholders, 100. (Paid $2.50) 25.
Volume o f business fo r 1938,
$52,493.14.
O fficers:
Will Reubembrauer, president.
Frank Hanser., vice president.
Harold Ness, secretary.
George Duxbury, treasurer.
Directors:
George Stamm, Gust Porath, Geo.
Schroeder, Geo. Sichler, R. W. Iliff.
Ralph Lebach, cheesmaker.
YORK CR EAM ER Y ASSO CIATIO N
Organized 1897.
Re-organized 1917.
Stockholders, 106.
Volume o f business for 1938, $88,-
068.88.
The building burned down on October
17, 1938. The new building constructed
at a total cost, for building
and equipment at $17,500.00. The
building was ready for making butter
again on February 15, 1939. They are
a member o f the Land O’ Lakes Central
Organization.
O fficers:
Edwin Thomley, president.
Alfred Ellickson, vice president.
Directors :
Charles Olson.
George O. Humphrey.
Theo. O. Thompson.
Arthur Johnson.
Peter Jarstad.
FARM ERS C O O P E R A T IV E
OIL COM PANY
At Hixton, Wisconsin.
Incorporated, May 29, 1929.
Incorporators— Byron Curran, Harland
Duxbury, John A. Thompson,
George A. Van Horn, Wm. D. Mulry.
Original officers and directors —
Wm. D. Mulry, president.
George Knutson, vice president.
Nels Skutley, secretary.
August Regez, treasurer.
John A. Thompson.
H. J. Dorrance.
Harland Duxbury.
Capital stock authorized, $2500.00.
Volume o f business, year ending
May 31, 1930, $26,000.00.
Volume o f sales, year ending May
31, 1938, $57000.00.
Number o f shareholders, May 31,
1938, 366.
Number o f shareholders at present.
389.
Shares outstanding, 682.
Present officers and directors:
John A. Thompson, president.
Roy H. Kunzelman, vice president.
Wm. D. Mulry, treasurer.
August Regez.
Simon Amundson.
Ole A. Hanson.
Arthur B. Hulett.
F. H. Randals, manager.
Donald Stromberg, secretary.
Drivers: Morris A. Peterson, Ralph
Erickson.
Increase in capital stock authorized
November 24, 1931.
Amount authorized, increase from
$2500.00 to $7500.00.
Miscellaneous facts:
Products handled: Gasoline, Kerosene,
Distillate, Oils, Greases, Antifreeze.
Three o f original Board o f Directors
still serving in that capacity —
W IS C O N S IN
DATED
The Delicious
Part of Every
Meal
INSIST ON
WISCONSIN
CHEESE
Alma Center Creamery Company
Manufacturers of American Cheese
' :: 9113
Brookside Cheese Company
Manufacturers of American Cheese
John A. Thompson, Wm. D. Mulry,
and August Regez.
Became affiliated with Farmers
Union Central Exchange August 9th,
1935, still continuing as an active
member o f the Co-op. Wholesale.
FARM ERS CO-OP
SHIPPING ASSO CIATIO N
Of Alma Center and Humbird, Wis.
Organized 1931.
Volume o f business, 1938, $75,-
000.00.
O fficers:
Peter Held, president, Alma Center.
Harry Hart, president, Humbird.
Edwin Kelsh, secretary and treasurer.
L. C. Fernholz, manager,- Alma Cen
ter.Directors:
Peter Larson, Alma Center, Henry
Tande, Alma Center; Peter Hemmy,
Humbird.
BLACK RIVER FALLS LIVE
STOCK SHIPPING ASSN.
Volume o f business for 1938, $96,-
258.56.
Number o f members 350.
Directors:
Ed Gearing, Jack Tibbetts, Carl
Klein, Lewis Stein, Frank Bright, G.
Kohnert, George Slosser, manager.
H IXTON L IV E STOCK
SHIPPING ASSO CIA TIO N
O f Hixton, Wisconsin.
Organized 1923.
Number o f members, 165.
Volume o f business, 1938, $158,-
144.93.
George O. Humphrey, president.
Mike Abend, George D. Maule,
secretary, Clarence Olson and H. E.
Burton, manager.
Petroleum products handled by
Co-ops in both rural and urban areas
topped $110,000,000 in 1937. Twenty-
four hundred Co-op stores with
330,000 members and $107,250,000
business were reported by the U. S.
Bureau o f Labor Statistics. Co-op
Credit Unions reported 2,000,000
members and assets well over $100,-
000,000 at the close o f the year.
The Co-operative Life Insurance
Co. o f America, Columbus, bought by
the Co-ops and transformed into a
Co-operative three years ago, increased
its coverage more than $8,000,000
last year. The Workmen’s Mutual
Fire Insurance Co., New York, reported
at its annual meeting a membership
o f 68,295 in 11 states.
Buy the Co-Op. way.
FARMERS - SHIP YOUR
LIVESTOCK CO-OPERATIVELY
Join your neighbors and ship your stock
through your own organization. Efficient
management, trained salesmen and intimate
knowledge of markets bring you the
best prices.
Co-operative marketing reduces cost of
shipping and gives the farmer the highest
possible return on his livestock.
Member or non-member make use of
your local shipping association. More members
and more business make stronger farmer
co-op organizations.
Help yourself by joining and patronizing
the farmers’ co-operative shipping associations.
BLACK RIVER FALLS CO-OP. LIVESTOCK
SHIPPING ASSOCIATION
FARMERS CO-OP. SHIPPING ASSOCIATION
ALMA-CENTER — HUMBIRD
HIXTON LIVESTOCK SHIPPING ASSOCIATION
i n u
For Child Growth and
Adult Health Use
Creamery BUTTER
Rich in energy- giving Vitamin A, containing growth-promoting Vitamin D and antisterility
Vitamin E, butter is world-famous as a superior food. And when produced in
Wisconsin, it attains the highest standards for deliciousness and nourishment.
Not only are Wisconsin creameries equipped with the most scientific laboratory and
manufacturing equipment—not only are its buttermakers skilled through years of experience—
but back of all these factors is one of the richest milk supplies in the world.
Bread and B U TTER
For in-between-meals nothing is quite so
healthful as a big slice of fresh bread and
butter. And it will be enthusiastically appreciated
by your youngsters as an afterschool
snack if the butter is really tasty—
the deliciously fresh, richly creamy sort
that you get when you buy butter made in
Jackson The goodness you taste in Wisconsin Creamery butter is more than “man-made”. It County Creameries.
begins with Wisconsin’s natural advantages of soil, climate, grains, grasses and clear
waters that favor the dairy cow. It continues through herds of splendid Holstein, Jersey, Guernsey, Brown Swiss, Aryshire and other
pure strains produced by years of scientific feeding and relentless control of cattle health.
Use Wisconsin Creamery Butter for cooking, baking and frying . . . . as a spread for bread, toast, rolls, biscuits, waffles, wheat cakes,
corn on the cob and many other favorite foods. More Wisconsin butter means better meals.
North Bend Co-operative Creamery
North Bend, Wisconsin
Farmers Co-operative Creamery Assn.
Black River Falls, Wisconsin
York Creamery Association
York, Wisconsin
Melrose Creamery Company
Melrose, Wisconsin
Disco Creamery Association
Disco, Wisconsin
Silver Mound Creamery Association
Sechlerville, Wisconsin
Taylor Creamery Association
Taylor, Wisconsin
PAGE NO. 8 THE BANNER-JOURNAL, Black River Falla, Wisconsin W ednesday, February 22, 1939
Miss Ann Rauk spent Saturday and
Sunday with home folks.
Donald Smart spent a few days o f
last week at the Deyo Relyea home.
Attorney Weinandy o f Cochrane,
was a business caller here Saturday.
Olaf Engebretson Jr. came home
Wednesday and remained until Friday.
W
. L. Larson and daughter Chloe
went to Minneapolis to attend a convention.
Lawrence Curran and Hero Hayes
were business callers at Eau Claire,
Monday.
Hollis Sulllivan accompanied Ted
Fosse here from Milwaukee over the
week end.
Mrs. C. J. Larson underwent an
operation at the Community hospital
Wednesday.
Mrs. Ed Hulett and Mrs. Art Hulett
spent Friday afternoon with Mrs.
Glen Sweeno.
Mr. and Mrs. Frank Vandervort of
Tomah, spent the week end with their
son Leon and family.
Mrs. De Anjou and son returned to
her home in Chicago after spending
a few days with home folks.
Mr. and Mrs. John Rumppee o f
Whitehall, and Mr. and Mrs. Will
Rumppee spent Sunday at Cashton.
Mr. and Mrs. S. F. Wallen and
John Hogan attended a birthday party
at S. A. Bue’s, at Hixton, Sunday.
Mrs. Leon Vandervort and Mrs.
Art Hulett entertained the basket
ball players Thursday night after the
game.
Henry Clipper, George Smart, Mrs.
Rose Lambert and Mrs. Ed Lambert
spent Friday with Mrs. Amy Smart at
Pigeon Falls.
Alvin and Normey Hulett, Cass
Marsh and Menford Olson spent Sunday
at their homes from their work
at Galesville.
Mr. and Mrs. Leon Vandervort,
Mr. and Mrs. C. E. Stevens and
daughter Jeanette spent Saturday
night at Deyo Relyea’s.
Attorney Eumer Mau o f West Salem,
was a business caller here Saturday.
He was also a supper guest
at the C. 0 . Rauk home.
Frank Gibson received word Monday
from his sister at Chicago, stating
that his mother was very ill. Mrs.
Gibson is nearing 90 years.
Mesdames M. J. Larson and Leon
Vandervort and John Preston and the
Boy Scouts went to La Crosse Saturday
for their swimm'ng lessons.
Mr. and Mrs. E. J. Smith entertained
a circle o f friends at their home
Friday evening. Mr. Smith showed
the moving pictures he has taken locally.
Miss Margaret Christianson spent
the week end at Minneapolis. On
her way back Sunday she met with
an accident which made her unable to
return until Monday.
Mrs. M. J. Larson entertained four
tables o f 500 at a valentine party at
her home Wednesday evening. Mrs.
R. L. Larson received high score and
Miss Anita Quirn low.
Oneal Burch was taken ill at the
funeral o f Mrs. Halverson and fell
down the flight o f stairs in the basement
o f the church. He dislocated
his shoulder and reecived several
bruises and cuts. Dr. Richards and
Mrs. Lawrence Curran, R. N., attended
him.
Mrs. Clarence Horn passed away at
Platteville, Wis. The body was taken
to B. R. Falls for burial, Tuesday,
to be laid to rest by her husband, Dr.
Horn. They were residents here at
the time o f the World war. She was
a very active Red Cross worker. Her
old acquaintances will be saddened to
hear o f her death.
T A Y L O R HIGH SCHOOL
Auline Joten
Last Monday the American History
students presented the following program
in honor o f Lincoln’s birthday:
Song, “ Star Spangled Banner”
Flag salute
The life o f Lincoln was presented
in episodes, given by representative
people, supposedly to have lived in
the Lincoln and Civil War era. Lois
Smith furnished appropriate background
music for the various scenes.
The reports were given in first person
and by the following people:
Episode 1— Norma Bemtson (a
neighbor woman) gave an account o f
Lincoln’s youth
Episode 2— Valborg Huseboe (an
Illinois girl) told about Lincoln in
Illinois
Episode 3— Romances o f Lincoln
were discussed by Mary Waller, enacting
Anne Rutledge’ s sister.
Audience sang America.
Episode 4— Ernest Rumppee gave
Lincoln’s political views as a friend
o f his.
Episode 5— Maynard Amundson (a
soldier) told o f experiences in the
Civil war.
Episode 6— Raymond Owen gave
the Gettysburg Address
Episode 7— Auline Joten told o f
her visit to Ford’s Theatre the night
Lincoln was shot.
Ralph Loken was stage manager.
The program was more or less impromptu.
Wednesday the history class will
present a George Washington program.
Lois Smith will be in charge
o f it. The program will be printed
next week, but— and this is a secret
— the band will offer several numbers.
_
Declamation began in earnest on
Monday. Taylor’s orators are: Alfred
Waller, Maynard Amundson,
Oliver Peterson and Paul Sutton. Representing
declamation are Ralph Loken,
Verna Berg, Marian Hulett. Eileen
Clipper. Ygdis Huseboe, Lois
Smith, Norma H rfltso.n and Olive
Petsch.
The Freshman English class have
finished the play “ Julius Caesar.”
Next Wednesday a quiz on the play
will be given, and on Thursday their
notebooks will be due.
The American Literature class has
finished the study o f poetry. The
work was climaxed by having poetry
collections turned in. This week they
are studying essays. In order to receive
a C a synopsis must be written
on each essay. For an A or B work
there will be supplementary texts.
Beef stew with dumplings and
Swiss steak served with French fried
potatoes were prepared in sophomore
Home Economics class this last week.
House plans have been completed
by the freshman girls who are now
studying interior decorations. Wall
finishes, kinds o f rugs, cultains and
furniture arrangement are included
in the discussions. Each girl will arrange
furniture for a house.
Natural resources and the conservation
o f resources have been the
topics for discussion in the Civics
group.
This year the Class C basket ball
tournament is to be held at Whitehall
High school gymnasium on Feb.
28, March 1, 2 and 3. Eight teams
will play in the tournament and will
be seleceted from the following High
school teams: Alma Center, Blair,
Hixton, Independence, Melrose, Mindora,
Taylor, Trempeaieau Whitehall.
There will be a total o f 11
games played in the tournament and
all games will be played at night.
Season tickets may be obtained at the
High school. Adult season tickets are
$1.25 and student season tickets sell
for 75 cent. Single admission tickets
are as follows:
Adults— Tuesday, Wednesday and
Thursday nights, 40 cents; Friday
night (championship game), 50 cents.
Students — Tuesday, Wednesday,
Thursday night, 25 cents; Friday
night (championship games) 35 cents
Independence 39— Taylor 26
Taylor battled Independence last
Thursday night for a chance to be cotitle
winners o f the Trempealeau Valley
basket ball conference but were
defeated in spite o f their efforts. Indpendence
led thruout the game and
at times it was a bare margin. At
the end o f the first quarter Indepen
dence led 11-5 but proceeded to
shave off the margin to 16-13 at the
half, both teams having played ex
cellent basket ball. Starting out the
third quarter with a tight defense
and a grand style o f offense, Independence
tallied 18 points to Taylor’s
4. The last quarter both teams added
5 points to their scores. The game
was a rather “ rough and tumble” affair
at the last with B. Arnold, the
referee, holding them in check. The
Taylor boys were pretty tired at the
end as some o f them had light cases
o f influenza the previous week and
were not in the best condition.
High scorers for Independence
were Mish with 10 points and Isaacs
with 9. C. Waller had 7 and Hulett
6 for Taylor.
This leaves Independence the undisputed
champions with Taylor holding
second place in the conference.
The Taylor 2d team was defeated
also in a close game 18-14. Hieh
scorer for Taylor was Peterson with
7 points. Sobotta and Resler led the
Independence seconds with six points
each. Maynard Amundson
T A Y L O R LU TH E RAN PARISH
A. J. Bringle, Pastor
Trempealeau V alley:
Morning worship at 10:30 (N orwegian).
This is also a communion
service. In the evening the film “ The
March o f Faith” will be shown. Lunch
will be served by the Center Circle
o f the Ladies Aid.
Ladies Aid meets March 1. Hostesses
are Miss Clara Tormoen, Mrs. Olaf
Anderson, Mrs. Goodwin Nelson and
Mrs. L. Buckholz. Topic leader—
Miss Mathilda Thompson.
Lenten services Wednesday evening,
March 1. Sermon theme— “ Rejected
by the Leaders, Rev. E. 0.
Christopherson will preach.
T aylor:
Morning worship at 9 (Norwegian)
Sunday school at 10 a. m.
Fireside Hour at 5 o’clock. The
film “ The March o f Faith” will be
shown. This depicts the early history
o f the Norwegian Lutheran,
church and no one should miss seeing
this. This is last o f the Fireside
Hours o f this season.
Remember Lenten services March 1
in Trempealeau Valley.
Beaver Creek:
Sunday school and worship, 2 p. m.
Parish Notes:
Lenten services each Wednesday
evening at 8, for all churches in the
parish. Services for March 1st will
be held in Trempealeau Valley.
Taylor Second
Hand Furniture
Store
TAYLOR, W IS.
Help us celebrate our anniversary
on March 4, 1939. Bargains
galore on high class second
hand furniture. Prices are
low on all furniture. Buy now
and save money.
A 34-piece dinner set given free
on that date. Valuable prizes to
all ladies. Cracker Jacks to all
children.
J. Cohen.
2w8
W RIG H TSVILLE
Edwin Swall spent the week end
at I. H. Bowen’s.
Mrs. Leroy Bunce spent last Tuesday
with Mrs. Geo. Gjerseth.
Mrs. Ed Gearing is staying with
her daughter. Mrs. L. Gilbertson.
Mrs. Will Gearing visited Monday
with Mr. and Mrs. Floyd Gearing.
Mr. and Mrs. R. Gearing and family
spent Sunday at Floyd Gearing’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Jim Sprinkle and
family visited relatives in Fairchild,
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Enos Bowen and
family were supper guests at I. H.
Bowen’s.
Mrs. Nelson Tucker spent Monday
until Tuesday with Mrs. Eva Bowen
and sons.
Mr. and Mrs. Randy Wilkinson and
family were Saturday afternoon callers
at Geo. Gjerseth’s.
Mr. and Mrs. F. Knapp and Mrs.
Eva Bo-sren drove to Sparta Monday
the latter to consult doctors.
Mr. and Mrs. Paul Bicket and son
James, and Mrs. Nellie Olson spent
Monday afternoon at Geo. Gjerseth’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Glen Bowen and Duane,
and Mr. and Mrs. Frank Knapp
were guests at I. H. Bowen’s, Sunday.
The Coop. Study club was postponed
two weeks ago on account o f sickness.
It will meet this Friday night,
Feb. 24 at the E. Rush home. Every
one is welcome.
SPRING CREEK
Mrs. C. Emerson visited Mrs. Tom
Holmgreen in the city, Saturday.
Mrs. Gaylord Emerson visited Mrs.
Minnie Nanstad in the city, Thursday.
Mr. and Mrs. Alfred Christenson
spent Saturday evening at Gust Hortum’s.
Mrs. Emil Engebretson spent Friday
afternoon with Mrs. C. Emerson
and Ruth.
Leonard Olson and Sigferd Peterson
spent Monday evening at the Ole
Wold home.
Ruby Engebretson went Thursday
to help Mrs. Heineck with her household
duties.
Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Wyss were
Sunday evening visitors at Mr. and
Mrs. Ernest Anderson’s.
Matt Peterson, daughter Hilma and
nephew, Lester Peterson, spent Friday
afternoon at Ole W old’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Charley Huber and
son Roger viisted her mother, Mrs. C.
Emerson and family, Sunday.
Mrs. Fred Durrin and Mrs. Harriet
Noble visited Mrs. Hans Nanstad in
the city, Thursday afternoon.
Henry Olson o f the Falls, spent a
few days with his brother, Matt Olson,
last week, cutting wood.
Mr. and Mrs. Merlin Peterson and
family o f Irving, were dinner guests
o f his brother Price and family, Sunday.
M
r. and Mrs. Geo. Mason and Mr.
and Mrs. James Harmer were Sunday
afternoon callers at Sophie Mason’s.
Miss Ruby Stamstad came Friday
evening and remained until Saturday
afternoon with her aunt, Mrs. Marcus
Emerson.
Mr. and Mrs. Gerald Hoonsbeen
and son drove out and spent the evening
with her parents, Mr. and Mrs.
A. M. Gilbertson.
Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Olson, Dick,
Mary and Carol, spent Sunday afternoon
with his sister, Mrs. Theodore
Johnson and husband at Warrens.
Mr. and Mrs. E. L. Giroulx and
Mrs. Carrie Strand motored here
from Marshfield and were guests for
dinner at Caroline and Henry Johnson’s,
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Frank Thomas called
on Mrs. Hannah Overlien and son
Perry last Monday evening. Garth
Thomas has been helping Perry the
past couple o f weeks.
Mr. and Mrs. Gust Hortum and son
Donald attended the examination for
the confirmands at the Lutheran
church in the city Sunday evening,
Donald being one o f the class.
Mr. and Mrs. Stanley Stratton o f
Trout, spent Sunday afternoon with
Mr. and Mrs. Price Peterson. Mr.
and Mrs. Norman Peterson and children
spent the evening with them.
Miss Webb, Mrs. Rose and Miss
Hanson called at the Spring Creek
school last week to hear a summary
o f a business letter project which
the 8th grade children had completed.
Fred Rockney, daughter Elna Mae
and two classmates from Northfield,
Minn., came to call on his mother,
Saturday afternoon. Mrs. Rockney
rode back with them and spent the
evening in the city.
U PPER SQ U A W CREEK
Miss June Haralson spent the week
end here with home folks.
Mrs. Sig Severson called on Mrs.
P. Stubrud, Tuesday afternoon.
Mrs. Roy Haralson and son, John
Robert, spent Tuesday afternoon with
Mrs. Alvin Engebretson.
Mahlon Stein and Peter Stubrud
and sons delivered tobacco at La
Crosse, last week Tuesday.
A nice crowd assembled at Ladies
Aid at Willie Anderson’s last Friday.
The Aid will meet with Mrs. Calmer
Halverson in two weeks.
Roy Haralson spent a few days o f
last week at Madison, with his brother
Rufus and family. He returned
home Saturday afternoon.
Mrs. Emil Engebretson and daughters,
Elva and Verna, Esther, Ruth
and Irwin and Sanford Stenulson
spent Sunday afternoon at C. Ofte’s.
Sewing club at Mrs. Carl Olson’s
last Thursday was well attended. A
nice lunch was served. Mrs. Louis
Stein will entertain the next meeting.
E
dwin and Adolph Peterson, Cora
and Blanche Olson, Adolph Olson and
family, Mabel and Merlin Olson and
the Haralson boys were Saturday evening
callers at Thorwald Engebretson’s.
Louis Stein, Mrs. Ida Stein and
family, Mr. and Mrs. Mark Engebretson
were among those from here who
attended the funeral services o f Mrs.
Hubert Johnson at the Little Norway
church, Sunday.
The Bingo Players group gathered
at the Ofte home Saturday evening
for a social time. Several games o f
bingo were played and nice prizes
were awarded the winners. A good
lunch was served.
Pershing Hohn, o f Minneapolis,
motored here last week and spent
Wednesday with his aunt, Mrs. Sig
Severson. He left Thursday for Madison
to visit Rufus Haralson and
family. He will go to Chicago from
there to spend a few days, and will
also visit friends in Iowa before returning
home.
BURTON
Mrs. Ed Lyons and daughter Ethel
were Thursday evening visitors at the
Charles Dorrance home.
Mrs. Lawrence Chappie and Mrs.
Morris Peterson spent Thursday afternoon
with Mrs. Harland Duxbury.
Mr. and Mrs. William Olson and
son Allen spent Tuesday evening at
the Elmer Henderson home in Hixton.
M
r. and Mrs. Francis Bergerson
and Mrs. Albert Hanson and children
spent Saturday evening at the William
Olson home.
Mr. and Mrs. Earl Jones, Mr. and
Mrs. Morris Peterson and Mrs. Jennie
Stolts were Sunday supper guests
at the Charles Dorrance home.
Mr. and Mrs. Charles Dorrance
and son James, Mrs. Amelia Dorrance
and Mr. and Mrs. Morris Peterson
and Mrs. Jennie Stolts spent Saturday
evening at the Earl Jones home
in Hixton.
Gas Gas AIITime Mrs. Jas. F iller says: "G as on m y stom a
ch was so bad I cou ldn’ t eat or sleep.
Gas even pressed on m y heart. A dlerlka
brought m e quick relief. N ow, I eat as I
g js h s le e p fine, never felt better.'* ADLERI KA
Lange’s Drug Store — in Alma Center
by Will’s Drug Store.
SQ U A W CREEK
Mr. and Mrs. I. Olson and son
called at S; Simonson’s one day of
last week.
Mr. and Mrs. T. Bunde assisted
Mrs. T. Stenulson at paper hanging,
Saturday.
Mrs. T. Stenulson and children
called at Grandma Holmgreen’s one
day last week.
Misses Shirley and Joyce Stenulson
spent Saturday with their grandmother,
Mrs. A. Stenulson.
Mr. and Mrs. T. Stenulson and
children called at A. Stenulson’s Sunday
afternoon. Adolph Peterson was
also a caller there.
A miscellaneous shower was given
at the home o f Mr. and Mrs. Richard
Stenulson recently. They received a
number o f nice gifts. A kensington
lunch was served and all enjoyed a
pleasant afternoon.
Sam Amundson has been ill o f flu
the past week.
Dr. I. H. Lavine visited briefly in
Chicago recently
Mr. and Mrs. Leo Martin spent
Monday in La Crosse.
O. L. O’Hearn was a Sunday business
caller in Winona.
Mrs. Howard Hemmy spent Thursday
in Black River Falls.
Miss Marjory Bibby spent the week
end at home from Galesville.
Miss Audrey Gilbert has gone to
Janesvilel for an indefinite period.
Geo. Dudley o f West Salem, transacted
business in Melrose Saturday.
Several o f the local Oddfellows attended
lodge in Sparta Monday night.
O. C. O’Hearn and Chas. Sparhawk
were Saturday visitors at B. R. Falls.
Mr. and Mrs. B. A. Finch o f B. R.
Falls, were Melrose callers Saturday.
Art Loomis o f La Crosse, was a
week end guest at the C. F. Patrye
home.
Mrs. Mae Milbright o f North Bend,
was a brief caller in Melrose Friday
evening.
Harold Emerson o f North Bend,
was a recent guest at the Wm. Sawyer
home.
Miss Grace Webb and Mrs. Pearl
Rose spent Wednesday at the Webb
farm home.
Mr. and Mrs. O. C. Howard and
daughters were La Crosse shoppers
on Saturday.
Mrs. Tenny Amidon was hostess to
the Shake Hollow Home Makers club
Friday afternoon.
Henry Stoker has been confined to
his bed the past week by a very severe
case o f the ful.
Mr. and Mrs. Wilbur Neidfeldt and
daughter spent the week end in La
Crosse with relatives.
Miss Marion Printz R. N., o f Madison,
was a recent guest o f her mother,
Mrs. Philip Printz.
Mr. and Mrs. Fay Button entertained
their pinochle club at their
home Saturday evening.
Archie Huber departed by truck
for Milwaukee over the week end,
where he went after a load o f horses.
Mrs. Ren Simms left Wednesday
for Chicago, to be with relatives for
a time while undergoing treatment.
Saturday business callers in B. R.
Falls included Mrs. Wm. Young, Mr.
and Mrs. Oscar Decker and Donna
Dean.
Miss Gwen White was in charge of
Cleo’s Beauty Shop on Monday while
Miss Cleo Patrye was a La Crosse
caller.
Mrs. Ray Sonnenberg returned on
Thursday from Minneapolis, where
she had been called by the death o f
her father.
Mr. and Mrs. Sidney Jensen of
Hixton were Sunday evening callers
at the Ed Erickson home en route
from Bangor.
Miss Dorothy Boeshel who attends
business school in Sparta, spent the
week end with her uncle, Ed Boeshel
in West Salem.
Mr. and Mrs. C. W. Tenner have
had as house guest for several days
the latter’s brother-in-law, Wm. Sullivan
o f Barron.
Chas. Stebbins fell on the ice Sunday,
causing an injury to his head
which necessitated several stitches to
close the wound.
Lyle Hafferman left this week for
Chicago, having been called back to
work after having been at his home
since before the holidays.
Mrs. C. N. Stebbins was hostess to
the bridge club at her home Tuesday.
Lovely refreshments were served
at the close o f the evening.
Mrs. Wayne Fabian had charge
o f the upper grades in the Melrose
school early in the week, substituting
for Mr. Wike, who was ill.
Mrs. Alta Higgins was hostess to
the G. P. bridge club at her home on
Monday. Very lovely refreshments
were served during the evening.
Friends will be pleased to learn
that Helmer Olson, who has been a
La Crosse hospital patient for several
weeks, is much improved and gaining
rapidly.
Mr. and Mrs. Jesse Spafford and
son Stanley, o f La Crosse, came Sunday
to attend the 59th wedding anniversary
o f Mr. and Mrs. A. D.
Pischke.
Mr. and Mrs. Howard Hemmy, Betty
and Miss Grace Webb motored to
La Crosse Saturday afternoon to visit
a relative who is a patient at the
hospital.
While in the yard o f her home on
Sunday Mrs. Jas. Curda fell, wrenching
her body to such an extent that
she has been in considerable pain for
several days.
The joint card party sponsored by
the Oddfellows and Rebeccahs Friday
evening was well attended. The proceeds
which are to be used for the
educational fund, netted $28.
Miss Addie Ostrander was taken
quite seriously ill on Friday evening
and has since been cared for at the
Elgie Brewer and J. Ralston homes.
Friends are pleased to learn that she
is reported some better.
There were no preaching services
Sunday morning due to the fact that
the guest speaker was unable to complete
the trip because of the icy condition
o f the roads. A brief devotional
service was held by those present.
M
r. and Mrs. C. A. Rydberg are
moving this week to their house recently
vacated by the O. L. O’Hearn
family. Joe Meyers, daughter and
granddaughter will take possession o f
the former Rydberg home which they
purchased last fall.
Mr. and Mrs. C. W. Tenner, their
house guest, Mr. Sullivan o f Barron,
and Mrs. Roy Lutz were Sunday
dinner guests o f relatives in West Salem.
Mr. Sullivan remained for a
longer visit and will retuni to Melrose
en route to his home in Barron.
There was a fair attendance at the
high school P. T. A. on Monday evening
considering the icy condition o f
the roads. As part o f the program
Miss Grace Webb and Douglas Curran
were present and exhibited pictures
with the new machine which has
been purchased for use among the
schools throughout the county.
Olaus Overlien drove to Winona
on Saturday, where he met his daughter
Miss Blanche, who came to spend
the week end from her duties as librarian
at the Rochester clinic. Miss
Overlien is very much improved in
health from her long siege at Madison
last year.
Mr. and Mrs. Merton Kelly have
closed their restaurant business and
spent a few days in Sparta. They
expect to return to Melrose to make
their home for the present. During
their short stay here the Kellys have
made many friends who regret to see
them go out o f business.
Members o f the E. E. Gilbertson
family motored to La Crosse Sunday
where they joined relatives in cele-
SNOW CREEK
Mr. and Mrs. Victor Eggen were
business callers in Neillsville Friday.
Miss Elmira Hanson, o f Melrose,
was a week end visitor o f Miss Martha
Gjerseth.
Mr. and Mrs. Lavern Scafe moved
Friday from the Iliff turkey farm to
the Betz farm.
Mrs. Donald Peasley accompanied
Mr. and Mrs. Paul Bicket to Stevens
Point, Tuesday.
Mrs. I. Schroeder o f Racine, visited
from Friday until Monday at the
Ernest Rush home.
Mrs. A. H. Eggen visited Tuesday
afternoon with her sister, Mrs. Geo.
Olson, in your city.
C. Hancock and sons and H. Gjerseth
and sons called Sunday afternoon
at W. Chapman’s.
Jean Rush was a week end visitor
of Ann Thornton at the Jennie Reichenbach
home in your city.
Miss Martha Gjerseth assisted her
aunt, Mrs. George Gjerseth with her
household duties last week.
Mr. and Mrs. H. B. Mathews were
Sunday dinner guests o f Mr. and
Mrs. Roy Rush and family.
Mr. and Mrs. Helmer Gjerseth were
Sunday night visitors at the Fred
Riggle home in Allen Creek.
Mr. and Mrs. Paul Haugstad and
son Arthur were Friday dinner guests
o f Mr. and Mrs. J E. Peasley.
Clarence Scafe o f Pardeeville came
Friday for an indefinite visit with
home folks, Mr. and Mrs. H. Scafe.
Misses Marguerite Eggen and Mable
Gjerseth were Monday supper
guests o f their aunt, Mrs. Donald
Peasley.
Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Rush and Mrs.
I. Schroeder were Saturday evening
visitors o f Mr. and Mrs. Glen Bowen
o f Wrightsville.
Mr. and Mrs. J. W. Hannon accompanied
Mr. and Mrs. Charles Sherwood,
o f your city, to Marshfield on
business last Wednesday.
Several o f the ladies in the district
were at the school house last
Tuesday afternoon helping the children
enjoy their valentine party.
Mr. and Mrs. Horace Scafe and
daughter Betty, and Mr. and Mrs.
Harold Reichenbach o f Wrightsville
were Sunday visitors at the Betz
home.
Kenneth Mathews and friend, Miss
Beulah Stetzer o f your city, went to
Sparta Saturday and spent until Sunday
at the home o f Mr. and Mrs. Roy
Heineck, and attended the ski tournament.
Mr. and Mrs. V ictor Eggen and
daughters accompanied by Mr. and
Mrs. Emil Peterson, spent Saturday
afternoon at Sparta. Miss Marguerite
remained with her cousin, Jeanette
Gjerseth, Sunday. Mr. and Mrs
Eggen drove there after her and visited
in the afternoon with Mr. and
Mrs. O. Gjerseth.
H ATFIE LD
Miss Agnes Staszak and a party of
friends spent the day in Eau Claire
recently.
Mr. and Mrs. Joe Jarolimek and
family were Sunday visitors in Columbia.
Muriel and Shirley Miller o f Humbird,
spent Saturday afternoon with
Sylvia Jarolimek.
A. J. Anderson and son Leonard,
of Halcyon, called at Geo. Meyer’s,
Sunday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Paul Safranek and
son Robert visited relatives and
friends in Chicago last week.
Mr. and Mrs. Eugene McKevitt and
Billy De Lapp spent Thursday evening
with relatives in Merrillan.
Mrs. Curtiss, who has been a patient
at the Krohn hospital in B. R.
Falls, was able to come home the first
o f last week.
Mr. and Mrs. Fred Miller and family
o f Humbird, were visitors at Ole
Falk’s, Saturday. Mrs. Miller remained
for a few days to help care
for her mother, Mrs. Falk, who has
been very ill. We are glad to learn
she is improving, tho slowly.
brating the 93rd birthday o f Gilbert
Gilbertson, father o f the late E. E.
Gilbertson, at the Geo. Thompson
home. Mr. Gilbertson, who has many
friends in Melrose, is still very active
and enjoys excellent health.
Miss Patty Bolger, daughter o f Mr.
and Mrs. Donovan Bolger, was honored
the past week by having a story
written by her recently chosen as one
o f the ten best for the week. It was
selected from among many sent in
each week to the University at Madison
from pupils throughout the state.
These stories are written at school
without help from any one, and sent
in by the respective teachers. The
winners are announced over WHA
and it was through this medium that
Miss Patty gained her first information
which was a thrill to her as well
as her teacher, Miss Mildred Haugstad
Bolger, coming over the air as
it did during school hours.
ATTENTION
Zanal Customers
at our home you may have seven
(7 ) packages o f either
Swish or J iffy Perfum ed Starch
fo r only $1.00. This is far below
wholesale price.
L. H. SCHROEDER
A LM A CENTER, W ISCONSIN
VSeijh m inq Ijou v
A G E S | $25-00 an{* UP
Fulfilling s present requirement with
a Rock of Ages marker is a wise first
step in a lifelong memorial program—
for Rock of Ages monuments and memorial
markers can be matched exactly
through the years to come. a ,
“ Consult us today on your problem
In the choice of monument or marker
as the beginning of a memorial plan.
BLACK RIVER FALLS
MONUMENT WORKS
W alter Kissinger, Prop.
BLACK RIV ER FALLS W IS.
PINE HILL
Miss Grace Deno spent the week
end at home.
Will Barnum had the misfortune to
fall and get some ribs broken.
Miss Joan Siegel spent the week
end in B. R. Falls, visiting friends.
Mr. and Mrs. Bert Bloom called on
Mr. and Mrs. Henry Deno, Monday.
Mrs. Frank Chatt spent Monday at
the Falls, with her daughter, Mrs.
John Rulland.
Mr. and Mrs. Otto Mess and Doris
called Friday evening on Mr. and
Mrs. Alex Vance.
Mr. and Mrs. Albert Rendig spent
Thursday afternoon with Mr. and
Mrs. Howard Burchard.
Mr. and Mrs. Mahlon Siegel and
family spent Sunday with his parents,
Mr. and Mrs. Charles Siegel.
Mrs. Orton Anderson of Milwaukee
is visiting this week with her father,
F. C. Bright, and Mr. and Mrs. Cecil
Bowen.
Alvin Bucholtz and Victor Burchard
left Saturday for Chicago where
they will visit friends and relatives
for a few days.
Quite a few from here attended
the party given by the Shamrock
club Friday evening. A nice time
was had by all.
Mr. and Mrs. Fremaine Burchard
are staying at Henry Rendig’s and
helping out with the work while Alvin
is in Chicago.
Mr. and Mrs. Alvin Culbert o f La
Crosse, spent a couple o f days with
her parents, Mr. and Mrs. John Murphy.
They also called on other relatives
while here.
Mrs. Annis and son Harold called
on their son and brother, Charles Annis,
Sunday. He has been very ill at
the home o f Mr. and Mrs. A. Vance.
He is on the gain now.
Those who spent Saturday evening
with Gust Buchholz and sister, Mrs.
Hattie Kuelper, were Mr. and Mrs.
Harry Dill and son, Mr. and Mrs.
Miles Laberee and Nina, and Will
Helferty. The evening was spent in
playing 500. Refreshments were
served by Mrs. Kuelper.
Our club, and some o f the Shamrock
club, together with people from
B. R. Falls, about 40 in all, gathered
at the home o f Albert Gomer, in your
city, last Wednesday, and gave their
Prof. L. M. Isgrigg
CHIROPRACTOR
OFFICES OVER MOE’S HfcW.
Where absolute relief is had from
Celds, Blood Pressure, Dizzy Spells,
Backache, Pain in Neck, Arms or
Legs, Heart, Kidney and Stomach
trouble.
Chiropractic is most effective in
nearly all types of disease, even in
many cases of Gallstones and Appendicitis,
which often make operations
unnecessary.
X-Ray Service
BLACK RIVER FALLS, WIS.
daughter, Evelyn, a miscellaneous
shower. She received many beautiful
gifts. Mrs. Wallace Heine left
that same evening by train for her
home in Sullivan, Wis. We wish her
a long and happy married life.
KENYON VALLEY
Martin Malchow was a visitor at
Ed McNulty’s, Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Lubow spent
the week end at Henry Lubow’s.
The Comfort club will meet with
Mrs. Harley Kunes on Friday, Feb.
24th.
Gary Cox spent last week witk his
grandparents, Mr. and Mrs. Albert
Lubow.
Mr. and Mrs. Frank Newton were
over night guests o f Mr. and Mrs.
Odas Newton, o f Eau Claire, Saturday.
The Roberts family are sorry the
names o f Rev. and Mrs. Allison were
omitted among the names o f guests
at the luncheon for Mr. and Mrs.
Wesley MacGregor at the Roberts
home on a recent Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Harley Kunes entertained
the following to dinner Sunday:
Mr. and Mrs. Harold Kunes o f
Eau Claire; Mr. and Mrs. Forrest
Kunes and family, Mrs. Jas. Curda,
o f Melrose; and Mr. and Mrs. B. A.
Finch.
NEW NASH “ WEATHER EYE” CAR, which has been making
sales gain after sales gain this year, is reported to be one o f
the most discussed cars in the motor world o f 1939. It features
the new Nash “ Weather Eye” conditioned air system
for winter driving, and its styling is said to have made a hit
with both automobile men and the public. Demonstrator cars
like the one above are now being used by ADOLPH’S GARAGE,
local Nash dealer, to show motorists how the car
weather-maker works.
CHARLIE SAVAGE’S BIG AUCTION SALE 120 Acre Farm — 55 Head of Fine Live Stock
at 10a.m.SATURDAY, MARCH 4
This farm is located 10 miles southwest o f Black River Falls, 6 miles
North o f Melrose, mile southwest o f the Catholic church, in the
Town o f Irving.
120 Acres o f Heavy Clay Soil, Rich, Fertile, Productive, 110 Acres
Cultivated, Balance Tim ber and Pasture with Spring Creek, Large
Basement Barn, Silo, Machine Sheds, Hen House, Com fortable D welling
House, and other Buildings. One o f the Best Farms in Jackson
County. You can BUY it on EA SY Terms: Only $1000 DOW N and
balance arranged to suit both parties. Come and look it over and be
on hand at 10 a. m. Ready for Business. The farm will BE SOLD
First to enable the Purchaser to BUY what he may want o f
THE PERSONAL PROPERTY
HORSES — Span o f Beautiful Roan Belgian Mares, aged 5 and 6,
weighing about 3000 pounds. Sound and Right, straight and True, a
TEAM that YOU will be proud to own and to drive. Span o f Colts,
8 months old, from these mares.
CA T T L E — 33 CHOICE H OLSTEINS, Fourteen Milk Cows, some
are Fresh, others will freshen soon. No loafers or boarders in this
Herd. Every one a Real Producer with an Outstanding Record o f
Production. Some Nice Two Year Oid Heifers. Several .Yearling H eifers,
and some Calves. Here is your chance to get some good Holstein
Cattle. Bangs Tested.
HOGS — Eight Shoates weighing about 100 lbs. each. Seven W inter
Pigs. The Strong, rugged, thrifty kind, growing into MONEY.
DOG — One Good Cattle Dog One Year Old. You will like to own it.
Full Line of First Class Farm Machinery, Implements
Small Tools, etc.
ALLIS-CH A LM ER S W . C. 12-23 TR A C TO R with Steel W heels and
Lugs, Only one year old and as good as Brand NEW . Allis-Chalmers
Tractor Plows. Allis-Chalmers Tractor Discs. NEW Case Side Delivery
Hay Rake. NEW Case Steel Hay Loader, No. 17. McCormick-
Deering Hay Mower. Four W alking Plows, one Brand NEW. A Four
Section Drag Harrow. Blizzard Ensilage Cutter, 14-inch. Three W agons.
One Sulky Plow. Van Brunt Grain Seeder. La Crosse Grain
Drill. Bob Sleigh. W ood Rack. New Ideal Manure Spreader. Corn
Binder. Hay Rack. Corn Planter. M cCorm ick-Deering Gasoline Engine
1 *2 b. p. Feed Cooker. M cCorm ick-Deering Spring Tooth Pulverizer.
DeLaval Cream Separator with Power Attachment. W ood
Saw and Arbor. Case Sulky Corn Cultivator. Walking Cultivator.
Pump Jack. Fifty Grain Sacks. Two Sets o f Good Heavy W ork Harnesses.
The Usual Run o f Small Farm Tools, Hoes, Forks, Shovels,
Axes, Log Chains, Some Carpenter Tools, and 1001 other articles
including
Hay, Grain and Miscellaneous Articles
About T W E N T Y -F IV E Tons o f Good Tame H A Y in the Barn. A b ou t-
Eight Hundred Bushels o f OATS. One hundred baskets o f CORN.
FOUR HUNDRED Oak Fence Posts. Twenty-five W agon Poles. Platform
scales 1000 lbs. capacity. Other articles.
TERM S on PERSO N AL PRO PER TY — All sums o f $15.00 or less,
CASH, larger amounts *4 cash and 6 months time, monthly payments
with 6 per cent interest. Special easy terms with at least one year’s
time will be given on the T R A C T O R and other large machinery.
Thorp Finance Corporation, Clerks, represented by
Wm. F. Neuenfeldt, Greenwood, Wis.
Lunch Stand on the Grounds will Serve Hot Coffee,
Doughnuts and Sandwiches all day.
Rem ember the Date and Time, 10 a. m. SA T., MARCH 4th, and be
with us.
Charlie Savage, Owner
Col. F. J. Bowman, Black River Falls, Auctioneer.
A t Y our Service with 25 Years Experience conducting over 2000
sales in 8 states and in 25 counties in W ISCONSIN. The Best sales
on record to my credit. W hen Better Sales are Made, BO W M AN
will make them. W rite or wire for DATES.
#
THE BANNER-JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin PAGE NO. 9
Sheriff Waldum was a caller in the
v illa g e M onday.
Mrs. A. B. Lowe visited relatives
at Whitehall several days last week.
Mr. and Mrs. James Johnson and
son Paul called on friends in the village,
Monday.
Mr. and Mrs. Herbert Chandler and
son Glen, o f Northfield, were Sunday
guests for dinner at Frank Dell’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Wm. Steinbring and
Postmaster Simons were entertained
At the Pringle home at B. R. Falls
Friday evening.
Mesdames Peter Faldet, Geo. R®18"
inger, Ben Hagen, L. H. Chandler
and Olson visited Mrs. Palmer Dahl
at Taylor, Wednesday afternoon.
D. E. Erickson and daughter Anna
o f Alma Center, and Arthur Erickson
o f Taylor, were guests o f Mr. and
Mrs. Ralph Erickson Saturday night.
A miscellaneous shower was given
Mrs. Ball, Miss Dorothy Preston, at
the home o f her parents, Mr. and
Mrs. Roy Preston, Thursday afternoon.
Mesdames Martin Ryerson, Emma
Northup and C. O. Pratt spent last
Friday with Mrs. Wm. Olson. It was
the birthday anniversaries o f Mmes.
Northup and Olson.
The Lutheran Ladies Aid will meet
at the home o f Mrs. Gorden Van
Gorden on Thursday afternoon, Feb.
23. Mrs. Peter Faldet will assist in
serving. Everybody welcome.
Catherine Tomsyck, Dorothy Hanneman,
Carl Godager and Eldon Pratt
o f Wisconsin Rapids, spent last Sunday
at the home o f the latter s parents,
Mr. and Mrs. C. O. Pratt.
The Hixton Study club held its
annual guest day Tuesday, Feb. 14,
entertaining the Merrillan, Alma Center
and Taylor clubs. Some 80 club
members were present. The program
opened with a few words o f welcome
by the Hixton club president, followed
by the Club collect and America
the Beautiful. Francis White, band
leader, and a group o f his band men
then gave a short concert, Mr. White s
solos being especially fine. Then followed
an hour at cards, and refreshments
completed a most delightful
afternoon. The club wishes at this
time to publicly acknowledge Mr.
White’s kindness. .
Presbyterian Ladies Aid Society
will meet in their church parlors on
Wednesday afternoon, March 1st.
Our pastor, Rev. P. F. Schroeder, has
requested that all the missionary o fferings
be turned in at church services
by next Sunday, Feb. 26. The
children o f the Presbyterian Sundayschool
are taking a very active part
in the missionary work i- which they
are each one giving their birthday offerings.
Very much credit should be
given to the children o f this community
who are taking such an interest in
the work o f the Sunday school and
its activities. The Sunday school is
now preparing their program for the
Easter services on Easter Sunday,
April 9th.
H IXTON SCHOOLS
Shorthand students are ready to
begin studying from their new Functional
Dictation books. They have
been taking unfamiliar dictation for
two weeks. Some o f the members o f
this class have received their O. G.
A. certificates. Let’s all get our certificates
as soon as possible in this
class.
Rollie Chappie and Eldon Jacobson
have written above the required 35
words per minute net speed requirements.
Eldon Jacobson. Harold Ludeman
and Paul Pattson are holding
honors for accuracy but not necessarily
speed. What is needed in typ-
BIG AUCTION! ! !
ON THE HOG FARM
2 Miles East o f Hixton
Friday, March 3rd
A T 11 A. M. SH A RP
52 Head o f V ery High Grade G uernsey
and Holstein Cattle
8 Guernsey cows, 6 Guernsey heifers
2 years old, 4 Guernsey heifers 1 yr.
old, 6 Guernsey heifers 8 months old,
2 Guernsey heifers 5 months old, 8
G uernsey calves, 6 Holstein cows, 2
Holstein heifers 8 months old. Bangs
tested.
5 Horses — 25 Feeder Pigs
12 Bred Sows — 1 Boar
800 bu. Oats. Some Hay and Fodder.
15-30 M cCorm ick-D eering T ractor 
plows and farm machinery.
Term s — Cash, bankable notes or arrange
finance with clerk b efore sale.
FRED F. BECKER, Prop.
GEO. H. BA R R Y ,
Arcadia, W is., Auctioneer
PIGEON FALLS ST A T E BANK,
Clerk
Fox Meat Wanted
W e pay up to 812 per head
FOR OLD D ISA B L E D HORSES
AND CR IPPLED C A T T L E
DEAD OR A L IV E
W e k ill daily. My trucks pickup
anywhere and pay cash.
1 PAY A LL PHONE CALLS
Walter Marg Fox Farm
PHONE 2-R-19
BLA CK R IV E R FALLS W IS.
FARMS FOR SALE
Federal Land Bank and Private
Farms — Call or Ses
The Gile Agency
Phone 85 Merrillan, Wis.
ing is speed plus accuracy. Harold
holds the best accuracy record to date
with two errors on a ten minute
speed test.
Hixton defeated Fairchild in one of
the most exciting games so far this
year. A good lead was obtained and
held throughout the game. The fine
display o f school spirit shown by the
pupils helped to win the struggle.
An interesting presentation on the
subject o f Infant Hygiene was enjoyed
by the girls attending that class
Monday. Movie reels were shown, illustrating
the course in a much better
way than the old lecture-demonstration
course.
A series o f tests in English grammar
are being given to the English
classes to determine which class has
retained the most practical English
usage. The Junior class is aread in
the upper class contest, but the
Freshmen are at the top o f the list
in the lower classes.
Superintendent F. W. Pauli attended
the Schoolmasters convention at
Eau Claire on Wednesday o f last
week. He reported an interesting
discussion.
Plans are now being made for a
bigger and better exposition to be
held in April.
A Good Citizenship Pilgrimage
to Washington, D. C., has been arranged
by the National Society,
Daughters o f American Revolution.
The Daughters o f the American Revolution
will take as their guests on
the Pilgrimage, one girl from each
o f the 48 states, selected from senior
classes o f the senior high schools.
Senior students in each public high
school may choose by vote, three
girls, members o f their class whom
they believe best qualified as good
citizens. From the three girls thus
selected the high school faculty shall
select one who becomes a good citizen
o f her school. The name o f this
girl shall be certified by the city superintendent
o f schools, or principal,
and sent to the state superintendent
o f schools, John Callahan, Madison,
Wis., on or before March 1, 1939.
Final selections shall then be made
under the supervision o f the state superintendent.
Three names shall be
drawn; if the girl whose name is
drawn first is unable to go, the second
may take her place and if she is
unable to go the third shall be given
the opportunity. This Wisconsin girl
will meet with the representatives o f
other states in Washington, Friday,
April 14. Three full days will be
given to sightseeing and the girls will
leave for home on Tuesday, Apr. 18.
Included in the program are visits to
Congress, The White House, Library
of Congress, Museum o f Natural His
tory, Arlington, Mount Vernon and
other places o f historic interest. The
Wisconsin girl received the Good Citizenship
pin, and an award o f the National
Society at the open session o f
the Daughters o f American Revolution
Congress, Monday evening, April
17. Elvina Nerby, Eunice Nordahl
and Florence Rogstad were the three
picked by the class and from these
three, Elvina Nerby has been chosen
the good citizen to represent Hixton
High school. The expenses o f this
trip, including rail transportation,
pullman fare, hotel room and meals
will be paid by the National Society,
Daughters o f the American Revolution.
For Prompt Ssrrics and Financial
Responsibility
Ship Yonr Poultry and Veal to
Richard J. Collins Co.
E s ta b lis h e d 1 8 6 8
8 4 0 F u lto n M a r k e t, C h ic a g o , IIL
FOUR CORNERS
Rollin Johnson was a week end
guest o f friends in Minnesota.
Mr. and Mrs. Ed Hertzfeldt visited
at the Maule home Sunday evening.
Ray Duxbury o f Garden Valley,
9awed wood for Asa Fox, Wednesday.
Misses M.randa Hanson and Amy
Kolden sper.t the week end at their
homes in Osseo.
Mrs. Marvin Johnon spent Wednesday
with Mrs. Asa Fox, and assisted
with wood sawers.
Miss Goldie Thompson who teaches
in the Grinde district, spent the week
end at her home here.
Mr. and Mrs. Asa Fox and sons
and Mrs. Stanley Jacobus were at B.
R. Falls Saturday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Paul Getman and
daughter Opal, o f Hixton, were Sunday
guests at the Asa Fox home.
Harold Downer o f Shady Glen, is
helping with the work at Maule’s during
the absence o f Rollin Johnson
Mr. and Mrs. Myron Goldsmith and
Nora Mae and Leonard were visitors
at the Lowe home Saturday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Osborne Thompson
and children o f Curran Valley spent
Thursday afternoon at the Thompson
home.
Mr. and Mrs. Marvin Johnson and
sons and Mr. and Mrs. Asa Fox and
sons visited at A. C. Bills’ , Friday
evening.
Mrs. Myron Larson o f Taylor, and
sister, Mrs. Ed Olson, o f Viroqua,
were supper guests o f Mr. and Mrs.
Dorrance Stolts, Tuesday.
Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Maule, o f
Dousman, and Mrs. Homer Fentil o f
Elmwood, Neb., visited from Tuesday
until Wednesday at Maule’s. They
also called on Mr. and Mrs. George
Van Horn and Robert.
Mr. and Mrs. Myron Nolop and
daughter June are spending a few
days with the form er’s father while
Mrs. Nolop is at La Crosse at the
home o f her son Osborne, one o f the
children being ill o f appendicitis.
TRO U T RUN
Tom Hanson has been sick a cou
pie o f weeks.
Wm. Burge visited friends at Warrens,
Sunday.
Herman Rosenbaum was ill last
week, o f flu.
Palmer Midtlien and family visited
at Melvin Nelson’s, Sunday.
Alfred Myhres received word Wed
nesday o f the death o f his mother at
Osseo.
The Ted Thompson family o f Walworth,
were recent visitors in this
county.
Mr. and Mrs. Stanley Stratton visited
at the Price Peterson home on
Sunday.
R. Zimmerman and daughter Evelyn
had dental work done in your city
Thursday.
Miss Marie Brauner was an over
Sunday guest o f Miss Marie Melichar
in your city.
Rev. Allison will preach at Trout
Run M. E. church next Sunday at
2 :30. All welcome.
A party by the name o f Smith has
rented the former Counrod place, recently
vacated by Wm. Hoppman.
Word has been received o f the
marriage at Christmas time o f Miss
Edith Shaw, daughter o f Mr. and
Mrs. Ray Shaw o f Missoula. Mont. to
Clarence Warren, o f that place. Edith
mother was formerly Emma Bailey o f
Trout Run, sister o f Clyde. She and
Edith visited him last soring and
many friends liei-e congratulate. They
will reside in Missoula.
SOUTH SE CH LER VILLE
Genevieve Skutley spent Saturday
at Eau Claire.
Walter Johnson has employment at
George Van Horn’s.
Evelyn Iverson was a Sunday caller
at Hans Nelson’s.
Mrs. J. D. Preston viisted Mrs. A lbert
Campbell Tuesday.
Mrs. Vernon Stalter and Helen Hagen
spent Saturday at Osseo.
Gordon Hestekind spent the week
end with friends at Melrose.
Herbert Sukopp was a caller at the
Albert Campbell home Monday.
Mr. and Mrs. Marvin Johnson spent
Monday evening at Evan Hegge’s.
Mrs. Marvin Johnson spent Tuesday
afternoon with Mrs. Eli Lyons.
Albert Campbell helped Arthur
Thompson with wood sawing, Friday.
Willard Johnson has employment
at the Harland Duxbury home at Hixton.
Mrs. Peter Faldet o f Hixton, was
a caller at the J. D. Preston home
Friday.
Mr. and Mrs. J. D. Preston and
Lu visited at George Van Horn’s, on
Tuesday.
Mr. and Mrs. Marvin Johnson spent
Wednesday at Asa Fox’, helping with
wood sawers.
Mr. and Mrs. Herbert Sukopp of
Hixton, spent Saturday evening at F.
W. Loasching’s.
Ralph Erickson o f Hixton, was a
caller at the Albert Campbell home
Sunday evening.
Ralph Erickson o f Hixton, was a
caller at the Albert Campbell home
uSnday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. F. W. Loasching
spent Saturday evening with Mr. and
Mrs. H. A. Sukopp.
Mrs. J. D. Preston and daughter
Lu were callers at the Mrs. Rose
Stolts home Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Marvin Johnson, Mr.
and Mrs. Asa Fox spent Thursday
evening at Arthur Bills’.
Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Amundson
of Northfield, spent Thursday evening
at Arthur Melby’s.
Elling Ellingson and son Arnold of
Osseo, visited at the J. D. Preston
home Tuesday afternoon.
John and Lu Preston attended the
Taylor,Independence basket ball game
at Taylor, Thursday evening.
Mrs. Harland Duxbury and daugh
ter Twila, and Willard Johnson spent
Saturday evening at Marvin Johnson’s.
Mrs. Eli Lyons fell on the ice in
the yard at her home Sunday. No
bones were broken but she was quite
badly bruised.
Lucile Skutley, who has employment
at Eau Claire, spent the week
end at the home o f her parents, Mr.
and Mrs. AndrewSkutley.
A number o f young people from
here attended the Hanson-Skutley
wedding dance at York Saturday evening.
All report a fine time.
Mr. and Mrs. Theo. Nelson and
Genevieve, and Mr. and Mrs. Martin
Ryerson and family spent Wednesday
evening at the Oluf Hagen home.
Evelyn Iverson, Althea Beatty,
Mrs. Hans Nelson, Mr. and Mrs. Andy
Larson, Agnes Campbell and Edgar
Sukopp attended a wedding
dance at Blair, Saturday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. H. A. Sukopp and
son Edgar, and Robert, and Mr. and
Mrs. Andy Larson were supper guests
at the Albert Campbell home Sunday.
Martin Jacobs was a caller there in
the evening.
The Sechlerville Home Makers club
met with Mrs. Oluf Hagen Friday afternoon
as the leaders had no new
work to demonstrate carpet rags were
sewed for Mrs. Hagen. A good time
was enjoyed by all and a fine lunch
was served by the hostess.
Harold Hakes o f Northfield, skidded
on the icy roads near the bridge
at Secrlerville Sunday evening. His
car left the road and went over the
embankment, tipping over on its side.
Fortunately no one was hurt and the
car was only slightly damaged.
John Preston accompanied his Boy
Scouts to La Crosse Saturday to
swim at the Central High school
swimming pool. On his way home
he visited the Henry Olson home at
Trempealeau. Mr. Olson was a former
principle o f the Taylor schools.
G ARD EN V A L L E Y
George Sherwood spent Monday at
Frank Ringrose’s.
John Gansel was a business caller
in your city Monday.
Edward Iverson was a caller at
Phil Dunn’s, Tuesday.
Fred Newton and Mr. Nelson were
callers at Steve Tichy’s, Friday.
George Ringrose o f your city, was
a caller in the valley last Tuesday.
Mrs. Vance Enerson spent the
week end at her home in Alma Center.
T
he neighbors had a shower for
Mrs. Harvey Harmon, last Wednesday.
Mrs. John Gansel and Mrs. H.
White were callers in your city Friday.
C
lifford Hanson spent the week end
with his parents from his work at
Waumandee.
Francis Pattridge o f Whitehall,
spent the week end with his mother,
Mr3. Charles Pattridge.
Mrs. John Gansel spent Monday
evening with Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Dahl
in West Garden Valley.
Louie Kelsh o f Milwaukee, and Irvin
Kelsh o f Humbird called in the
valley Saturday afternoon.
Walter Gorkowski went to Cleveland
Thursday evening to help his
cousin for a few days with his work.
Martin and Georgie Atkinson o f
Alma Centre, spent the week end
with their grandmother, Mrs. H.
White.
Miss Ellen Larson and mother, Mrs.
B. O. Larson o f West Garden Valley
spent Sunday with Mr. and Mrs. Edward
Hanson.
Mrs. John Gansel and son George
went to Stockton, Minn., Saturday,
to attend the funeral o f Mrs. Madermann.
Mrs. Borger returned home
with Mrs. Gansel.
SOUTH BE EF RIV ER
Louis Larson is helping Tom Loken
cut wood.
Carol Rindahl spent Tuesday evening
at Ioken’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Albin Person were
Sunday visitors at M. Westegard’s.
Roy Myhre and Roger Olson spent
Thursday evening at Norman Severson’s.
L. Jermstad and family were Sunday
evening visitors at Martin Jermstad’s.
Richards boys have been cutting
wood for Louie Larson and Sever
Pederson.
Mrs. K. Rindahl, Margaret and
Donald spent Sunday afternoon at S.
Pederson’s.
Olga Dahl, Georgie and Anton
Larson spent Wednesday evening at
Marvin Olson’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Louie Jacobson visited
at the Louie Larson home Sunday
afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Richards and Adeline
were dinner guests at the Clarence
Zank home at Augusta, Sunday.
F A L L COULIE
Archie Lindberg was at Arcadia on
Saturday.
Stanley Faldet spent Sunday with
home folks.
Daniel Simonson visited Sunday at
Selmer Faldet’s.
Miss Ethel Lien visited Friday until
Saturday at Henry Eide’s.
Mrs. Henry Eide and Ethel Lien
visited at Sever Eide’s, Saturday.
Mr. and Mrs. Christ Vildahl visited
Saturday evening at Oscar H off’s.
Mrs. Selmer Faldet and son Manuel
visited Thursday at Simon Faldet’s.
Mrs. Hellick Olson and daughter
Laura visited Tuesday at Henry
Eide’s.
Rev. E. B. Christopherson called
Thursday on Ole H off, who is not
very well.
Mrs. Marit Asegaard and Mr. and
Mrs. Gust Johnson visited Ole Hoff,
Wednesday.
Mrs. Lester Duxbury and children
visited a few days last week at her
home here.
Mr. and Mrs. Juel Nelson and family
were Sunday visitors at the Henry
Eide home.
Mr. and Mrs. Henry Eide and Bernice
Eide visited at Juel Nelson’s, on
Saturday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Amundson
and family visited Saturday evening
at Anton Thompson’s.
Mrs. Charles Holman and daughters,
Lucille and Thelma, visited at
Morris Faldet’s, Saturday.
Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Olstad and
Mrs. Christ Vindahl visited their
father, Ole H off, Tuesday.
Vernon Faldet o f Eau Claire, spent
the week end with his folks, Mr. and
Mrs. Selmer Faldet and family.
Misses Olga and Mayme Thompson
and Dorothy Fitzpatrick were visitors
Tuesday with Mrs. Inga Embretson.
M
artin Asegaard and daughters,
Mae and Muriel, and son Lester, and
Beatrice Hjornevik visited at Gust
Johnson’s, Sunday evening.
Orville Lindberg and Evelyn Bondeli
spent the week end at Melvin
Lindberg’s. Milton Schei and Malcolm
Faldet visited there Sunday.
There will be lenten services March
1st with Norwegian communion at
10 :30 o’clock, and on March 5th there
will be English service with communion.
Mrs. Selmer Faldet, Mr. and Mrs.
Tom Thompson and daughters, and
Miss Dorothy Fitzpatrick attended
Ladies Aid at the home o f Nygaard
Bros, and Melby on Friday.
Misses Hannah Lien and Marjorie
Johnson visited Saturday at the Tom
Thompson home. Miss Johnson and
Cassie Thompson were also brief visitors
with Mrs. Selmer Faldet.
SCH ERM ERHORN
Mr. and Mrs. Lewis Lundstad spent
Sunday at A. J. Lien’s.
Chas. Olson and Edwin Larson have
been quite ill o f grippe.
Mrs. John Magelee called on Mrs
Ringlien, Monday afternoon.
Newlyn Nelson and Lavore Olson
o f Whitehall, spent the week end at
the former’s home here.
Mr. and Mrs. Menick Ringlien visited
with Mr. and Mrs. Bill Rlilling
one evening last week.
Mr. and Mrs. Olger Koxlien and
son were called to Whitehall Sunday
by the illness o f the latter’s brother,
Franklin Sandbergen.
Our valentine party at the school
house Tuesday afternoon was well at
tended by the others and little tots.
A nice lunch was served and a short
program given by the pupils.
Home Makers meeting will be at
the Ringlien home Saturday afternoon
Feb. 25th. Mrs. Edwin Larson
is assisting hostess. As the delegates
have no lesson for this time, each one
bring their own work.
A shower was held for Mr. and
Mrs. Truman Skutley at the Hanson
home Sunday afternoon and attended
by nearly 100 friends and relatives.
They received a large amount
o f nice and useful articles.
Community club Friday evening
was not so largely attended as usual.
Servers for March are Martin Hagen,
Dokkestul and Hagenstad. W orkers
are Mrs. Alvin Halverson, Mrs.
Leonard Olson and Mrs. Joel Olson.
Mrs. Edwin Larson and Hazel
Fredrickson accompanied Mr. and
Mrs. Ernest Fredrickson to La Crosse
Friday to attend the funeral o f a
great-aunt. Mrs. Fredrickson returned
home after taking care o f her
aunt in her last illness.
Quite a few from here attended
Ladies Aid at the S. L. hall at Pigeon
Falls Wednesday. Mrs. John Gilbertson,
Ella Gilbertson and Mrs. Tom
Nelson were servers. Next Aid there
will be March 2, when we again have
servers from here, Mrs. Oluf Hagen,
Mrs. George Gilbertson and Mrs. Oliver
Hagen.
HALCYON
Mr. and Mrs. Roy Flood were at
Humbird, Saturday.
Mrs. Rose Sindelar visited Mrs.
Frances Jarolimek Sunday.
Miss Gwen Bunce spent the week
and with Miss Ruth Anderson.
Miss Beverly Bunce spent the week
end with friends in B. R. Falls.
Mr. and Mrs. W. Flood o f Humbird,
were supper guests at Oscar
Teenies’, Friday.
Mrs. J. Prusa and son Edward, o f
Hatfield, visited Mrs. Rose Sindelar
Thursday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. La Roy Bunce and
son attended a card party at Wm.
Duchow’s at Humbird, Saturday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. 0 . Erickson attended
a birthday party on Mrs. Fred
Sonnenberg at Melrose, Thursday
evening.
Mrs. Ed Matthews and Pearline,
Mrs. Guy Babcock. Mrs. D. Edwards
and Mrs.' Oscar Teeples visited school
Tuesday.
Our teacher. Ingwald Olson, gave
the pupils and eruests a fine treat of
a lovely cake decorated with hearts,
to suit the occasion. He also served
cookies and coolade. Some o f the ladies
brought in home made candy.
Each o f the children received numerous
valentines.
G ARFIE LD
Martin Lund was at Whitehall on
business last Friday.
W. B. Kitelinger, Nordahl Westegard
and Louis Jacobson had their
wood sawed recently.
Mildred Lund spent the week end
with her parents here and returned
to her duties at B. R. Falls, Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Hildor Hanson, Mr.
and Mrs. Storm Wilson and Mr. and
Mrs. Elmer Person were at Eau
Claire last Tuesday.
Mrs. Clara Rodell, Selmer Person,
Mr. and Mrs. Raymond Benz and Jr.,
Mr. and Mrs. W. B. Kitelinger and
La Verne spent Saturday evening at
the Elmer Person home.
Miss Lillian Lund returned Sunday
to her school duties at Pleasant Valley
near Melrose, after a forced vacation
o f a month, having undergone
an operation for appendicitis.
POLE G ROVE
Misses Ruth and Rilda Newell of
Osseo, spent Sunday at home.
Abel Knutson and son were business
callers in Mondovi Saturday.
Henry Lien is on the sick list. He
consulted doctors at the Krohn clinic
Tuesday.
Mr. and Mrs. Bud Newell attended
the Hanson-Skutley wedding dance
at York Saturday night.
Don’t forget the Pole Grove Sewing
Circle meets Thursday afternoon,
March 2, at Mrs. Harve Getman’s.
Ed Duerkop, Mrs. W. P. Duerkop
o f Hixton, and Ray Zhe o f Osseo,
were callers at Henry Lien’s, Saturday.
Mrs. Joe Hanson and children o f
Eleva, visited over the week end at
the home o f her parents, Mr. and
Mrs. S. A. Bue
Mr. and Mrs. Walter Duerkop and
sister, Miss Elsie Knutson attended
the Iverson-Beck wedding dance at
Blair Saturday night.
Miss Knutson and her pupils had
a valentine party at the school house
Friday afternoon. This was very
much enjoyed by the pupils.
Lewis Johnson had the misfortune
to lose his house with a chimney fire
Monday morning. Coming this time
o f the year it is surely a terrible loss.
He has our sympathy.
The following spent Sunday at Sever
Bue’s, and helped Mr. Bue celebrate
his 76th birthday: Mr. and
Mrs. Joe Hanson and children o f Eleva,
Mr. and Mrs. Angus Olson and
children, Mr. and Mrs. Adolph Olson
Mr. and Mrs. Nels Thompson o f
Blair, Sedolph Bue, John Haugen and
Mr. and Mrs. Silas Wallen o f Taylor
and we all join in wishing him many
more years o f happiness and health.
PR A Y
Bill Kling o f City Point, was a
Sunday caller at the Field home.
Henry Heiberg is visiting his sister,
Mrs. Oscar Loken and family at Taylor.
Mr. and Mrs. Florian Theil o f
Spaulding, spent Sunday at the Axel
Thiel home.
Bernice and Lyngaard Jepsen, ef
Wisconsin Rapids, spent Sunday at
their home here.
Mrs. Julius Kale underwent an appendectomy
at the Krohn clinic at B.
R. Falls. Saturday.
Mr. and Mrs. Martin Field attended
the funeral o f Mrs. Hubert Johnson
at B. R. Falls, Sunday.
Mrs. Marth Field and Edwin Field
spent Thursday evening at the Herbert
Jensen home at City Point.
James Churchill, who attended the
annual session o f Northern Wisconsin
Forest Rangers, at Tomahawk, returned
home Saturday.
Ray Nelson, who has been assisting
with the work at the Bert Han
cock home at Vesper during Mr.
Hancock’s illness, returned home on
Tuesday.
Mrs. Eva Hancock and son John
spent Sunday at the Clinton Hancock
home near B. R. Falls. They also
made the acquaintance o f their'little
granddaughter and niece, Janice Maren.
W E S T G ARDEN V A L L E Y
Little Janis Brager spent Saturday
with Margaret Dahl.
Alfred and Mathilda Dahl were
callers at Z. N. Nelson’s Saturday
evening.
Mrs. B. O. Larson is visiting her
daughter, Mrs. Edward Hanson for a
few days.
John Erickson o f Waumandee,
spent the week end with his mother
and sisters.
Mr. and Mrs. Louis Erickson were
callers at Z. N. Nelson’s, Wednesday
evening.
Ralph Erickson o f Hixton, and Anna
Erickson spent Wednesday evening
at Alfred Dahl’s.
Mrs. Ralph Erickson spent Thursday
with her parents, Mr. and Mrs.
Z. N. Nelson and Elmer.
Mrs. N. Thulin and Matilda Dahl
spent Friday afternoon with Mrs.
John Erickson and family.
Mr. and Mrs. Andrew Erickson and
Emil were dinner guests at the home
o f G. A. Erickson, Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Nels Thulin spent
Saturday evening with Mr. and Mrs.
Andrew Erickson and Emil.
Mr. and Mrs. Albert Hendrickson
and children spent Tuesday evening
with Alfred and Matilda Dahl.
Mrs. Aaron Brager and daughter
Janis, also Mrs. B. O. Larson spent
Friday afternoon at Louis Erickson’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Ralph Erickson o f
Hixton, Arthur and Anna Erickson
weer visitors at George Erickson’s,
Tuesday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Andrew Erickson,
Emma Larson and Oscar Jacobson attended
Ladies Aid at Melby and Nygaard’s,
Friday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. George Dahl, Mr.
and Mrs. Nels Thulin, Alfred and
Matilda Dahl, Mr. and Mrs. Louis Erickson
and Irene were dinner guests
at Will Ringrose’s, Sunday.
W. O. Larson o f Minneapolis, and
Herbert Lindblom o f Dassel, Minn.,
spent Thursday afternoon at Z. N.
Nelson’s and also conducted services
at the church in the evening.
SUNNY V A L E
Mrs. Joe Kostohryz called on Mrs.
John Garalius, Monday.
Mrs. Anna Schlegel called on Mrs.
Fred Cooper, Wednesday.
E. Shultz and family o f Neillsville
have rented the Julius Erickson farm.
Mr. and Mrs. John Garalius and
son were callers at B. R. Falls, Saturday.
The shower Wednesday at. the
home o f Mrs. Charles Kelner was well
attended. She received many pretty
gifts. The time was spent playing
games after which a fine lunch was
served.
NOTICE OF FORECLOSURE AND SALE
STATE O F W ISCONSIN, CIRCUIT COURT,
Jackson County
Federal Farm M ortg ag e C orporation, a b od y
C orporate, P la in tiff,
vs
Ciois L ouise Curran, also know n as C. L ou ise
Curran and Louise C u rra n ; and C.
Louise Curran as A dm inistratrix o f the
estate o f John A . Curran, d ecea sed ; and
R oger A. Curran, D efendants
By virtue o f a Judgm ent o f F oreclosure
and Sale made in tire a b ov e entitled action
on the 16th d a y o f February, 1938, the
undersigned Sheriff o f Jackson C ounty,
W iscon sin, will sell at the fro n t d o o r o f the
cou rt house in the city o f Black R iver
Falls, J ackson C ounty, W iscon sin, on the
7th day o f A pril, 1939, at ten o ’clock in
the foren oon o f that d a y, the real estate
and m ortgaged prem ises described by said
Judgm ent to be sold and therein described
as fo llo w s :
The southw est quarter (S W 4 ) and the
southw est quarter o f the northw est quarter
(SW 4 N W 4) Section tw en ty-fou r (2 4 ),
T ow nship tw en ty-tw o 22) N orth, R ange six
(6 ) w est, su bject to public highw ay through
said land as said highw ay is now located
and to easem ents o f record fo r transm ission
o f electricity heretofore given W isconsin-
M innesota L igh t and P ow er C om pany and
the N orthern States P ow er C om pany, co n tain
in g tw o hundred (2 0 0 ) acres, m ore or
less, Jackson cou n ty, W isconsin.
Dated February 21, 1939.
Term s o f Sale— Cash.
O L A F R. W ALD U M
Sheriff o f J ackson C ounty, W is.
DO N O VA N . GLEISS GOODM AN. A tto rneys
at Law,
Sparta, M onroe County, W is.
Feb. 22-M arch 29
NOTICE TO CREDITORS
STA TE OF W ISCONSIN, C OU N TY COURT,
J ackson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f Elizabeth
H ohn, deceased
Letters o f A dm inistration having been
issued to Steven Hohn in the estate o f
Elizabeth H ohn, deceased, late of the Tow n
o f Alm a, in said c o u n ty ;
N otice is hereby given th a t all claim s
against the said Elizabeth Hohn, deceased,
late o f the T ow n o f Alm a, in Jackson
cou nty, W isconsin, m ust be presented to
said cou n ty cou rt at Black R iver Falls, in
said cou n ty, on or b efore the 19th day of
June, 1939, o r be b a rred ; and that all such
claim s and dem ands will be exam ined and
adjusted at a term o f said cou rt to be
held at the cou rt house in the city o f Black
R iver Falls, in said cou nty, on Tuesday, the
20th day o f June, 1939, at 10 o ’ clock in the
foren oon o f said day.
Dated February 15th, 1939.
B y O rder o f the C ourt,
H A R R Y M PE R R Y . Judge
E. S. JED N EY . A ttorn ey
Feb. 22-M ar. 8
NOTICE OF APPLICATION FOR PROBATE
OF W IL L AND NOTICE TO CREDITORS
STA TE OF W ISCON SIN , COU N TY COURT,
Jackson C ounty
In the M atter o f the E state o f M ary W al
den. Deceased
N otice is hereby given that at a term
o f said C ourt to be held on Tuesday, the
14th day o f M arch. 1939, at 10 o ’clock in
the foren oon o f said d ay, at the court house
in the city o f Black R iver Falls, in .= aid
cou n ty, there will be heard and considered
The application o f In g ob er Hubbard and
Tillie W alden Johnson fo r the p robate of
the W ill o f M ary W alden, deceased, and
fo r the appointm ent o f an executor or a d m
in istrator with the will annexed o f the
estate o f said M ary W alden, deceased, late
o f the city o f B lack R iver Falls, in said
c o u n ty ;
N otice is fu rth er given that all claim s
against the said M ary W alden, deceased,
late o f the city o f Black R iver Falls, in
Jackson C ounty, W iscon sin, m ust be presented
to said cou nty cou rt at B lack R iver
Falls, in said county, on o r b efore the 19th
day o f June. 1939, or be b arred ; and that
all such claims and dem ands will be ex
am ined and adjusted at a term o f said
cou rt to be held at the cou rt house in the
city o f Black R iver Falls, in said county,
on T uesday, the 20th day o f June, 1939,
at 10 o ’clock in the foren oon of said day,
Dated February 11th, 1939.
B y O rder o f the Court,
H A R R Y M. PE R R Y . Judge
E. S. JE D N E Y . Black R iver Falls. W is
E. S. JE D N E Y , A ttorn ey,
Black R iver Falls, W iscon sin.
Feb. 1 5 -Mar 1
Mr. and Mrs. William Casper and
family spent Sunday evening with
Mr. and Mrs. R. Bue.
Mr. and Mrs. Mose Castona and
family and Mrs. Frank Staech o f
Dancy, spent Sunday with their children,
Mr. and Mrs. Roy Staeck.
Mr. and Mrs. Wililam Ghode entertained
several friends Saturday evening.
The time was spent playing
cards, Chinese checkers and dancing.
The next meeting o f Home Makers
will be March 1 at Mrs. Peter
Held’s. If you have thread to be
waxed please bring it with you. Don’t
forget your household hint or recipe.
The Home Makers club had an
oyster stew at Henry Edward’s home
at Alma Center Tuesday evening. The
evening was spent playing progress
500. Nearly all the members and
their husbands were there, and every
one had a splendid time.
SOUTH ALM A
Mrs. R. Bue has been on the sick
list the past week.
Francis Ludeman was a business
caller at B. R. Falls, Thursday.
Mrs. Roy Staeck spent Tuesday
with Mr. and Mrs. George Gee and
family.
Miss Betty Phillips o f Merrillan,
spent the week end with Miss Florence
Ghode.
Mr. and Mrs. Wm. Ghode spent
Sunday with Mr. and Mrs. Ed Bue, o f
Oak Grove.
Mr. and Mrs. La Verne Scafe o f
B. R. Falls, spent Friday evening at
Arthur Collum’s.
NOTICE OF HEARING ON FINAL SETTLEMENT
AND DETERMINATING OF
INHERITANCE TAX
STA TE O F W ISCON SIN . C OU N TY COURT.
Jackson C ounty
In the M atter o f the E state o f P eter C ollins,
deceased
N otice is hereby given that at a term o f
said cou rt to be held on Tuesday, the 14th
d a y o f M arch, 1939, at 10 o ’clock in the
foren oon of said day, at the cou rt house
in the city o f Black R iv er Falls, in said
cou n ty, there will be beard and considered
The application o f B. L. V an Gorden, adm
in istrator o f the estate o f P eter Collins,
deceased, late o f the tow n o f Curran, in
said cou n ty, fo r the exam ination and allow ance
o f his final accou nt, w hich a ccou n t is
n ow on file in said cou rt, and fo r the allow
ance o f debts or claim s paid in good
faith w ithout filin g or allow an ce as re
quired by law, and fo r the assignm ent of
the residue o f the estate o f said deceased
to such persons as are by law entitled
th e re to ; and fo r the determ ination and adju
d ication o f the inheritance tax, if any,
payable in said estate.
Dated February 11, 1939.
B y O rder o f the Court,
H A R R Y M PE R R Y , Judge
D. M. PE R R Y , A ttorn ey
Feb. 1 5 -Mar 1
NOTICE OF HEARING APPLICATION FOR
ADMINISTRATION AND NOTICE TO
CREDITORS
S T A T E O F W ISCONSIN. C OU N TY COURT,
J ackson County
In th e M atter o f the E state o f A lbert
Casper, deceased
N otice is hereby given that a t a term o f
said cou rt to be held on T uesday, the 7th
day o f M arch, 1939, at 10 o ’clock on the
foren oon o f said d ay, at the cou rt house
in the city o f Black R iver Falls, in said
cou n ty, there will be heard and considered
The application o f W illiam Casper fo r the
appointm ent o f an adm inistrator o f the
estate o f A lb ert Casper, deceased, late of
the Tow n o f Alm a, in said co u n ty ;
N otice is fu rth er given that all claim s
against the said A lbert Casper deceased, late
e f the Tow n o f A lm a, in Jackson county,
W isconsin, m ust be presented to said county
cou rt at Black R iver Falls, in said county,
on or b efore the 12th day o f June, 1939, or
be b a r re d ; and that all such* claim s and
dem ands will be exam ined and adjusted at
a term o f said cou rt to be held at the
cou rt house in the city o f Black R iver Falls
in said cou n ty, on Tuesday, the 13th o f
June, 1939, a t 10 o ’clock in th e foren oon
o f said day.
Dated February 3, 1989.
By Order o f the Court,
H A R R Y M. PE R R Y , Judge
D. M. P E R R Y , A ttorn ey
Feb. 8-22
NOTICE OF APPLICATION FOR PROBATE
OF W IL L AND NOTICE TO CREDITOR
S T A T E O F W ISCON SIN , C OU N TY COURT,
Jackson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f Bernt T
B erntson, deceased
N otice is hereby given th at a t a term
o f said cou rt to be held on T uesday, the
7th d a y o f M arch, 1939, at 10 o ’clock in
the foren oon o f said day, at the cou rt house
in the city o f Black R iver Falls in said
cou nty, there will be heard and considered
T h e application o f Nels O. Berntson for
the prob a te o f the will o f B ernt T. Bernt
son, deceased, and fo r th e appointm ent of
an execu tor or adm inistrator w ith the will
annexed o f th eestate o f said B ernt T
Berntson, deceased, late o f the V illage o f
T aylor, in said co u n ty ;
N otice is fu rth er given that all claims
against the said Bernt T. Berntson, deceased,
late o f the village o f T aylor, in Jackson
cou n ty, W iscon sin, m ust be presented to
said cou n ty cou rt at Black R iver Falls, in
said cou n ty, on or b efore the 12th day of
June, 1939, or be b arred ; and that all such
claim s and dem ands will be exam ined and
adjusted at a term o f said cou rt to be held
a t the cou rt house in the city o f Black
R iver Falls, in said cou n ty, on Tuesday,
the 13th day o f June, 1939, at 10 o ’clock
in the foren oon of said day.
Dated February 3, 1939.
B y Order o f the Court,
H A R R Y M. PE R R Y . Judge
D. M. PE R R Y , A ttorn ey
Feb. 8-22
NOTICE OF APPLICATION FOR PROBATE
OF W IL L AND NOTICE TO CREDITORS
STATE OF WISCONSIN, COUNTY COURT.
J ackson County
In the M atter o f the Estate o f Alex T hom pson,
deceased.
N otice is hereby given that at a term o f
said cou rt to be held on Tuesday, the
7th day o f M arch, 1939, at 10 o ’clock in
the foren oon o f said day, at the cou rt house
In the city o f Black R iver Falls, in said
cou nty, there will be heard and con sid ered :
T h e application o f M artin Thom pson,
T h eod ore T hom pson and Stella Larson fo r
the p rob a te o f the will o f A lex Thom pson,
deceased, and fo r the appointm ent o f an
executor or adm inistrator with the will annexed
o f the estate o f said A lex Thom pson,
deceased, late o f the Tow n o f N orthfield,
in said co u n ty ;
N otice is fu rth er given that all claim s
against the said A lex T hom pson , deceased,
late o f the tow n o f N orthfield, in Jackson
cou n ty, W isconsin, m ust be presented to
said cou n ty cou rt at Black R iver Falls in
said cou nty, on or before the 12th day o f
June, 1939, o r be b a rred ; and that all such
claim s and dem ands will be exam ined and
adjusted at a term of said cou rt to be held
at the cou rt house in the city o f Black
R iver Falls, in said cou n ty, on Tuesday,
the 13th d a y o f June, 1939, at 10 o ’clock
in the foren oon o f said day.
D ated February 6th, 1939.
B y Order o f the C ourt,
H A R R Y M. P E R R Y , Judge
R A L P H S. LU N D , A ttorn ey
Feb. 8-22
NOTICE OF SALE
S TA TE OF W ISCON SIN . C OU N TY OF
Jackson— In Circuit C ourt
Frank J. Benish and John H. Benisb, P la in tiffs.
vs
A lm a Sieger, Defendant.
By virtue o f a Judgm ent o f P artition and
Sale m ade in the a bov e entitled action , on
the 15th d a y o f D ecem ber, 1938. the un dersigned.
will sell at the fro n t d oor o f the
cou rt house in the city o f Black R iver Falls,
J ackson county. W iscon sin, on the 3rd day
o f M arch, 1939, at ten o ’clock in the fo re noon
o f that day, the real estate directed
by said judgm ent t o be sold, and therein
described as fo llo w s: The south east quarter
of tb » south ea r; quarter of section th irteen,
except railroad rig h t-of-w a y and the
north one-h alf o f section tw en ty -fou r, all in
Tow nship tw en ty-fou r, north, range five
w e«t, except railroad rig h t-o f-w a y acrost
the north east cerner o f the north east
quarter o f the north ea st quarter and excep
t highw ay rig h t-o f-w a y and except five
acres in the north east corner o f the south
east quarter o f the north east quarter,
described as fo llo w s: Com m encing at the
north east corner o f said fo rty , thence running
w est fo r t y ro d s ; thence south twenty
rod s: thence east forty rod s; thence north
tw enty rods to the place o f beginning, a*
described in 47 o f Deeds on page 267.
Term s o f Sale— Cash.
Dated January 17, 19 39.
GEORGE H. DETTIN GER. Referee
D. M. PE R R Y . P la in tiff's A ttorn ey.
Black R iver Falls. W isconsin.
Jan. 18-Feb. 22
NOTICE TO CREDITORS
S T A T E OF W ISCON SIN , C OU N TY COURT.
Jackson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f E unice
Bowlen, deceased
Letters o f A dm inistration havin g been
issued to Lida Sprester in the estate o f
E unice Bowlen, deceased, late o f the city
o f B lack R iver Falls, in said c o u n ty ;
N otice is hereby given that all claim s
against the said Eunice Bowlen, deceased,
late o f the city o f Black R iver Falls, W is consin,
in J ackson cou nty, W iscon sin, m ust
be presented to said cou nty cou rt a t Black
R iver Falls, in said cou nty, on or before
the 12th day o f June, 1939, or be b a rred ;
and th at all such claim s and dem ands will
be exam ined and adjusted at a term o f said
court to be beld at the cou rt house in the
city o f Black R iver Falls, in said county,
on T uesday, the 13th day o f June. 1939,
at 10 o ’clock in the foren oon o f said day.
D ated February 7th, 1939.
By Order o f the Court,
H A R R Y M. P E R R Y , Judge
Feb. 8-22
NOTICE OF FORECLOSURE AND SALE
STA TE O F W ISCONSIN, CIRCU IT COURT.
Jackson County
Federal Farm M ertgage C orporation, a body
C orporate, P la in tiff,
vs
A lb ert H anson and M am ie H anson, his
w ife. D efendants.
By virtu e o f a Judgm ent o f F oreclosure
and Sale m ade in the a bov e entitled action
on the 19th day o f January, 1938, the undersigned
sheriff o f Jackson cou n ty, W isconsin,
will sell at the fron t d oor o f the
Court H ouse in the City o f B lack R iver
Falls, Jackson C ounty, W iscon sin, on the
10th day o f M arch. 1939, at eleven o ’clock
in the foren oon o f th a t day, the real estate
and m ortga ged prem ises described by said
judgm ent to be sold and therein described
as fo llo w s :
W est on e-h alf ( W ) o f the N ortheast
quarter (N E 4) o f Section tw enty-n ine
(2 9 ), T ow n sh ip tw en ty-th ree (2 3 ) N orth,
R ange fiv e (5 ) W est, J ackson C ounty, W isconsin.
Dated January 28, 1939.
O. R. W A LD U M .
Sheriff, Jackson C ounty. W is.
DO N O VAN , GLEISS GOODM AN, A ttys.
Sparta, M onroe County, W isconsin
Jan. 25-M ar. 1
NOTICE OF FORECLOSURE AND SALE
STA TE O F W ISCON SIN , C IRCU IT COURT,
Jackson County
The Federal Land Bank o f Saint Paul, a
body C orporate, P la in tiff,
vs
A nton L a rs o n ; M arvin O ls e n ; Mrs. Marvin
Olson, his w ife ; and the Osseo N ational
Farm Loan A ssocia tion , a C orporation,
D efendants.
By virtue o f a Judgm ent o f F oreclosure
and Sale m ade in the a bove entitled action
on the 19th day o f January, 1938, the undersigned
S heriff o f Jackson C ounty, W isconsin,
will sell at the fro n t d oor o f the
Court House, in the city o f Black R iver
Falls, Jackson cou nty, W iscon sin, on the
10th day o f M arch, 1939, at ten o ’clock in
the foren oon o f th at day, the real estate
and m ortgaged prem ises described by said
Judgm ent to be sold and therein described
as fo llo w s:
South h alf o f the Southeast quarter (S 
SE *4) o f Section th irty-th ree (3 3 ), T ow n ship
T w en ty -fou r (2 4 ), N ortb R ange six
(6 ) W est, and the N orth h alf o f the N orth east
Quarter (N N E *4 ) o f Section fo u r
(4 ), Tow nship T w en ty-th ree (2 3 ) N orth,
Range six ( 6 ) , W est, con taining one hundred
sixty (1 6 0 ) acres, m ore o r less, a ccordin
g to the G overnm ent survey thereof,
Jackson C ounty, W isconsin.
Dated January 23, 1939.
Term s o f Sale— Cash.
O. R. W A LD U M
S heriff, Jackson C ounty, W is.
DO N O VAN . GLEISS GOODM AN. A ttys.,
Sparta, M onroe C ounty, W isconsin
Jan. 25-M ar. 1
DR. M. A. FOSTER
Optometrist
EYES EXAM IN ED —
GLASSES FITTED
O ffice Over Zimmerman'* Store
Phone Red 126, Neillsville, W it.
C. W . REIELS
Painting and Decorating
Phone 21 7-Black
823 Tyler St., Black River Fall*
DR. CA RL PFLAN Z
D EN TIST
O ffice* in Rozmeno*ki Bldg.
Phone 301 Black River Fall*
BLACK R IV E R LODGE NO. 74
F. A A. M.
Meeting* 2nd and 4 th Thursday
o f each month. Viaitor* W elcom e
R. C. GEBHARDT
DENTIST
First Door E u t of Court Hooa*
Slack River Fall*, Wisconsin
DR. MYRON MOEN
DENTIST
Office Over Post Office
Black River Falls, Wisconsin
PAG ENO. 10 THE BANNER-JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin W ednesday, February 22, 1939
NORTH SOUTH ALMA
Mrs. Albert Jacobson entertained
the card club at her home Friday
evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Sidney Farrington o f
La Crosse, called at the Clarence
Keach home and with Mrs. Lilly Farrington,
Monday.
Mrs. Geo. Galster, Ruth Ann, and
Wendell visited over the week end at
the Orville Nyman home at Orfordville.
Mrs. Geo. Galster and Ruth
Ann will remain for a longer visit.
Mrs. Henry Edwards o f Alma Center,
entertained the South Alma
Home Makers club and their husbands
at a card party and oyster supper
Tuesday evening.
Peter Held attended the funeral o f
Peter Werner, in Slinger, Saturday.
South Alma Home Makers club will
meet with Mrs. Peter Held, March 1.
Each member must respond with a
household hint for roll call.
W A N T ADS
H OU SE A N D LOTS FOR S A L E — Inquire o f
M RS. A N N A K LE V EN . C ity. lw p
FO R SALE — Used shoe m achine. May be
seen at H A N COCK'S H A R D W A R E , Black
R iver Falls, W is. lw
FOR SALE — Guernsey bull o f serviceable
a ge from an accredited herd. OSCAR
EIDE, H ixton, W is. lw p
BULLS FOR SA LE — One Guernsey short
tw o years, one H olstein 14 m onths. H.
GJERSETH, Tel. 36 R16, City. lw p
W O R K W A N T E D — Married man wants work
on farm by the m onth or year. C L A R ENCE
Y A H N K E . Stoddard. W is. lw p
TE AM FOR SALE — Mare with foa l and a
4 -yea r-old horse. JOH N A SK E, R oute 2,
H ixton , W is. *WP
FOR SALE— Baled hay and straw . W ill
sell on farm or deliver. P hone 69 R13.
FR AN K S AV E RD A. Melrose, W is. 9-2p
W A N T TO BUY— A violin. Give m ake.
con dition and description o f violin and
bow . W rite B an ner-Joum al office. 6-4p
Taystee
B I ( e A d
WHAT BREAD
DID I TELL
YOU TO GET ?
FOR FRESHER BREAD BUY TAY5TEE BREflD
W ISH TO R EN T— Fully equipped farm . In quire
Banner-Journal lw p
FOR SA L E — Show case and Quaker oil b u rner.
Inquire B-J.
FOR SALE— One g o o d w ork horse about
1500 pounds. One brood sow due first
o f April. A lso a few feed er pigs. O R V ILLE
SIMONSON, R. 1. B ox 8. H ixton, W is. Ip
W A N T E D — Man to sell Baker P rod u cts in
established local territory. N o cash investm
ent. Car needed. For in form a tion
w rite S. F. B AK ER CO.. K eokuk. Ia. 6-3p
STORE FOR REN T— In p rosperous fa rm ing
com m unity. General or va riety store
needed. Address B A N N E R -JO U R N A L. B. R.
Falls, W is. _____________________________ lw p
NOTICE— Buy it in b u lk ; A pples, Oranges,
Bagas, Onions, N orthern grow n p o tatoes
o f very fine quality. A R T U PTON ,
B. R. Falls, W is. lw p
W A N T E D — Single man to w ork on farm
b y the month*. P hon e 22 R 2, JAM ES
K L IR farm , B. R. Falls, or inquire at FED.
CO-OP. O IL CO., City._____________________lw p
FOR SALE— A lfa lfa hay, oats, ear corn
barley, and tim othy hay. T elephone H ixton
39. TH E CHAS. SECHLER EST., Sechlerville.
W is. _______________ lw
FO R SA L E — 120 acre farm on County
Trunk P. F or cash o r w ill trade fo r
p roperty in tow n as part paym ent. Inquire
a t B anner-Journal. lw p
N O W IS T H E TIM 7— T o place you r orders
fo r U. S. Certified chicks. Som e one will
be at the hatchery at all tim es. P hone 278.
IL IF F ’S H A TC H E R Y, B lack R iver Falls.
W is. 8 -tf
W A N T E D — Girl o ver 18 years old o r an
older w om an fo r general house w ork.
M ust be experienced. Call telephone N o.
259-J or w rite BOX E, Black R iver Falls.
W is._______________________________________ lw
FOR SALE— One 7-tu be P h ilco radio (new
batteries). One organ in good con dition.
T w o N ever-F ail incubators, 600 and
300 egg size. W ill trade the above for
w ood or anything I can use. GUST T W ETE ,
T aylor, W is.__________________________ 7-2wp
LA CROSSE REN DERING W O R K S— R em
oves dead or disabled anim als free and
prom ptly. Call Genther’s Service Station
Black R iver Falls, P hone 58, or W m . Steinbring,
No. 3, at H ixton. R everse all phone
calls. 4 6 -tf
SALESM AN W A N T E D — F or Black R iver
Falls and vicinity. I f you want to make
m oney and willing to w ork, w rite SALES
MANAGER, 119 Lake St.. Eau Claire.
W is. lw p
AUCTION S— I f you are planning on having
a sale I would be glad to talk it
over by phone at m y expense or write
you. E fficiency. C ourtesy. Satisfaction.
H A R R Y G. W IL L E Y , A uctioneer, Phone
7744, Sparta, W is. 7-4wp
S T R A W B E R R Y P L A N T S — W ell rooted straw
berry plants— Beavers $4.00 per th ou sand,
65 cents per hundred; Prem iers $5.00
per thousand. 75 cents per hundred. Discou
nt on large orders. P lace your orders
early. R E L Y E A D A H L IA GARDENS, T a y lor,
Wia. 8 -tf
FOR SALE— Used tractors 10-20 M cCorm
ick Deerings, Fordsons, Case. Silo fillers.
Some fine horses and cattle. A lso
10 roll M cCorm ick Deering corn shredder. |
ERICKSON IM PLEM EN T CO., Melrose, W is
Case and Allis-Chalm ers Dealers. 42-tf
FOR S A L E OR TR A D E — New and used
m achinery and tra ctors on hand. 3 horses,
9 tractors, 8 tractor plow s. 5 horse plows,
w agon, water tank, m ilking m achine, canary
grass seed, seed oats, 1000 posts, 4 springer
heifers. M assey-H arris dealer. A DAM
ST A T Z , A lm a Center, W is. 6 -tf
LOAN S TO FARM ERS— B orrow ed at cost
when you borrow from the N EIL L SV IL L E
PRODU CTION CREDIT ASSOCIATION at
6 per cent interest. L ocal R epresen tative:
R. M. Horswill at cou rt house on Saturdays,
10 to 12 a. m. Helm er Gilbertson,
M elrose; W m . F. Curran, T aylor, W is.
Hundreds of Low Prices During A and P’s 80th
FOUNDERS WEEK
The week o f February 20th-25th marks the 80th Anniversary
o f the founding o f A P Food Stores. W e o ffe r these extra low
prices as part o f the big celebration! Stock up now— Prices are
lo w !
1 lb. can Cold Stream Pink SALMON .................... 1 0 c
Caught in northern waters and canned in nearby canneries.
1 lb. can Sultana RED SALMON.............. 1 Q C
Carefully packed and cooked— fresh from Alaskan waters.
Sunnyfield FLOUR, 49 lb. b ag.......... 99c Sunnyfield is a high quality all-purpose flour sold with a money
back guarantee.
44 oz. pkg. Cake Flour SWANSDOWN.............. 21c H ere’s a new low price which will be another big saving to you !
Pure Lard HORMEL’S ..... 4 lb. ctn. 3 3 c
Buy your requirements at this special price! Thursday, Friday
and Saturday on ly!
Fruits and Vegetables
Big Mac
Head Lettuce . .2 for 15c
Fancy
Winesap Apples 4 lbs. 25c
F resh
Ripe Tomatoes . .lb. 19c
California Na.vel 288 size
Oranges .........2 doz. 27c
Green Top
Carrots ........... per bch 5c
Texas
Grapefruit . . . .6 for 17c
Solid Head
Old Cabbage ......... lb. 2c
Florida Muckland
Celery .........................10c
Wslxed W isconsin
Rutabagas t ........... lb. 3c
5 ox. can* Salad
Shrimp . .2 cans 25c
1 lb. ja r Land O ’ Lakes
Honey ..................17c
44 oz. pkg. M cK en zie’ s M agic
Cake Flour ......... 19c
15 oz. pkgs. Sunnyfield
40 per cent
Bran Flakes 2 for 25c
W iscon sin B rick
Cheese ........... lb. 17c
2 lb. pkg. E xcel o r S u per
B akt Soda
Crackers ............. 13c
10 lb. can B lue L abel
Karo .................... 49c
20 oz. pkg. S unnyfield
Pancake
Flour .................... 5c
Q t. Btl. R ajah B lended
Syrup ..................27c
1 lb. pkg. N .B .C . R itz
Crackers ........... 21c
3*4 oz. pkgs. A nn P age
G elatin
Sparkle . . .3 for 10c
2 lb. ja r Sultana Peanut
Butter ..................22c
GOLD MEDAL
BISQUICK
40 OZ. PKG.
27c
D A ILY
DOG FOOD
16 OZ. CANS 6 cans 25c
RED H E A R T
DOG FOOD
Diets A, B, C. 16 oz. cans 3 cans 25c
Michigan Pea
Beans . . . . 10 lbs. 34c
8 oz. btl. Ann Page French
Dressing ............. 12c
20 oz. cans Iona Diced
Carrots . . 4 cans 25c
10 H oz. can Campbell’* asst.
Soups . . . .2 cans 19c
14 H oz. cans W hite House
Milk . . . . 4 cans 22c
20 oz. cans Ann Page Apple
Sauce . . . .2 cans 15c
1 lb. pkgs. Encore Medium
Egg Noodles 2 for 25c
24 oz. pkgs. Marvin unpitted
Dates ..................21c
500 sheet pkg. Fastidia
Cleansing
Tissue ..................19c
2 lb. pkg. Domino
Loaf Sugar ......... 20c
1 pt. can Rajah
Salad Oil ........... 22c
36 oz. pkg. Linit
Starch ..................27c
d p U P U P 'GO SALES
If you have been paying I0C or A A l l
more for bread you can now O A V E 25n THE N EW FAVO RITE IN
SO FT-AS-O LD LINEN
SC0TTISSUE
3 rolls 20c
DOUBLE WRAPPED
TO HOLD ITS FRESHNESS
Fine Granulated Beet
S U G A R
1 0 lbs. 5 0 C
A and P Donuts
per doz. I Q c
TEM-TING
ASPARAGUS
All Green Cuts and Tips
15oz.can 15c
A P F o o d S t o r e s . mm ■ — V I D O L 0 A ' t S T E R N D I V I S I O N . ■ ■
Owned and operated by The Great Atlantic P acific Tea Co.
FOR SALE— 100 b ig ty p e Legh orn laying
h en s; kitchen range, good con d ition ; V ictor
C onsole victrola w ith 100 records. Farm
tools including shop tools, axes, saws, horse
shoeing ou tfit, etc. C abinet; 3 ta b les; M odel
T Ford. A t a bargain. Must be tak en
b efore Feb. 26. LE STE R E. FRIED ,
A lm a Center, W is., c -o F. P om roy farm
7-2w p
C L A IR SM ALE— General auctioneer. I will
secure a finance corporation to handle
y o u r sale and advertising or will cooperate
w ith any local bank o r sales agency. Let
a man sell you r property who know s livestock
and m achinery. S atisfaction gu aranteed.
N o sale too large or to o small.
F or sale dates or in form a tion call DR. F.
E. S ILL IC K , N eillsville, a t m y expense.
C L A IR SM A LE. 8-2p
W A N T E D A T ONCE— T w o experienced
salesm en with ca r fo r selling baby chicks,
equipm ent, b rood er, laying, hog, and tennant
houses, small hom es, cottages, garages,
tou rist cabins, etc. Can sell all buildings
on F H A loans w ith 10 per cent dow n.
Steady year around w ork w ith chance fo r
p rom otion . G ood pay. R eferences and small
cash bond required. W rite o r apply in
person evenings or Saturdays. GLEN W A D D
E L L , A blem an, W is., located 2 miles out
o f A blem an tow ard R eedsburg on H y. 136
8-2w
A U C TIO N SALE — F or Best R ESU LTS and
the M ost $$$ call F. J. BO W M A N . Black
R iv er Falls, W is., w ith 25 Y ears E xperience
C onducting over 2000 SALES in 8 states
and in 25 counties in W iscon sin. Satisfied
Custom ers Built This Business. The Leading
Farm ers, Stock Men, Business Men, and
H ORSE D E A LE R S are M y P atrons. My
R eferences are the Thousands o f P eople
fo r W hom and T o W hom I have SOLD.
M ay I be o f S ervice to Y o u ? S atisfaction
Guaranteed o r N o Charges. N o P lace T oo
Far. N o Sale T o o L arge o r T o o Small.
T he Best Sales on R ecord to My Credit.
W hen B etter Sales are M ade, BO W M A N
w ill M ake Them . I C o-O perate with any
Clerk, Bank, or Finance C orporation. A r range
E arly fo r DATES. W rite o r W ire
at M y Expense. lw
N OTICE OF H E AR IN G A P P L IC A T IO N FOR
A D M IN ISTR A TIO N A N D NOTICE TO
C REDITO RS
In the M atter o f the E state of Carrie G.
P op e, deceased f
N otice is hereby given that a t a term o f
said cou rt to be held on Tuesday, the 21st
day o f M arch, 1939, a t 10 o ’clock in the
SPECIAL SALE
THURSDAY, FRIDAY, SATURDAY FEBRUARY 23, 24, 25, 1939
CORN . ton lot $19.00
5 ton Truck Loads —
No. 4 Corn . .ton $17.50
No. 2 Corn . .ton $18.00
Dairy Queen Flour
49 lb. sack ........... $1.39
(The Best Flour M illed)
FREE your choice o f a Knife,
Fork, table spoon or tea spoon.
Soy Bean Meal
44 per cent Protein
Ton lots ........... $29.00
Sack lots ............. $1.50
This is the best Soy Bean Meal
you can buy
MOTOR OIL
5 gal. lots . . . . gal. 35c
1 gal. lots ................40c
2 gal. can Motor Oil
including can . . . .89c
HYBRID SEED CORN
T racy’s Hybrid Seed Corn
95-100 or 105 day Flats
per bushel ........... $6.50
95-100 or 105 day Round
per bushel ........... $5.00
Thom pson’s Hybrid Corn
per bushel ........... $6.00
Place Y our Order Now
EGG MASH
100 lb. b a g ........... $1.69
DAIRY FEED
100 lb. b a g ........... $1.05
Ton lots ........... $20.00
PLACE YOUR ORDER
NOW WITH US FOR
GRASS SEEDS
W e have special prices until
March 1st. W e have some real
buys
SALT . . . .100 lbs. 79c
This is clean granulated salt.
MINERAL 100 lb. $2.25
This is an all purpose Mineral.
M AYTAG WASHING
MACHINES
W e have a few machines left
that we are closing out
2 Rd. Tub Maytag Elec $49.50
4 Round Tub Maytag Twin
Engine ----------------------- $59.50
1 Aluminum Tub Maytag
Demonstrator Electric $49.50
1 Aluminum Tub Used
Machine ____________ $33.50
1 Single Cylinder M otor $6.95
2 Twin Cylinder M otors $15.00
These are priced to sell. W e
must move them. W e will finance
any o f these machines.
SWEET SUE FLOUR
98 lb. b a g ...........$2.10
49 lb. b a g ...........$1.09
2 4 lb. b a g ...........63c
(E very sack Guaranteed)
Ground Corn Oats
Contains about o f each
Ton Lots ........... $20.00
Sacks extra
Ground Corn Feed Meal
Ton Lots ........... $17.00
Sack lots ............. $1.00
Sacks extra
MEAT SCRAPS
100 lb. b a g ...........$2.79
TANKAGE
100 lb. b a g ........... $2.79
FERTILIZER
Prices are less this year so place
your order with us now. W e
make our own and know what
is in it. It contains 5 different
forms o f nitrogen which gives
your plant a start at 5 different
intervals. Our fertilizer has a
lime base. W hy buy sand?
H. H. VAN GORDEN SONS
BLACK RIVER FALLS
foren oon o f said day, at the court house
in the city o f .B la ck R iver Falls, in said
cou n ty, there be Jieard and con sid ered ;
The application o f Ellis H orsw ill fo r the
appointm ent o f an ad m inistrator o f the estate
o f Carrie G. Pope, deceased, late o f the
city o f B lack R iver Falls, in said C o u n ty ;
N otice is furth er given that all claim s
against the said Carrie G. P ope, deceased,
late o f the city o f Black R iver Falls, in
Jackson cou n ty, W iscon sin, m ust be presented
to said cou n ty cou rt at the cou rt
house in said cou n ty on or b efore the 26th
day o f June, 1939, or be b a rred ; and that
all such claim s and dem ands w ill be exam ined
and adjusted at a term o f said cou rt
to be held at the cou rt house in th e city
o f B lack R iver Falls, in said cou n ty, on
T uesday, the 27th o f June, 1939, at 10 o ’clock
in the foren oon o f said day.
Dated February 14, 1939.
By Order o f the Court,
H A R R Y M. PE R R Y . Judge
H A N S H ANSON , A ttorn ey for the Estate.
Black R iver Falls, W is.
Feb. 22-M arch 8
2 Deliveries Daily Phone No. 216
Waughtal's
Sugar ...............1 0 lb. bag 4 5 c
Raisins . ...................................................4 lb. pkg. 25c
Golden Crust Bread, IV2 lb. loaf 7 c
Mustard, quart jar ............................................... .... .9c
Deerwood Golden Syrup ............. .. 10 lb. pail 41c
Oatmeal, 42 oz. pkg.......................................... 2 for 25c
Peaberry Coffee .............................................3 lbs. 37c
Macaroni or Spaghetti .................... .. .5 lb. box 22c
Sweetheart Toilet Soap. . . . 3 for 19c and 1 for lc
Corn, 20 oz. cans ...............................................4 for 25c
Golden Yellow Bananas 4 lbs. 1 9 c
Lettuce, 5 doz. size ................................. per head 5c
Cabbage, nice solid heads .........................10 lbs. 15c
Rutabagas ..................................................... 10 lbs. 13c
Oranges, 288 size .......................................... 2 doz. 23c
Prices Slashed on Flannel Shirts
89c values going at ................................................... 49c
$1.25 values going at ...............................................99c
$1.98 values going at .......................................... $1.49
Mince Meat ............ 2 lbs. 2 5 c
Oysters, direct from the coast .................... per qt. 39c
Cut Lunch H erring.......................................... 2 lbs. 25c
Neck Bones ..................................................... per lb. 5c
Sliced Bacon ................................................. per lb. 25c
Beef Roast and Boiling Beef . . . .per lb. 10c to 17c
Cut from young steers and heifers
Pork Roast ......................................per lb. 14c to 18c
DRY OAK WOOD FOR SALE
where in the city.
— Delivered any-
YOUR FAVORITE FOOD DEALER
CAN SUPPLY YOU
WISCONSIN
SATURDAY, FEBRUARY 25, 1939
FREE Coffee!
Carlton Club Coffee will be served,
hot, with Colby Cheese, Krispy Crackers
and Sunshine Butter Cookies !!
LISTED BELOW ARE DAILY
SPECIALS you can’t afford to miss
-------------THURSDAY, FEBRUARY 23R D --------------
JUST 500 POUNDS OF HORMEL’S
PURE LARD ...........perlb.7V2C
One Day Only
---------------- FRIDAY, FEBRUARY 24T H ------------------
JUST 100 LADIES 80-SQUARE PRINT FAST
COLOR NEW SPRING
DRESSES ........................5 0 c
New Styles, sizes 14 to 20— 36 to 44. Regular $1.00
Value — One Day Only
------------- SATURDAY, FEBRUARY 2 5 T H --------------
JUST 300 PAIRS MEN’S OSHKOSH B’GOSH
OVERALLS ................ $1.29
One Day Only
A Special Factory Representative will be here for
this one day only to give you a perfect fit.
REMEBER THIS SALE ENDS SATURDAY NITE,
FEBRUARY 25th
CHAIMSOK’S
Phone No. 9 Black River Falls, Wis.
- The Sign of » D e p e n d a b le S to ra ~ fig 
Macaroni or Spaghetti 5 lbs. 24c
Oatmeal .............. 5 l b - b a g 2 1 c
Pork and Beans 28 oz. 3 cans 29c
COFFEE SPRY
3 LB. CAN
Fels Soap
10 BARS FOR 2 lb 49c 49c 43c
ORANGES ..................................................... 2 doz. 29c
LETTUCE, large heads ............................... 2 for 19c
CELERY, ................................................... 2 stalks 19c
SATURDAY AFTERNOON, FEBRUARY 25th —
The Dorcas Society will Coffee and Lunches at our
Store. Be sure and come in.
BRING US YOUR EGGS
PHONE No. 6 W E DELIVER
</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
