<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_minimal.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_minimal.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>B39M02D08</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>BAND AND ORCHESTRA ED CLIFFORD LOST
MOTHERS WELL PLEASED Mrs. Lydia Clifford and son Donald
The Band and Orchestra Mothers , are very much concerned by the fact
sponsored a program featuring the t at a T u n a ,®.t0 t?c their
Crago Players o f Merrillan in “ The son and brother, Eddie. He was last
Phantom Mine” , last Thursday eve j heard from at Deer Creek General
ning, at the high school auditorium. ! Delivery, Washington state Through
There was a fine attendance and all a friend, Frank Galster, o f Leola S.
enjoyed the three act play and the D„ who has been trying to get in
special acts put on by the Crago ! touch with him, they learn that he
Plavers I s n een seen or heard o f for the
The program opened with an over I past five months. He left on a trip
ture by the high school orchestra un j at that time.
der the direction o f Miss Verna Keefe j He was here a year ago last Sepand
this was followed by an overture i tember, and at that time went to
by the high school band under the Spokane, Washington, driving his
direction o f Jay R. Jotgensen. They own truck there from Leola, South
were unusually excellent offerings
and more than enjoyed by the large
audience. The band also played a
selection during the first and second
and the play closed with another selection
from it.
The Band Orchestra Mothers Association
was more than pleased with , . ,
the results o f the benefit. They rea i mation as to his whereabouts would
lized $72.48 as their part of the pro be gratefull received by his family,
ceeds and $14.00 from the sale o f
Dakota, where he had been operating
his truck for the past five years.
He was 42 years o f age January
2nd. Five foot four inches tall,
brown hair, blue eyes, thick set,
weighing about 154 pounds, both up 
Mr. and Mrs. Duane Hoffman were
visitors in La Crosse last Friday.
Merlin Collum and son Wayne
were visitors in Winona last Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Adolph Borufka were
business visitors in Eau Claire, Tuesday.
E. E. Homstad and Price Moe were
visitors on business in La Crosse last
Friday.
Mr. and Mrs. F. J. Bowman were
visitors at the G. A. Hackett home
in Tomah, Friday.
Mr. and Mrs. J. C. Tollack were
Sunday evening guests at the home
o f O. H. Overlien.
Mr. and Mrs. Erwin W iffler o f Arcadia,
were visitors at the L. D. Anderson
home Monday.


Mrs. Anna Leighton left Sunday to
spend a few days at Sparta with Mr.
per and lower teeth gold crowned, and Mrs. W. C. Woods.
I Quiet and unassuming. Any infor 
He also has two sisters, Mrs. R. J.
Perrin, o f Rhame, N. D., and Mrs.
P. B. Tuttle, o f Walteria, California,
who are worried about him.
It has been suggested that possibly
candy which had been donated by
members o f the association and was
sold by members at the auditorium.
They greatly appreciate the courtesy
and performance o f the Crago Players
and also wish to thank the nerchants
who contributed ads for the
program.
Prizes were awarded to the boy
and girl selling the highest number 
o f tickets for the TA L K S ON “ SH ADO W
Mr. and Mrs. E. S. Jedney spent
Saturday afternoon with their daughter,
Miss Mary, in Baraboo.
Mr. and Mrs. C. L. McDonald entertained
friend at a dinner party at
their home Sunday evening.
L. D. Anderson returned Monday
from Milwaukee, where he spent the
he started on a trucking trip which ! week end, going down Friday,
took him into the mountains and that j S. J. Knudsen and Charles Ludden
heavy snows or slides may have pre returned last week after spending a
vented his return. Friends o f the
family hope that he will turn up safe
and sound.


o f whom were t„o r e ceive a
award o f $2.50. The prize for the
boys went to Clifford Manthe, who
sold 34 tickets, and for the girls to
hPaadtt ya Aclnonse Preurnrnye, rw uhpo isno lDd o1n®n a Mae® |j b e e n fp. a ss ing al on fg, s o m ex o f hoev.r in 
O VER EU RO PE”

Mrs. Clarence Olson, history teacher
in our schools and a student of
what is going on in the world, has
! formation during the past week. She
has been finding the most interested
o f audiences. She talked before the
Quackenbush, who sold 18.
“ IN A N T I Q U E SH. O.P ” . Ameri. can .Le.gio.n . A.ux.ili ary and, .her
The Fine Arts depart beau fame spread. Friday night she was
tiful plaLyC lV.b—In1 S — A n t i q u e S, h o p ” . i!?v.ited V sPea.k ,.befo.re
which was written by Ethel Hawthorne
Tewksbury. It will be given
Monday night, February 20th, starting
at 8 p. m., in the high school auclub
at the Methodist church. Monday
night before the Rotary clu which
invited the members o f the Lions
club down for her talk,
r • • • os. I Her talk is a boiled down version
ditTorhieu mp.r ogAradmm iswsiilol no pise n with selec I 0f th e h is t o r ic a l ba c k g r ou n d . forr p re stions
from the Schubert club under
the direction o f Rufus Dimmick. The
Woman’s club chorus, under the direction
o f Mrs. Irwin Krohn, will
sing during the presentation o f some
o f the numbers. Mrs. Esther Peterson
is piano accompanist and Miss
Verna Carlson will accompany some
of the numbers with the violin.
There will be solos by Mrs. Myron
ent European conditions and is presented
from the light o f facts rather
than opinions.


week in Milwaukee on business.
Mrs. Mabel Ott returned to Milwaukee
Monday after remaining since
the holidays at the Lanning home.
Misses Vesta Reineck and a friend,
Miss Myrtle Bliss, o f Sheboygan, are
guests at the home o f Mr. and Mrs.
S. J. Knudsen.
Grant Hilliker returned to Madi
son Sunday to resume his work at
the University after spending the
week at home.
Bill Sorenson and Miss Lorraine
Johnson o f Wyeville, were Sunday
visitors at the home o f Miss Pearl
Marie Bowman.
Miss Ava Hilliker returned home
recently from Madison. She visited
her brother Lee, at Wisconsin Dells,
on her way home.
Ray Reesman returned last Wednesday
from Milwaukee, where he
had spent a week at the home o f his
son Wayne and family.
C. L. McDonald went to Neills 


FA TH E R PETERS SURPRISED A L E X THOMPSON JAM ES V. LUKAS
Father Vincent Peters was ordain i Alex Thompson, a son o f T olef and "James V. Lukas was bom in Lued
ten years ago. He may have | Berget Heimdahl, was born in Khit j zany, Bohemia, on September 14th,
thought o f the fact last Thursday but | seid, Telemarken, Norway, on July I 1869, and departed this life January
only in a casual manner. AIembersj21, 1853, and passed away at the 28th, 1939, at the age o f 69 years,
Roy Kunzelman and H. T. J. Krae ville this morning to attend a special
mer, o f Alma Center, were guests a t ; meeting o f the Neillsville Credit Prothe
Rotary club that evening. | duction Association, o f which he is a
Mr. and Mrs. J. J. Wynne and son director
Brendon have moved to East St. Paul
where Mr. Wynne has been transferred.
They moved here in November,


H. Moen, Mrs. Robert Flugstad and , j 935 f rom Hudson, although Mr.
Mrs. Thomas Mills, and a trio, Mes Wynne had been coming here since
dames Duane Hoffman, Irwin Krohn 1931 j j e was an operator while here and. Tm h. omas oMf fi' llll s, , w — ti l1l conv. tI r .il bu114t" eA tI on • . a . . . . . . » .
the musical program.
The play is being directed by Mrs.
Bert F. Johnson. Mrs. John Sypulski
is chairman o f stage properties.
 n charge o f a shift at the Levis station
and will continue that line of
work in East St. Paul. Brendon attended
school and was in the eighth
grade. Their daughter, Miss Mary
which were in the nature of farewell
parties. Mr. and Mrs. Wynne will
both be missed in St. Joseph’ s church
in which they were very active workers.
The good wishes of the many
friends they have made here accompany
them to their new home.
Several o f the cast drove to Eau j j ane wb0 graduated from high school
sCalmaier ep lTauye wsdhaiych awftaesr nboeoinn g tpo resseeen tthede I ere last Jun e , is— n ow ta k ing nu rs e’s
theFroel. lowing is a .br.ie. f summary o i
the episodes and cast o f characters:
Antique shop girl— Ruth Ann Bailey
First episode, The Sampler Mrs.
A. W . Heilsberg .
Second episode, The Spinner— Mrs.
Myron H. Moen ,
Third episode, The Cradle— Mrs.
Robert Flugstad
Fourth episode, The Old Arm
Chair— Mrs. Rufus Dimmick
Fifth Episode, Colonial Dames
 Mesdames Hans Hanson, hostess,
Mrs. A. P. Jones, Mrs. O. F. Waldum,
Mrs. Herman Weckwerth.
Sixth episode, Paisley Shawl Mrs.
Jay Jorgensen
Seventh episode, Quiltmg Bee— 
Mesdames Adolph Borufka, Matt
Christianson, Jacob Bloom, Miss Emma
Neindorf
Eighth episode, The China Dog—
Miss Elsa Mork . .
Ninth episode, The Old Fan— Mrs.
Orval Iserloth and Miss Ruth Zodt 
Tenth episode, Godey’ s Lady Book
— Miss Lulu Thompson
Eleventh episode, The Prairie Mother—
Miss Agnes Hanson


Twelfth episode, The Candle—
Mrs. L. J. Gardipee
Thirteenth episode, The Lovers—
Misses Mason Werner and Miss Sylvia
Dunnum
Robert Upton, son o f Mr. and Mrs.
John Upton, o f Shady Glen, was seriously
injured last Thursday afternoon
"at his home when the tank of
a gasoline engine he was running for
power while gumming a saw, exploded.
He was drenched with the gasoline
which instantly burst into
flames as well as the building in
which it was housed. Although near
James Dimmick and Mr. and Mrs.
Rufus Dimmick and sons, Jimmy and
Earle, were guests Sunday at the
home o f Dr. and Mrs. E. A. Winter of
Augusta.
Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Dettinger, of
Northfield, and the latter’s mother,
Mrs. Sara Harris, o f Hixton, were
guests Sunday at the home o f Mr.
and Mrs. James Hulett.
Mrs. Clarence Olson and son Duane,
and Mrs. William Duchow and
little daughter, Connie Jo. were visittraining
at St. Mary’s hospital, St. M p h w X a r 31 h° me
PueU o fIrhoanod ! H o ird l n e went to Madison
New Freeman Lhoft.ell Sunday a fte r ;1 .M onday' tos nsepcieanld aeserviceurlatlu rwael esktsu dtiaeks
noon, and at the home of Mr. and o
Mrs. Leo Bielinski Sunday evening,
Miss Julia Clausen is arriving today
from Chicago for a week or so visit
at the home o f Misses Mary and Jane
Spaulding. Miss Clausen has had em . „ , .
ployment for the past four years with to Chicago Sunday on a business trip.
He is a son o f Mr. and Mrs. E. P.
Prindle, o f Alma Center.
Misses Harriet Hendrickson, Palma
Gilbertson, and Maurice Turner and
Vilas Welda were visitors in La
Crosse Sunday and attended the ice
races held there that day.
Mrs. Joseph Widmar and Mrs. Eldred
Rickey entertained friends at
cards at the Widmar home Saturday
evening. Mrs. Bert Sanford was
prize winner for the evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Mason Werner went
the law firm o f Winston, Strawn 
Shaw, o f Chicago, and resigned her
position only last week. Her engagement
to Clyde I. Bowman, o f Portland,
Oregon, has been announced
and her marriage will take place April
15th. Her mother, Mrs. H. W.
Clausen, is a niece o f the Misses
Spaulding and was a daughter o f the
late Mrs. C. D. Osborn, oldest daughter
o f the Spaulding home here. Miss
Clausen has visited here ever since
she was a little girl and has many
friends who will be interested in
learning o f her coming marriage.
They expect to return tomorrow. Miss
Mary Upton is taking care o f Sharon
and Helen during their absence.
Mrs. S. J. Knudsen entertained
friends at a 500 party last Wednes
day afternoon. Prize for high score
went to Mrs. L. D. Anderson, and
consolation to Mrs. Herbert Popp.
Miss Evelyn Peterson o f Oshkosh,
spent the week end with Mr. and Mrs,
Guy Crandall. Mr. and Mrs. Earl
Langworthy, junior, o f Alma Center,
were also guests at their home Sunday.
M
rs. Jerome Hostrawser, formerly
Miss Grace Posvic, was the guest of
There is much interest in the W o j honor Monday night at a bridal showman’s
club program being given this
evening at the Lutheran church, at
which Mrs. Joseph C. Baird, Mrs. A.
Eugene Hatch, Mrs. L. T. Boortz, and
Mrs. James W. Jensen o f Eau Claire,
will be the guest entertainers. The
board o f directors, members o f the
er at the home o f Miss Pearl Marie
Bowman. She received many lovely
gifts.
Mrs. Marion Helling came from
Madison last Friday and returned
Monday noon. She was a guest while
here at the homes o f Mr. and Mrs.
drama department and the reception ! Fred Lange and Mr. and Mrs. Mason
committee is having a dinner party
at the New Freeman hotel this evening
for Mrs. Baird and her friends
before the program is given at the
church. A fter the program a lunch
T door the names p r e v e n t hfm will be served by Mrs William Hoff
from getting through it and he jump man division o f the Ladies Aid.
ed through the window. A large! g essje p 0mroy and daughter
window with many panes he jumped , jrs Ray Wilkinson, drove here from
through the upper sash and never Harvard, Illinois, yesterday, and are
even broke a pane in the lower. His puestg at the home o f N‘Irs Laura
wife and mother •were attending a c ampbell. They stopped in Prairie
shower on Mrs. Lloyd Casper at the
Gus Casper home and Mr. Upton was
in the barn, some distance away at
du Sac to see Mrs. Myrta Fey and
she drove up with them. They also
; saw Mrs. Vella Van W orner at New
the time. He tore off his burning Lisbon, where she and Mr Van W orjacket
and managed to extinguish the 1 nler are staying at his sister’s home
flames but was badly burned about wbi e she is in the hospital at Madithe
head and hands. He has been son. Mrs. Pomrov came to attend
Werner.
Misses Dolores Dettinger and Betty
Jean Perry returned to Madison
by bus Sunday to resume their wrork
at the University. They attended
the school concert held Sunday afternoon
before going back.
Mr. and Mrs. Henry E. Olson, Mr.
and Mrs. Clayton McCallum, Janet
and Katy were La Crosse visitors on
Sunday ,and dinner guests o f Mr. and
Mrs. J. T. McCallum in the evening.
The men attended the ice races.
Miss Verna Berg returned Sunday
from a visit o f a couple o f weeks in
Milwaukee with her cousin, Mrs.
James Trebilcock and aunt, Miss Mabel
Berg. She spent the week end
with friends in Edgerton on her way
home.
coming to the hospital daily for dress to business matters at this time. Mr. and Mrs. Gerald Hoonsbeen
ings and is getting along satisfactor , ..... n , „ ,
fly. About 2 Vz years ago an emery j Mrs. E. A. Homstad was guest o f ! fjl Iv1t w t v u ? Saturday
wheel broke while he was gumming honor at a very pleasant party at her! " e J c ’ S.e j
a saw, and his face and head were . home Friday afternoon which was at ' ~ recently vacated by Mr. and
cut by flying fragments, so saws are j tended by about twenty o f her
not his lucky pices. J friends. The party had been planned
by Mrs. E. E. Homstad in honor of
the 80th anniversary o f Mrs. Homstad’s
birth. She has taken a very
active part in social and church circles
in the city for many years, and
has a host o f friends who wish her
many happy returns o f her anniversary.
Laurel Vandervort, of Decorah, la.,
who was so seriously injured last fall
by a fall from a horse, has finally
been discharged form the hospital at
Rochester where he has been under
treatment and is now at his home.
He has had a long, hard siege o f it
and although he is recovered sufficiently

to return home he will never Charles Kelly, son o f Mr. and Mrs.
have the full use o f his injured j Oliver Kelly o f Shamrock, was able
shoulder. He has been in the hospital , to leave the hospital last Monday afever
since the accident except for j ter a little better than two weeks unspending
a few days at home over j der medical treatment. He is much
Christmas. He has had the sympathy 'improved. We wishes to extend his
o f his friends here, who are glad that deep appreciation to his many kind ..
 h e i' s i’ mproved. friends and neighbors for their calls, I Krametbauer o f this city, Mr. and
Mrs. S. J. Knudsen. They have been
living in the Lloyd Gilbertson house
in the second ward.
Mrs. Ray Millis and little daughter
Sandra Jean, returned to their home
in Shamrock from the hospital at
Sparta, where little Sandra had been
under treatment for intestinal poisoning.
She is only three months o f age
and had been seriously ill. Friends
are glad to learn she is better.
Emil Krametbauer, who makes his
home with Mr. and Mrs. Theodore
Bunde, o f Squaw Creek, was 70 years
o f age Sunday and was guest o f
honor at a party held at the Bunde
home to celebrate the occasion. Those
present were Mr. and Mrs. Charles
o f his parish thought of it, however,
in a more than casual manner. They
planned to celebrate the occasion and
certainly succeeded in their undertaking.
Thursday night, the first in the
month, was holy hour service. Word
was sent throughout the parish for
all to attend the service. Father Peters
was gratified by the large attendance
and spoke o f it. After the service
those in attendance went down
to the social rooms but were very
quiet about it. Later, on some pretense,
Dr. W. L. Boehm took Father
Peters down and the crowd there surprised
him completely.
Mrs. Joe Bielinski had made a beautiful
birthday cake, large enough to
serve 100, to do honor to the occasion.
Refreshments were served and
a social hour enjoyed and after the
close of the first show at the Falls
theatre all were invited there to see
a film showing Father Peters at the
time o f his ordination and the first
mass he held at his home town of
Plain.
Father Peters had been called to
Plain Wednesday by the death o f a
friend. His parents, Mr. and Mrs.
Peter Peters, who had been advised
o f the party in his honor, returned
here with him for a visit and were
present at the party.
There was another ce?ebration in
Father Peters’ honor when Mr. and
Mrs. George Laubmeier and two
daughters, Carol and Jeanette, of
Mineral Point, arrived Friday and remained
until Sunday at the Peters
home. Mrs. Ben Kraemer o f Plain,
and Mr. and Mrs. Ed Kraemer and
family were also guests there. Their
daughter, Iris, was the little girl who
was the bride at the first mass Father
Peters gave. Peter Peters returned
to Plain with Mrs. Ben Kraemer
Sunday, and Mrs. Peters remained
for a longer visit.
Father Peters will go to Dane tomorrow
to attend a class reunion of
his class which graduated ten years
ago from St. Francis Seminary, Milwaukee.
Ten o f the 17 members of
the class are still in Wisconsin, and
all o f the members are alive. Father
Kreibich, now of Plum City, and
Father Fischer, o f Waumandee, both
o f whom have been in charge here,
are members o f the class.
home o f his son in Northfield on I four months and 14 days.
January 29, 1939 at the age o f 85 I He came to A m ericaat the age o f
years, six months and eight days. 18 years, and immediately established
On June 4, 1880, he was married I his citizenship in this country. On
to Berget Thompson, who preceded I May 21st, 1891, he was united in
him in death on Nov. 13, 1903. To marriage to Antonia Kapek, in Chithis
union ten children were born,
five o f whom have preceded him in
death, namely Alfred, Henry, Helen,
John and Sebert. He leaves to
mourn his death, three sons: Theodore,
o f Eau Claire; Martin, of
Northfield; Edgar, o f Minneapolis,
C E LE B R A TE SILVER W EDDING
Mr. and Mrs. Art Hoimgreen, of
Squaw Creek, were surprised Wednesday
evening, February 1st, when
some forty o f their relatives and
friends gathered at their home to help
in the celebration o f their silver wedding
anniversary.
It was a very pleasant occasion,
with games being played and a bountiful
lunch served. The members o f
their family presented thfem with a
very nice dinner set as a remembrance
o f the occasion and. their
friends with a collection o f money
for which they purchased a beautiful
lamp.
Mr. and Mrs. Holmgreen are highly
respected citizens and have a family
o f eight children. They are Mrs.
Helen Lee, Mrs. Lillian Peterson and
Mrs. Mildred Melbye, all o f this city;
Harold, Mahlon, Avis, Winifred and
Jean, at home.
H ELW IG O D EN BREIT
Mrs. Blanche Helwig and Henry
Odenbreit were united in marriage at
a ceremony performed Saturday afternoon,
February 4, 1939, at the
Methodist parsonage at Waukon, la.
Rev. Lee Roberts performed the ceremony.
They were accompanied by
Miss Irma Helwig and Ervin Galster,
a half brother o f the bride.
Mrs. Odenbreit has had employment
for some time at Emma’s Cafe.
Mr. Odebreit is from Waukegan, 111.,
and is a carpenter who has been employed
on the new postoffice building.
He is a brother o f George Odenbreit,
o f this city. Their many friends
join in wishing them happiness.
DOG TE A M HERE T O D A Y
Carl and Rudy Schubert, o f Cumberland
House, Saskatchewan, are in
town today with a seven dog team,
sled and six puppies, about a month
old, born en route. Three o f their
dogs are mostly wolf, the leader is
a Labrador hound. They have been
traveling over two months and 1500
miles and are on the way to Chicago.
They travel 35 to 40 miles a day.
They are at the school house this
afternoon and students will have a
chance to see the dogs and hear something
about them.
cago, where they resided until 1898,
when they moved to Hillsboro, Wis.,
where he continued as a merchant
tailor. He moved with his family and
business to Taylor in 1912, where he
resided until his death.
A kind father, devoted to his home
and family, will be sadly missed by
j his six children, who are left to
Minn.; two daughters, Mable, Mrs. [ mourn his departure. They are Mrs.
L O. Neperud o f Deerfield; Stella, Harland Bradley and Mrs. Clarence
Mrs. Herman Larson, o f Black River Johnson, o f Minneapolis, Minn.; Ani
grandchildren, one great ton and Edward Lukas, of Milton
grandchild, and two sisters, Thorild Junction, Wis.; Mrs. Frances Rump 
I: !’ ° L aUo Claire, and Mrs. Car j pe and Mrs. Tilford Schansberg, of
Taylor; two brothers, Karl Lukas,
o f Friendship, Wis., and Martin Lukas,
of Wilson, Kansas; also nine
grandchildren.
The funeral was conducted at the
home and Taylor Lutheran church on
Tuesday, Jan. 31st, with Rev. A. J.
Bringle officiating. He was laid to
rest in the Woodlawn cemetery beside
rie Myers o f Seattle, Washington.
Besides these there are a host of
other relatives and friends who
mourn his passing.
Mr. Thompson came to America in
1871 when he was only 18 years old.
The sailboat Ruken, which brought
him here, was on the ocean six
weeks and two days.
He spent the first year here in I his wife who preceded him in death
Stoughton, and in the fall he came ;n July, 1933.
to Black River Falls. In 1877 he
bought a farm in Northfield, where
he had since resided. He has been
an invalid for the past eight years.
He was one o f the founders of the
Upper Pigeon Lutheran church, of
which he was always a faithful memher.
Until his family was grown he
was both mother and father to them,
and he has shown his patience and
Those in attendance at the funeral
from away were Mr. and Mrs. H. L.
Bradley; Mr. and Mrs. C. J. Johnson
and Mrs. Louie Matson, o f Minneapolis,
Minn.; Mr. and Mrs. A. V. Lukas,
Mr. and Mrs. Edward Lukas, and
Mrs. Edward Kapek, o f Milton Junction,
W is.; Mr. and Mrs. Karl Lukas,
Mr. and Mrs. Walter Cizvarek,
o f Friendship, W is.; Robert Prohazcheerfulness
o f character all during ka, o f Neillsville, W is.; Mr. and Mrs.
his invalidism.
Funeral services were held on Feb.
1, from the Upper Pigeon church.
Reverend E. B. Christopherson conducted
the services. Interment was
made in the Upper Pigeon cemetery.
His three sons, Theodore, Martin and
Edgar; two sons in law, Louie Neperud
and Herman Herman Larson;
and his grandson, Eldon Thompson,
acted as pall bearers. Two nieces,
Betty Jane Thompson and Avis June
Neperud, had charge o f the flowers.
Those from away who were in attendance
at the funeral were Mrs.
Clara Thompson and daughters, Eileen
and Mrs. Alice Feely, and Mr.
and Mrs. Lee Peterson o f La Crosse;
Mrs. Sadie Jennings, Mrs. Norma
Sorlie, Mrs. C. A. Hall, Mr. and Mrs.
Lyman Larson and Miss Leona
Nemec, o f Black River Falls; Mr.
and Mrs. George Maule, Hixton;
Louie and Ralph Schansberg, Whitehall;
and Mrs. H. J. Schansberg of
Blair. 
MRS. M ARY W ALDEN
Mrs. Mary Walden, one o f the oldest
residents of the city, died at 1 :30
a. m. Tuesday, February 7, 1939, at
the home of her daughter, Mrs. H.
H. Hubbard, o f Minneapolis, according
to word received by her daughterin 
law, Mrs. Edith Walden.
Mrs. Walden had been staying with
her daughter for the past three years.
She had been gradually failing in
health, suffering o f hardening o f the
arteries and accompanying complications.
She suffered a fall from the
davenport last Wednesday, and had
Thompson, o f Alma Center; Mr. and since been in a critical condition. Her
Mrs. Kermit Wussow, Mr. and Mrs.
Carl Malchow, Mr. and Mrs. Theodore
Andresen and son Lyle, Mrs. Olaf
Larson and Ray, and Casper Waller,
o f Black River Falls; Mr. and Mrs.
Victor Tweed, o f Minneapolis; Mrs.
Harold Pribbenow, o f Richland Center;
Mrs. Bertha Olson, Mr. and
Mrs. Waldemor Andresen; Mr. and
Mrs. Mike Abend, Frank and Bernard
Abend, Victor Larson and Malcolm
Andresen, o f Hixton. 
Dr. A. S. Trondson and daughter,
Miss Marian, Mrs. Emma McCallum,
Mrs. W. F. Maddocks, Mrs. John Rulland
and Mrs. John Bolger were La
Crosse visitors Sunday. Mrs. Maddocks
visited Mrs. J. R. Ogden and
daughter, Miss Grace
daughter, Mrs. Emil Johnson, o f Ste
phen, Minnesota, had been with her
at the Hubbard home for weeks before
the holidays and was called ba :k
Wednesday and was with her when
she passed away.
Funeral services will be held Friday
afternoon at 2 o’clock at the
Lutheran church in this city, conducted
by Rev. A. M. Romstad. Mr. and
Mrs. Hubbard and Mrs. Johnson are
coming from Minneapolis tomorrow
and Mr. and Mrs. Bowman Walden
will be here from Merrill to attend
the services.
had gone to see her niece, Miss Avis
Swanson, who works in the advertising
department of the Trane company
and found on arrival that Miss
Swanson had gone to the races. She
then called the Harrison Church home
thinking she would call on them, and
discovered that Mrs Church was a
patient at the La Crosse hospital,
where she had undergone an opera 
MRS. A R T SANDERS
Mrs. Art Sanders died at her home
about 10 o ’clock Tuesday night, Feb 
MfS; Bolger ; ruary 7, 1939. She has been in poor
Mrs. Emma Gilbert and son Bill,
and granddaughters. Misses Jean
Boyer and Maxine Tucker, returned
home Friday from St. Paul, where | tion three weeks before for a severe
they spent several days with their appendicitis, which was followed by
daughters and aunts, Mrs. Herbert peritonitis. Friends will be pleased
Alberg and Mrs. Viola Kelly. They I to learn that she wras getting along
had the pleasure while there o f at 1 all right and hoped to be up in a day
tending the St. Paul winter carnival 1 or two. The others o f the party atwhich
were held on the shores o f j tended the national skating races held
Lake Como, and which was a beau in La Crosse Sunday and all were
tiful sight. Mrs. Gilbert’s nephew, ; dinner guests at the home o f Mr. and
Bobby Specht, o f Superior, had ap , Mrs. Jack McCallum.
peared at the carnival a short time 1 ~ , „ „
before, and she regretted that she ! Mesdames E. E. Homstad, Bert F.
was not there to see him then. He is I Johnson, Orval Iserloth and Jacob
now in Chicago. I B oom drove to Eau Claire Tuesday
health for many years, suffering o f a
complication o f troubles. She suffered
a stroke Monday which resulted in
her death. She has long been a familiar
figure on our streets as she
was taken around in her wTheel chair
by Mr. Sanders. She was 59 years
o f age.
Funeral services will be held Friday
afternoon at the Mattson Funeral
home and interment made in Riverside.
sunshines and many thoughtful kind Mrs Ted Stenulson and Mr. and Mrs.
Miss Jane Spaulding fell on the j nesses extended to him during his so 1 Charles Falk, o f Hatfield.
iceQ SX IuI ndH art Vy Aa ♦ft 4 e rt rMnM oA oA nM an1d 1 brokL eA br Ao tt hn '' j o u .r n !i n tX h1 e. 1h o s p i t1 al. T AtaAVM A W T A I + + ♦ C! f
bones o f her lower left arm. The 1 
water had run over the walk leading j Joe Oakland, o f Milwaukee, was a
from their home, and although she
was exercising care she slipped on
the ice and fell, striking on her arm.
She has her injured arm in a cast
and it will be some time before she
regains its use. Her friends are as
sorry as they can be about her accident.
visitor in town one day last week and
called on his cousin, Andrew Oakland,
in this city while in town with
Mr. and Mrs. Manford Christianson,
c f Taylor. Mr. Oakland. Joe Berntssn.
Ebert Oakland came from Milwaukee
to attend the funeral o f the
late Bernt I. Bemtson, o f Taylor.
Jerome W oelffer o f Sparta, and his
brother Gerald W oelffer, o f Baraboo,
left Friday for a two weeks stay in
Florida which they have been awarded
by their insurance company. Mrs.
W oelffer is visiting at the home o f
her parents, Mr. and Mrs. A. N. Larkin,
during their absence. The trip
was awarded by the Farmers Mutual
Automobile Insurance Co. o f which
Jerome W oelffer is district manager.
afternoon to attend the production
o f “ In An Antique Shop” , which was
presented by a cast from the Eau
Claire Woman’s club. Mrs. Johnson
Miss Marion Cheney is now spending
a couple o f weeks in Chicago after
closing her home here for the rest,
o f the winter months. She had plan j is coaching the same play which will
ned on spending the winter in the 1 be shown here February 20th, and
south but had not definitely decided the others are members o f the cast,
just where when she left here. She They said the play w as beautiful,
was in Mexico last year and more | Mrs. L. T. Boortz, who is appearing
than liked it there, so we hope she on the program at the Lutheran
will find her way back there this year i church tonight, was the leading charand
enjoy it as much as she did be j acter. A tea, incharge o f Mrs. Earl
fore. We wish her a fine trip and Pongratz, was given after the play,
a safe return ■ ■ — 
Mr. and Mrs. Leslie Wells, o f Roar 
MRS. B. HAHN
Mrs. B. Hahn o f Alma Center, died
at her home Tuesday morning, February
7th. She had been in poor
health for some time.
Funeral services will he held at
the Alma Center Catholic church at
10 o ’clock Thursday morning.
MRS. NELLIE M ITCHELL
TO GIVE T R A V E L TALK
Mrs. Nellie Mitchell will give her
travel talk at the court house at 2 :30
p. m. Monday. Sponsored by club
women the talk is open to the public
and all are invited. Mrs. Mitchell has
spent three years abroad and has
been appearing in radio and stage
programs since her return. She will
be here for the week end.
Harlan Lea, who has been attend 1 ing Creek, are driving to Madison
ing state teachers college in La
Crosse, has transferred to the University
o f Wisconsin, where he will
continue his course in accounting,
entering the second semester o f his
sophomore year at the University. He
and George Reesman, who spent the
today where Mr. Wells will enter the
Wisconsin General Hospital for treatment
and examination. He has been
in poor health for several years, suffering
o f stomach trouble, and hopes
that he may find relief in Madison,
Clayton W. Clark, o f Melrose, was
elected to membership in the University
o f Wisconsin chapter of Phi Kappa
Phi, national honor society. The
purpose o f the society is to recognize
scholarship and outstanding contributions
to the life o f the university
through participation in major campus
activities. Prof. C. A. Dykstra
and 56 senior students, 24 women
and 32 men, were honored by memmership
at this time.
a hope in which their many friends
between semester vacation at the join. He will remain at the hospital
home o f his parents, Mr. and Mrs. , and Mrs. Wells will return tomorrow.
Ray Reesman, drove to Madison Sun — 7 — . . , „ .
day . Warren Pugh returned from spend | Cooperative medicine were given by
The Black River Co op. Club met
at the home of Mr. aid Mrs. Richard
Faldet Monday evening. Topics on
ing last week in Duluth, where he four o f the members. After the dis 
Mrs. Tillie Everson and Mrs. Isaac | attended the Marshall Wells Associ cussion a few stunts were played, and
Nelson, o f Whitehall, were visitors in 1 ation Hardware store convention Mr. Faldet was presented with a fine
town Tuesday afternoon on their way j where there were about 500 in at comical gift, the occasion being his
back from Tomah, where they1 had tendance. Allen Kimball o f Melrose 1 birthday. At the close o f the meetdriven
with Mrs. H. Van Gorden, who
will visit there.
was there, and also representatives ; ing Mrs. Faldet served tasty refreshfrom
Blair and Strum. ments.
A N N U AL M EETING OF THE
FED ERATIO N CO OP. O IL CO.
The annual delegate meeting o f the
federation Co op Oil Co., was held
at the court house at Black River
Falls, Friday, January 27th, with
about 60 delegates attending from
Galesville, Fall Creek and Black
River Falls.
The meeting was called to order by
the president, Gust Kohnert, about
10:30 a. m. Most o f the forenoon
was spent in explaining the audit report
by Richard Faldet, the manager.
The meeting adjourned at 12:30 p
m. for dinner at Kasik’s cafe.
The afternoon meeting was called
to order at 1:30 and A. J. Smaby,
o f Midland Co operative Wholesale at
Minneapolis, gave a very good talk
with assistance o f charts on credit
problems o f co operatives and compared
the situation o f the local co op
with other co operatives in this respect.
He recommended that a strict
credit policy be adopted in order that
accounts receivables be kept to a minimum.
William Rubenbauer o f Alma Center,
was elected a member o f the
board o f directors to succeed Gust
Kohnert, whose term expired at this
time. Harvey Gilbertson was elected
to fill the place o f William Sawyer
whose term expired. Bert Congdon,
who was also up for re election, was
elected for another term.
The meeting declared that 6 interest
be paid on stock outstanding.
Present officers and members o f
the board are:
President— Janies Bullock, Melrose
Vice President— Henry Graff, Fall
Creek
Secretary— Ed Rau, Fall Creek
Directors— Bert Congdon, Galesville;
James Haug, Holmen; Harvey
Gilbertson, B. R. Falls; Wm. Rubenbauer,
Alma Center.
Delegates present w ere: Ed Ellison,
Robert Bullock, John Baird,
Lloyd Haugstad, Ed Storandt, Lester
Patterson, Jeff Peasley, Wm. Rubenbauer,
Frank Drescher, Ed Gearing,
Earl Horswill, Ray Hurlburt, Ed Larkin,
Oscar Hauge, Lewis Stein, Nels
Nelson, Anton Eggen
E. R. Prindle, F. J. Newton, Louis
Updike, Tom Stodola, A. J. McNab,
Ray Reichenbach, Irwin Bowen, Geo.
Schlegel, Harvey Gilbertson, S. A.
Gilbertson, Mike Filkowski, Harvey
Harris, Fred Black, B. M. Johnson,
Ludwig Lee, Carl Smikrud, Lawrence
Suttie
W. J. Smith, Julius Hegge, Lloyd
Ekem, Kilmer Erickson, Oscar Van
Vleet, Leslie Gartner, Lawrence
Oines, Henry Olson, George Newton,
August Scheiffelbein, Ed Weideman,
Herman Strauch, William Hass, Walter
Volkman, Frank Zetzman, Herman
Hass, Fred Scheiffenbein.
D IRECTORS ELECT
CREAM ERY OFFICERS
At a meeting of the board o f directors
held Saturday at the Farmers
Cooperative Creamery in this city, o fficers
were elected for the coming
year. There was no change made 
and C. S. Ristow will again serve as
president, John Wyss as vice president
and Helge Rustad as secretary
and treasurer.
There was considerable discussion
at the meeting as to ways and means
o f cutting down expenses at the plant
for the coming year and to make
savings in the operation. It was decided
that after the 15th o f February
butter will not be retailed in less
than ten pound lots except to patrons
o f the creamery, who will not be affected
by the change.
The directors appreciate and thank
the business men of the city for their
contributions for serving dinner to
the stockholders and patrons at their
annual meeting and also wish to
thank the restaurants for their fine
service.
W AR REN JONES APPO IN TED
TREASURER
Warren Jones was appointed to
serve as treasurer o f the school district
in Black River Falls, to fill the
vacancy created by the death o f Mrs.
Mary O. Mills, who had filled that
office for some time past and wa?
reelected in 1938 to serve until 1940.
Mr. Jones was appointed by the
other two members o f the board, E.
S. Jedney, director, and E. E. Homstad,
clerk. He will serve until the
coming school election in July when
the members o f the district will elect
an officer o f their choice for that
position.
VA CCIN ATIO N PROGRAM
TH U RSD AY
The vaccination program being
sponsored by the school and Woman’s
club will be carried out Thursday
afternoon, beginning at 1 :30 p. m. in
the domestic science room at the high
school building. There will be a
charge o f 50 cents.
Parents o f preschool children are
urged to bring their children at this
time.
COUNCIL REPEALS
O RDINANCE 145
At the regular meeting o f the city
council held last evening an ordinance
was passed to repeal Ordinance
No. 145 relative to the manner of
choosing the treasurer, city clerk, assessor,
city attorney and marshal. The
above officers shall be elected by the
voters.
OLSON S B A K E RY
GETS HIGH RATING
Olson’s Bakery got a rating o f 98
per cent on a loaf o f t h e i r b r e a d
which was tested by the Bay S t a t e
Milling Company, o f Winona. M r . Olson
was warmly congratulated on his
loaf as one o f the finest commercial
loaves checked in their laboratories.
NEW CAR AGEN CY
Frank’s Auto Sales has accepted a
Dodge and Plymouth agency, which
they are advertising for the first
time in this issue. They have been
in business over four years here and
last year built a new building for
their business just east o f the Jackson
County shop.
James Boyle, a young man from
Detroit, was taken very ill here last
Thursday and with no place to go
was taken to the county jail by Sheriff
Waldum who summoned a doctor
in the case. The young man was
taken to the hospital for an operation
for intestinal obstruction and is making
a satisfactory recovery.
PAGE NO. 2 THE BANNER JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin W ednesday, February 8, 1939
H U LL’S APPO IN TM EN T DUE TO
M ERIT, NOT PO LITICS
 Galesville Republican 
The appointment o f Congressman
Merlin Hull to a place on the banking
and currency committee is gratifying
to his host o f friends in the
Ninth district. This is one o f the
most important committees in the
house o f representatives, ranking
along with that o f appropriations and
foreign affairs.
And Congressman Hull’s friends
have no doubt that the appointment
came to him because o f merit. He is
a Progressive, and as such is o f a
minority party. Very much in the
minority.
Furthermore, no one, regardless of
party affiliations, will doubt that Congressman
Hull will make good on this
important committee, and bring further
honor to Wisconsin and himself.
BOY SCOUTS TRO O PS 59 AND 41
Troops 41 and 59 met at the gym
Jan. 18th, 19S9 and played volley
ball and basket ball.
On Jan. 25th, 1939, Mitchell Red
Cloud and his two sons entertained
us. Mitchell Red Cloud showed us
how to make snowshoes, and he showed
us some fine bead work and Indian
dolls. His boys danced with the
help o f some scouts, and Mitchell Red
Cloud beat the Indian drum.
Feb. 1st, 1939, we met at 7 :00 p.
m. at the high school gym. There
we played volley ball and basket ball.
On Jan. 29th, 1939, there was a
mixed hike o f skiis ant toboggans. A
fine time was enjoyed by all.
FRANCIS SMETANA, Scribe
Troops 41 and 59
NOTICE
Where?— Shamrock hall.
What?— A valentine party.
When? Friday night, Feb. 17.
By whom? Shamrock Good Will
Club.
Entertainment?— Cards and dancing.
L
unch will be served.
NOTICE
The annual stockholders and patrons
meeting o f the Alma Center
Creamery Co. will be held in the town
hall, Monday, Feb. 13th, at 1 :30 p. m.
H. E. NESS, Sec.
R O Y A L NEIGHBORS
Royal Neighbors will meet second
and fourth Saturday afternoons each
month at 2:30 o’clock at the Marsh
hall.
NOTICE TO T A X P A Y E R S
OF BLA CK RIVER FALLS
The tax roll is in my hands for
collection. During tax collection time
I will be at the city clerk’s office the
first ten days o f each month and
every Saturday.ROSE MCDONALD,
2 7w City Treas.
D on’t Miss T h e
16 C H A M P IO N S
H IP B O X IN G
M A T C H E S
in th e
G O L D E N
G L O V E S
F I N A L S
a t L in c o ln F ie ld H ou se
Wis. Rapids
Thursday,
Feb. 16
a t 8 P . M.
R in g sid e S e a t s $ 1 . 1 0
R e se rv e d B le a c h e rs
and B a l c o n y 8 5 c
G en . A d m . 5 5 c
S tu d e n ts 2 5 C
 Tax Included 
F o r re s e rv a tio n s send
ch eck o r m oney o rd er to
T h e T rib u n e . W is . R a p id s .
SINGER Sales Service
by Representative H. E. Kaun
Hancock Hardware Co.
Com plete Service on Singer and other
Make . Also Used Machines fo r Sale.
ZERB EL K AU FM AN
The wedding o f Miss Alma Zerbel,
daughter o f Mr. and Mrs. Paul Zerbel,
and Mr. Laverae Kaufman, son
o f Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Kaufman,
was celebrated at St. Joseph’s Catholic
church, Fairview, at 9 :30 Saturday
morning, Jan. 28, 1939, the Rev.
J. J. Sheridan officiating.
The bride was prettily attired in a
wedding gown o f rose colored silk,
and her bridesmaid, Miss Arelia
Kaufman’s gown was o f dark blue
silk, each having accessories to match.
The groom and his attendant, Mr. Joseph
Pflieger, Jr., each wore dark
blue suits. Flowers were gardenias.
A fter the impressive ceremony the
wedding party returned to the home
o f the bride’s parents where an excellent
wedding dinner, served by the
bride’s mother, was partaken. In the
evening a dancing party was given at
the town hall in their honor. The
bride was the recipient o f many dainty
and useful gifts from relatives
and friends.
At present, Mr. Kaufman and his
bride will make their home with his
parents on the farm west o f town,
expecting to start housekeeping in
the spring in one o f the nearby
homes.
All friends o f the newlyweds join
in wishing them a happy and prosperous
journey through life together.—
The Humbird Enterprise
TRO XEL H AN SEN
Miss Bernadine Troxel o f Alma
Center, and Albert Hansen, Neillsville,
were united in marriage at Sunset
Point, Tuesday, Jan. 31, 1939, at
11 o ’clock a. m., Rev. G. W. Longenecker
performing the single ring
ceremony.
The bride is a graduate o f the
Neillsville high school with the class
o f 1937 and has since Deen employed
in various homes, her domestic experiences
fitting her well for the duties
she assumes. She is a daughter
o f Mr. and Mrs. Vilas Troxel o f Alma
Center.
The groom is a son o f Mr. and
Mrs. Harry Hansen o f Neillsville, rural
route one, farming being his occupation.
A gown o f navy blue and pink, bolero
style, was worn by the bride,
the bridesmaid, Miss Evelyn Hansen,
o f Neillsville, rural route one, sister
o f the groom, wearing black, similarly
styled. Vernon Troxel, brother of
the bride, attended the groom.
At the noon hour an informal dinner
was served at the home o f the
bride’s parents to ten guests. The
couple will be engaged in farming at
Loyal.— Clark County Pres3.
MRS. CH ARLES CLARK
Louisa Dana Clark was born in
New York state on August 13, 1853
and passed away at the home o f a
relative at Black River Falls on Jan.
24, 1939, at the age o f 85 years, five
months and 11 days.
In 1870 she was united in marriage
with Charles A. Clark. This union
was blessed with three sons, Edward,
William and Arthur. Edward and
William passed away in their younger
years. Soon after their marriage Mr.
and Mrs. Clark located at Portage,
where they resided six years. From
there they moved to Tomah, where
they spent the remainder o f their
lives. Mr. Clark died in 1908.
Mrs. Clark has been in ill health
for a number o f years but has recovered
from previous attacks to live out
a long and full life. In her younger
years Mrs. Clark was a great
worker in the church o f her choice
and in the Eastern Star lodge, o f
which she was a member for many
years. Eternity only can reveal what
was accomplished in this earnest
work.
Mrs. Clark is survived by her son
Arthur, of Tom ah; one sister, Mrs.
Hattie Kelly, o f Mauston, who is 91
years old; also many relatives and
friends.
Funeral services were conducted
from the White Funeral Home here
on Saturday afternoon at 2 o’clock,
the Rev. W. F. Schuelke officiating.
Interment was in Oak Grove cemetery.—
Tomah Monitor Herald
NOTICE TO ALBIO N
T A X P A Y E R S
The tax roll is now in my hands
for collection. I will be at the Albion
town hall every Friday and Saturday
in February for the purpose
of collecting taxes.
52 tf A. C. SANDBERG, Treas.
NOTICE TO A L M A T A X P A Y E R S
The tax roll for the town o f Alma
is now in my hands for collection. I
will be at the Alma Center bank each
Tuesday and at the Merrillan bank
each Saturday during February for
the purpose o f collecting taxes.
WM. HAYDON
6 2w Treas. Town o f Alma
Keller’s Laundry
Service
There will be laundry service
twice a week from Black River
Falls for Hixton, Alma Center
and Merrillan. The wagon will
call at LinnelFs Cafe, Hixton;
Harold Hanson’s Barber Shop,
Alma Center and Van Sickle’s
Meat Market, Merrillan, every
Tuesday and Thursday.
“ Let the Laundry Do It”
KELLER’S
BLACK RIV ER FALLS, W IS.
BO W LIN G N EW S
The weeks bowling served only to
tighten up the face for first place to
such an extent that the two teams
tied for second place are only one
game back o f the pace setting Chaimson
Maytags, the 4th place team is
only two games out and so on down
to the 7th spot Coca Cola outfit
which is only four games out o f first
place.
Tuesday night Camp Irving took a
pair from B. A. E although out hit
2496 to 2464. Jack Nandory led the
losers with 537 and Howard Gutgesell
led Camp Irving with 494.
In the 2d set the Chaimson Maytags
met up with the fast stepping
Tollack Coals and dropped a pair to
the Coals 2537 to 2408. Mahlon
Richards’ 598 led the Coals and Jack 
Sypulski’s 524 topped the Maytags.
Wednesday night in the first match
the Moe Clothing Co. took a pair
from the Jones Creams in another
match in which the winners were outscored,
2630 to 2570. Father Peters
nice 616 set led the winners and
Lud Gilbertson’s 568 paced the
Creams. In the second match the
Millis Contractors finally shook their
losing streak and won a pair from the
Jackson Box Co. 2565 to 2423. H.
Leicht led the Box makers with 442
and Gib Gomer with 529 topped Millis.
Thursday night saw a pair o f clean
sweeps. First S. C. S. won all three
from Coca Cola 2560 to 2517, and in
the second Hagen’s Clothiers won all
three from the Larkin Hardwares
2719 to 2321. Elwood Quick and
Tommy Mills were high for their
teams with 501 and 516 respectively
in the first match and in the second
set Ossie Kleven led Hagens with 571
and Myrle Haralson was high for the
Hardwares with 473.
The week’s best games:
Single Individual, Ossie Kleven .473
Set, Individual, Fr. P e te rs ........... 616
Single, Team, Jones Creams . . . .937
Set, Teams, Hagen Clothiers ..2 7 1 9
The Standings: Won Lost Pins
Chaimson Maytags . . . . 2 8 17 846
Hagen Clothiers ........... 27 18 863
Moe Clothing Co.............27 18 850
Tollack Coals ............... 26 19 788
B. A. E ............................25 20 838
Millis C ontractors........ 25 20 821
Coca C o la ........................24 21 774
Jones Creams ............... 21 24 783
S. C. S............................... 21 24 733
Larkin H ardw ares........ 16 29 784
Camp Irving ................. 16 29 734
Jackson Box Co.............. 14 31 638
The Big Ten: Father Peters, Moes,
193; O. Kleven, Hagens, 180; M.
Davis, Chaimsons, 178; A. Haralson,
Hagens, 175; C. Lipinski, Millis,
175; H. Cole, Chaimsons, 175; H.
Kleven, Hagens, 174; W. Boehm,
Moes, 174; S. Knudsen, B. A. E.,
174; R. Stai, B. A. E „ 173; J. Sypulski,
Chaimsons, 173.
Jan. 31
NOTICE
Bids will be received until February
11th for nine cords o f chunk
wood and two cords o f kindling wood
for the Oak Grove school house, Jt.
Dist. No. 8, Albion and Alma. The
Board reserves the right to accept or
reject any or all bids.
CLARA WUSSOW, Clerk
4 3w Route 4, City
TO IRVING TAXPAYERS
The tax roll for the Town o f Irvin
gis in my hands for collection. I
will be at the Black River Falls Implement
Co. in Black River Falls,
every Saturday and the last two
Tuesdays in the month o f February.
PALMER MIDELIEN
4 5w Tres. Town o f Irving
1st 2nd 3rd T ot.
G. A llen ........................... ....149 150 149 448
165 145 147 457
156 150 188 494
137 103 125 365
H. Zw eifel ........................ 129 144 145 418
94 94 94 282
T ota l ........................... 830 786 848 2464
B. A. E .:
...1 3 2 178 179 489
152 136 181 469
J. N andory ...................... ..... 154 199 184 537
R. Stai .............................. 177 195 122 494
S. K nudson ................. .... .....159 148 155 462
H andicap .................... .....15 15 15 45
.....'789 871 236 2496
Jan. 31
Chaim son M aytags :
1st 2nd 3rd T ot.
. 200 131 193 524
H. Cole .......................... ..... 135 165 205 505
O. Iserloth ..................... ..... 168 147 145 460
R. Lund ............. .......... .....177 123 149 449
M. D avis ............ ............ .....156 145 145 446
H andicap ....................... ... 8 8 8 24
T ollack C oals:
H. H. R icharsd ...... 181 166 137 484
A . H agen ........................ .....162 137 148 447
D. P erry .......................... 162 179 115 456
O. T ollack .................... 159 170 151 480
191 137 170 498
H andicap .................. 54 54 54 162
909 853 775 2537
Feb. 1
Jones Creams—
1st 2nd 3rd T ot.
L. G ilbertson ................ 208 163 197 568
B. Jones ............................ 161 159 104 424
H om er R ichards ......... 169 176 151 496
190 144 143 477
151 141 199 491
....58 58 58 174
T otal ............ ............ ......937 841 852 2630
M oe C lothing Co.—
140 142 197 479
156 166 159 481
H. P op p ...... 166 188 127 481
W . Boehm ..................... ...... 147 166 179 492
190 213 213 6 6
7 7 7 21
......806 882 882 2570
Feb. 1
Jackson B ox C o.:
1st 2nd 3rd T ot.
. ,130 159 153 442
....105 104 149 358
E. Gardner ..................... 114 111 134 359
98 126 324
E. R eber 145 161 133 439
167 167 167 501
Total .......................... 761 800 862 2423
Millis C ontractors—
W . Jones ..... .................... ...... 163 178 168 509
R. M illis ........ ................. .. .163 173 152 488
M. Stenulson ................ 154 174 137 465
... .188 160 181 629
C. Lipinski ...... 148 179 160 487
H andicap ...... 29 29 29 87
Feb 2
1st 2nd 3rd T ot.
S. C. S .:
E. Quick 178 165 158 501
R . W o lff ......................... ...... 176 137 142 455
R. Rasm ussen ................ 104 151 117 872
Osborne Johnson ......... ...... 105 168 158 431
J. Zellinger ..... ............... ...... 157 163 157 477
H andicap ....................... 108 108 108 324
T ota l ..................„ ..... ...... 828 892 840 2560
C oca C ola:
G. Sullivan ..................... ...... 143 177 181 501
R . K rohn ....................... .164 157 148 469
H. Galston ................. . ...... 116 158 104 378
E. R in g r o s e ..... ............... ... 152 156 153 461
T . Mills ............ ...... ............... 184 164 168 516
H andicap ........................ ...64 64 64 192
T ota l .................................823 876 818 2517
Feb. 2
H agen C lothiers:
1st 2nd 3rd T ot.
E. R udolph 173 223 146 542
A . H aralson 191 198 151 540
O. K leven ............................176 168 227 571
M. H aug .................................194 153 199 546
H. Kleven ........... .................. 148 192 180 520
T ota l .................................882 934 903 2719
Larkin H ardw are:
M. H aralson 144 188 141 473
N. Larkin ............................. 155 145 96 396
M. W erner ............................131 137 152 420
0 . Johnson ................. .......... 135 105 171 411
C arl P fla n i ... ......................159 146 160 465
H andicap .............................. 52 52 52 156
W O M A N ’ S B O W L I N G C L U B
J a n . 1 6
I t s e e m s e v e r y w e e k s o m e o n e g o e s
w ild a n d b o w l s w a y o v e r t h e i r h e a d .
T h i s w e e k i t w a s H a z e l K n u d s e n w it h
h i g h s in g l e o f 2 1 2 a n d 1 5 4 , 1 5 1 a n d
2 1 2 f o r 5 1 7 f o r h i g h s e t . M a r g a r e t
T a n n e r ’ s 1 4 7 , 1 1 3 a n d 1 4 1 f o r 4 0 1
h a d s e c o n d h i g h s e t.
T h e S t a n d i n g s : W o n L o s t
M illis T r a n s f e r s ................................1 6 8
L e s t e r s .................................................1 3 11
B . R . C a f e .......................................... 1 1 1 3
I . G . A ........................................................ 9 1 5
T h e B i g F iv e — H a z e l K n u d s e n 1 4 1 ,
M a r y B lo o m 1 3 0 , J o y c e M c M a n n e r s
1 2 8 , B e a t r i c e Z a h r t e 1 2 6 a n d A l i c e
Z a h r t e 1 2 6 .
Millis T ran sfers:
Hazel Knudsen .................. 154 151 212 517
A lice Zahrte ....................... 124 146 112 382
T ootie G om er ................. ..... 119 90 96 305
A gnes Millis ......................... 90 91 88 269
Celia T ollefson su b 100 123 126 349
T otals ................. ...............587 601 634 1822
1. G. A .—
Lorraine Rutland ............. 77 75 98 250
F em e Johnson .................... 91 134 141 366
M argaret Tanner ..............147 113 141 401
M ary B loom .................... 99 119 103 321
Delores H anson su b 80 63 69 212
H andicap ............................ 30 30 30 90
T otals .................................624 534 582 1640
L esters:
J o y ce McM anners ..............128 118 120 366
Helen Fisher su b . 152 98 93 343
D olly K leven .......................114 96 103 313
B etty Prehn ......................... 89 106 88 283
L ouise H elbling .................. 132 96 98 326
H andicap ............................ 32 32 32 96
T otals 647 546 534 1727
Black R iver C afe:
B eatrice Zahrte 126 101 138 365
B abe Johnson .....................112 93 70 275
N eva G irouard ..................... 99 96 98 293
D ora Davis .......................... 90 139 88 308
Edna Sullivan .....................117 132 91 340
H andicap 3 3 3 9
T otals ................. ............ 547 555 488 1590
Jan. 23
The maples were quite difficult to
push around this week, resulting in
several splits for most o f us. It
couldn’t be that we were hitting that
head pin in the nose, no— not much!
Millis Transfers took 2 from Lesters
and B. R. Cafe took all 3 from
I. G. A.
The Standings: Won Lost
Lesters .......................................14 13
Millis T ra n sfers....................... 18 9
B. R. Falls C a f e .......................14 13
I. G. A .......................................... 9 18
The Big Five: Hazel Knudsen
141, Mary Bloom 128, Joyce McManners
128, Beatrice Zahrte 127 and
Alice Zahrte 127.
Hazel Knudsen had high single of
169 and high triple o f 169, 148 and
125 for 442. Beatrice Zahrte was
second high with 418 and Alice Zahrte
third with 405.
COMMON SENSE CO N SERVATIO N
By L. H. Kingston
Assemblyman Youngs, o f Oconto,
is introducing a bill to compel the
conservation department to open fire
lanes to deer hunters. Mr. Youngs
no doubt believes that his proposal,
if it becomes a law, would be a favor
to deer hunters, but in this he is certainly
mistaken and sportsmen, conservationists
and deer hunters themselves
should oppose his bill.
Fire lanes are built into wild, remote
and inaccessible regions for the
sole purpose o f controlling forest
fires which, once started would otherwise
burn tremendous areas. We do
not have to think back very far to
remember when many o f our northern
counties were nothing but fire
blackened wastes. Now all that has
been changed and the acreage burned
annually by forest fires is almost
negligible all due to an efficient forest
fire prevention system put in e ffect
and maintained by the conservation
department.
Remote and inaccessible regions
are few enough these days and we
all ought to want those we have left
preserved. Many o f our native birds
and animals will live only in solitudes
and if we want to preserve these species
we must maintain wild places
for them to live in. Because they
are hard for the average hunter to
penetrate, these areas have always
formed fine refuges for deer and especially
bears. No matter how many
deer were killed in an open season
there were always plenty left in the
far places for seed.
When fire lanes were cut through
these natural refuges there was a
good deal o f apprehension as to the
effect they would have on the wild
life, but the threat o f forest fires
left little choice; then, too, the conservation
department had ruled that
fire lanes would be closed except to
fire fighters.
Now comes this bill to throw fire
lanes wide open. Who is behind this
proposal? Certainly not fair minded
sportsmen. There is, however, one
type o f hunter that I can think o f
who would heartily favor this bill—
I refer to the meat hunter type, the
man who wants to go where he can
Millis T ransfers:
A lice Zahrte ..........................149 111 145 405
H azel Knudsen .................. 169 148 125 442
T ootie G om er ................. ..... 120 92 114 326
Helen Fisher ....................... 112 114 116 342
A gnes Millis .......................103 111 144 358
L este rs:
J ayce M cM anners ............. 119 120 138 377
Clarice B axter ..................... 131 106 89 326
L ouise H elbling 60 137 111 308
B etty Prehn 131 125 98 354
D olly K leven ....................... 100 141 113 354
H andicap 32 32 32 96
B. R. C afe:
Edna Sullivan 91 106 101 298
D ora D avis 117 103 102 322
Babe Johnson ....................... 103 120 90 313
N eva G irouard 100 84 93 277
B eatrice Zahrte 127 153 138 418
H andicap 11 u n 33
1. G. A .:
M argaret Tanner 135 112 105
Fern Johnson ....................... 94 87 89
M ary B loom ......................... 89 131 111
L orraine Rulland ................ 83 71 106
M ildred A nderson .............. 80 83 78
H andicap ....................... 28 28 28
T otals .............................. 609 512 517
The Thrift of A B R A H A M
L I N C O L N
When Abraham
Lincoln was a
lawyer in Springfield
Illinois, his annual earnings were
only $1,500 to $2,000, largely because
of his low fees. In one of his letters he
writes: "If the case is as stated I will
handle the case before the Supreme
Court for ten dollars."
Yet Lincoln made regular deposits in
a local savings bank over a period of
12 years. He saved one half of his
£25,000 salary as President. He left
an estate valued at $110,974.62— equal
to $500,000 today. •
Jackson County Bank
Black River Falls, Wis.
With Stations at T «yloc, Hixton, Alma Center and Merrillaa
jump out o f his car and start shooting.
W
e grant that there have been
abuses in connection with the control
o f fire lanes; game wardens and fire
wardens have practiced favoritism,
fire lanes have not been closed soon
enough so that some groups have
been locked out while earlier groups
were not, some unauthorized individuals
have been given keys, all o f
which has made a bad impression
among people in some localities, but
those are minor administrative problems.
Certainly they are no evcuse for
throwing the whole system o f fire
lanes open to the modem horde o f
gunners.
If you have the welfare o f our
wild life at heart why not let your
legislature at Madison know how you
feel about keeping fire lanes closed.
■INCOME TAX CONSULTANT.
STATE FEDERAL
LEO W. FOSTER
NEILLSVILLE, WISCONSIN
Phone Red 126
A Suggestion from the Tender Krust Bakers
SERVE A VARIETY OF BREADS AND TOAST
An economical and simple way to add extra interest to each meal
T K Rye L oaf— Light Am erican Rye Bread
T K Milwaukee Rye A heavier rye loaf.
T K W hole W heat— W ith that nutty whole wheat flavor.
T K Kracked W heat— Nutritious; supplies healthful roughage
T K Graham— Fine Textured and Tasty.
T K Raisin White W edn esdays — A real treat.
T K Vienna L oaf— T h ursdays — A Hearth Baked bread.
T K Date Nut Bread— F rid a y s — Dates and Chopped Walnuts.
Your Toaster Will Tell You the Quality Story
Tender Krust Baking Co.
Eau Claire, Wisconsin
SHIP VIA
BRIGGS
TRANSFER
CO.
Daily Refrigerated
Service
To and From
Chicago and
Twin Cities
Experienced Household
Goods Moving
Phone 435
BLACK RIVER FALLS
EYE OPENERI W ith
a ll its ex tr a v a lu e , this
Buick sedan lists a t $ 5 1
less th an a y e a r a g o !
R i g h t now we’d like to point
out that with the first feel of
spring in the air, there’s going to be
another scramble to get these beautiful
new Buicks.
There’s going to be a rush to get
behind this great car’s lively Dynaflash
straight eight power plant, to
take in the budding countryside
from behind its new wide paned
windows.
There’ll be a sudden hurry
to trade in cars that have
begun to pass their prime,
and step out in the cushioned
smoothness of Bui 
Coil Springing’s full float
ride.
No question about that, not when
you recall last fall, when we had to
sell cars on a five and six week delivery
basis.
On the other hand, you can get rid
of a lot of grief by trading an old
car now. Get rid of weak batteries,
slick tires, slow starting engines,
brakes that may be needing a relining
job soon.
Y ou’ll get a car in this well made,
well mannered, well groomed new
Buick that’ll take the rest of the
N O O T H E R C A R IN T H E W O R L D
H A S A L L T H E S E F E A T U R E S
 D Y N A F L A S H V A L V E I N H E A D S T R A IG H T E IG H T
E N G I N E B U I C O I L T O R Q U E F R E E S P R I N G I N G
 G R E A T E R V IS IB ILITY H A N D IS H IF T T R A N S M IS S IO N
 R O O M IE R U N ISTE EL B O D Y B Y FISHER T O R Q U E 
T U B E D R I V E T I P T O E H Y D R A U L I C B R A K E S
 C R O W N S P R IN G C L U T C H " C A T W A L K C O O L I N G "
 O P T I O N A L R E A R A X L E G E A R R A T IO S F L A S H 
W A Y D IR E C T IO N S IG N A L S E L F B A N K IN G
K N E E A C T I O N F R O N T S P R I N G I N G
Easy on the eye— easy to buy— on G en era l
M otors term s!
winter right in stride, and just be
warmed up when spring comes.
Y ou ’ll get it at p rices low er than
a yea r ago, lo w er than you d exp ect,
lo w er even than on som e sixes.
You’ll get a better allowance on the
car you’re now driving—and like as
not avoid some heavy servicing
bills.
So why wait until sometime “in the
spring’’ ? Shop early for your Buick,
the most satisfying car you ever
drove—shop wisely and avoid the
rush!
U thi. m i.htr Buick Dyn»fl» t»
a u e s t o p t h e earn u 
deI „ •»!' « " “ " crT 'Metier buu Buick NOWT EXEMPLAR OF GENERAL MOTORS VAIUE
E A R L H A R D Y
Black River Fails, Wis.
THE BANNER JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin PAGE NO. 3
P E R SO N ALS
Mrs. Gus Johnson visited in Eau
Claire last Saturday.
Mrs. C. I. Nielsen was an Eau
Claire caller last Saturday.
Mrs. Fred Krome spent a day or
two last week with Mrs. B. W. Hicks.
Mrs. Oscar Olson entertained the
Card and Thimble club Tuesday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Ray Gile are in St.
Paul for the week, going up last Sunday.
,
Mrs. Edwin Pierce was at Taylor
last Friday visiting at the Roy Comstock
home.
Mrs. George Dean and children visited
in La Crosse from Thursday until
Sunday.
Mrs. Southworth o f Whitehall, was
a guest at the Van Sickle home over
the week end.
Mr. and Mrs. Bud Comstock o f
Taylor, viisted friends and relatives
here last Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. J. S. Johnson o f
Levis, were business callers in the
village on Monday.
A son was born to Mr. and Mrs.
Walter Simonson at the Krohn hospital
last Thursday.
Rev. Grover and Miss Link, o f
Kendall, were last Sunday guests at
the H. Van Winter home.
Mr. and Mrs. August Manzow of
Plain view, Minn., were visiting his
father here Saturday and Sunday.
Orley Beck o f Merrill, and Senator
Kroneberg o f Wausau, were Sunday
guests at the L. L. Sherman home.
Mrs. Sam Vincent has gone to Sycamore,
111., to be with her daughter,
who is rather ill at the present time.
Mrs. George Purnell entertained
the Study club Tuesday. Mrs. Harry
Comstock presented the Study Club
lesson.
Miss Jean Barritt, who is attending
Eau Claire State Teachers college
was home recently for an over Sunday
visit.
Mr. and Mrs. Lew Pitcher went to
Altoona last Saturday to help Mr.
and Mrs. Bruce Smith celebrate their
first wedding anniversary.
Mrs. Addie Russell is helping with
the household duties o f Mrs. Anna
Forbush while the latter is nursing a
broken arm. And Mrs. Forbush, by
the way, is getting along very nicely.
Billy Gile arranged a surprise party
for his mother a few days ago to
which several ladies were invited.
Games, etc., helped to pass a very
pleasant evening. A picnic lunch was
served.
Gordon Sutton left for Chicago on
Friday where he is taking a month’s
study on refrigeration and air conditioning.
Gordon has been taking a
correspondence course on these subjects
for the past year and a half and
the course is finished with actual
work with material along that line.
A fter the month he hopes for a job
and all his friends hope so too.
The local cribbage club met with
Eric Erickson last Friday evening.
Mrs. Erickson, another one o f Merrillan’s
good cooks, served a fine 6:30
dinner and o f course the boys were
all hungry. The score for the evening
was as follows: O. F. Peterson
210, Fred Helbling 188, Gib Gile for
Nels Erickson 160, Camden Nolop
160, Joe Stiehl 159, Ed Persson 15S,
Robert Hamilton 123, Eric Erickson
112, Clarence Johnson 111, Oscar
Erickson 105, Oscar Rickard 105,
Harry Hendrix 88.
The R. N. A. recently elected their
new officers for the ensuing year
and they were installed at the home
o f Mrs. Emma Rickard just a short
tima ago. They are: Mrs. Hannah
Hayden, Or.; Mrs. Iva Sutton, V. O.;
Mrs. Julia Hicks, P. O .; Mrs, Nellie
Hamilton, R ec.; Mrs. Laura Dahlstrom,
Recorder; Mrs. Emma Rickard
and Mrs. Gladys Quinn, Marshals;
Mrs. Nolop, In. Sen.; Mrs.
Ruth Motte, O. Sen.; Mrs. Bird
Granger, Chap.
The Royal Neighbors entertained
33 members at a 6:30 dinner at the
Campbell cafe last Monday night,
hiany coming over from Alma Center.
A fter dinner they adjourned to
the home o f Mrs. Persson and the
balance o f the evening was enjoyed
playing 500 and Chinese checkers.
For 500 Mrs. Joos was high and Mrs.
Edwards low. In checkers Mrs. Sobczak
was high and Mrs. Jennie Dunn
low. A very delightful evening was
enjoyed.
A number o f ladies o f the North
Branch Homemakers club spent the
day recently at the C. J. Johnson
home. Those present were Mrs. Lawrence
Krueger, Mrs. M. Simons, Mrs.
Otto Kutz, Mrs. Enoch Enerson, Mrs.
Claire Enerson and little son, and
Miss Blondine Nohelty. A picnic
dinner and a 4 o’clock lunch was enjoyed
by all.
Word was received here last Tuesday
o f the death o f Dr. E. M. Rogers
of Rice Lake. Doctor Rogers was a
dentist and in the 1890’s was operating
in Augusta and for a long time
had an office here in Merrillan, coming
down once a week or so. He will
be remembered by many o f the early
residents.
MORE SICK, MORE AILIN G
Miss Rogene Olson, daughter o f Mr.
and Mrs. Harold Olson, was taken
to the hospital at B. R. Falls last
week and an operation for the removal
o f the appendix performed.
Mrs. George Bouchard was operated
at the county hospital last week
for an infected appendix.
Mrs. Archie Elmore was taken to
the “ Pines” , a sanitorium near Stevens
Point, last Thursday, where she
will receive treatment for a month or
so.
Evert Lunderville is confined to his
home since last Tuesday with one
foot wrapped in bandages. He and
his father were splitting wood, and
the axe handle broke and the axe
kept on going, hitting his foot, cutting
off the end o f the second toe
and cutting a deep gash in the big
toe. Dr. Hewson was called and he
attended the injury and Mr. Lunderville
is getting along nicely.
Mrs. Eva La Zotte was operated
on last week at the Krohn hospital
for the removal o f appendix.
Mrs. Anna Erickson has been obliged
to remain in bed for several
days because o f high blood pressure,
but is improving.
Giles Rickard was entertaining
“ miseries” the first o f the week from
the effects o f having some teeth pulled.
TH AN K S
I wish to express my thanks and
appreciation to the doctors and the
nurses at the Krohn clinic for all the
good care and kindness I received
while there. I also wish to express
my sincere thanks and appreciation to
others for all the nice cards and letters
,and especially do I thank Mrs.
Donald Clifford and Mrs. Thompson
for the nice sunshine baskets, and to
the ladies sewing project for their
lovely gift.
BESSIE AMUNDSON
Last Wednesday one o f the worst
snow storms hit throughout this section.
It was accompanied by a heavy
wind from the east. In the afternoon
it almost turned to rain.
A daughter was bom to Mr. and
Mrs. Elmo Johnson at the hospital
at B. R. Falls last Friday. The new
mother was formerly Miss Alice Rickard
o f this village.
PRISCILLA NOTES
The Priscillas were hostesses on
Tuesday, Jan. 31, to the ladies o f the
village at an International Fellowship
tea. The following program was given:
S
ong— Assembly
Prayer
Song— Assembly
Purpose o f Fellowship Tea— Mrs.
Fahlgren
Violin solo— Mr. Davidson
Foreign Missions— Mrs. Stuart Olson
Home Missions— Mrs. Kelly
A poem, “ The Burden” — Florence
Porter
American Bible Society— Mrs. Virgil
Oliver
Workers o f Good Will— Mrs. Willard
Nichols
Christian Education — Frances
Johnson
Song— Assembly
Mrs. Ray Auston was organist
Following the program tea was
served at a beautifully appointed table.
Sweet peas were given for the
occasion by Mrs. S. Olson and Misses
Hanson and Smith. Mrs. Fahlgren
and Mrs. Kelly poured tea.
Every one present had a very enjoyable
afternoon and look forward
to the fourth tea to be given next
year.
M ETH O DIST CHURCH
F. A. Fahlgren, Pastor
L in coln'! Sunday:
Humbird:
9:30 Public worship
10:40 Sunday school
Alma Center:
10:00 Sunday school
11:00 Public worship
7 :00 Epworth League
M errillan:
1 0 :00 Sunday school
7 :30 Public worship
6 :45 Epworth League
Church supper is being planned for
Thursday, Feb. 16.
Jesus said: “ And every one that
heareth these saying o f mine and doeth
them not, shall be likened unto a
foolish man, which built his house upon
the sand” . Matt 7 :26.
Mrs. Kelly and Mrs. Fahlgren will
be co hostesses to the Priscillas on
Tuesday, Feb. 14, at the home o f the
latter. It will be in the nature o f a
valentine party.
M ERR ILLAN M IXTU RE
Editor ..................... Geneva Rhoades
M errillan Taylor Game
The second Merrillan Taylor game
C o E d itor.................... John Jarolimek I was fought to a fare thee well at the
S p o rts ......................... John Jarolimek
H u m o r..............................Who Knows
Social ..............................Lottie Pasek
Class —Frances Larson, Esther Buttek,
Virginia Christianso n, Vivian
Ransom, Minnie Sorlie and June
Meyers.
A 10 pound son was born to Mr.
and Mrs. Vance Bates last Wednesday,
Feb. 1st. The youngster has
been named Vance Lionel. Mother
and child are doing nicely and Vance
seems to be in good health too.
A bad chimney fire at the home o f
Adolph Thompson last Wednesday at
11:10 a. m. called out the fire department.
It was a bad morning for
a fire, as the wind was blowing a
terrific gale.
Several ladies surprised Mrs. J. H.
Stiehl at her home last Saturday evening
to help her celebrate her birthday.
It is authentically reported that
Merrillan will have a resident doctor
on March 1st. 
Drops from the Co E ditor’s Pen
We have just passed the first week
after our semester finals and perhaps
this is rather a good time to say some
thing about learning and types o f ;1
learning. . ' 
Almost everyone wili agree that no
two students grasp things exactly
alike, but we can divide them gener 
Taylor gym last Friday. In spite o f
the final score o f 37 16, we think it
was a good game. Both o f the teams
were right in there fighting for the
ball.
Merrillan was first to score with a
beautiful long shot, almost from the
center o f the gym, made by Olson.
Taylor came back with a basket almost
instantly. This shot, was from
the center o f the floor. Again Merrillan
scored and took the lead for
the first few minutes. Then Taylor
Waged ahead and stayed ahead for
the rest o f the game. Merrillan had
the ball in their possession more o ften
and longer than Taylor, but it
1st and 2nd Grades
Last Friday afternoon we brought
our favorite books to school. We
spent most o f the afternoon looking
at pictures and reading stories.
We made a Lincoln and Washing
ton border for our room. We are
busy making valentines, now.
These pupils got 100 in their spelling
test last Friday— Junior Andrews
Larry Anger, Janet Bates, Phil Barrett,
Dorothy Blazek, Clajrton Erickson,
Eline Erickson, Bobby Ehlers,
Robert Galtrude, Alvina Illbeck,
Clarita Illbeck, Charlotte Nash, Ronald
Olver, and Laura Mae Rush.
M ONDAY NIGHT LEAGU E
The Monday night league boys
went to Alma Center and played
their team. The Merrillan boys won
25 to 12. These boys are coached
every Monday night by Geo. Frost.
This is very important because the
boys learn fundamentals and rudiments
o f good basket ball and know
what it is all about when they go
out for basket ball in high school.
The line up:
R. Andrews G, H. Benson G, R.
Walters C, B. Kearney F, H. Butterfield
F, V. Simonson G, K. Anger C,
Herrick F, B. Austin F, V. Van Sickle
G.
Tande G, Bartholomew G, Johnson
C, Van Gorden F, J. Van Gilder F,
M. Van Gilder G, Ness G, Borchard
C, Rousy F, Speth F.
LOST, FOUND AND W AN TED
LOST— A report card. Can be
easily identified by the four red “ F” .
It belongs to one o f the freshies.
LOST— Dignity— the dignified seniors.
FOUND— Lipstick in Tom Crago’s
car. It probably belongs to his
mother. 
WANTED— A new car with windows
not o f cardboard. The Crago
Brothers.
WANTED— A nice quiet assembly
period to catch up on sleep in.— Dorothy
Quinn.
WANTED— A girl friend that can
play the sax, by John Jarolimek.
The other day Mr. Schultz was
telling his Chemistry class about the
wonders o f 1939. He said that he
was getting gas the other day from a
fellow who filled the tank with a
cigarette in his mouth. When asked
if he did that often the fellow replied
that it was safe enough because “he
lit it with a safety match” .
Mr. Schultz: “ I take great pleasure
in giving you a 90 in General
Science.”
Shirley A .: “ Aw, make it a 100
and really enjoy yourself.”
Teacher: “ Now, Robert, what is
the nitch in a church?”
Bobby: “ Why, it is the same as
an itch anywhere else, only you can’t
scratch it as well.”
Miss Hilger: “ If you subtract 25
from 37, what’s the difference?”
Student: “ That’s what I say,
teacher— I think it’s the bunk too.”
Father o f Joke Columist: “ I don’t
care if you are the editor o f the joke
column or not; you arn’t going to
get funny with me.”
Mr. Davidson: “ Do you know
Lincoln’s Gettysburg Address?”
Virg. Bates: “ No, I didn’t know
he lived there.”
ally into these four groups: T h o s e Jfeemed that they couldn’t do anywho
learn fast and forget easily; 11 J‘ J 1
those who learn easily and forget
slowly; those who learn slowly and
forget slowly, and those who learn
slowly and forget fast.
Just glancing over these we can
see that all these students have not
the same chance in the school. Perhaps
some o f the students we have
fail in normal high school work, but
would be successful in a vocational
or trade 9chool.
There is another kind o f a student
we have. Every school has one or
more. This is the kind that really
have normal and average intelligence
but are too lazy and indifferent to
use it. Modern subjects and teaching
are doing away with this type of
person.
After reading this small discussion
on learners, you will, perhaps, be able
to understand why some students do
superior work and others— opposite.
We have the big problem o f ability
and also the initiative to use this
ability. Pass or— fail.
Soil Conservation
Last Mon jay morning two young 
men from the Irving camp at Black | English Literature very interesting—
 — :n" " O'’ '''"1 we are now reading the play “ Mac
thing with it when they did have it.
Taylor controlled most o f the jump
balls and really went for baskets
when they got the ball.
We are sorry we were unable to
get the box score for you this week
but we will publish it next week on
request. The score was Taylor 37;
Merrillan 16. Nowak from Eau
Claire refereed the game.
Seniors
Each member o f the Social Problems
Class has submitted a plan o f
Merrillan and how he would like to
have it. One o f the plans will be
USfed when we make our model village.
Juniors
In Chemistry for the past week, the
Juniors have been studying the chapter
on ions, which brought forth a
test this Monday.
Last Friday, in History class, we
had the most interesting current
events we have ever had this year.
Every Friday the class is assigned to
bring current events. Mr. Davidson
remarks: “ What is going on today
is what makes history.”
Miss Smith is making our study o f
beth” , b’T Shakespeare. She also
made it more interesting by giving
us a new seating arrangement like
Mr. Davidson.
Another member has dropped from
our class— Mary Ann Bouchard which
leaves the total a mere 15.
River visited Merrillan high school
and entertained the grades and the
high school students with slides about
erosion. It showed the different
types and the different ways o f preventing
it.
When questions were asked, most
o f us were surprised to hear our upand 
coming young farmers give the
correct answers.
Music Notes
The band and orchestra are progressing
as we have seen from the
last pep meeting and at the play
sponsored by the band last Monday
night. The girl’s Glee club has some
excellent voices which are to be heard
in the school concert scheduled for
Friday, February 17th.
Vocal and instrumental solos and
duets will add much to the band and
orchestra program for that evening.
A large attendance, at the popular
prices o f 5, 10 and 15 cents, is desired,
because part of the proceeds
will go for gowns to be used by our
girls at the Eau Claire musical festival
in May.
Letter Club H onor Roll u A f a a t t 01 cl“' 01 ~ S ‘ .prid jr Seniors— Frances Larson, 98 ; Dale
Austin, 83; John Jarolimek, 76.
Juniors— Virginia E., 94; Geneva
Rhoades, 82; Esther Buttke, 77.
Sophomores — Virginia Ch., 6 6 ;
Dorothy Nash, 63; Marcella Heath,58.
Freshmen— Shirley Austin, 69; Suzanne
Helbling, 65; Carolyn Olson,60.
Sophomores
In English class the Sophomores
have been studying biographies.
In World History there are two
students each day that find outside
material and give a report concerning
the lesson. The reports lately have
been mostly on the Renaissance.
Rogene Olson is absent from school
with an operation for appendicitis.
5th and 6th Grades
 The 6th grade has finished their
North Sea country’ bulletin board.
They have some very attractive cutwork
posters o f Holland.
The 5th grade pupils are fixing a
geography bulletin board o f advertising
material o f all the different
things manufactured in the Central
States.
Twenty two out o f 24 received 100 |
Our contest is
NORTH BRANCH
Arnold Giese visited Sunday at
Mike Janke's.
Charlie Pinhack visited at Louie
Janke’s, Tuesday.
Mr. and Mrs. Louie Janke were at
Johin Janke’s, Saturday.
Miss Ruby Kutz spent last week at
home from her school duties at Madison.
 •
E. H. Thayer and family were dinner
guests at Mrs. Almeda Ormsby’s
on Sunday.
Mrs. Jennie Stolts and Mrs. Amelia
Dorrance spent Tuesday at Harvey
Carpenter’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Kutz o f Eau
Claire, spent Sunday and Monday at
Otto Kutz’.
Mike, August and Chester Janke
were callers at Louie Janke’s, Sunday
evening.
Miss Marjorie Nelson o f New Richmond,
spent a few days last week
with Ruby Kutz.
Mr. and Mrs. Otto Kutz attended
the funeral o f Mrs. Kutz’ aunt at
Portage last Saturday.
John and Casper Nygaard and Lin 
A w u t a t fflattBim
 uur y im rra l S irrrto r
Ambulance Service
Nearly a Quarter Century o f
Service
B LA CK R IV E R F A L L S, W IS.
Grades 3 and 4
Mrs. Zinn and Mrs. Barrett visited I
our room last Tuesday afternoon.
We had another musical program in
the music room Friday afternoon.
Miss Williams came to hear our selections.
Nancy Purnell played two
 piano solos entitled: “ The Bluejay
iT T C N n A v r i: i Mazurka” and “ My Puppy” . Phyllis
PERFECT A TTE N D AN C E Fahlgren played “ The Nightingale !
Those who have perfect attendance j Song” and “ Alabama Cabin” ; Viva J
in high school this year so far are: Erickson sang “ Mr. Dolly” ; Esther,
Dale Austin, Elwood Austin, Shirley ! Patsy and Irene sang “ A Song for |
I Austin, Betty Gearing, Belva Gold February” ; three group.s o f boys and '
I smith, Letha Goldsmith, Forrest Hal j girls in our room sang ‘Lovely Even !
| verson, Suzanne Helbling, Kathleen ! ing” and two groups sang the “ Kite |
j Kutcher, Luella Kutcher, Geraldine iSong” in two part harmony. We en 
Quinn.
We have named our annuals “ The
400” . W e are planning on having
some advertising in them. This is
to help toward the cost o f our annu 
I als. We have signed a contract for
I joyed every number, and we are look 
| ing forward to another musical program
soon.
Mr. Olson: Kenny, did I hear
you swearing?”
Kenny: “ I don’t know,
our annuals including pictures, etc. you listening?”
Were
 Falls Theatre 
Black River Falls, Wis.
TH U R SD AY, FR ID A Y SAT.
FEB. 9, 10, 11
Double Feature
TEX RITTER in
“ Song of the
Gringo”
with
Monte Blue
Fuzzy Knight
also
Noah Beery Jr.
Dorthea Kent in
“ Some Blondes
are Dangerous”
with
Wm. Gargan
Nan Grey
Two free candy bars with each
paid adm. Saturday at Matinee
at 2:0 0 Adm. 10 20c
SUN., MON., TUES., W ED .
FEB. 12, 13, 14, 15
JOEL McCREA and
ANDREA LEEDS in
“ Youth Takes
a Fling”
with
Frank Jenks and
Dorothea Kent
Matinee Sunday at 2:00
Adm. 10 and 20c
dahl Melbye visited at Archie Barnett’s,
Monday evening.
Miss Darlene Laing spent the week
end with her grandparents, Mr. and
Mrs. Christ Johnson o f Hixton.
A few friends helped Marie Simons
celebrate her birthday at Lorenz
Krueger’s, Saturday evening.
Miss Kathryn Burnett spent from
Thursday until Sunday at her home
from her school duties at Madison.
Ralph Sheffer and family, Anton
Varklick and family and Jamie Lyons
spent Friday evening at Nvgaard
 Melby’s.
A shower was given Mrs. Francis
Bergerson, nee Eleanor Hanson, at
the Nygaard Melbye home Friday
afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Enoch Enerson and
Blondine Nohelty, also Mr. and Mrs.
Morris Emerson and son Dean were
guests at Claire Enerson’s, Sunday.
Mrs. Stanley Laing and daughters,
Darlene and Violet, also Mrs. Lorenr
Krueger and Marie Simons attended
the junior class play at Hixton Friday
night.
friend from Eau Claire were visiting
at the Graf home.
Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Frost were at
Alma Center to attend her brother,
Albert Casper’s funeral, Monday.
Mrs. Eva La Zotte was operated at
the hospital for appendicitis, Friday.
Ray Jacobson came from Milwaukee
last week.
Mrs. Krome and son Lester came
from B. R. Falls and she will remain
for a few days and help care for
Mrs. B. W. Hicks.
Barney Rhodes was very pleasantly
surprised by his friends at his home
to help him celebrate his birthday.
500 was enjoyed by all.
Members o f the W. R. C. met at
Mrs. C. Nolop’s, Thursday, and got a
quilt ready to tie, which will be sent
to the Waupaca Home soon as it is
finished.
PINE CREEK
Mrs. Axel Sedahl and daughters
called at Melvin Kinney’s, Saturday.
Menford Bersing and family spent
Saturday evening at Calmer Halverson’s.
Elmer Anderson and family called
at Wallie Satrum’s, one evening o f
last week.
Mr. and Mrs. Wm. Perpr and children
spent Sunday evening at Calmer
Halverson’s.
Miss Ella Anderson will entertain
the Pine Creek Ladies Aid on Friday,
Feb. 17. Every one welcome.
Mrs. Harry Chrisinger and Harold
spent Sunday at Elmer Anderson’s.
Miss Kathleen spent the day at Halverson’s.
Pay your subscription to the B J
now. Only $2.00 for the year.
M ERRILLAN
Mrs. Clifford Christianson is home
and feeling fine.
Mrs. J. C. Hooker is improving
slowly and can sit up a while each
day.
Ruth Jacobson o f Altoona, visited
her mother and other relatives one
day last week.
The Crago Players will assist the
high school band in a play tonight in
the gymnasium.
Hugh Barrett is home form the
hospital and is feeling good, which all
are glad to know.
Mrs. Clem Graf and baby, and a
DO YOUR FEET HURT?????
DR. JOHN S. BALL
FOOT SPECIALIST
will be at the
FREEMAN HOTEL
MONDAY, FEBRUARY 20, 1939
FOR APPOINTMENT CALL 127
. . . an d a g a in in 1939
p eo p le e v e ry w h e re a re sa y in g ,
"CHEVROLET’S THE CHOICE!” 
Chevrolet outsells all others because Chevrolet
out values all others! That’s the
verdict of discerning buyers in all parts of
the country, and it will be your verdict,
too, when you weigh the many extra value
features Chevrolet is offering. Modern
features— important features—exclusive
features like Vacuum Gearshift , Valvein 
Head Engine, New "Observation Car”
Visibility, Perfected Knee Action Riding
Systemf, and Tiptoe Matic Clutch—features
available nowhere else at such
' " ‘e r , ,
A Gonoral M otors V alue
extremely low prices! Only Chevrolet
gives so much for so little, and that is why
— "Chevrolet’s the Choice!”
 At'ailabl on all model at alight extra coat. Available on Master D e Luxe model only.
SEE YO U R LOCAL CHEVROLET DEALER
HARDY CHEVROLET CO.
BLACK RIVER FALLS, WISCONSIN
 w m STANDARD RED CROWN
G E T T H I S S P E C I A L W I N T E R G A S O L I N E F R O M T O U R S T A N D A R D O I L D E A L E R
PAGE NO. 4 rHE BANNER JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin
Subscription p rice $2.00 jer year.
E ntered at the p oa toffice a t Black R iver
Falls as second class m atter.
M ERLIN H U LL. Publisher.
H A R R IE T TH OM AS NOBLE, L oca l E ditor.
H E N R Y E. OLSON. Business M anager.
J. H. W ID M A R , J ob and A d Departm ent.
C L A R A B. OLSON, M achine O perator
HELEN MAE W A LTE R S. B ookkeeper
M ERLIN H ULL’ S L E TTE R
The crash o f an army plane on a
California field started a new discus
sion in Congress, not about the death
o f the pilot nor the cause o f the accident,
however. In the plane when it
went down was an officer o f the
French army. The plane was o f the
very latest o f those designed for our
own national defense, and supposedly
was equipped with secret gadgets and
appliances which our War department
did not desire to have other governments
know about. With all the secrecy
as to the plane’s construction and
its performance, along with the general
secrecy about our national de
fense, a foreign officer was receiving
full information. How he came to be
in the plane was one o f the mysteries
among the many mysteries o f the National
Capital.
The discussion had scarcely begun
when it was revealed by the War de
partment that the French officer was
in the plane by permission, but that
the secret devices had been taken o ff
before the flight. Whether or not the
plane was o f a special design, in itself
supposed to be secret was not
mentioned. From the first admission
others came rolling after, with possi
bly many others still to come. France
proposes to buy $65,000,000 worth of
war planes from our factories. Its
agents are here selecting the kind and
the designs. The administration favors
the sales, and apparently proposes to
facilitate action by letting France
know about our own air defense, secret
or otherwise. So, whatever advantage
we may have due to invention
designing and construction will be
shared in by the French army.
Why the War department issued its
statement that the secret appliances
were taken o f f the plane to prevent
their discovery by the French officer
has not been very fully explained. If
the administration proposes to aid
France in building up its air force as
a defense for democracy against totalitarian
countries, will it do less
than let France have the best, including
all the plans and perfections o f
our own air defense. Will France consent
to anything less, or will it accept
out moded planes for its millions,
well knowing that there are better
planes to be had.
The discussion o f the subject is
gradually broadening the question as
to htiw far our country should go in
furnishing war materials to other
countries in time o f peace as well as
in war. We have a neutrality law
passed by the last Congress to keep
us out o f foreign entanglements. It
has not been as effective as many
•hoped for so far as war supplies are
concerned. Now comes a counter proposal
that the vast resources o f our
country shall provide a balance of
power in Europe, a step toward entanglement
very similar to that at the
beginning o f the World war.
Nor can it be said that we are helping
others without danger to ourselves.
In a former instance our country
supplied other nations with submarines.
When the World war came
on, that invention and its development
in our country became a formidable
weapon which was turned against
us. In fact, but for the submarines
we might have kept out o f the World
war. Aiding France with war planes
may be also o f aid to other countries,
and nobody can say that, should war
come, the very devices which are
deemed so formidable may not be
used in the bombardment o f our own
cities.
Building a bit o f temporary prosperity
by sales o f war materials
abroad made many millionaires before
and during the World war. Supplying
Europe and Japan with war
stuffs may be profitable now. Over
$ 68,000,000 o f planes and plane parts
were exported last year. Other exports
for war preparation amounted to several
times as much. The DuPont Munitions
Plant made a profit o f fifty
millions in the year just closed. There
is biff money in making and selling
war supplies, but that form o f foreign
trade seems to contribute little toward
prosperity for the multitude.
Why there should be so much attention
paid by Congress and by the
people to foreign affairs when we
have so many problems here at home
is not so plain, but domestic affairs
seem to be relegated to the rear for
the present. The farm question and
that o f unemployment, foreclosures of
mortgages on homes and farms, revival
o f industry, and expansion o f
credit, are only a few o f many pressing
problems uppermost in the minds
o f millions, but all are subordinated
to the discussion o f foreign affairs in
Europe, Asia, and South America.
Only recently the Reconstruction Finance
Corporation made another advance
to the export bank to finance
purchases o f industrial commodities
by South American and other countries.
There are many small business
concerns which have been pending
before the K. F. C. applications for
loans which are not acted upon. Were
$25,000,000 to be spent in relieving
farmers who are losing their homes
by foreclosure, it would do more good
than it will in expanding our South
American trade.
Officials o f the Federal Reserve
Banks are again professing alarm over
the possibilities o f a boom. They
point to the more than three billions
o f excess bank reserves, and warn
that such reserves would be ample to
provide an expansion o f credit to the
point o f a “ disastrous inflation” .
Those same officials have similarly
expressed themselves during the depression.
There are billions o f idle
money which ought to be working.
Not many people want a boom and
probably none desire “ disastrous inflation”
. But if the federal reserve
officials can and will devise a plan
to use the idle billions to put ten
million men back to work, give the
farmers living prices for their products,
and set the wheels o f industry
humming, they will touch a responsive
chord in the minds o f many who
would be willing to risk a boom and
a bit o f inflation to see all that accomplished.
W ednesday, February 8, 1939
MRS. B. I. GREENLEE
Mrs. F. J. Reichenbach was called
to La Grange, Illinois, by the serious
illness o f her sister in law, Mrs. B
I. Greenlee, who passed away Janu
ary 21, 1939. They have been resi
dents o f La Grange since 1913. Mr,
Greenlee is superintendent o f public
works in that city. Also surviving are
two children, Charles P., o f Cleve
land, Ohio, and Janet P., o f La
Grange; one brother, Weston, of
Kansas City; and a sister, Mrs. Mandell,
o f Cleveland. Deep sympathy
is extended by friends here to the
family.
Mrs. Greenlee apparently was an
outstanding character, with a host o f
friends. At the service her pastor
paid a beautiful tribute to her mem
ory and to her characteristics o f
kindness, thoughtfulness and consideration
o f others. She was buried at
Ivanhoe cemetery, west o f Libertyville.
Her two grandfathers who
helped build the little community
church which celebrated its hundredth
anniversary last summer, Mrs. Green
lee taking part in the celebration.
The following is taken from the
La Grange paper.
There was universal sorrow in La
Grange last Saturday evening when
the news was whispered around that
Mrs. Byron I. Greenlee had passed
on. It had been known for days that
she was in the shadow o f the valley
but that did not lessen the grief o f
innumerable friends when they learned
that her activities were ended.
Few women in La Grange have
ever been active in so many different
groups. A former librarian, she
served for 14 years as a member of
the board o f directors o f the La
Grange public library. She was i
loyal member o f the First Congregational
church: she had been active
in the Woman’s club; in La Grange
Chapter o f the D. A. R.’s; in the
Community Nurse and Service association;
the League o f Women Voters
and in the Garden club. In each
group she had formed a circle of
warm, personal friends.
Lillian Partridge was born in Waukegan
56 years ago, the daughter of
Charles A. Partridge, a pioneer editor,
historian and for many years Adjutant
General o f the G. A. R., Department
o f Illinois, with headquarters
in the Chicago Public Library.
She lived in Waukegan up to the time
she and Mr. Greenlee moved to La
Grange in 1913 with the exception
o f three years when she served as librarian
at the State Teachers college
at Valley City, N. I . Previously she
had been assistant librarian at Waukegan.
COUNTY A G E N T NOTES
Dairy Meeting
Glen Vergeront, former County
Agent o f Jackson county and at the
present time Extension Dairyman at
the College o f Agriculture, will appear
on the program at the annual
meeting o f the county cow testing
association to be held at the court
house on Saurday, Feb. 11th, at 1:30
m.
The meeting will be open to the
public to give every one interested in
dairy problems an opportunity to
hear Mr. Vergeront’s talk.
The annual meeting o f the testing
association members will be held immediately
following the general meeting.
An application for a marriage license
has been made by Welton
Craig, son o f Mr. and Mrs. Oswald
Craig, o f this city, and Dorothy Mae
Larson, o f Warrens, daughter of
John Pischke.
BIRTHS
A 3 pound, 2 ounce daughter
was bom at the hospital Sunday,
February 5, 1939, to Mr. and Mrs.
Lawrence Casper, o f Shady Glen. The
baby is being cared for in the incubator,
and is doing pretty well.
A daughter, Barbara Ann, was
born February 3, 1939, at the hospital,
to Mr. and Mrs. Elmo Johnson,
o f this city.
A daughter, Sandra Kay, was born
February 3, 1939, to Mr. and Mrs.
Walter Simonson, o f Merrillan.
A son, Frank Richard, was born
at the hospital February 4, 1939, to
Mr. and Mrs. Richard Harmon, of
Shamrock.
A son, Vance Lionel, was born
February 1, 1939, to Mr. and Mrs.
Vance Bates, o f Merrillan.
A son was born at the hospital,
February 3, 1939, to Mr. and Mrs.
Raymond Duxbury, o f Hixton.
A daughter was born February 4,
1939, to Mr. and Mrs. Charles Tooley
o f this city.
T R E M P E A L E A U T R A IL
BR O A D C AST
The Trempealeau Trail Association
will begin a series o f radio broadcasts
over WEAU, the Eau Claire station,
starting Thursday, Feb. 9th, at 4:45
m.
George T. Ringrose, secretary of
the association, will speak at that
time on the background and future
o f the association.
JOINT IN STA LLA TIO N OF
KNIGHTS AND SISTERS
There was joint installation o f o f
ficers o f the Knights o f Pythias and
Pythian Sisters held Monday evening
o f last week at the lodge hall. Each
member was privileged to bring
guest and it was a particularly interesting
meeting.
Refreshments were served after the
installation services and the remainder
o f the evening spent at Bingo,
prizes for which were donated by the
Knights. Everybody had a good time
Mrs. Mayme Berg served as installing
officer for the Sisters, assisted by
Grand Manager Clara Johnson. Otto
Flugstad was installing officer for the
Knights. The following officers of
the two lodges were duly installed:
Pythian Sisters—
Grand Senior— Lulu Pierce
Most Excellent Chief— Elizabeth
Staffon
Most Excellent Senior— Doris Reber
Most Excellent Junior— Mildred
Anderson
» Manager— Helen Heineck
Mistress o f Records and Treasurer
— Rachel Shankey
Mistress o f Finance— Agnes Manthe
Guard— Stella Boyer
Protector— Sarah Helbling
Past Chief— Beatrice Landers
Knights o f Pythias—
Chancellor Commander— L. D. Anderson
Vice Chancellor— Dexter Onstad
Keeper o f Records and Seals— Milton
Haug
Master o f Finance— Gerald HoonsbeenM
aster o f Exchequer— Lloyd Gilbertson
Master o f Arms— Archie Haralson
Master o f Works— C. W. Helbling
Prelate— Harold Westerfield
Inner Guard— Henry Kleven
Outer Guard— George Dettinger
R O Y A L NEIGH BOR
IN STALLA TIO N
The Royal Neighbors installed o fficers
at their last meeting with Mrs.
Lily Pflanz, past president, officiating
as installing officer, assisted by Mrs.
Sophia Pearce as ceremonial marshal.
Lunch was served after installation
and the remainder o f the evening
given over to bingo. Mrs. Clara
Johnson was the winner o f high prize
and second prize went to Mrs. Hazel
Gilbertson.
The following officers were installed
for the coming year:
Oracle— Rachel Shankey
Past Oracle— Elizabeth Staffon
Vice Oracle— Emma Gilbert
Chancellor— Mary Quackenbush
Receiver— Alice Gates
Marshals— Pearl Vincent, Sarah
Helbling
Captain o f Degree Staff— Lily
Pflanz
Faith— Irma Loomis
Courage— Merle Haralson
Modesty— Mayme Berg
Endeavor— Helen Heineck
Unselfishness— Ida Flannigan
Inner Sentinel— Mabel German
Outer Sentinel— Isabel Loomis
Recorder— Alma Weekwerth
Musician— Junettie Erickson
Manager— Emma Kutchera
Physician— Dr. Irwin Krohn
CLASS IN CITIZEN SH IP
There is a prospect o f establishing
W PA project o f a class in citizenship
if enough people who are interested
will register for it.
Registry may be made at the office
o f Clerk o f Court Oliver Ristuben,
first door at the right from the south
entrance o f the court house. The
class is especially for those who have
already filed their petitions as citizens
and they should register with
Mr. Ristuben if interested. If there
are not enough registering the class
will not be established. It might not
be an entirely bad idea for some o f
our fully established citizens to join.
Americanism is one o f the neglected
isms.
RED CROSS A P P E A L
FOR CH ILEANS
George Dettinger, chairman o f the
local Red Cross society, has an appeal
from national headquarters at
Washington regarding the Chilean
disaster. There are 30,000 deaths reported,
and 50,000 injured.
The Red Cross has sent $10,000
in cash and another $ 10,000 worth
o f f upplies up to this time.
I f any one wishes to contribute to
this cause they may leave their contributions
at the Jackson County
Bank with John R. Bolger, treasurer.
The contributions will be gratefully
received and sent on to national headquarters.
SU ND AY CONCERT A
HUGE SUCCESS
The music department wishes to
thank all those who attended their
first concert, helping to make it a
success. Programs o f this type are
planned for the first o f next month
and in the following month.
The following are numbers presented
by the music department under
the direction o f Miss Keefe—
Sarabands— Handel
Prelude in C— Bach
Rondo in G from Symphony No.
12— Mozart
Played by the string orchestra. Selections
by high school girls glee club
with Miss Aleen Trask as soloist and
Miss Verna Carlson as accompanist
were
Since You Went Away, Johnson
Allah’s Holiday, Friml
The high school band under the
able direction o f Jay R. Jorgenson
were applauded for their presentation
o f—
The Pilgrims Chorus from Tannhauser,
R. Wagner
Old Comrades March, Carl Teike
Jolly Robbers Overture, F. Von
Spuppe
L’Arlesienne Intermezzo, George
Bizet
America We March, Henery Fillmore
With the March New Colonial by
R. B. Hall as an encore.
The community singing directed by
Miss Keefe with Verna Carlson as
accompanist, was enjoyed so thoroughly
by every one that the plan is
to have group participation at all o f
the concerts.
Three hundred attended the concert.
This was a nice group but it
did not fill the auditorium. The
next concert should fill the auditorium.
T H EY P A Y T A X ON M ONTHLY
PLAN , N EVER MISS THE M ONEY
How can paying taxes be made
easy instead o f an annual headache?
Jackson County Federal Savings
and Loan Association reports that its
borrowers pay their taxes by the
month. When a borrower comes in
to make his monthly payment on interest
and principal, he leaves an additional
sum,representing one twelfth
o f the next tax bill. By the end of
the year, the tax money has been accumulated
without the home owner
feeling any strain . The cost o f in
surance on the home is taken care of
in the same way.
The Jackson County Federal is
mailing checks totalling $1129.40 to
city, village, and town treasurers for
taxes on homes owned by its borrowers
in Black River Falls, Pleasant
View, Blair, Melrose, Hixton, Alma
Center and other neighboring communities.
W O M A N ’S CLUB
The Business and Professional W oman’s
department o f the Woman’s
club met at the city library on Friday
evening, Feb. 3, 1939, at 8 o ’clock.
The usual business meeting was
carried on after which the reports of
two standing committees were given
by Miss Grace Webb and Mrs. Norma
Krametbauer. Miss Agnes Hanson
gave a brief review o f the work o f
the school children in preparing valentine
favors for the veterans in the
hospital at Wood, Wisconsin.
Mrs. Sadie Cadby, as chairman o f
the program Committee, had two very
interesting one act plays read, by
Mrs. Philip Mills. Every one was
glad to have the privilege o f hearing
Mrs. Mills again.
Lunch was served at Lloyd’s restaurant
at the close o f the meeting.
IRVING LAD IES AID
There will be Irving Ladies Aid
kensington meeting at the home o f
O. H. Overlien Wednesday, Feb. 15,
Every one is welcome.
NOTICE
American Legion Auxiliary meets
first Wednesday o f month.
HOOSIER B O W !
The last meeting was held Jan. 27
at the home o f Rachel Simonson. Pie
and ice cream were served for lunch.
The next meeting a valentine party,
will be held at the home o f Jane
Davis, Feb. 10th.
SIS GILBERTSON, Reporter
NOTICE OF SEALED BIDS
Sealed bids will be received on my
property in Taylor, Wis., consisting
o f house, garage, bam and lots.
The bids will be open until Feb. 28,
1939. The owner has the right to accept
or reject any or all bids.
Mail bids to O. O. LOVAAS, at
6 3w Litchville, North Dakota.
EV A N G E L IC A L LU TH ERAN
PARISH
A. M. Romstad, Pastor
Confirmation class Saturday morning
at 10 o ’clock.
Black River Falls:
Thursday, 2 :30, The Ladies Aid I
will be entertained by Mrs. Enoch
Locken, Mrs. George Ness and Mrs.
E E. Homstad. The topic will be
The Christian Getting Along with
Others” . Leader, Mrs. Eilert Hagen
Thursday, 3:30, Children’s choir;
7:00 Junior choir; 8:00 Senior
choir.
Sunday, 9:30, Sunday school
Sunday, 10:45 Divine worship. The
pastor will continue the series o f sermons
on the Ten Commandments.
Sermon on the Fifth Commandment,
“ Thou Shalt Not Kill.”
Monday, 8 :00 Dorcas Society meets
to be entertained by Agnes and Sylvia
Emerson, Olga Jacobson.
Monday, 8 :00, Meeting o f the
Church Council
Little Norway:
The Irving Ladies Aid will have a
kensington at the home o f Miss Caroline
Overlien, Wednesday, Feb. 15.
Squaw Creek:
Divine services Sunday afternoon
at 2 o’clock. Sermon on the fifth
Commandment “ Thou Shalt Not Kill”
TH E M ETHODIST CHURCH
A. M. Allison, Pastor
Black River Falls:
Thursday, Feb. 9th, Choir rehearsals:
Junior choir after school; Intermediate
choir at 7 :00 p. m .; Adult
choir at 7 :45 p. m.
Friday, Feb. 10, The Woman’s
Home Missionary Society will meet
with Mrs. Harold Allison at 2 :30 p.
m. at the parsonage.
Sunday, Feb. 12th. Services approprite
to Lincoln’s birthday. Church
school at 9 :45 a. m. Morning worship
at 10:45 a. m. Junior League
at 6:30 p. m. Epworth League at
7 :30 p. m.
Wednesday, Feb. 15, Boy Scout
meeting at 7 :30 p. m.
Trout Run:
Church school and Divine worship
at 2:00 p. m. Sunday, Feb. 12th.
FULL GOSPEL T A B E R N A C L E
Paul J. Bicket, Pastor
John Newton’s favorite expression
to his friends was, “ I am not what I
ought to be; I am not what I wish
to b e ; I am not what I hope to b e ;
but by the grave o f God, I am not
what I used to be.” What progress
have you made, even in this year in
spiritual things. Come to church
where help is offered. The church
services are as follows:
Sunday school 10 a. m.
Morning worship 11 a. m.
Evangelistic service, 8 p. m.
Thursday, 8 p. m.
Bible Study o f Acts, Chapter 2.
CH RISTIAN SCIENCE SO CIETY
Services Sunday, 11 a. m.
“ Soul” will be the subject o f the
Lesson Sermon read in all Churches
of Christ, Scientist, on Sunday, Feb. I
12. The Golden Text is taken from
Isaiah 2 5 :9 :
“ Lo, this is our God; we have
waited for him, and he will save us;
this is the Lord.”
Every one is cordially invited to
attend this service.
ST. JOH N’S LUTH ERAN CHURCH j CA TH O LIC SERVICES
. . .A. Klemp, Pastor Sunday, 8:30, Mass at Black River
Service 2:30 p. m. Sunday. I Falls; 10:30 Mass at Roaring Creek.
OWNED HOMES
are
HAPPY HOMES
Parents buy a home because it brings
security and economy, and children
approve because it means no more
moving about changing schools and
friends. You’ll like our home financing
plan . . . it brings you happy,
debt free home ownership.
Jackson County Federal Savings
and Loan Association
Rufus Dimmick, Sec. Black River Falls Phone 79
Valentine
Floral Gifts
Phone
No.
The Shamrock Good Will club is
sponsoring a valentine party at the
Shamrock town hall, Friday night,
Feb. 17. Lunch will be served. Cards
and dancing. Every one welcome.
50c up 25
HEINECK’S GREENHOUSE
NOTICE
A dinner dance is to be held at the
New Freeman Hotel, Feb. 17th, at
:30 p. m. Jack Pingle is to furnish
the music. Owing to accommodations,
it will be limited to the first forty
couples who make reservations at the
Freeman Hotel by Feb. 13th. Tickets
to be paid for when reservations
are made.
ST. JO SEPH ’S CARD PA R T Y
The last card party o f the season
will be held next Wednesday night,
February 15th, at the social rooms j
o f St. Joseph church. All who are
interested are extended a cordial invitation
to attend. Lunch will be
served.
Both House and Senate made some
effort to take politics out o f W PA
by adding amendments to the deficiency
bill, particularly as to soliciting
M ETH ODIST M ISSION ARYS
O CIETY
The Methodist Missionary Society
will meet at the home o f Mrs. H. A.
Allison, Friday afternoon at 2:30
o’clocfl. Guests are welcome.
campaign funds from W PA workers.
They stopped short o f removing WPA
from politics, as should be done. The
Senate also adopted an amendment to
prevent all government workers from
being “ influenced” by politicians to
make campaign contributions. That
amendment failed because it would
interfere with modem methods of
party financing. Some day Congress
may get around to investigating the
entire matter o f political contributions,
a form o f un Americanism
which costs the public dearly, though
most people do not realize it. Such
an investigation would require a long
time and furnish sensational headlines
every day. But maybe it is too
much to expect. MERLIN HULL.
BEE LINE
Your Car for Safe Driving
Only with this type o f equipment can you know that your car is
correctly adjusted for Camber, Caster, Toe in, etc.
Only with this type o f equipment can your frame, front axle, housings,
etc., be precision straightened without removing them from the
car. Only com petent men experienced with this type o f equipment
can serve you as you have a right to expect. A complete checkup on
our B Line machine costs you nothing.
D RIVE IN T O D A Y AND CO NVINCE YOU RSELF
Ask for “CHUCK” the BEE LINE Man
Phone 47
A complete Checkup
Absolutely Free ! ! !
HARDY CHEVROLET CO.
Black River Falls, Wis.
FREE! ta k e k l o o k '. Nf ’ea T ° u 1, ;
,h iH r.e»r th ’ N o t a n flo o r
„ o extra CO, nit of j0t three
C o m e I n . . . T a k e a L o o k a t t h e
m z N e w D o d g e L u x u r y L in e r — It C o s t s
E v e n L e s s t h a n L a s t Y e a r ’ s D o d g e
THIS year, decide for yourself! W e believe that the new
1939 Dodge Luxury Liner can tell its own exciting story
better than w e can. So instead of bothering you with our
opinion, w e simply say : “ T A K E A L O O K —THAT’S ALL D O D G E
ASKS!” Before you m. 2 up your mind about any car, take a
look at this new kind of Dodge from every angle. Compare
it any way you choose. See why w e are leaving the selling
part to you!
So, w h y not com e in today? Y o u ’ll see a m uch bigger,
room ier D o d g e ...a longer w h e e lb a se ...w id e r w in d sh ield ...
an d a fro n t sea t th a t’ s
w ider than the re a r seat
o f m any cars!
Y o u ’ll find a n ew , easier
w ay to shift gears at the
s te e rin g w h e e l...a c o n cealed
luggage compart 
m ent that is 27 largert
A n d w h en you TAKE A
LOOK at the price tag,
you ’ll be am azed to learn
that the n ew 1939 D odg«
L u x u ry L in e r —a ctu a lly
sells for even less than laat
year’s D odge 1 "
TAKE A LOOK! NEW Individual 
Action front springing with Amola
steal springs U v ilt oat the roadl
Frank’s Auto Sales Bla£iEiver
THE BANNER JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin PAGE NO. 5
ALMA CENTER NEWS
George Ringrose is spending some
time in Eau Claire.
Mrs. Gus Porath is out again after
a two weeks illness.
Mr. and Mrs. Gil Lynnes spent
Sunday at Greenwood.
A1 Fenney o f Taylor, was a caller
here Saturday evening.
Garrett Fox o f Wausau, spent the
week end with his family here.
Mr. and Mrs. Dana Waters were
B. R. Falls callers one day last week.
Mr. and Mrs. Neal Duxbury and
family were B. R. Falls visitors Saturday.
Mr. and Mrs. Nathan Merrill left
Thursday for their home in Wright,
Kansas.
Mr. and Mrs. P. M. Chapman and
Mrs. Ed Bopp were visitors at B. R.
Falls, Sunday.
Miss Helen Duxbury and children
visited Mrs. Jack Merrill at the hospital,
Sunday.
Miss Phyllis Atkinson was taken
to the B. R. Falls hospital where she
will receive medical care.
Mrs. Geo. Atkinson went to B. R.
Falls to be near Phyllis, who will undergo
an operation for appendicitis.
Mr. and Mrs. R. W ilcox and Mr.
and Mrs. L. Duxbury spent Sunday
with Mr. and Mrs. L. Dunn at Merrillan.
Mrs. Mart Lastofka and Mrs. Bill
Plumer o f Neillsville, spent from
Friday until Sunday with their sister,
Mrs. Willard Cole.
Come to the Dairy Rally the evening
o f Feb. 9. Everyone welcome.
No admittance fee. A good program
and a good time will be had.
The Junior Hi basket ball team will
play against Merrillan Jr. Hi team at
Merrillan. on Monday evening, Feb.
13th. The valentine party has been
postponed because o f the game.
Mr. and Mrs. Albert Hart o f Norwalk,
spent a day last week with the
latter’ s mother and husband, Mr. and
Mrs Willard Cole, and made known
that they were going to start for Florida
in a few days, and also visit
many other places o f interest on the
way.
A new club has been organized in
our community, which was named
“ Good Cheer.” The ladies meet once
a week and may bring any kind o f
work or play to suit themselves. A
very sociable afternoon was spent a
week ago with Mrs. Ormsby and last
Friday with Mrs. Thayer. Only one
restriction was made, and that is “ no
eats” .
MRS. JOSEPH INE BILLERBE CK
Mrs. Josephine Billerbeck, daughter
o f Joseph and Minnie Wiegert,
was bom in Manitowoc, Wis., March
8th, 1871 and passed away January
25, 1939, at the Krohn hospital in B.
R. Falls.
She was baptized and confirmed in
the Lutheran faith When a small
girl she moved witn her parents' to
Garden Valley where she has resided
most o f her life.
She was married to Henry Billerbeck,
who with three children, James,
Charles and Lillian, preceded her in
death. Five children are left to mourn
her death: William, Stevens Point;
George and Joe and Mrs. Sadie Jennings,
o f Alma Center; Mrs. A rthur
Chandler, Tomahawk, two brothers,
George Wiegert, Alma Center,
and Will, of Fairchild; 18 grandchildren,
seven great grandchildren
besides numerous other relatives and
friends.
Among those from away who were
here to attend the funeral were Mr.
and Mrs. Arthur Chandler and son,
Tomahawk; Mr. and Mrs. William
Billerbeck, Mr. and Mrs. Russell Rustad,
Mrs. Paul Lupenski, Stevens
Point; Mr. and Mrs. Glen Cartmill
and Clyde Billerbeck, Milwaukee;
Mrs. J. A. Risberg, Minneapolis; Mrs.
Mary Billerbeck, Leo Billerbeck, Mrs.
Frank Fisher, Eau Claire: Mr. and
Mrs. Harley Dunn, De Soto; Mrs.
Walter Campbell, Mrs. Walter Rush,
Mrs. Gilbert Baalrud, Mrs. A. Stoneberg,
Mrs. Estella Hughes, Tomahawk;
Mr. and Mrs. Ralph Lyons,
Mr. and Mrs. Martin Thompson,
Northfield; Mr. and Mrs. Theo.
Thompson, Eau Claire; Mrs. Lewis
Neprud, Madison; Mrs. Effie Chandler,
Hixton.
The funeral was held at the Lutheran
church at Alma Center conducted
by Rev. Christopherson o f Pigeon
Falls. She was buried in East Lawn
cemetery.
Mrs. Billerbeck was a kind and loving
mother and will be deeply mourned
by the children as well as the
grandchildren. She has cared for one
grandson, James Billerbeck, since the
age o f 11 months and she will be
sadly missed by him. Six grandsons
acted as pall bearers.
NOTICE
The annual Fathers and Sons banquet
will be held Wednesday evening,
Feb. 15, at 1 o ’clock in the M. E.
church dining room. Price 35 cents.
Taystee
b , Ie a d
 WHICH BREAD MAKES
THE BEST TOAST ? I ILL
FOR FRESHER BREAD TOMOXfiOH BUY TAY5TEE BREAD foM y
A V A L O N
M OTIO N PICTURES ARE YOUR BEST ENTERTAINMENT'
T W O D A Y S O N L Y
W E D N E SD A Y and TH U R SD AY F E B R U A R Y 8, 9
A M IG H T Y FILM
9 from the
novel that
ten million
readers have
thrilled to!
Produced by V I C T O R S A V IL L E A KING VIDOR production
FR I., SAT. FEB. 10, 11
SUN., MON. FEB. 12, 13
SAMUEL GOLDWYN presen t,
GARY COOPER
MERLE OBERON
!
with PAT SY K E L L Y f
WALTER BRENNAN
I •
Continuous Showing Sunday
starting at 1:00 p. m. f '
TU E SD AY FEB. 14
Now Showing
m m ihg
mam ss Maureen O 'SU LLIV AN • LE W AYRES
M G M Collegiate Lore Storyf
a«~d O.IWPUI SPRING DANCE"
125 125 125 125
W ED., THURS. FEB. 15, 16
j In M G M'c daring j
revelation of the
theatre w orld !
p
PLUS
“A Criminal is Born”
 Crim e Doesn’t Pay Series 
also
Lowell Thomas Travel Talk
isle of Pleasure’
G RAC E LU TH E RAN CHURCH
E. A. Klemp, Pastor
Sunday school 9:45 a. m.
Services 10:30 a. m.
The meeting o f the Aid Association
for Lutherans has been postponed
a week. It will be held at Wm.
Rubenbauer’s home Feb. 16th, at 8
p. m.
THE M ETH ODIST CHURCH
F. A. Fahlgren, Pastor
Lincoln Sunday
10:00 Sunday school
11:00 Public worship
7 :00 Epworth League
Rev. Earnest E. Clarke, D. S. o f
Eau Claire, will give the address at
the Father Son banquet Wednesday,
Feb. 15. This is an annual event
sponsored by the Brotherhood o f the
Methodist church. Get your boy or
boys as quickly as possible. They
want to go. Tickets are being sold
by the men. The address will be on
some patriotic theme because this
event falls between Lincoln’s and
Washington’s birthday. This will be
something worth while to come to.
Alma Center school news was
crowded out this week. Look for
them in our next issue.
Among those from the county who
attended the annual road school held
in Milwaukee last week were Commissioner
O. H. Overlien, Duane
Hoffman, Emil Gilbertson, R. H. Hartmann,
S. J. Knudsen, Sam Amundson,
Peter Bever, Charles Ludden, C.
Nelson and Ben Schweinker, all of
this city, also Charles M. Olson, of
Hixton. That traffic safety occupies
an important place in the minds of
men who build and maintain Wisconsin’s
highways was well demonstrated
at the road school. Attendance at
the school broke the all time record.
Leo Foster, o f Neillsville, was a
business visitor in town Tuesday afternoon.
He reports his family well
and well pleased with their new home
in Neilslville, which was the home o f
the Foster family before they moved
to La Crosse.
Mrs. Kenneth Linnell entertained
last Friday evening at a shower in
honor o f Mrs. Robert Meek. A lovely
lunch was served and she received
many beautiful gifts. Entertainment
was 500, with Mrs. Noel Jacobson
high and Mrs. Ray Landers low.
Mr. and Mrs. L. D. Anderson entertained
their 500 club at their home
last Wednesday evening. Mrs. Anderson’s
mother, Mrs. Julia Luke, of
Frederick, was a guest at the club.
Mrs. Ralph Lund was given a
shower by the members o f the Mission
Circle Monday afternoon at the
home o f Mrs. A. M. Romstad.
The Study club o f St. Joseph’s
Catholic church met at the home of
Mrs. Alex Bielinski on February 1.
They are now studying the life of
Christ. Lunch was served.
Among the patients at the hospital
who have been operated this week
for appendicitis are Oren Peterson.,
o f Taylor; Rogene Olson and Eva
La Zotte, o f Merrillan.
Mrs. A. C. Kuhn is again at home
after several weeks under treatment
at the hospital. She is much improved,
which is very pleasing news to
her friends.
Mary Grace Doud, daughter o f Mr.
and Mrs. Earl Doud, was operated
Saturday morning for acute appendicitis.
She is getting along nicely.
Fred Hobart, o f Fairchild, was
brought to the hospital la3t Thursday
by Dr. Hendrickson for medical treatment.
Virginia Leffingwell is a patient at
the hospital following an operation
Saturday night for appendicitis.
THE INDIAN NEW S
The Indians cutting woods use by
crosset saw, and split and pile them
for school house. They said they
work for public welfare department
office. A. Johnson, John Swallow,
Dono Greengrass and Rubin Hall.
Mr. and Mrs. George Lewis and
their children o f Greenwood were visit
at Indian Mission last Saturday.
Rev. John Stacy and Alvin Stacy
went Tomah Indian hospital. They
took Lester Young Thunder has been
having sore eyes, and we understand
that 3 or 4 haS been cured.
William Waukon has gone to Tomah
Indian hospital last Sunday, and
first place thought he had bad cold,
but he have to go to hospital now.
Mr. and Mrs. Sam Little Soldier
and Mrs. Nellie Wallace and Mrs.
Belle Standing Water went to Waupun
last Saturday to see the Tom
Wallace.
Mr. Yubank from Tomah visit the
school last Wednesday, and Mrs. Emma
Olson, our teacher she think find
everythings o. k. in this 49 school children
and every one attending every
daytoo.
We understand that “ Indian Mission”
will be start in Chicago. Reverend
Fred White Eagle, who was powwow
chief in Merrillan, is one of
them, who will help the things along.
There are many Indians in Chicago,
and the Mission will help those who
need help.
These two gentlemen were here
last week, we did not have in last
week paper. Mr. A. M. Morris and
Mr. G. B. Yubank o f Tomah Indian
school were here to see some Indians
on business.
Mr. John Smoke is working on RA
at Monroe county, and he says his
forman told him there are some o f
his men lay off 15th o f this month,
and Mr. Smoke said he wish to be
continue on his job.
There is a man went to hunt deer
when season open, deer hunting, and
he went about 9 miles from his home,
and he left his car, edge o f woods and
he had cover it up his radiator some
kind robe, and evening he was lost
on his way to find his car. Finally
he found, when he come through the
woods he saw standing a deer, so he
shot at 3 or 4 times and he notice
that deer did not move, so he went
up there to see, but that his car to
shoot a radiator and he can not get
car started. He had to walk 9 miles to
his home and his wife has more difficult
her mind, not come home after
midnight.
CARD OF TH AN KS
We wish to extend our heartfelt
thanks and deep appreciation to the
many friends and neighbors who so
kindly expressed their sympathy at
the time o f our bereavement, the
death o f our dear mother, Mrs. Billerbeck.
We also wish to thank Rev.
Christopherson, Mr. Jensen, those
who sent floral bouquets, donors of
cars, and all who in any way assisted
us at this time.
Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Chandler
and Son
Mr. and Mrs. William Billerbeck
and Family
Mr. and Mrs. Joe Billerbeck
and Family
Mrs. Sadie Jennings and Family
George Billerbeck
CARD OF TH AN KS
We wish to extend our sincere
thanks to the neighbors, friends and
relatives who helped during the illness
and death o f our father; to those
who sent floral tributes, cards and
memorials and to Rev. Christopherson
for his comforting words we express
thanks.
Mr. and Mrs. Theodore Thompson
Mr. and Mrs. Martin Thompson
and Family
Mr. and Mrs. Edgar Thompson
Mr. and Mrs. Louie Neperud
and Family
Mr. and Mrs. Herman Larson
and Family
SHOP AND SAVE AT
Waughtal’s
3 Deliveries Daily Phone 216
Pillsbury’s Pancake Flour, 3 Mb. b a g ................21c
K.C. Baking Powder, 25 oz. c a n .............................19c
Sugar ........................................................10 lb. bag 49c
Dutch Toilet Tissue ......................................6 rolls 25c
Flour, guaranteed ................................. 49 lb. bag 95c
Corn
20 oz. cans
DICED
Carrots Cut Beets
Cream Style
Cash Price 20 oz. can
20 oz. can
69c d°z‘ 5c each 5 C each
Su uA, A£a Ht4
cj b i 3 for C R I S C O
■ y| 3 lb. can 1 lb. can
the soap of JL riEW | C 1 m I Q if 
beautiful women JL w w
Gelatine Dessert, assorted flavors ................3 for 10c
Tomatoes, 29 oz. cans ................................. 2 for 25c
Prunes, 90 100 size ......................................4 Ihs. 19c
Coffee ...............................................................3 lbs. 39c
FRUIT DEPARTMENT
Oranges, 344 size ...............................................doz. 9c
Grapefruit, 126 size ........................................ doz. 25c
Bananas ............................................................ 4 lbs. 23c
MEAT DEPARTMENT
Fresh Meaty Neck Bones and 1 quart Saur 
Kraut, all for ........................................................25c
Nice Weiners, small, 1 lb. weiners and 1 quart
Saurkraut all for ................................................... 25c
W e have same extra nice T Bone Steaks . .2 lbs. 35c
Beef Stew ......................................................per lb. 10c
Nice Beef Roast ............................. per lb. 12c to 16c
Young Pork R oast.............................per lb. 14c to 18c
Pork Shoulders, whole, or Fat Side Pork per lb. 12c
Extra Nice Fresh Oysters, direct from the coast
per quart 39c per gallon $1.49
Fresh Herring ............................................ . .4 lbs. 25c
Fresh Red Salmon ......................................2 lbs. 35c
OPENING!! FRIDA Y , FEBRUARY 10th
MILUS SERVICE STATION
PHONE 323 ACROSS FROM LARKIN HDW.
Cities Service Products
Koolmotor Gasoline and Koolmotor Oil
Acme Tires Acme Batteries Accessories
Servicing and Greasing
FREE1 Qt. Cities Service Oil Free with each purchase
of gasoline of $1.00 or more.
Special O il Deals
Koolmotor, 2 gal. can $1,60 5 gallon can $3.90
Cities Service 2 gal. can $1.30..... 5 gallons $3 15
Blue Club ... .2 gal. can 98c........ 5 gallons $2.25
Prices include a 5 gallon Kerosene Can or Tractor Fill 2 bushel Measure ! ! !
Complete Grease Job 60c
Oil Change, Koolmotor, reg. $1.50 for.......... $1.20
Oil Change, Cities Service, reg. $1.25, for.........95c
PRICES on Guaranteed BATTERIES
Prices $6.50 to $10.25
$2.00 Allowance on Your Old Battery. Guaranteed 9 to 21 Months
These Special Prices Good until Feb. 18 only
CARD OF THAN KS
We wish to express our sincere
thanks and appreciation to friends
for their kindness during the illness
and death o f our father. We thank
those who sent flowers and memory
wreaths, the pall bearers, those who
sang, Rev. Bringle, Mr. Gibson and
all who rendered assistance in any
way. THE LUKAS FAMILY
NOTICE OF HEARIN G A P P L IC A T IO N FOR
A D M IN ISTRATION AND NOTICE TO
CREDITORS
STATE OF W ISCONSIN. COU N TY COURT,
Jackson County
In th e M atter o f the E state of A lbert
Casper, deceased
N otice is hereby given that at a term o f
said cou rt to be held on Tuesday, the 7th
day o f M arch, 1939, at 10 o ’clock on the
foren oon o f said day, at the court house
in the city of Black R iver Falls, in said
cou nty, there will be heard and considered:
The application o f W illiam Casper fo r the
appointm ent o f an adm inistrator o f the
estate o f A lbert Casper, deceased, late o f
th e Town o f A lm a, in said cou n ty;
N otice is furth er given that all claims
against the said A lbert Casper deceased, late
o f the Tow n o f Alm a, in Jackson county,
W isconsin, m ust be presented to said county
cou rt at Black R iver Falls, in said county,
on o r b efore the 12th day o f June, 1939, o r
be b a rred ; and that all such claims and
dem ands will be exam ined and adjusted at
a term o f said cou rt to be held at the
cou rt house in the city o f Black R iver Falls,
in said cou nty, on Tuesday, the 13th o f
June, 1939. at 10 o ’clock in th e foren oon
o f said day.
Dated February 3, 1939.
By Order o f the Court,
H A E R Y M. P E R R Y , Judge
D. M. P E R R Y , A ttorn ey
Feb. 8 22
FOR BETTER
FEED GRINDING
CALL
JOS. BRAUNER
PHONE 36R7
BLACK RIVER FALLS, W IS.
 . r
DANCE
ALMA CENTER
FRI., FEB. 10th
Music by
Earl Rhoda and His
Swingsters
Return Engagement o f this fine
Swing Band
“ Where Frineds Meet”
CARD OF THANKS
We wish to express our sincere
thanks to all who sent flowers, the
pall bearers, flower girls, those who
furnished cars, also Rev. Klemp and
Mr. Mattson and all who helped us
in any way during the illness and upon
the death o f our brother, Albert
Casper.
MR. AND MRS. WM. CASPER
AND FAMILY
USED
CAR BARGAINS
1938 Buick 41 Special Sedan
1938 Chevrolet Deluxe Sport
Sedan
2 1938 Chevrolet Deluxe Town
Sedans
2 1938 Chevrolet Master “ 85”
Town Sedans
1938 Plymouth Deluxe 2 door
Sedan
1937 Buick 47 Special Sedan
1937 Chevrolet Deluxe Town
Sedan
1937 Chevrolet ton Pickup
1937 Ford “ 85” 2 door
1937 Plymouth Deluxe 2 door
1937 Lafayette 2 door
1936 Buick 41 Special Sedan
1936 Buick 48 Special Coach
1935 Ford 2 door Trunk Deluxe
1936 Chevrolet Standard 2 dr.
Sedan
1935 Ford Coach
2 1935 Ford Pickups
1933 Chevrolet Coach
1933 Chevrolet 1 ton Short
Dual
1932 Plymouth 4 door Sedan
1931 Chev. Coupe, 5 pass.
1931 Chevrolet Coupe
1931 Buick Sedan
1931 Ford Coupe
1930 Ford Sedan
1930 Chevrolet Sedan
1930 Chrysler 2 door
1930 Plymouth Sedan
1929 Ford Coupe
1929 Ford Coach
1928 Chevrolet Pickup
HARDY CHEVROLET CO.
Phone 47 Black River Falls, Wis.
YOUR FAVORITE FOOD DEALER
CAN SUPPLY YOU
PAGE NO. 6 THE BANNER JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin W ednesday, February 8, 1939
A D L E R I K A
A LLE N CREEK
Mrs. Howard Doud has been on the
sick list.
Fred Riggle had wood sawers on
| Tuesday.
Earl Metcalf called on Fred Riggle
Saturday.
Perry Sullivan spent Sunday night
with Alfred Olson.
Gilbert Hagen called at the Fred
Riggle home Sunday.
Walter Hurlburt called on Otto
Gaede Wednesday afternoon.
Alice Hurlburt helped Mrs. Riggle
with the house work on Friday.
Mrs. Odanah Squires called to see
Fred Riggle, Tuesday afternoon.
Art Hagen and family were county
seat visitors Saturday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Joe Han us o f Hatfield,
called on Fred Riggle Friday.
Mr. and Mrs. Otto Gaede and
daughter spent Saturday evening at
Olson’s.
Jeanette Brown was an over night
guest at the George Gjerseth home in
Wrightsville.
Clarence Gaede and family spent
the fore part o f the week at the Elmus
Rush home in Merrillan.
Jeanette, Duane and Sidney Brown
attended the basket ball game and
dance at the High school gym Friday
night.
Webb Meek brought Mrs. Will
Pierce and Mrs. Jean Randle out to
«ee Fred Riggle, who was somewhat
better that day.
Mrs. Johnnie Krome and daughters
Bernice and Norma Jean spent last
week end in the city with Mr. and
Mrs. Henry Narva.
Mr. and Mrs. Oliver Olson and
family, also Betty Jane Gaede called
on Mrs. Olson’s mother, Mrs. Daisy
Heath, on the East side, Sunday.
Those visiting at the Fred Rigele
home Wednesday evening were Mr.
and Mrs. Victor Eggen. Mr. and Mrs.
Otto Gaede and Betty Jane, also Mr.
Ed Brown and son Jack.
Mrs. Otto Gaede and Betty Jane
spent the afternoon Saturday at Fred
Riggle’s home as Mrs. Rig eie had to
sro to town on business. They found
Mr. Riggle improving some.
Those calling at the Fred Riggle
home Sunday were Mr. and Mrs. Jeff
Peasley. Miss Jennie Reichenbach,
Mr. and Mrs. Dan Smith, Mrs. Johnnie
Krome, Mrs. Oliver Olson, Miss
Betty Jane Gaede, Mr. and Mrs. Albert
Roningen and children, Mr. and
Mrs. Puschel and Mr. and Mrs. Gilbert
Hagen.
K ENYO N V A L L E Y
Mrs. Sheda and sons Raymond and
John were callers at Henry Lubow’s
Tuesday night.
Mr. and Mrs. Norman Cox and son
Gary spent the week end at the Albert
Lubow home.
Mr. and Mrs. Ed McNulty and
family attended the concert at the
High school, Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Donald Lubow and
family were visitors at Henry Lubow’s,
Monday evening.
Mrs. Fred Krome spent several
dayt o f last week in Merrillan helping
care for Mrs. B. W. Hicks.
Visitors at Henry Lubow’s Sunday
were Mr. and Mrs. Robert Zamrzla
and Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Lubow.
Ed Brauner has been quite ill and
under the doctor’s care for several
days, but is better at this writing.
Mr. and Mrs. Frank Newton spent
Sunday with their daughter and husbsnd,
Mr. and Mrs. Claude Sprester.
Odas Newton o f Eau Claire, was
an over night guest o f his parents,
Mr. and Mrs. Frank Newton, Saturday.
Mr. and Mrs. Kermit Huebner and
son Maynard left for Shawano last
Thursday where they expect to have
employment.
Miss Dorothy McNulty and Robert
Nortman motored to Racina last
Sunday and visited at the Wilbur Gilgon
home for several days,
Mrs. Frank Brauner entertained
the Comfort club Friday. New officers
were elected: Mrs. Wm. Onstad,
President; Mrs. Harley Kunes, Vice
President; Mrs. Alvin Roberts, Secretary
and Treasurer; Mrs. Norman
Cox and Mrs. Everett Drecktrah on
the Sunshine committee. Mrs. Newton
gave a synopsis o f her trip to
Los Angeles, California, which was
much enjoyed by the members. The
next meeting is to be with Mrs. Harley
Kunes Friday, Feb. 24th. Visitors
are welcome.
SPRING CREEK
Mrs. Harriet Noble spent Thursday
afternoon at the Thomas home.
Mrs. Sophia Mason spent Thursday
afternoon with Mrs. Art Hagen, in
the city.
Mrs. Ella Rockney visited her son
Fred and family in the city Sunday
afternoon.
P. O. Peterson o f Irving, was a
Monday afternoon caller at the J. P.
Wiggin home.
Miss Alice Hurlburt o f Snow Creek
visited her sister, Mrs. Ed Moldenhauer
and family, Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Price Peterson and
Bonnie Jean spent Sunday evening at
the John Wiggin home.
Henry Nelson and son and daughter
o f Shake Hollow, called at Ole
W old’s, Saturday afternoon.
Archie Emerson and Phillip Thomas
came from Neillsville and spent
the week end with home folks.
Mr. and Mrs. Alvin Engebretson
and Phyllis were Sunday evening
guests o f Mr. and Mrs. Irvin Johnson.
Mrs. Maria Benson and Alfred
Rockney called on the latter’s mother,
Mrs. Ella Rockney, Saturday evening.
Wilma Emerson, Josephine Anderson~
and Julian Larkin called on Mr.
and Mrs. Ernest Anderson Saturday
evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Fred Durrin and
John Thomas spent Sunday afternoon
with Mrs. Harriet Noble and family
in the city.
Mr. and Mrs. Ed Moldenhauer and
children, Mrs. Iola Johnson and Miss
Edna Johnson spent Friday evening
at the Ole Wold home.
Mr. and Mrs. Gaylord Emerson
spent Sunday afternoon with her sister,
Mrs. Ronald Gee, husband and
children at Alma Center.
Mrs. Elmer Bush called on Mrs.
Ernest Anderson Monday afternoon.
Mrs. Art Anderson and son spent
Thursday afternoon there.
Mr. and Mrs. Ray Peterson, Arland
and Allen, o f Irving, George and
Alice Johnson called on Henry and
Caroline Johnson Sunday evening.
Ethel Gilbertson and brother Elwood,
also Osborn Johnson came from
your city Sunday and had dinner with
Mr. and Mrs. Irvin Johnson, Miss Edna
Johnson and Oliver Gilbertson.
Mrs. Gust Hortum visited Mrs.
John Hanson Saturday afternoon.
Mrs. Oscar Ramsey and son o f North
Bend were spending a few days with
her parents, Mr. and Mrs. Hanson,
sister and brother.
Mrs. A. M. Gilbertson and Mrs.
Otilda Sannes attended the concert in
the city Sunday afternoon and were
supper guests o f Mr. and Mrs. Bert
Engebretson. They also called on Mr.
and Mrs. Gerald Hoonsbeen in their
new home.
B J SMOKE SIGNALS
By Red Cloud
Providing that we believe in ground
hog day, we’ll have more than six
weeks o f winter ahead o f us. The
ground hog saw his shadow twice,
once in the day time and there was a
bright moonlight night the same evening.
“ Hit and run” is about the lowest
form o f human behavior that we as
a nation have to cope with. But there
are always two sides to everything.
To be able to “ hit and run as the big
“ Bambino” proved to the world is the
basis o f all big baseball salaries .
One o f the secrets o f being a great
and successful guffaw provoking radio
star is to be extraordinarily and
brilliantly dumb.
Nat ons are like individuals. They
are now living in an era of ill feeling.
Who will be the one to pour oil on
the troubled waters.
One o f the best laughs I’ve ever
had came to me one day about eight
years ago when I first heard o f the
origin o f the Winnebagoes. Joe
Widmar o f the B J force, and Clinton
Scafe went into a huddle and came
out with the following story. “ Way
back in Old Testament times there
was a man named Levi who had five
sons o f which one was named Lehman,
who was the notorious Public
Enemy No. 1 o f that time. Every
trait o f a vicious character was his,
and o f this Lehman the Indians are
descendants.” That is the story and
it sounds plausible too. Lehman’s
character was the cause o f the Redman’s
reddish color. What puzzles
me is where in the course o f years
past did the Redman swap character
with the pious descendants o f the
other sons o f Levi?
This story reminds me o f another
plausible story, and if you have heard
it before, stop me.
There was an old negro pasto who
in a course o f a sermon said to his
congregation, “ You’ve all heard of
the rolling red hot sizzling molten lava
from volcanoes? Well, they use
that for ice cream in Hades, being
that it is the coldest thing down
there.”
The population has increased a million
fold since he said this, which
may account for the few volcanic
eruptions o f modern time. The demand
for “ ice cream” down there is
greater than the supply. I shudder
to think o f what they might use for
hot coffee.
Kind o f scared myself with this
story so I’ll just postpone the escapade
I had in mind. I hope “ U”
wouldn’t mind.
The way the deer are scattering
over the area and breaking up the
herds indicate we’ll have a spell of
warm spring weather.
The people o f the U. S. A. are
just like one big family. When a
delicious tid bit is brought home for
every one to enjoy and relish there
is a squabble to see who gets the
biggest piece. And that tid bit is the
WPA.
Prof. L. M. Isgrigg
CHIROPRACTOR
TAYLOR NEWS ITEMS MELROSE
Wayne D ittloff was a caller in
Iowa, Thursday.
Mr. and Mrs. Frank Gibson spent
Saturday at Onalaska.
Hollis Iverson of Milwaukee, spent
the week end with home folks.
Dr. and Mrs. E. J. Smith were
callers in La Crosse Wednesday.
Mrs. J. H. Hansen and son Verdal
were callers at La Crosse, Friday.
Mr. and Mrs. Carl Rauk attended
a funeral at Spring Grove, Tuesday.
Mr. and Mrs. Lawrence Curran
spent Sunday afternoon at Will Curran’s.
Mrs. Verdal Hansen and daughter
Valarie spent Tuesday at Somel Henning's.
Mrs. Helga Folkedahl and Mrs. A.
S. Waller were callers at La Crosse
on Friday.
Mr. and Mrs. Jamie Finn and son
James spent Saturday evening at the
Roy Bue home.
Mr. and Mrs. Olof Kjome and son
Arthur, o f Osseo, spent Sunday at the
N. Nichols home.
The Ed Matson family moved this
week to near Hegg, the place they occupied
being sold.
Martin Kjorstad, Mrs. Cora Nichols
and son Wallace spent Sunday at
Julies Tjerstad’s, near Hegg.
Mr. and Mrs. Helmer Olson and
Janice, o f Milwaukee, spent Saturday
and Sunday at the Blix home.
Mrs. E. J. Smith and Mrs. H. M.
Huseboe celebrated their birthday on
Thursday and Thursday night.
Mrs. Anna Prestlyken and Mrs.
Eugene Hanson and son Dickie spent
Friday at H. Stai’s, in Ettrick.
Dr. and Mrs. E. J. Smith and children,
Glen and Lois, spent Sunday
with relatives at Alma Center.
Hans Iverson was taken to the B.
R. Falls hospital Saturday. He is
quite poorly, with heart trouble.
The Boy Scouts went to La Crosse
Saturday to receive some tests which
are required to gain their merits.
Mrs. Geo. Bergseth and Mrs. Hans
Rygh entertained at a silver tea on
Wednesday at the Bergseth home.
Russell Stevens, Douglas Finn, Dorothy
Hulett and Goldie Finn attended
the basket ball game at Winona
Friday night.
Mrs. C. J. Larson entered the Community
hospital at Whitehall Thursday.
Her many friends wish for a
speedy recovery.
Mesdames S. F. Wallen, A. S. Wallen,
O. E. Anderson and Owen entertained
the basket ball boys Friday
night at the Anderson home.
National Boy Scout week is Feb.
8 to 14. The Boy Scout organization
was founded in February, 1910.
President Roosevelt will speak over
the radio Wednesday evening in honor
o f the Boy Scouts. There are 14
boy scouts in the local troop, with
John Preston as scout master. Two
Eagle scouts, Vernon and Karl Rauk.
Star scouts are Gerald Larson, David
Wallen, Alfred Waller, Junior, Neri
Waller, and Dean Van Gorden. First
class— Devere Vandervort; Second
class— Robert Anderson, Calvin Fisher,
Otis Larson and Ralph Loken;
Tenderfoot— John Matson, Ralph Anderson,
Roger Smith and Roger Waller;
committee— A. S. Waller, Dr.
E. J. Smith, O. E. Anderson and
M. J. Larson. The scouts have their
meeting every Wednesday night. During
the week the Boy Scouts will have
window displays. Last year 11 o f our
local scouts camped at Camp Decorah
for a week. On Saturday the
Boy Scouts will serve lunch to the
public at the Legion hall to help raise
funds. Sunday they will attend
church in a body. Every Saturday
they go to La Crosse to practice
swimming in the pool there. Turn
out and help these young people support
such an honored organization.
Your support will be appreciated.
TA Y L O R HIGH SCHOOL
By Valborg Huseboe
Scenes in “ Julius Caesar” are to
be dramatized in the Freshman English
class. Maurice Knutson, Eileen
Clipper, Russel Owen, Marian Hulett
and Vivian Benedict are coaches. The
dramatic highlights o f each o f the
five acts are to be presented before
the class. The coach, before the presentation,
will report to class on setting
and characters attire. In this
way, we shall all be made acquainted
with Roman costumes, homes, senate,
and army camps.
In class, Miss Christianson is reading
the play; outside o f class each
individual is making a booklet containing
a synopsis o f each act, pictures
and anything pertinent to
Shakespeare or Roman life.
The junior class are studying a
very interesting subject in American
History, the Civil war. Did you know
that out o f the 2,000 battles fought
only 150 o f them were important?
The Junior and Senior American
Literature classes are progressing
qtiite rapidly on their poetry not5
books. They will be due on Feb.
IGiii. Many interesting covers are
being made. 
Some interesting talks on contemporary
literature are given m class
each Friday.
Thr Ftv ninan Homo F con ntc.i
class is making and studying house
plans.
The Sophomore Home Economics
class is studying meats o f all kinds.
Basket Bail Newt
Reporter— De Vere Vanderv ort
Taylor vs Merrillan
Taylor defetated and outplayed
Merrillan here on this floor by a
score o f 37 to 16.
Taylor played a good defensive
game throughout all four periods. Allen
Hulett started scoring with two
beautiful long shots. A fter this Taylor
kept a lead thruout the game.
High point man for Taylor was
Clayton Waller with 17 points, who
made some nice shots. Allen Hulett
and Raymond Owen followed with 6
points each. For Merrillan Stuart Olson
had 8 points which took high
honors for them. The score by quarters
was 5 4, 14 4, 28 12 and 37 16.
Taylor Seconds W in
The Taylor second team added one
more victory to its credit by defeating
Merrillan second 29 6. High point
man was Alfred Waller Jr. with 12
points. Howard Lambert followed
with 8 points. Score by quarters
was 6 2, 20 2, 20 4, 29 6.
T A Y L O R LU TH E RAN PARISH
A. J. Bringle, Pastor
Taylor:
Morning worship Sunday, Feb. 12.
The Boy Scouts will be guests at this
service in keeping with Boy Scout
week.
Fireside Hour at 5 p. m. Rev.
Sweger will be guest speaker, giving
an address on his trip to California
last year. Other special musical
numbers. All welcome.
Friday evening Men’s chorus practice
in Taylor fo r all churches .
Trempealeau Valley:
Please note change in services because
o f Boy Scout week. Service in
Trempealeau valley a week from Sunday.
On Sunday evening, Feb. 12th, the
Luther League meets with Rev. Sweger
as speaker.
On Wednesday afternoon Ladies
Aid will meet at the Carl Rauk home.
Assisting hostesses are: Mrs. John
H. Hanson, Mrs. Nels Larson and
Mrs. George Bergseth. Topic leader—
Mrs. B. A. Peterson.
Beaver Creek:
Sunday school worship on Sunday
afternoon, Feb. 12th, at 2 p. m.
Parish Notes:
Men’s chorus rehearsals for the
parish meets on Friday evening at 8
o ’clock in Taylor.
The Fireside meeting last Sunday
had one o f the largest crowds since
its beginning two years ago.
About $400.00 was raised during
the last two weeks for the Budget o f
the Synod in the churches o f the parish.
PINE HILL
Little Miss Judy Gomer has been
on the sick list.
Clarence Gomer sprained his back
while at work in the Falls.
Miss Susie Thompson is helping
Mrs. Harry Gomer a few days.
Robert Bright called on his mother,
Mrs. E. E. Bright, Sunday.
Mrs. Henry Deno called on Mrs.
Selma Waughtal Sunday evening.
Mrs. Henry Deno and Janis spent
Sunday with her mother, Mrs. Janette
Waughtal.
Mr. and Mrs. Cecil Bowen and F.
C. Bright were Sunday guests at E.
J. Bowen’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Glen Bowen and Duane
were calling Tuesday on Mr. and
Mrs. Cecil Bowen.
Harry Gomer with a force o f men,
is busy cutting and putting up ice for
himseif and others.
Mr. and Mrs. Charles Siegel and
family spent Saturday evening with
Mr. and Mrs. Frank Chatt.
Mrs. Nina Hoffman and daughter
were calling on her mother, Mrs.
Amelia Printz, Sunday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Bill Hunter and Mr.
and Mrs. Mahlon Siegel and family
spent Sunday with their parents, Mr.
and Mrs. Charles Siegel.
Mrs. Frank Chatt, Mrs. John Rulland
and Miss Marion Trondson and
Laurence Sprester called on Mrs. Edna
Onstad in La Crosse, Tuesday.
Those who spent Saturday evening
with Mr. and Mrs. Henry Deno were
Mr, and Mrs. Alex Vance and Robert,
Mr. and Mrs. Howard Burchard,
Mr. and Mrs. Carl Johnson, Albert
Johnson and Albert Deno sr. The
evening was spent playing 500.
Those who spent Saturday evening
with Mr. and Mrs. Harry Gomer were
Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Upton, Mr. and
Mrs. Lee Casper, Mr. and Mrs. Bert
Sanford, Mr. and Mrs. Art Upton and
Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Northup. The evening
was spent playing 500: Refreshments
were served at midnight.
SHAMROCK
Mrs. Ray Windsor was cn the sick
list the last week.
Lois Irene Brown has been a victim
o f intestinal flu.
Mrs. Mary Kelley, Mr. and Mrs.
Pliny Kelley were callers in Sparta
Saturday.
Mrs. Geraldine Millis was operated
last Monday at the Krohn hospital
for appendicitis.
Mr. and Mrs. Dona'.d Thompson
have rented rooms in the Geo. Zahrte
home in your city.
Miss Irene Olson o f Squaw Creek
has been a guest at the O. P. Kelley
home for the last few days.
Charles Kelley suffered a relapse
Saturday and was taken to the Krohn
hospital for further treatment.
Little Sandra Jean, daughter o f
Mr. and Mrs. Ray Millis, who has
been very ill at the Sparta hospital,
o f intestinal flu, is improving.
Mr. and Mrs. Ray Mann, sons David
and Ray, went to Neillsville last
Saturday to attend the funeral o f a
brother in law and uncle, Martin
Wing. Burial was in Cataract.
Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Harper accompanied
Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Paulson
to Alma Center Friday to make
the acquaintance o f a little daughter
o f Mr. and Mrs. Harvey Harmon.
The Shamrock Good Will club will
have its valentine party at the home
o f Mrs. Albert Ball Feb. 16. There
will be an apron parade and exchange
of patterns. All members are requested
to attend.
C LO VE RD ALE
Earl Horswill and family called on
Fremont Avery, Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Joe Capen visited at
Carl Stratton’s, Sunday.
Mrs. Ressie Wyss spent last Friday
with Mrs. Ford Harmer.
Jacob Wyss is having his buildings,
rewired for electric lights.
Merlin Engebretson was a caller at
Tillie Emerson’s, last Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Philip Nortman were
Sunday dinner guests at George
Nortman’s.
George Nortman returned home on
Saturday from the clinic, feeling a
lot better again.
Emma Stiehl and Esther Marie
spent Sunday afternoon with Verna
Huber, in Melrose.
Lois Capen, Emma Stiehl and Esther
Marie called on Anna Wyss last.
Tuesday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Clyde Bailey and children
accompanied Arthur Peterson
and family to Humbird Sunday to see 
Albert Kersting and family.
M ILLSTON
Charles Pitts, o f Roberts, spent
the week end at home.
Mr. and Mrs. Roland Pitts and Mrs.
Lewis Epstein attended the Woman’s
club card party Friday evening.
Mrs. M. S. Pitts entertained Mrs.
Floyd Tessman, Mrs. Fern Bernette,
Mrs. Wm. Harkner and Mrs. Roland
Pitts with 500 and potato pancakes
Wednesday afternoon.
Little Richard Olson caused his parents
no little worry when a paper
sucker stick lodged in his throat. He
was choken and badly frightened, but
succeeded in coughing up the sw ,‘
stick on the way to B. P
the hospital. Pa" 
Th „
 .inpfW sy'mpatViy .all is exgntted
to Mr. and Mrs . Edward La
on the deSLth o f their fivemonth
Md son, Robert Hugh, who
passed ■away in the hospital Saturday
with pneumonia. He had been sick for
some time and was taken to the hospital
Thursday.
Mr. and Mrs. Steven Biszak o f
Chicago, form er Millston residents,
announce the marriage o f their
daughter Evelyn, to Harry Jenkerson
in Chicago, January 21, 1939. Mr.
Jenkerson is the son o f Mr. and Mrs.
Edward Jenkerson o f Sandy Plains,
and is now employed in Chicago
where the newly married couple will
continue to make their home. Sincere
good wishes o f all their friends is
extended for a most successful and
happy future.
AUCTIONEER RO ARIN G CREEK
Mrs. H. W. Zuehlsdorff had dental
work done in your city last week.
Glenn Zuehlsdorff was a business
caller at Mrs. Anna Haugstad’s, on
Thursday.
Mrs. Merlin Peterson and son Lyle
spent Friday afternoon with Mrs.
Glen Zuehlsdorff.
Mr. and Mrs. G. L. Zuehlsdorff
and son spent Sunday evening at the
Harvey Meyers home.
Earl Overlien went to Northfield,
Minn., where he is entering St. Olaf
college for the second semester work.
The Haugstad girls are living in
your city during the cold weather,
spending the week ends with their
mother here.
Miss Edna Laughnan who had been
with her cousin, Miss O’Conner, while
the latter was convalescing from an
appendectomy, returned to her home
here last week Saturday.
Mesdames Midtlien, Haugstad,
Meyers, Bert Gilbertson and Miss
Caroline Overlien attended Lutheran
Ladies Aid held Wednesday with
Mrs. Grace Millis in Pleasant View.
The home o f G. G. and Donald
Gilbertson is quarantined, the older
son, Donald Gilbertson, being ill of
scarlet fever. The school in Irving is
closed for a period o f two weeks. We
sincerely hope there are no more
cases.
Mike Lemanski now supplys a
com plete AU CTION SALES
SERVICE. W ill arrange for the
sale bills and advertising matter
secure a Clerk or Finance Com pany
who will take the notes
and pay you the cash also A u ctioneering
that pays big Dividends
at no extra cost.
W rite me at once o r phone 8644
MIKE LEM ANSKI, Eau Claire
S E K 0 V
THE PROVEN
METHOD FOR
WEIGHT
REDUCTION
AUCTIONEER
SOUTH A LM A
Ray Williams o f Millston, spent
Thursday afternoon and evening with
R. Bue.
Addison Burlingame o f Merrillan
has been helping Otto Bradeson the
past week.
Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Collum and
daughter Fern, spent Thursday evening
with relatives at Black River
Falls.
Mr. and Mrs. Herman Casper and
two sons o f Menomonie, attended A lbert
Casper’s funeral services, January
31st.
Miss Beula Sullivan o f Madison is
spending the week between semesters
with her relatives and friends in
and around our community.
Albert Casper o f South Alma died
at the Krohn hospital Friday evening
January 27th. He was born at Black
River Falls in 1870 which made him
68 years, eleven months and 21 days
old. He was baptized and confirmed
in the German Lutheran church at
Black River Falls. He was a member
o f Alma Center Lutheran church.
Funeral services were Tuesday afternoon
at Alma Center.
SE K O V is a modern scientific
form ula, consisting o f herbs,
tonics and glandular extracts. It
is based upon a combination o f
herbs and tonics that H AV E
D EFIN IT ELY PROVEN in laboratory
research to be o f great
value in NORM ALIZING and
TONING up the system in general.
SE K O V is used and endorsed
by reliable physicians as a
healthful and corrective method
o f W E IG H T REDUCTION.
MISS ROSE BENESH
Graven in everlasting granite, tke
m em ory o f a loved one is recorded for
posterity. In all the unfamiliar details
o f creating an expressive memorial
you will find our experience and fa 
cilities o f the utmost value. Consultation
is w elcom ed—at our diapU yor
by appointment.
motored to B. R. Falls on Sunday to
meet Miss Sarah, who has employment
in Milwaukee. She came to attend
the funeral o f her grandmother,
Mrs. Roseland sr., which was held on
Monday in Beaver Creek.
Members o f the Ralph Meirow
family, Silas Amidon family, Mr. and
Mrs. Wm. Miller o f Bangor, and Albert
Meirow o f Canada, gathered at
the Puls home at B. R. Falls on Sunday
and assisted Mr and Mrs. Carl
Puls in celebrating their 37th wedding
anniversary.
SEKOV REDUCING
STUDIO Constipated? “ For 30 years I had constipation, awful
gas bloating, headaches and back pains.
Adlerika helped right away. Now, I eat
sausage, bananas, pie, anything I want 
Never felt better.” Mrs. Mabel Schott.
BLACK RIVER
FALLS MONUM
ENT W ORKS
W alter Kissinger
Proprietor
122 2 So. Barstow Street
EAU V L A IR E , W ISCONSIN
Dial 3936 fo r Appointm ent For your protection
EVERY ROCK OF
AGES MEMORIAL
BEARS THIS SEAL
etched tn the it one.
THE BANNER JOURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin PAGE NO. 7
Services at the Lutheran church on
Sunday, Feb. 12, at 2 o’clock.
Mrs. Bertha Olson spent a few days
in Chicago with her daughters Bernice
and Alice.
Mr. and Mrs. Bert Pringle o f B. R.
Falls, were dinner guests at Steinbring’s,
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Bill Regez o f Onalaska,
spent the week end here with
relatives and friends.
Roy Larson o f Minneapolis, spent
several days last week with his parents,
Mr. and Mrs. E. M. Larson.
Miss Reinetta Reisinger o f Port
Edwards, spent the week end with
her parents, Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Reisineer.
The following helped Mrs. Peter
Faldet celebrate her birthday Friday:
Mr. and Mrs. Eddie Nelson, Mrs.
Lawrence Larson and daughters Mavis,
Mary Lou and Shirley, Mrs. Simon
Faldet and son Frances, Mr. and
Mrs. Selmer Faldet and son Bailon.
On Saturday evening 21 friends came
in and helped her celebrate. A fine
lunch was served and every one had
a good time.
Mrs. Wm. Steinbring, chairman o f
the village o f Hixton for the President’
s birthday fund campaign wishes
to thank all those who helped in any
way toward raising money toward the
fig h t against in fa n t ile paralysis. Special
praise should be given the Hixton
Study club, the Elm Homemakers
unsolicited contributions toward this
club and Postmaster Simons for their
great cause. The committee is very
grateful to these people.
H IXTON HIGH SCHOOL
The senior English class has been
studying Milton and his writings.
They find it very interesting.
Every one who attended the junior
class play Friday night claimed it to
be a “ howling” success. The sound
effects were so realistic that we were
all afraid o f our own shadow. It is
fortunate that none o f the Hollywood
talent scouts were out or we would
probably lose some o f our schoolmates.
Much credit is due Mr. White
the new director, and the cast, for
putting on such an excellent performance.
Congratulations! Due to the
excitement and interest backstage,
Mr. White forgot his “ thank you
speech. He and the Junior class wish
to take this opportunity to thank
every one who furnished stage properties
and attended the play.
The Student Council had an open
forum meeting in the assembly Monday
forenoon. The que ion concerning
news reporters wa" brought up.
We decided to draft three students
each week to act as reporters. La
Verne Emery suggested Mr. Dewey s
independent study plan. The plan is
as follow s: Two days o f the week
the students are allowed to come to
school whenever they wish and leave
when their work is satisfactorily completed.
These students must have at
least a B average. This plan enables
the student to devote a greater portion
o f time to the studies in which
he is interested. Each student who
would ordinarily be behind would
strive to be on this list. This plan
A U C T I O N
On the Old Knut
Bergseth Farm
 mile South o f Taylor on
County Trunk N
WED., FEB. 15
A T 1 P. M. SH ARP
H ORSES— Sorrel mare in foal,
8 years old, sorrel mare colt 8
months old, bay mare 8 years
old.
L IV E STOCK and G RAIN —
3 good cows to freshen this
spring. Guernsey bull 8 months.
3 W hite brood sows to farrow
first part o f April.
100 New Hampshire red pullets
laying good now. All Hay, and
Straw, etc.
A L L M ACH IN ERY, ETC.
Terms o f Sale. Cash or Bankable
notes.
Mrs. Teubordt
Thompson, Prop.
Jackson County Bank, Clerk
GEO. H. B A R R Y , Arcadia, Wis.
Auctioneer.
ATTENTION
Zanal Customers
at our home you may have seven
 7 packages o f either
Swish or J iffy Perfum ed Starch
fo r only $1.00. This is far below
wholesale price.
L. H. SCHROEDER
A L M A CEN TER, W ISCONSIN
Fox Meat Wanted
W e pay up to $ 1 2 p e r head
FOR OLD D ISA B L E D HORSES
AND CR IPPLED C A T T L E
D EAD OR A L IV E
W e kill daily. My tracks pickup
anywhere and pay cash.
I PAY AL L PHONE C A LLS
Walter Marg Fox Farm
PHONE 2 R 19
BLA CK R IV E R FALLS WIS.
FARMS FOR SALE
Federal Land Bank and Private
Farms — Call or Se 
The Gile Agency
Pkone 85 Marrillan, Wia.
For Prompt Service and Fin acial
Responsibility
Ship Your Poultry and Veal to
Richard J. Collins Co.
Established 1868
840 Fulton Market, Chicago. IIL
would eliminate report cards. It
would also do away with the “ trouble 
makers” who congregate in the
halls and downtown, because students
who have an average below B do this.
The student body approves o f the
plan. This is the first o f the series
of forum to be held in every threeweek
period. The purpose is to develop
initiative and good attitudes toward
school. The Dewey plan itself
has not been accepted.
The Junior Chemistry class is studying
about the properties and uses
o f sulphur.
The Sophomore Biology class is
studying about the growth o f corn
and beans.
The Hixton Wildcats were defeated
at Alma Center Thursday night. The
score was 23 17.
The four amateur basket ball teams
keep the students entertained during
the noon hour. At present the Bees
are the leading team.
Allen Tande is working on a jig saw
in manual training. This is one o f
Allen’s own inventions.
The Algebra class is learning how
to invest money. They know how
much it takes at 5 , 6 and x to
earn $1000.
The Sophomore Home Ec. class is
working on wool projects. The Freshmen
are working on quick breads for
breakfast.
Some report cards are still missing
so we will be unable to print the
honor roll this week. Signed:
VIRGINIA BERGERSON
ELVINA NERBY
FLORENCE ROGSTAD
Reporters
YO R K
Mrs. Carl Knutson spent Tuesday
at Aaron Hulett’s.
Glen Erickson helped Leonard Shae
haul wood last week.
Severin Thorpen and family spent
Saturday evening at Knut Haugen’s.
Melvin J. Larson and Robert Wilson
were Disco and B. R. Falls callers
Tuesday.
Mr. and Mrs. Harold Long were
Saturday dinner guests at Philip
Steiner’s at Independence.
Mr. and Mrs. Robert Wilson and
Mrs. Emma Wilson were business visitors
at B. R. Falls, Monday.
Stanley Dettinger and Eddie Erickson
and families were Saturday evening
visitors at Ray Knutson’s.
Mrs. John Dettinger and daughter
Miss Lillian, and grandsons, were B.
R. Falls vistiors Sunday afternoon.
Mrs. Robert Wilson and son Bobby,
and Aaron Hulett were visitors at
Carl Knutson’s one day last week.
Mr. and Mrs. Gale Pringle and son
Jimmie were visitors at the home o f
her parents, Mr. and Mrs. Oscar Larson,
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Stanley Dettinger
and son Eugene, and Miss Lillian
Dettinger were shopping at Eau
Claire Thursday.
Oscar Vesta and family, Mr. and
Mrs. J. B. Howden and daughter Ila
and T. S. Vesta were Sunday afternoon
visitors at Wilson’s.
Miss Lillian Dettinger spent from
Wednesday until Thursday at the
home o f her aunt, Mrs. Christina
Dettinger at Northfield.
Mr. and Mrs. Edwin Eid and daugh
ter Marion were Sunday afternoon
visitors at the home o f her parents,
Mr. and Mrs. John Olson.
A 9 pound son was born to Mr.
and Mrs. Clarence Larson on Monday,
Jan. 30, 1939, at the hospital
at Whitehall. Mother and babe are
doing nicely.
The workmen installed the chum
in the creamery last week and all
other machinery will be installed this
week. The annual creamery meeting
will be held on Thursday, Feb. 16th.
William Olson went to Minneapolis
with Elmer Myers after the new
chum for the creamery Tuesday.
Mrs. Olson and son Roger spent the
day at the home o f her parents, Mr.
and Mrs. Aaron Hulett.
FOUR CORNERS
Donald Johnson went to Madison
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. George Miller were
guests o f her parents at Merrillan on
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Johnson of Charter
Oak mill, visited at Geo. Miller’ s, on
Friday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Dorrance Stolts and
son Tully viisted at Asa Fox’s, on
Thursday evening.
Waldo Hertzfeidt, who spent the
past few days at Fort Sheridan, returned
home Friday.
Mr. and Mrs. George Maule visited
with Mrs. Ida Holmes and Sherman
Saturday evening.
A son was bom to Mr. and Mrs.
Raymond Duxbury at the Krohn
hospital, Friday, Feb. 3, 1939.
John R. Johnson and sons and Miss
Luella Torken were last Sunday visitors
at Maynard Yeskie’s, at Disco.
Misses Olive and Goldie Thompson
called to see their brother Teman, on
Sunday, who is a patient at Krohn
hospital.
Mr. and Mrs. Alfred Letson and
sons, Harold and Claire, and daughter
June spent last Saturday evening
at Asa Fox’s.
Mrs. George Maule attended the
funeral o f Mr. Lukas, at Taylor, on
Tuesday. Mr. Maule spent the afternoon
with Peter Peskun.
The Maule family received a telegram
stating the death o f their sister,
Mrs. Charles Wheeler in Upland, Cal.,
last week. The funeral was held
there on Thursday.
Mr. and Mrs. Asa Fox and Mr.
and Mrs. Marvin Johnson visited at
the Van Horn home Saturday evening.
Willis and Wendell Fox spent
the evening with the Johnson boys.
Word was received by friends here
o f the birth o f a son, Marvin George,
to Mr. and Mrs. Albert Macklin, on
Jan. 8, 1939, at Sunland, California.
Mrs. Macklin was fom .erly Miss Shirley
Vanatter.
SE CH LER VILLE
Evelyn Iverson is assisting Mrs.
Griffin with her house work.
The H. H. Smith family spent
Sunday with relatives at Neillsville.
Mr. and Mrs. C. B. Stolts visited
Mr. and Mrs. Jas. Chatt at Hixton,
Sunday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Edward Hanson o f
Garden Valley, visited the Ray family
here Wednesday.
Mr. and Mrs. Eli Lyon have returned
from a visit o f several days
with friends at Taylor.
E. L. Mortiboy and family o f Curran,
took Sunday dinner with his parents,
Mr. and Mrs. R. E. Mortiboy.
Andrew Skutley had the misfortune
to have a breakdown with his
feed mill a while ago, but now he has
a new hammermill and is again at
work.
SOUTH SE CH LER VILLE
Gordon Hestikind was a week end
visitor at Melrose.
F. W. Loasching spent Monday
evening with Albert Campbell.
John Preston accompanied his Boy
Scouts to La Crosse, Saturday.
Evelyn Iverson was a Sunday visitor
at the Hans Nelson home.
Marvin Johnson and Martin Ryerson
were Melrose callers Thursday
afternoon.
Oluf Hagen and family were Sunday
afternoon visitors at F. W.
Loasching’s.
Martin Ryerson was a caller at
the Albert Campbell home Wednesday
afternoon.
John Preston entertained a friend
Howard Stevens, o f Taylor, as dinner
guest, Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Albert Campbell and
Agnes spent Saturday evening at the
Henry Soukop home.
Agnes Campbell and Edgar Soukop
visited Mr. and Mrs. Andy Larson
Thursday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. George Maule were
Saturday afternoon and evening visitors
with Mrs. Ida Holmes.
Mr. and Mrs. Albert Campbell and
Agnes spent Tuesday evening at the
A. W. Bates home at Hixton.
Mr. and Mrs. Marvin Johnson and
sons Willard and Walter spent Tuesday
evening at Ernest Nordahl’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Henry Soukop and
grandson Robert were Sunday visitors
with friends at Black River Falls.
Mr. and Mrs. Hans Nelson entertained
their daughter and husband,
Mr. and Mrs. Knudsten, Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Marvin Johnson and
family were Sunday dinner guests at
the home o f the form er’s uncle, Eli
Lyons.
Mr. and Mrs. Eli Lyons who have
been spending the past week with
friends at Taylor returned home on
Friday.
Mrs. Andrew Skutley, Mrs. David
Short and Mrs. Arthur Melby were
Tuesday evening callers at the J. D.
Preston home.
The Leaders group meeting o f the
homemakers clubs will meet at the
home o f Mrs. David Short Tuesday,
February 14 th.
A number from here attended the
card party at Hixton Monday evening
which was sponsored by the Ladies
Study Club.
Mr. and Mrs. Albert Campbell and
daughter Agnes and Edgar Soukop
spent Wednesday evening at the F.
W. Loasching home.
Vernon Stalter who has spent the
winter at the home of his w ife’s parents,
Mr. and Mrs. O. K. Hagen, left
for the east, Thursday.
Mrs. A. W. Bates and Mrs. Albert
Campbell spent Tuesday afternoon
with the latter’s daughter Mrs. Herbert
Soukop at Hixton.
Mr. and Mrs. Andy Larson, Evelyn
Iverson, Agnes Campbell and Edgar
Soukop were Black River Falls
callers, Sunday evening.
Lucile Skutley who has employment.
at Eau Claire spent the week
end at the home o f her parents Mr.
and Mrs. Andrew Skutley.
Lu Preston who has employment
at tie Carisch Beauty Shop in Black
River Falls, spent the week end with
her parents, Mr. and Mrs. J. D. Preston.
Mr. and Mrs. Andy Larson, Evelyn
Iverson, Mr. and Mrs. Herbert
Soukop and Edgar Soukop were Sunday
afternoon callers at Albert
Campbell’s.
Mrs. Ward Lowe and daughter
Betty, Mrs. Campbell and daughter
Agnes and Mrs. Herbert Soukop of
Hixton, visited Mrs. F. W. Loasching
Wednesday afternoon.
W E S T G ARD EN V A L L E Y
Mrs. B. O. Larson visited friends
at Merrillan, Saturday.
Miss Christine Erickson spent last
Sunday at her home here.
Lucille Hendrickson spent Thursday
with Mrs. George Dahl.
Little Lucille Hendrickson spent
Friday with Mrs. Z. N. Nelson.
Mrs. Louis Erickson spent Thursday
afternoon at Z. N. Nelson’s.
Mr. and Mrs. George Dahl spent
Saturday evening at Aaron Braeger’s.
Herbert Lindbolm left Monday after
spending a week here among his
friends.
Mr. and Mrs. Erick Olson and
John spent Sunday evening at Z. N.
Nelson’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Louis Erickson and
Arnold spent Saturday evening at
Alfred Dahl’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Albert Hendrickson
arnd George Dahl were callers at
Whitehall, on Thursday.
A. Haydon and Theodore Hanson
o f Ettrick were callers at George
Dahl’s, Saturday evening.
D. E. Erickson, Arthur and Anna
were callers at Ralph Erickson’s at
Hixton last Saturday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. George Dahl and
Margaret were guests o f Mr. and
Mrs. Harold Eberdt at Warrens last
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Erick Olson and
John, also Alfred Erickson and Maynard
Oligney were callers at Ralph
Erickson’s at Hixton, Tuesday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. George Dahl and
Margaret spent Wednesday evening
with Mrs. Albert Hendrickson in honor
o f her birthday. Johnny Olson
was also there.
Nicholas Moroz o f Milwaukee, a
Russian Gospel worker was a Saturday
night guest at the D. E. Erickson
home and also held services Sunday
morning at the church, which was
enjoyed by a large gathering. He
has been holding services and showing
slides o f the Soviet Union in Russia
at the churches at Taylor, Blair
and Hixton.
NORTH SOUTH ALM A
The card club met at the Victor
Capaul home Sunday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. A. S. Hart were recent
callers at the George Galster
home.
Alfred Blencoe and son Everett
called at the George Blencoe home,
Sunday.
Several from here attended the
funeral services o f Albert Casper on
Tuesday.
Mrs. Albert Jacobson attended the
funeral o f Mrs. Billerbeck in Alma
Center, Monday.
Mrs. Orvis Burnett and son Merton
visited at the C. Keach home on
Thursday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Donald Clifford of
Meirillan, called at the George Galster
home, Sunday.
Mrs. Clarence Keach, Josephine
and Frank visited Sunday at the
George Blencoe home.
Clark Burnett and Joe Gillis attended
the basketball game in Alma
Center, Tuesday evening.
I. R. Barnim o f Chicago, and Mrs.
William Bamum o f Black River Falls
called at tfife' C. Keach home, Monday.
M
r. and Mrs. Leroy Getman motored
to Madison Monday. Miss
Beula Sullivan returned home with
them.
F A L L COULIE
Paul Hanson visited at his home
here on Sunday.
Christ Vindahl was a caller at
Whitehall Friday.
Andrew Bolstad was a caller at Oscar
H off’s, Sunday.
Andrew Bolstad visited at Edwin
Embretson’s, Sunday.
Mrs. Harold Hanson visited Mrs.
Simon Amundson, Friday.
Miss Cassie Thompson is visiting
Miss Rachel Curran in Taylor.
Raymond H off visited at Melvin
Olson’s and Pete Eidet’s, Sunday.
Mrs. M. Hagenstad is still confined
to her bed, but somewhat better.
Mr. and Mrs. Christ Vindahl visited
Saturday evening at Oscar H off’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Morris Johnson visited
Saturday evening at Alvin Johnson’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Selmer Faldet visited
Sunday afternoon at Simon Faldet’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Gower and
family visited at Gust Johnson’s, on
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Dettinger
were callers Saturday at Simon Amundson’s.
Mr. and Mrs. John Peterson visited
Saturday evening at Simon Amundson’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Harvey Carpenter
visited Sunday evenirg at Thomas
Thompson’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Bemt Thompson and
Theo. Thompson visited Monday at
Melvin Olson’s.
Mrs. Gust Johnson and daughter
Helen visited Monday afternoon at
Hellick Olson’s.
M. Ringlien and Oluf Hagen and
J. Rogstad called at C. Vindahl’s
Friday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Carl Steig and children
and Paul Hanson visited at Simon
Amundson’s, Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Emil Berget and Lorraine
were visitors at Ener Embretson’s
Saturday afternoon.
Mrs. Alvin Johnson and daughter
Beverly, and Hannah Lien visited
Mrs. Simon Faldet Monday.
Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Thompson
and daughters visited Monday evening
at Harvey Carpenter’s.
Mr. and Mrs. John Hanson visited
Tuesday with their daughter, Mrs.
Lester Duxbury and family in Alma
Center.
Mr. and Mrs. Henry Eide and son
Merlin, Mr. and Mrs. Sever Eide and
family were dinner guests Sunday at
Martin Hagen’s.
Mrs. C. Vindahl visited Saturday at
B. R. Falls with her daughter Harriet
and also called at the hospital to see
Grandma Whiting.
Mr. and Mrs. Morris Hoff and family
o f Stevens Point, visited Saturday
at Oscar H off’s to see his father,
Ole H off, who is not so well.
Mr. and Mrs. Charles Olson, Mr.
and Mrs. Leonard Olson and children
and Andrew Bolstad visited Friday
evening at Simon Amundson’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Simon Amundson and
daughter Melva, Margery Johnson,
and Clement Rasmussen visited at
Arnold Olson’s at Whitehall, Tuesday
evening.
Mrs. Simon Faldet, Mrs. Oscar
Eide and Mrs. Thomas Thompson
and daughters Olga and Mayme visited
Saturday afternoon with Mrs.
Selmer Faldet.
Mr. and Mrs. John Hanson and Elsie
visited Saturday with their daughter
and sister, Mrs. John Merrill, at
the Krohn hospital, and became acquainted
with the little twins.
There will be Sewing circle meeting
at the Burton school house Tuesday
afternoon, Feb. 15. A quilt will
be sold. Every one welcome. Ladies
please bring something for lunch.
Mr. and Mrs. Wm. Carlson and
daughters o f Blair, and Even Olson
and Mr. Helgeson also o f Blair, visited
at Hellick Olson’s, Sunday. Mr.
and Mrs. Oluf Solberg and Mrs. Carl
Bjorge and son James spent the afternoon
there.
There will be community club at
the Burton school house Friday evening,
Feb. 10. The committees are as
follows: Serving— Mrs. Mike Abend,
Mrs. John Simonson, Mrs. Charles
Dorrance; Program— Mrs. Simon
Amundson, Mrs. Alvin Johnson, Mrs.
William Olson. There will be a very
good program with a play from
Northfield, Mr. White o f Hixton will
be there to entertain, and also some
other good numbers.
SCHERM ERHORN
Casper Magelee is enjoying a 1936
V 8.
Dr. R. N. Leasum o f Osseo, was
called to see C. P. Lunde, who is
quite ill.
Mrs. Alvin Erickson, who teaches
near Augusta, spent the week end at
her home.
Mrs. Joel Olson and Mayme Olson
spent Thursday afternoon with Mrs.
Spencer Hanson.
Mrs. P. H. Eidet and Mrs. John
Magelee spent Saturday afternoon
with Mrs. John Rogstad.
Mr. and Mrs. Arnold Ringlien and
son Gorden, o f Fly Creek, spent Sunday
afternoon at the Menick Ringlien
home.
Mr. and Mrs. Edwin Larson and
Wallace were Whitehall callers Friday.
They also visited at the Phillipson
home.
Andrew Bolstad has returned home
from a month’s visit with his daughter
and other relatives and friends
in Minneapolis.
Mr. and Mrs. Anton Bunderson and
sons and Olger Erickson o f Fall Coulie
spent a Sunday afternoon recently
with Mr. and Mrs. Alvin Erickson.
Mrs. Gaylord Jacobson and sons returned
home from Osseo, where the
boys spent three weeks and Mrs. Jacobson
one week after her recent operation.
Mr. and Mrs. Lewis Lundstad o f
Eau Claire, called at the Lien home
Sunday on their way to Whitehall,
taking their daughter, Mrs. Lukas
Ekem and son home after spending
the week end at Eau Claire.
Mr. and Mrs. W. P. Faldet o f Hixton,
Mrs. Martin Hagen, Mrs. Eddie
Nelson, Mr. and Mrs. Menick Ringlien
helped Mrs. John Rogstad celebrate
her birthday, Thursday afternoon.
George and Hazel Fredrickson spent
the evening there.
Miss Hazel Fredrickson .accompanied
by her aunts, Mrs. H. E. Hanson,
Mrs. L. J. Schansberg and Mrs. Gust
Steig, also Mr. Steig o f Whitehall,
spent Sunday at La Crosse, to see
Mrs. Holm, who is very ill. Mrs.
Fredrickson is caring for Mrs. Holm.
The following spent Friday evening
at the Rogstad home helping
John celebrate his birthday anniversary:
Mr. and Mrs. Spencer Hanson,
Halvor Hanson, Mr. and Mrs. Manford
Hagen, John Magelee and Robert,
Mayme and Gaylord Olson. Whist
and Chinese checkers were enjoyed
by all.
"Y ou look hollow chested and thin”
said the air pump to the inner tube.
“ What seems to be the trouble?”
“ Income tacks” , wearily replied
the inner tube.
E A ST H IXTON
Henry Sukopp was a dinner guest
at the John Upton home Friday.
Archie Randals o f your city spent
a couple days with Archie Kelley.
Our Homemakers meet Thursday
afternoon with Nancy Casper, Feb. 9.
Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Downer will
entertain their card club Saturday
evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Douglas Nolop were
callers at Lew Randals an afternoon
last week.
Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Downer spent
Saturday evening at the Mahlon Nordahl
home.
Mrs. Mahlon Nordahl spent a few
days at your city helping her mother,
Mrs. Fisher.
Mr. and Mrs. Ed Brandt spent
Friday evening with Mr. and Mrs.
Robert Upton.
Mr. and Mrs. Ed Brandt and
daughters spent Sunday evening at
John Upton’s.
Barbara Jean Upton spent a few
days with her aunt, Mrs. Blaine Entwistle,
at your city.
Mr. and Mrs. Leonard Casper and
Gus Casper spent Saturday evening
with Mr. and Mrs. Bob Upton.
Mr. and Mrs. Si Knudsen and son,
and Miss Vesta Reineck were Sunday
dinner guests at Adolph Reineck’s.
Mrs. C. F. Goldsmith spent the
fore part o f last week at Merrillan
with Mr. and Mrs. Edgar Goldsmith
and family.
Mr. and Mrs. Mike Abend, Mr. and
Mrs. Lee Casper and son were Sunday
visitors with Mr. and Mrs. Lloyd
Chri singer.
The shower Thursday afternoon at
Mrs. Leonard Casper’s for Mrs. Lloyd
Chrisinger was well attended and she
received many nice gifts.
Mrs. Ed Brandt and daughter accompanied
her brother, Chas. Kilberg
to see Mr. and Mrs. Basil Burnett
and family Sunday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. John Upton and Barbara
Jean, Mr. and Mrs. Mahlon
Nordahl, Jimmy and Patty were Sunday
visitors with Mr. and Mrs. Charles
Nordahl and family.
Mr. and Mrs. Robert Upton were
dinner guests o f Mr. and Mrs. Blaine
Entwistle as Bob had to go to the
clinic to have his bums dressed. They
are much better at this writing, and
he will soon be on the job again.
Robert Upton met with what might
have been a very serious accident on
Thursday afternoon when the engine
which he was using for power to
gum saws, exploded and he was badly
burned about the face, neck, ears
and arms.
NORTH SH ADY GLEN
The Pole Grove sewing club will
meet with Mrs. H. C. Getman March
2, in the afternoon.
Sewing club met with Mrs. Ben
Oppegard last Thursday, and was not
very largely attended.
Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Knutson
spent Sunday at the home o f their
son Donald, near Hixton.
Mr. and Mrs. H. C. Getman spent
Saturday afternoon at the home o f
their son Paul, in Hixton.
Mr. and Mrs. Dud. Downer and
Mrs. Chris Engum spent Friday afternoon
with their sister and daughter,
Mrs. Kennie Linnell, at B. R.
Falls.
Mr. and Mrs. Paul Casper entertained
the following company Sunday:
Mr. and Mrs. Jess Jarrett, Mr.
and Mrs. H. C. Getman, Mr. and Mrs.
Milton Knutson, Robert Jarrett and
friend from Curran Valley.
SAN D Y PLAINS
Ed Straight has men cutting pulp
wood.
Mrs. Ed Jinkerson was a visitor in
town Monday.
Mr. and Mrs. Solomon Johnson visited
at Clarence Johnson’s, Sunday.
Miss lone Pickering, missionary to
the Jews in Austria and Czechoslovakia,
will speak at Sunday school
hour at Sandy Plains school house on
Feb. 19th, at 2 o’clock.
Mrs. Leroy Jones was in town on
Monday to visit her new grandson,
Frank Richard Harmon, born Feb. 1,
1939, at the hospital, to Mr. and Mrs.
Richard Harmon, o f Shamrock.
NOTICE OF SALE
STA TE O F W ISCON SIN . C OU N TY OF
Jackaon— In C ircuit C ourt
Frank J. Benish and John H. Benish, P la in tiff .
vs
Alm a Sieger, D efendant.
B y virtu e o f a Judgm ent o f Partition and
Sale m ade in the a b ov e entitled action , on
the 15th d a y o f D ecem ber, 1938. the undersigned.
will sell at the fro n t d oor o f the
court house in the city o f Black R iver Falls,
Jackson county, W isconsin, on the 3rd day
o f M arch, 1939, a t ten o ’clock in the fo re n
oon o f that day, the real estate directed
by said judgm ent to be sold, and therein
described as fo llo w s: The south east quarter
ef the south east quarter o f section thirteen,
except railroad rig h t of w a y and the
north on e h alf o f section tw en ty fou r, all in
Tow nship tw en ty fou r, north, range five
west, except railroad rig h t of w a y acrosp
the north east corner o f the north east
quarter o f the north east quarter and except
highw ay rig h t o f w a y and except five
acres in the north east corner o f the south
east quarter o f the north east quarter,
described as fo llo w s: C om m encing at the
north east corner o f said fo rty , thence running
w est fo rty ro d s ; thence south tw enty
rods ; thence east fo rty rods ; thence north
tw enty rods to the place o f beginning, a 
described in 47 o f Deeds on page 267.
Term s o f Sale— Cash.
Dated January 17, 1939.
GEORGE H. DE TTIN G E R. R eferee
D. M. PE R R Y . P la in tiff's A ttorn ey,
Black R iver Falls, W isconsin.
Jan. 18 Feb. 22
NOTICE T O CREDITO RS
S T A T E OF W ISCONSIN. C OU N TY COURT,
Jackson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f Lee B.
Gearing, Deceased.
Letters o f A dm inistration having been
issued to F. H. D uxbury, in the estate o f
Lee B. Gearing, deceased, late o f the tow n
o f Alm a, in said co u n ty :
N otice is hereby given that all claims
against the said Lee B. Gearing, deceased,
late o f the tow n o f A lm a, in Jackson County,
W iscon sin, m ust be presented to said
County C ourt at Black R iver Falls, in said
County on o r b efore the 5th day o f June,
1939, o r be b a rred ; and that all such
claim s and dem ands will be exam ined and
adjusted at a term o f said court to be held
at the cou rt house in th e city of Black
R iver Falls, in said cou nty, on T uesday, the
6th day o f June, 1939, a t 10 o ’clock in the
foren oon o f said day.
Dated January 25, 1939.
By Order o f the Court,
H A R R Y M. PE R R Y . Judge
D. M. P E R R Y , A ttorney
Feb. 1 15
NOTICE OF E XE CU TO R ’S OR A D M IN ISTR
A TO R ’S SALE OF R E A L ESTATE
STA TE O F W ISCONSIN. C OU N TY COURT,
Jackson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f Ida C. Ball,
Deceased
N otice It H ereby Given that by virtu e of
and pursuant to an order m ade in said
m a tter on the 31st day o f January, 1939,
by the County C ourt o f Jackson C ounty, the
undersigned, Kerm it A. H anson. A dm inistrator,
will, on the 25th day o f February,
1939, at 10 o ’ clock a. m. at the prem ises o f
the late Ida C. Ball, in the city o f Black
R iver Falls, in said county, offer fo r sale
at public auction, and sell to the highest
bidder, subject to the ap p roval o f the cou rt,
the follow in g described real estate o f Ida
C. Ball, deceased, late o f the city o f Black
R iver Falls, situated in the City o f Black
R iver Falls, in said cou n ty o f Jackson , to 
w it: L ot tw en ty tw o 2 2 , in B lock six
 6 o f L. G. M errill’s A ddition to the village
 n ow city o f Black R iver Falls. J ack son
cou nty, W isconsin.
Term s and con ditions will be made
know n at tim e and place o f sale.
Dated January 31. 1939.
KE R M IT A. H ANSON , A dm inistrator
Feb. 1 15
SCHERM ERHORN
Mrs. Menford Hagen spent Tuesday
at Ringling’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Spencer Hanson spent
Sunday at L. Bolstad’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Spencer Hanson spent
Sunday at Oluf Hagen's.
Andrew Bolstad spent Saturday a fternoon
at Julius Olson’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Alvin Halvorson spent
Sunday at Olger Koxlien’s.
Milton Embretson assisted Gaylord
Olson with the wood, Saturday.
Gaylord and Mayme Olson spent
Sunday evening at Emil Berget’s.
Andrew Bolstad was a supper
guest at Lars Bolstad’s Friday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Budd Newell and son
spent Wednesday evening at Lars
Bolstad’s.
Mr. and Mrs. A. Ringling and son
o f Whitehall, spent Sunday afternoon
at Mike Ringling’s.
Mrs. Spencer Hanson visited her
Sarents, Mr. and Mrs. M. Sagan,
[onday and Tuesday.
The Upper Pigeon Ladies Aid will
meet at the Nygaard Melbye home
Friday afternoon, Feb. 17.
Mr. and Mrs. Joel Olson and son,
and Hazel Grunlien visited at Oluf
Grunlien’s, Tuesday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Hakon Embretson
and son, and Matt Grunlien visited
at Joel Olson’s, Saturday evening.
Mrs. Joel Olson and son Duane,
and Mayme Olson spent Thursday
afternoon with Mrs. Spencer Hanson.
Andrew Bolstad returned home on
Wednesday from St. Paul and Minneapolis,
where he visited for the past
month.
Mr. and Mrs. Chas. Olson, Mr. and
Mrs. Leonard Olson and children and
Andrew Bolstad spent Friday evening
at Simon Amundson’s.
George Hanson, Clara Olson, Mr.
and Mrs. Joel Olson and son, Mrs.
Julius Olson, Mrs. Chas. Olson and
Mrs. Leonard Olson attended Ladies
Aid at Roy Knutson’s near Northfield
on FYiday.
Mrs. Joel Olson and son Duane,
Mrs. Julius Olson and daughter, Mrs.
Menick Ringling and son Philip, and
Hazel Grunlien and Lowny Larson
helped Janis Olson celebrate her
birthday, Tuesday afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Spencer Hanson, Gaylord
and Mayme Olson, Mr. and Mrs.
Menford Hagen, John Magelee and
son Robert, Halvor Hanson and Casper
Magelee helped John Rogstad celebrate
his birthday Friday evening.
NOTICE OF A P PLIC A TIO N FOR PR O B ATE
OF W IL L A N D MOTICE TO CREDITORS
STA TE O F W ISCONSIN, C OU N TY COURT,
Jackson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f John S.
J acobs, D eceased.
N otice is hereby given that at a term
o f said cou rt to be held on Tuesday, tl
21st day o f February, 1939, at 10 o ’ clocV
in the foren oon o f said day, at the court
house in the city of Black R iver Falls, in
said cou nty, th ers will be heard and c.
sid ered :
The application o f M artin Jacobs fo r 1
probate o f the will o f John S. Jacobs, de
ceased, and fo r the appointm ent o f an execu
tor or adm inistrator with the will an
nexed o f the estate o f said Joh n S. Jacob 
deceased, late o f the Tow n o f Franklin,
in said c o u n ty ;
N otice is furth er given that all claim s
against the said John S. J acobs, deceased,
late of the tow n o f Franklin, in Jackson
cou n ty, W iscon sin, m ust be presented to
said cou nty cou rt at Black R iver Falls, in
said cou nty, on or b efore the 5th day o f
June, 1939, or be b arred ; and that all such
claim s and dem ands will be exam ined and
adjusted at a term o f said cou rt to be held
at the court house in the city o f B lack R iver
Falls, in said cou nty, on T uesday, the 6th
day o f June, 1939, at 10 o ’clock in the
foren oon o f said day.
Dated January 25, 1939.
By Order o f the Court,
H A R R Y M. PE R R Y . Judge
D. M. P E R R Y , A ttorn ey
Jan. 25 Feb. 8
NOTICE OF HEARIN G A P PLIC A TIO N FOR
AD M IN ISTR A TIO N AN D NOTICE TO
CREDITORS
STA TE OF W ISCONSIN, C OU N TY COURT,
Jackson County
In the M atter o f the Guardianship o f Eva
Joss, A lleged to be Insane.
N otice is hereby given that at a term
o f said cou rt to be held on Tuesday, the
21st day o f February, 1939, at 10 o ’ clock
in the foren oon o f said day, at the court
house in the city o f Black R iver Falls, in
said cou n ty, there will be heard and con sidered
:
The application o f Cecelia Jackson fo r
the appointm ent o f a guardian o f E va Josu,
alleged to be incom petent and insane, of the
tow n o f A lm a, in said c o u n ty ;
N otice is fu rth er given that all claims
against the said E va Joss, o f the tow n of
Alm a, in Jackson county, W iscon sin, m ust
be presented to said cou nty cou rt at Black
R iver Falls, in said cou nty, on o r b efore the
5th day o f June, 1939, or be b a rred ; and
that all such1 claim s and dem ands will be
exam ined and adjusted at a term o f said
cou rt to be held at the cou rt house in the
city o f Black R iver Falls, in said county,
on Tuesday, the 6th o f June, 1939, at 10
o ’clock in the foren oon o f sai L day.
Dated January 17, 1939.
By Order of the Court,
H A R R Y M. PE R R Y . Judge
H A N S HANSON, A ttorn ey fo r the P etitioner
Black R iver Falls, W isconsin
Jan. 25 Feb. 8
NOTICE TO CREDITO RS OF TH E PIGEON
M U TU A L FIRE IN SU RAN CE COM PAN Y
STATE O F W ISCONSIN, IN CIRCUIT
C ourt, Trem pealeau County
Curtis Kaas, P lain tiff,
vs
The P igeon M utual Fire Insurance C om pany,
an Insurance C orporation located at
P igeon Falls, W iscon sin, Defendant.
By an ord er o f the C ircuit C ourt o f
Trem pealeau C ounty, W iscon sin, dated the
20th day o f January, A . D. 1939, Curtis
Kaas was appointed R eceiver o f the Pigeon
Mutual Fire Insurance Co., o f P igeon Falls,
W iscon sin, and it was furth er ordered that
Fire Insurance Com pany file their claim s
all creditors o f the said P igeon Mutual
with the Clerk o f the C ircuit C ourt fo r
Trem pealeau C ounty, W isconsin, at W hitehall,
W iscon sin, on or b efore the 4th day
o f M arch, 1939, o r be forev er barred.
N otice is th erefore given that all persons
havin g claim s against the said P igeon Mutual
Fire Insurance Com pany o f Pigeon Falls,
W iscon sin, file their claim s with Clarence
Johnson, Clerk o f the C ircuit C ourt of
Trem pealeau C ounty, W isconsin, at W hitehall,
W iscon sin, on or before tire 4th day
o f M arch, 1939, or be forev er barred.
Further, th at exam ination o f all such
claim s will be m ade by the said C ourt on
the 4th day o f M arch, 1939, at the cou rt
house in the city o f W hitehall, W isconsin,
at ten o ’clock in the foren oon or as soon
thereafter as counsel can be heard.
Dated this 20thr d a y o f January, A. D.
1939. CURTIS K A AS, R eceiver
OLE J. EGGUM, A ttorn ey,
P. O. A ddress, W hitehall, W isconsin
Feb. 1 15
NOTICE OF FORECLOSURE AN D SALE
STATE OF W ISCONSIN, CIRCU IT COURT,
Jackson County
The Federal Land Bank o f Saint Paul, a
body C orporate, P la in tiff.
V 8 A nton L a rson ; M arvin O ls o n ; M rs. M arvin
Olson, his w ife ; and the Osseo N ational
Farm Loan A ssociation, a C orporation,
D efendants.
B y virtue o f a Judgm ent o f F oreclosure
and Sale m ade in the a bove entitled action
on the 19th day o f January. 1938, the undersigned
Sheriff o f Jackson C ounty, W isconsin,
will sell a t the fron t d oor o f the
C ourt H ouse, in the city o f Black R iver
Falls, Jackson cou nty, W iscon sin, on the
10th day o f M arch, 1939, at ten o ’clock in
the foren oon o f that d ay, the real estate
and m ortga ged prem ises described by said
Judgm ent to be sold and therein described
as fo llo w s :
South half o f the Southeast quarter S fc
SE 4 o f Section th irty th ree 3 3 , T ow nship
T w en ty fou r 2 4 , N orth Range six
 6 W est, and the N orth h alf o f the N ortheast
Quarter N N E 4 o f Section fou r
 4 , Tow nship T w en ty th ree 2 3 N orth,
R an ge six 6 . W est, con taining one hundred
sixty 1 60 acres, m ore o r less, a ccordin
g to the G overnm ent survey thereof,
Jackson C ounty, W isconsin.
Dated January 23, 1939.
Term s o f Sale— Cash.
O. R. W A LD U M
Sheriff, Jackson County, W is.
DO NOVAN . GLEISS GOODM AN. A ttys..
Sparta, M onroe County. W isconsin
Jan. 25 M ar. 1
W RIGH TS VILLE
Mr. and Mrs. I. H. Bowen spent
Thursday evening at Geo. Gjerseth’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Will Fields were
dinner guests at Clarence Philips’, on
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Glen Bowen and son
were Sunday dinner guests at Arthur
Button’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Glen Bowen and son
were dinner guests at Cecil Bowen’s,
on Tuesday.
Mr. and Mrs. Clyde Reichenbach
visited Monday at Frank Knapp’s and
Eva Bowen’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Floyd Gearing and
family were dinner guests at Helmer
Gjerseth’s, Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. F. Sherwood and Mr.
and Mrs. I. H. Bowen were Sunday
dinner guests at Enos Bowen’s.
Mr. and Mrs. Joe Widmar and Mr.
and Mrs. Chas. Eddy visited Sunday
with Mrs. Eva Bowen and sons.
Mr. and Mrs. Randy Wilkenson
and baby, Bud Wilkinson spent Saturday
evening at Geo. Gjerseth’s.
Mr. and Mrs. F. Knapp and Kenneth,
and Mrs. N. Tucker were dinner
guests at L. Bowen’s, Sunday.
The Co op. Study club will meet
at the Ernest Rush home Friday evening.
Chinese checkers will be played
and lunch will be served.
Mrs. Geo. Gjerseth and Dona Mae
accompanied by Mr. and Mrs. Helmer
Gjerseth and Mrs. Frank Gearing
spent Wednesday in La Crosse.
N O TIC E OF FORECLOSU RE A N D SALE
ST A T E O F W ISCON SIN , CIRCU IT COU RT,
Jackson County
Federal Farm M ortgage C orporation, a body
C orporate, P la in tiff,
va
A lb ert H anson and M am ie H anson, his
w ife. Defendants.
By virtue o f a Judgm ent o f F oreclosure
and Sale m ade in the a bov e entitled action
on the 19tb day o f January, 1938, the undersigned
sh eriff o f Jackson cou nty. W isconsin,
will sell at the fron t d oor o f the
Court H ouse in the City o f Black R iver
Falls, Jackson C ounty, W iscon sin, on the
10th day o f M arch, 1939, at eleven o ’clock
in the foren oon o f that day, the real estate
and m ortgaged prem ises described by said
judgm ent to be sold and therein described
as fo llo w s :
W est one h alf W o f the N ortheast
quarter N E 4 o f Section tw enty n ine
 2 9 , T ow nship tw enty three 2 3 N orth,
R ange fiv e 5 W est, J ackson C ounty, W isconsin.
Dated January 28, 1939.
O. R. W ALD U M .
Sheriff, Jackson C ounty, W is.
DO NOVAN . GLEISS GOODM AN. A ttys.
Sparta, M onroe County, W isconsin
Jan. 25 M ar. 1
NOTICE OF HEARIN G ON A P P U C A T IO N
TO SELL OR IN CU M BER R E A L ESTA TE
STA TE OF W ISCONSIN. C OU N TY COURT.
J ackson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f Ingrid Chester,
also w ritten Ingri K ooster, Deceased.
N otice Is H ereby Given that at a term
o f said cou rt to be held on Tuesday, the
21st day of February, 1939, at 10 o ’clock
in the foren oon o f said day, at the cou rt
house in the city o f Black R iver F a lls
in said cou nty, there will be heard and con sidered
:
The application o f Ole B. Pederson, adm
inistrator o f the estate o f Ingrid Chester,
also w ritten Ingri K ooster, deceased, late of
the Tow n o f N orthfield, in said cou n ty, to
sell o r incum ber all o f the real estate b elonging
to said estate, and described as
follow s:
The N orth on e h alf of the N orthw est
quarter o f Section fourteen in Tow nship
T w en ty th ree N orth o f R ange six W est in
Jackson C ounty, W is. The Southeast quarter
o f the Southeast quarter, except a piece
o f land in the southw est corn er o f said
fo rty o f about 3 6 acres being 26 reds long.
N orth and South and 22 rods wide. East
and W est.
A part o f the Southw est quarter o f the
Southeast quarter situated in the N ortheast
corner, being a piece o f land 22 rods wide.
East and W est, and 26 rods long. N orth and
South, and con taining about 3 Vi acres o f
land.
The N ortheast quarter o f the Southeast
quarter, all o f the a bov e being in Section
T h irty tw o, in Tow nship T w en ty tw o N orth
o f R ange E ight W est in Trem pealeau cou nty,
W isconsin fo r the paym ent o f the debts,
legacies and funeral expenses o f said d ecedent,
and the expenses o f adm inistration.
Dated January 23, 1939.
By Order o f the C ourt,
H A R R Y M. P E R R Y , Judge
R A L P H S. LUND, A ttorney.
Jan. 25 Feb. 8
NOTICE OF H EARIN G ON F IN A L S E TT
L E M E N T AN D D E TE RM IN A TIN G OF
IN H ER ITA N C E T A X
STA TE O F W ISCONSIN, C OU N TY COURT,
J arkson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f Belle M.
M axw ell, Deceased.
N otice is hereby given that at a term of
said cou rt to be held on Tuesday, the 28th
day o f February, 1939, at 10 o ’clock in the
foren oon o f said day, at the coUrt house, in
the city o f Black R iver Falls, in said county,
there will be heard and con sid ered :
The application o f R. H. H am ilton, adm
inistrator o f the estate o f Belle M. M axwell,
deceased, late o f the village o f M errillan,
in said cou nty, fo r the exam ination
and allow ance o f his final accou nt, which
account is now on file in said cou rt, and
fo r the allow ance o f debts or claim s paid
in good faith w ithout filin g o r allow ance as
required b y law, and fo r the assignm ent o f
the residue o f the estate o f said deceased
to such persons as are by law entitled
th e re to ; and fo r the determ ination and
adjudication o f the inheritance tax. If any,
p ayable in said estate.
Dated January 31, 1939.
B y Order o f the Court,
H A R R Y M. PE RR Y , Judge
Feb. 1 15
DR. M. A. FOSTER
Optometrist
EYES EXAM INED—
G LASSES FITTED
O ffice Over Zimmerman’s Store
Phone Red 126, Neillsville, Wis.
C. W . REIELS
Painting and Decorating
Phone 217 Black
823 Tyler St., Black River Fall 
DR. CARL PFLAN Z
DEN TIST
O ffice in Rozmenoski Bldg.
Phone 301 Black River Falla
BLACK RIVER LODGE NO. 74
F. A A. M.
Meeting 2nd and 4tk Thursday
of each month. Viaitor Welcome
R. C. GEBHARDT
DENTIST
First Door Eaat of Coart House
Black River Falls, Wisconsin
DR. MYRON MOEN
DENTIST
Office Over Post Office
Black River Falla, Wisconata
PAGE NO. 8 THE BANNER JQURNAL, Black River Falls, Wisconsin W ednesday, February 8, 1939
D O E R F L I N G E R ’ S
U R
THURS. « ," to . . , to
6 p. m. Feb. 16th 6 p M
Every year when February peeks around the
corner, thousands of Wisconsinites, Minnesotans
and Iowans impatiently await for news of
Doerflinger's Dollar Day. They hare learned
from long experience that the merchandise
and quality per dollar at Doerilinger's is consistently
greater than at any other place in
which they've shopped!
ASK FOR EXTRA STAMPS
WORTH OF VALUABLE CASH DISCOUNT
STAMPS with every J1 CASH purchase of
regularly priced merchandise in the Housefurnishings,
Linens, Notions, Toiletries, Gifts,
Yard Goods, Men’s Apparel, Ready to Wear,
Corset Shop and Furniture.
$
I 24 in. Royal Honor Wood Heater — O EIH5
$30.00 Value ........................................
122 in. Combination Wood and CoalftoW JM A P
Heater, $20.00 valu e...........................JL a • 2 3
28 in. Allen's King Wood Heater
$15.00 value ........................................ 
128 in by 24 in. Cast Draft Airtight
Heater, $6.00 valu e..................................? Jr 9 
No. 19 Dixie Round Oak Heater — i | A O E ?
$19.00 Value ........................................ uS
20 in. Dixie Circulator Heater O B? iS;
$30.00 value ........................................ A « • lU i 
Challenger Ball Bearing Washer—
 Electric , $50.00 value..................
Challenger Ball Bearing Washer— E f i l
Briggs Stratton Engine, $75 value
3 burner Gasoline Range, Table l i l l A P A
Top, $80.00 value............................. M w 9 9 1 1
3 burner Diktator High Power Kero aV O E I
i Stove, with back. $30.00 value.........
12 burner Gem Wickless Kero Stoves O O
! $5.00 value .................................................
3 burner Gem Wickless Kero Stoves P A g 
with legs. $9.00 va lu e.............................
6Y2 ft. Stewart Warner Refrigera V Q C f l
tor, 5 yr. warranty, $170 value . . .
Perfection All Porcelain Cabinet F A
Range, $105.00 value...................... k P D « l t V w
8 Tube Perf. Stewart Warner Con I 4 A P A
sole Radio, $50.00 valu e................ I w w « w ls J
 All Wave Push Button 
6 Tube Table Model Stewart Warner i PV f t C
Radio, $25.00 valu e............................. • w
O I L B U R N E R S 2 5 t o 5 0 p e r c e n t
D i s c o u n t W h i l e T h e y L a s t
Shoe Skates, Hockey Tube Alfred O C
Johnson $5.00 v a lu e.............................M w o w V
Shoe Skates — Wizards f t t f
 $4.00 value ...............................................1
I Hard Toe Hockey Skates 1
I $4.50 value ............................................... 9 
14 ft. Toboggan 1 P 
$5.00 v a lu e ................................................. i f r w w
'4 ft. Skiis O F 1
I$1.25 value ............................................... O c J w ’
I 5 ft. Skiis 1 f t
I $1.50 value ............................................... I
,6 ft. Skiis £■« C f t I
$2.00 value .................................................
f! kviailfu e ........... •••••••••••••••• c i q c
| Coal Hods galvanized O C 
I 75c value ................................................... M w C |
57 ft. Clothes Drying Rack O f t i
'$1.75 value ...............................................S p l o v t i
• Fast Drying Floor Varnish, extra O f t 
| special, $2.00 value, per gal...................1
| All Prices Subject to stock on hand 
' Hancock Hdw. Co. ;
Where Main Street Begins Black River Falls
W ANT ADS
W AN TE D — Used brood er houses. Call Phone
N o. 182. City. lw
FOR SALE — Sow with six pigs. ARC H IE
W . RICE. B. R. Falls. lw p
FOR SALE— T railers and farm wagons.
M AYN ARD COLE, Blacksm ith shop.
City 1 tf
FOR SALE— Jersey cow s, fresh and closeup
springers. A lso three head o f horses.
RCBT. BIBLE, D isco, P hone 17 R19. 6 2wp
FOR SALE— A pair o f 3 year old colts.
At ke heavy d ra ft horses. M AHLON
HOUGHTON on C ounty F, P hone 12 R 8. Ip
FOR REN T— 4 room upper apartm ent, large
room s, nice location, close to down town.
$15.00. Inquire o f C. L. HIGGINS. City lw
FOR SALE— One new oil heater. W ill heat
three good sized room s. Call 238 B lack.
V IR G IN IA H. H A L L , City. lw p
FOR SALE— A sow to fa rrow betw een Mar.
1st and 15th. D E XT E R LIN N ELL, R. F.
D., City. lw p
FOR SALE— Baled hay and straw . W ill
sell on farm or deliver. P hone 69 R13.
F R AN K SA V E R D A , M elrose, W is. 9 2p
W A N T E D — J ob as truck driver o r any sim
ilar jo b by a g ood reliable man. Ad
dress B ox 116, Blair, W is. lw p
FOR SALE — M cC orm ick D eering No.
Cream separator. W ill sell cheap. H. M,
SOLBERG, T aylor, W is. lw p
W A N T E D — M arried couple w ithout children
to work on farm starting M arch 1. P H IL IP
M E R RILL. Taylor, W is. 6 2p
W A N T TO B U Y— A violin. Give make.
con dition and description o f violin and
bow . W rite Banner Journal office. 6 4p
C LAIR SM ALE, General Auctioneering,
Farm auctions a specialty. Call DR. F,
E. SILLICK , N eillsville, W is. S atisfaction
guaranteed. 6 4w p
FOR SALE— 60 or 70 laying hens, laying
g oo d . Y ear old pullets, mixed breeds,
IR A B E N T L E Y, R oute 1. Merrillan, half
mile from highway 12. lw p
FOR SALE— Clover, tim othy, alfalfa, hay
A lso ear corn. TH E CHAS. SBCH LER
ESTATE, Sechlerville, W is., P hone H ixton
39. lw p
FOR SALE — T w o Shorthorn bulls, baled
straw and hay. A lso bright loose tim o thy
and clover hay. FRED R ILLIN G , T a y lor,
W is., on H ighw ay 95. lw p
FOR SALE— Tw o you n g H olstein bull:
from accredited herd, T. B. tested. A,
M. ENGEN, 6 m iles south o f B lack R iver
Falls on highw ay 54 . lw p
FOR SALE— A bou t 7 tons o f hay, 4 Y mi.
north o f B. R. Falls, in Snow Creek, at
$6.00 per ton. W ill sell any am ount of these
7 ton or all. Inquire at B J office. Ip
FOR SALE— A bou t 35 tons o f hay on the
T row farm one mile north o f M errillan on
No. 12, at $3.00 per ton. See or call ERIC
ERICKSON, M errillan 6 2p
W A N T E D TO R EN T— Farm w ithout person
al property, near tow n and close to highway
preferred. W ill pay cash rent. Phone
2 R19, W A L T E R MARG, R oute 2, City 6 2p
FOR SALE— Corn shocks with corn in. Also
yearling heifers and bulls. W ill trade.
Phone 2 R19, W A L T E R M ARG, R oute 2,
City. 5 2w p
W A N T TO B U Y— Fresh o r springer cow s.
A ny breed. A lso feeder pigs and thin
sows. P hone 2 R19. W A L T E R M ARG, Route
2, City. 5 2p
W A N T E D — Man to sell Baker P rod u cts in
established local territory. No cash in
vestm ent. Car needed. For inform ation
w rite S. F. B AK ER CO., K eokuk, la . 6 3p
FOR SALE— Special low prices on used
electric washers, radios, m otors and vac
cuum cleaners. See PU G H ’S B A TTE R Y 
ELECTRIC SHOP, C ity. lw
FOR R EN T— Centrally located, well furnished
sleeping room s with bath, furnace heat
and telephone. R easonable rates. A lso light
housekeeping apartm ent. Phone 428. lw
FOR SALE— Three T oggen b u rg m ilch goats
and one billy. All are o f a very g ood
milk strain. W ill sell cheap. MRS. J
FENCIL, Hatfield. P. O. Me rillan, R oute 1,
W is. lw p
FIRE AND TORN AD O IN SU RAN CE— E ttrick
M utual Fire Insurance and the W is
consin F arm ers’ M utual Hail C yclone
Com pany. Call O. M. O D EM ARK, P hone
52 R3, T aylor. W is. lw
FOR SA L E OR REN T— 145 acre farm in
the tow n of A lm a. If rented, renter to
furnish horses, m achinery and part o f the
cow s. Inquire o f MRS. BESSIE POM RO Y,
c o Chas. Dunlap, A lm a Center, W is. Ip
LA CROSSE REN DERING W O R K S— Rem
oves dead or disabled anim als free and
prom ptly. Call Genther’s Service Station
Black R iver Falls, P hone 58, o r W m . Steinbring,
N o. 3, at H ixton. R everse all phone
calls. 46 tf
FOR SALE— N o. 850 D elco L ight plant and
batteries in A l condition. W ill sell ou tright
o r trade fo r you n g stock o r horse.
A lso a used kitchen range with h ot w ater
fron t. N YG AA R D BROS. M ELBY, Alm a
Center, W is. 5 2w p
Is Y our F IR S IN SU RAN CE with a reliable
Com pany ? The Integrity M utual, of
A ppleton, has am ple reserves and losses are
paid prom ptly. Be protected 1 A lso w indstorm
anc car insurance. W . F. CURRAN ,
T aylor, W is., Teleph®ne H ixton 20 R3 3 4w
FOR SALE— Used tra ctors 10 20 M cCorm
ick Deerings, Fordsons, Case. Silo fillers.
Some fine horses and cattle. A lso
10 roll M cCorm ick D eering corn shredder.
ERICKSON IM PLE M E N T CO., Melrose, W is.
Case and Allis Chalm ers Dealers. 4 2 tf
FOR SALE — M y beautiful $650 P layer
piano and rolls for $49.60 before m oving.
$5 a month? to responsible party. W rite
me today and I will tell you w here in Black
R iver Falls m y player piano m ay be seen.
W rite MRS. M ARY SCH U LTZ, R oute 5,
Box 229 A , W aukesha, W is. 5 2wp
FOR SALE— My beautiful $650 P layer P iano
and rolls fo r $49.60 before m oving.
$5 a m onth to responsible party. W rite me
today and I will tell you w here in M errillan
m y player piano m ay be seen. W rite
MRS. M ARY SCH U LTZ, R oute 5. B ox 229A
W aukesha, W isconsin. 5 2w p
FOR SA L E OR TR A D E — New and used
m achinery and tra ctors on hand. 3 horses,
9 tractors, 8 tra ctor plow s, 5 horse plows,
w agon, w ater tank, m ilking m achine, canary
grass seed, seed oats, 1000 posts, 4 springer
heifers. M assey H arris dealer. ADAM
ST A T Z, Alm a Center, W is. 6 tf
FOR RENT— On shares, m y 168 acre farm
in tow n o f Irving, with all personal p ro perty.
Modern hom e equipped withr electric
lights, hot and cold running water, bath and
furnace. An excellent opportunity fo r reliable
party. Telephone 128, EDGAR GILBERTSON,
B. R. Falls. W is. lw p
FOR SALE— 3 good w ork horses, about
1300 to 1400, cheap if b ou gh t this week.
Som e cow s and heifers, som e to freshen
soon, som e open Guernsey heifers. Large
good farm w agon, 6 wheels fo r same. Good
m anure spreader. 1 Guernsey bull, 1 Chester
W hite boar. AUGU ST M ATTSON, City lw
AUCTION SALES— F or Best RESU LTS and
the M ost $$$ Call F. J. BOW M AN . Black
R iver Falls, W is., with 25 Years Experience
con du cting over 2000 Sales in 8 States and
in 25 Counties in W ISCONSIN. Satisfied
Custom ers Built This Business. The Leading
Farm ers, S tock Men. Business Men, and
HORSE DEALERS are My Patrons. My
R eferences are the Thousands o f People
F or W hom and T o W hom I H ave SOLD.
M ay I be of Service TO Y O U ? N o P lace
T o o Far. N o Sale T o o Large o r T oo Small.
S atisfaction Guaranteed or N o Charges. I
C o O perate with any Clerk, Bank, o r Finance
C orporation. A rrange E arly fo r
Dates. W rite or W ire at M y Expense. 5 tf
NOTICE TO CREDITORS
STATE OF W ISCONSIN. COUNTY COURT.
Jackson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f Eunice
Bowlen, deceased
Letters o f A dm inistration having been
issued to Lida Sprester in the estate o f
Eunice Bowlen, deceased, late o f the city
o f Black R iver Falls, in said co u n ty ;
N otice is hereby given that all claims
against the said Eunice Bowlen. deceased,
late o f the city o f Black R iver Falls, W isconsin,
in Jackson cou nty, W isconsin, must
be presented to said county cou rt at Black
R iver Falls, in said cou nty, on o r before
the 12th day o f June. 1939, or be b arred ;
and that all such claims and dem ands will
be examined and adjusted at a term o f said
court to be held at the court house in the
city o f Black R iver Falls, in said county,
on T uesday, the 13th day o f June, 1939,
at 10 o ’clock in the foren oon o f said day.
Dated February 7th, 1939.
By Order of the Court,
H A R R Y M. P E R R Y , Judge
Feb. 8 22
NOTICE OF A P PLIC A TIO N FOR PR OBATE
OF W IL L AN D NOTICE TO CREDITORS
ST A T E OF W ISCONSIN. COU N TY COURT.
Jackson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f A lex T hom pson,
deceased.
N otice is hereby given that at a term o f
said cou rt to be held on Tuesday, the
7th d ay o f March, 1939, at 10 o ’clock in
the foren oon o f said day, at the cou rt house
in th e city o f Black R iver Falls, in said
cou nty, there will be heard and con sid ered :
T he application o f M artin Thom pson,
T heodore T hom pson and Stella Larson fo r
the p robate o f the will o f A lex Thom pson,
deceased, and fo r the appointm ent o f an
executor or adm inistrator with tire will a n nexed
o f the estate o f said A lex Thom pson,
deceased, late o f the Tow n o f N orthfield,
in said c o u n ty ;
N otice is furth er given that all claims
against the said Alex T hom pson, deceased,
late o f the town o f N orthfield, in Jackson
cou nty, W isconsin, m ust be presented to
said cou n ty cou rt at Black R iver Falls in
said cou nty, on or b efore the 12th day of
June, 1939, o r be b arred ; and that all such
claim s and dem ands will be exam ined and
adjusted at a term o f said cou rt to be held
at the cou rt house in the city o f Black
R iver Falls, in said cou nty, on Tuesday,
th e 13th d ay o f June, 1939, at 10 o ’clock
in the foren oon o f said day.
Dated February 6th. 1939.
B y Order o f the Court,
H A R R Y M. P E R R Y . Judge
R A L P H S. LU N D, A ttorn ey
Feb. 8 22
NOTICE OF A P PLIC A TIO N FOR PROBATE
OF W IL L AN D NOTICE TO CREDITOR
S T A T E OF W ISCONSIN. COU N TY COURT.
Jackson County
In the M atter o f the E state o f Bernt T.
B erntson, deceased
N otice is hereby given that at a term
of said cou rt to be held on T uesday, the
7th d ay o f M arch, 1939, at 10 o ’clock in
the foren oon o f said day, at the cou rt house
in the city o f Black R iver Falls in said
cou nty, there will be heard and considered :
T he application o f Nels O. Berntson fo r
the probate o f the will o f Bernt T. Berntson,
deceased, and fo r the appointm ent of
an executor or adm inistrator with the will
annexed o f th eestate o f said Bernt T.
Berntson. deceased, late o f the V illage o f
T aylor, in said co u n ty ;
N.otif i8 r th e r given that all claims
against the said Bernt T. Berntson. deceased,
late o f the village o f T aylor, in Jackson
cou nty, W isconsin, m ust be presented to
• aid county cou rt at Black R iver Falls, in
said cou nty, on or before the 12th day o f
June, 1939, o r be barred; and that all such
claim s and demands will be exam ined and
adjusted at a term o f said court to be held
at the cou rt house in the city o f Black
R iver Falls, in said cou nty, on Tuesday,
the 13th day o f June. 1939, at 10 o ’ clock
in the foren oon o f said day.
Dated February 3, 1939.
B y Order o f the Court,
H A R R Y M. PE RR Y . Judge
D. M. PE R R Y , A ttorn ey
Feb.. 8 22
OD RIN ANCE N O. 146
An Ordinance to repeal O rdinance N o.
145 relative to the manner o f ch oosing the
Treasurer, C ity Clerk, A ssessor, City A tto r ney
and Marshal.
T he Com m on Council o f the C ity o f Black
R iver Falls, do ordain as follow s:
1. Ordinance N o. 145 relative to the m anner
o f ch oosing the Treasurer, Clerk, A ssessor,
A ttorn ey a n i Marshal is hereby repealed.
2. The Treasurer, Clerk, A ssessor, A tto rney
and M arshal o f the City o f Black R iver
Falls shall be elected by the voters.
 This ordinance shall tak e effect and be
in force from and after its passage and
publication.
AN TO N HAUGER, M ayor
E ILER T M. HAGEN, City Clerk
Dated Feb. 7, 1939
Passed Feb. 7, 1939
Published Feb. 8, 1939. lw
The Banner Joumal is like a good
letter from home. $2.00 will bring
you 52 letters. Subscribe now!
The Sign of a Dependable Store
Soap Chips........... 5 lb. box 30c
Soap, R and W Naptha 5 bars 19c
Hilex, quart ja r ...................IJJg
Pineapple
30 oz. Homestyle
2 49c
N A VY
Beans
4 lb 19c
14 oz. bottles
 Catsup
10c
Matches, 6 box carton ........ 19c
2 lb. jar Peanut
Butter
25c
i ib.
 
 
can B. W .
'ocoa
13c
Wheaties
8 oz. pkgs. 2 21c
Oranges .................2 doz. 29c
Graepfruit................ 3 f ° r 1 0 e
Lettuce.................... 2 f°r 19c
Carrots, Cal............ 2 bches 15c
BRING US YOUR EGGS
PHONE No. 6 W E DELIVER
CHAIMSOIS’S
Phone No. 9 Black River Falls, Wis.
42 oz. Deerwood Oatmeal 15c
28 oz. Deerwood Wheat Cereal 19c
14 oz. UBC
Catsup 2 21C
2 lb. UBC Cocoa..... 15c
24 oz. Upright Tomato Juice...... 10c
8 oz. Cello pkg. Wheat
Puffits 2 15c
U be See 42 oz. Box Cup and Saucer
OATMEAL...................... 23c
2 lb. pkg. Bulk
Soda ... 9c
Navy
Beans 7 lb 25c
BROOMS 4H£ hw? d alily 29c
FRUITS and VEGETABLES
Size 344 Golden Ripe Oranges Bananas
2 doz. for 2 5 c
New
Cabbage
4 lbs. for 1 0 c
4 lbs. for 25c
Size 6’s Lettuce 5c
New York Stark Apples
5 lbs. for 25c
THE MEAT YOU LIKE TO EAT
M e a t y Neck Bones 5 c
Hormel’f Boiled Ham ..lb. 39c
Tender Round Steak lb. 23c
Bulk Mince Meat 2 lb 23C
CHEESE, 2 lb. box Swift’s ... 43c
FRESH FISH — OYSTERS
Week End Sale
Gluten Feed ........ 100 lbs. $1.09
Contains 20 per cent Molasses
Pure Bran...........100 lbs. 31.09
Standard Middlings 100 lbs. $ 1 . 0 9
Red D og.............. 100 lbs. $ 1 .1 9
16 per cent Dairy Feed 100 lb $1.05
FLOUR SALE
This is a get acquainted o ffe r on our two own brands o f Flour. W e
just received a straight car o f flour to get these prices down to these
figures.
Dairy Queen Flour 49 lb bag $1.29
Vour choice o f Silverware, Spoon, Fork or K nife Free with each
sack. Dairy Queen is the best flour money can buy. Try a sack or
barrel and you will be more than pleased.
Country Girl Flour. .49 lb. bag 95c
W ith every sack o f Country Girl Flour during this sale we will give
you absolutely free a beautiful dish towel. This towel cannot be duplicated
any place for less than 10c. This flour makes wonderful
bread, cake and pastry. W e sell this as an all purpose Flour.
H. H. Van Gorden and Sons
Black River Falls, Wisconsin
1 2 o z . can Arm ou—«r ’os 42. uduozt.. mMuoinmarric.ihi uOrraannggee rP eenkooee Corn Beef ...21c TeaBalls.... 25c
Large Bars P G“
8 oz. cans stems pieces Mushrooms 32c
20 oz. cans Monarch Vegetables
for
Soap ... 6for23
Candy per lb. 10
W isconsin O i l r r Cheese... lb. 16c Salad. .2 cans 25c
 £
 1 lb. ppnkgg.. vGj iluoasss uorr C oorrnn L a r~ge Bars Toilet Starch 2 pkg. 15c Soap . .6 bars 25c
Salt or Oyster Shells 100 lb. bag 79c
Eggs are going up........ Call No. 5
I.G .A . Gigantic COFFEE SALE
EVERY POUND GROUND FRESH
Red A Coffee 3 lbs. 43c 1 lb. 15c
Blue G Coffee 1 lb. bags. .2 for 49c
A Genuine Chinex Cup and Saucer or Dinner
Plate Free
Peak Coffee.......... 1 lb. can 29c
The Peak of Quality
WITH IGA COFFEE SERVE A BREAKFAST
OF CHAMPIONS
Wheaties, 8 oz. pkg.............. IQ g
Blended Prunes ......... 3 lbs. 17c
Prunes, lge 40 50 size... 3 lbs. 25c
Peaches, IGA 29 oz. can 17c
Grapefruit Juice, IGA 18 oz can Q c
10 oz. pkgs. KrakKrisp
Wheat Flakes............ 2f°r19c
Bran Flakes, IGA, 8 oz. pkg...... Q g
Pancake Flour, IGA, 5 lb. bag 2 1 c
IGA Golden Amber
Syrup.................5 lb pail 29c
Bulk Dates ...............2 lbs 17c
15 lb. bag U. S. No. 1
Idaho Potatoes .................. 38c
Oranges, table size per doz— 23c
A n d e r s o n F o o d M a r k e t
Phone No. 1 . We Deliver
G. R. Sechler Co.
Phone No. 5 — Monarch Finer Foods— Phone No. 5
Specials Thursday, Friday and Sat.
Country Girl Flour.. 49 lb. bag 9 5 c
FREE HEMMED DISH TO W EL W ITH EVERY SACK
Gold Medal Flour 49 lb. bag $ 1 .4 9
Granulated Sugar..... IQ lbs. 47c
</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
