<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M09D06</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Mrs. Lillian Harrison of Winneba­ go, Nebraska, was
            here again and when she arrived at Indian Mission most Indians had
            gone to cranberry marsh. She went with them at Phil­ ip Bennett’s
            marsh. Willie Hall Jr. and Indian report went to Merrillan and
            Millston sell­ ing basket handle. Sold quite a few handle. It is
            time now talk about cranber­ ry marsh. We always talk about
            cranberry marsh this time of a year. September. Ben Potter’s marsh,
            he thought last two weeks to pick his cranberries, he want hired
            some In­ dians, hand pickers commenced 28 of August, finished only
            two days, and he never think could finished only two days. Ten acres
            o f cran­ berry last only two days. Mr. James Noble was here again
            and they went to north some where, vacation. Mrs. Noble is going to
            fish­ ing, and we hope to have good luck that fishing. Mr. and Mrs.
            Gilbert Lowe and Mrs. Jennie Decorah were working hard to clean
            school house and school dining room and they gave short no­ tice to
            do work. Hotonga schol be­ gin yesterday. The school children are
            very glad to have school again. They begin with 39 scholars. Two
            teacher, Mrs. Emma Olson and Misi Hansen. Forman WPA, Dick Walters
            says still they waiting for plaster. New building has not been
            finish yet and as soon as plaster come it wouldn’t take very long to
            finish. RA work began yesterday. They had new Forman O’Brien and
            they said they don’t play Hawkin’s game. John Whitedog passed away
            first day of September in midnight. 1939. He is about 54 years old
            and he was born in Jackson county, raised right here in all his
            life, and every one know him well. He is always ready to help the
            people meet him, he or she. Funeral service held yesterday
            afternoon. There were quite a few people to see him his last
            tributes, Indians and white people know him at La Crosse where he
            was working WPA gang and his neighbors, lots o f Indians come, from
            every Indian Set­ tlement. George Funmaker Jr.. his son Clarence
            Whitedog, David White Decorah and Charles R. Lowe Cloud went there
            to see him, and some oth­ ers but we could not put all their names
            whoever were there. Feel sor­ ry for him those who know him. The
            sympathy goes to his family, his wife, his daughter, Mrs. Lee Brown,
            his brother, Julius Whitedog and his mother, Mrs. Joe Thunderking. A
            boy was born to Mr. and Mrs. Frank B. Thunder of Hunter Bridge on
            Tuesday, August 29th, 1939, at Tomah Indian hospital, and both are
            doing well the mother and baby. Myron Lowe, his brother Emanuel Lowe
            went back to school week ago last Tuesday and next day Myron went
            back too, at Haskell Institute, Kansas. This is third years this
            sea­ son and hope they will study hard their own less finish as soo
            nas they can. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
