<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M08D02</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Mr. and Mrs. C. A. Winneshiek o f Waupaca, were here
            during Indian pow -wow and they came with one white girl,* her name
            Marjorie Mykel, 721 Seventh street, Waupaca, Wis. She was dancing
            with her Sunday evening. They had lot of things going on this Indian
            pow-wow and special those Chippewa Indians from north of this state,
            every one of them had enjoy themselves while they are here and when
            they going home promised an­ other for next summer. It seemed
            everybody like to this old pow-wow ground and so with these
            Winnebago Indians too. Mr. and Mrs. John Thompson and Mrs. Whitegull
            and Indian reporter went to Tomah Indian Agency office last Monday
            and on business. They have been talk about the old home­ stead, some
            of them. The county trying to make tax on them, but the congress has
            always fix up for every twenty five years for these Indians
            homestead. The next program is Pittsville Indian pow-wow, some
            coming next Friday and some are going today, to prepare the things.
            Mrs. Tall Decorah is in the Tomah Indian hospital, has been report
            improving gradually and they said she had two or three different
            sickness. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
