<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M03D29</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>The Indian report came back from Indian hospital
            last Sunday. Everybody got that cold. We al­ ways have this cold
            weather spring, and still cold wind too. ind R. A. worker they
            finished work for this month, last half day was yes­ terday. Supt.
            Peru Farver of Tomah Indian school had talk to Indian report last
            Saturday forenoon, talk about some Indian money lost and also about
            they are going to build some more houses. If that is not politic,
            they will. Too bad news. Mr. and Mrs. Jim Funmaker lost one infant
            baby last week. The baby was born at Tomah Indian hospital but
            dostor said she was born before her time, and sym­ pathy goes to
            parents, Mr. and Mrs. Jim Funmaker. Indian reporter had letter from
            two women as following: 22643 W. Mich., Dearborn, Mich. March 18,
            1939 Dear Mr. Low Cloud: Am very sorry to hear you are ill and I
            wish you a speedy recovery. We read your news in the Banner-Jour­
            nal and enjoy them a great deal. Hope you will continue writing them
            for us. Sincerely yours, Mrs. Bergine O. Peterson Mrs. Clara E.
            Dates Indian reporter went to Indian Mis­ sion looking for some
            news, but he could not any, only one cigar. The sewing project at
            Indian Mis­ sion they said they are making some Indian women dress
            for those who need. I wish to thank, who has written kind words sent
            it to me, during I was staying 19 days at Indian hos­ pital, and
            those readers o f Banner- Journad and special those three
            Trempealeau county newspaper pub­ lisher, G. L. Kirkpatrick o f the
            In­ dependence News W ave; H. Cf. Kirk­ patrick o f the Blair Press:
            and Bert A. Gipple o f the Galesville Republi- an. I am thanking for
            everybody and they came to see me. Too bad road to travel on some
            jlace at present, these two car stay in mud all night. Mr. and Mrs.
            Clar­ ence Moniga rand their children o f Greenwood, Wis., they were
            coming to Indian Mission last Saturday. They come down as far as
            east o f 30 or 40 rods from use to be Joe Valance alace, got stuck
            in mud near the lorse shoe curve and after while Mr. Dan Bearheart
            came along, try to help them but he could not do any­ thing, so he
            told them he could take his family to the Indian Mission but Mr.
            Monigar says no and Mr. Bear­ heart went on toward Indian Mission
            but he did not go very far, he got stuck in mud too and these two
            cars staying on all night. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
