<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M03D22</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>There are lots of patients at Tomah Indian hospital this week. It is time now spring. You can tell by the weather. Remember we had mild
            winter and spring cold weather. Indian reporter came out at 16 of this month. Yesterday was here and he is alright but only little bid too
            weak his nerves. The Tomah Indian school building, want tear down. As we understand those building, when they build for the Winnebago
            Indians of Wisconsin, and also use some Indians money too. About 46 or 50 years ago the Indians they could not say anything about these
            buildings, but they had right to say somethings and you know cost lots of money when they built. A baby girl was born to Mr. and Mrs.
            Joseph Thunder Cloud at Tomah Indian hospital March 16, 1939, 7:05 a. m. She weigh seven pounds. John Brown had broken finger last Monday
            night and still they got him in the hospital Tuesday morning, and we don’t know how long they will keep him up there. The Indian reporter
            had received a letter from Mr. and Mrs. Daniel M. Gross of Chicago, and three Trempealeau county newspaper publisher. Dear Mr. Lowe Cloud:
            Read in Banner-Journal where you were sick and hope this card finds you well again. Black River Falls being my home town I enjoy all the
            paper but being a stranger my wife reads only the “Indian News” of which there are many clippings in her scrap book. We both join in
            wishing you a speedy recovery. The card said “Gosh! you musta caught sumpin’ You hadn’t oughta catch. And now you’re ill in bed Not
            feeling up to scratch. Hope you’ll get your health back As quickly as can be, For the news that you’re entirely well and strong can’t come
            too fast for me.” Mr. and Mrs. Daniel M. Gross. March 17th, 1939 Our dear Lowe Cloud: The “our” above is used because this letter is
            written for three Trempealeau county newspaper publishers — G. L. Kirkpatrick of the Independence News-Wave; H. C. Kirkpatrick, of the
            Blair Press, and myself, Bert A. Gipple, of the Galesville Republican. And herewith you will find their compliments in the form of three
            “scraps of paper.” You may prevail upon your banker to accept them in lieu of wampum; and if you do, then accept them along with our
            assurance that we appreciate your column clipped weekly from the Banner- Journal, and so do our readers. Now if the newspaper boys
            else­where who are shearing your product from week to week will come across with similar greetings, some of the grief will be taken out of
            Lowe Cloud’s hospitalization. Very truly yours, Bert A. Gipple The adult night school at Indian Mission school started last Wednesday
            evening. The meeting was held in the dining room. Mr. George Metalas of Merrillan is teacher. The first meeting was spent playing cards
            and Chinese checkers. Our road are beginning to get very muddy, some tough going from now on for a while. Marie Stacy and brothers, Morris
            and Alfred accompanied by Tillie Stacy took in the band and orchestra concert in the city Sunday. Mrs. Alice Funmaker was taken to the
            Tomah hospital Thursday. The first and second grades at school had “a hot cocoa” party last Friday. They wore their party caps. One out of
            each group acted as the hostess. The table was set with pretty little dishes, animal cookies, cheese crackers, Easter candy, eggs and
            cocoa was served. Each little tot did their best to show good table manners. A promise of another was given them. The other grades did
            library reading from the many new books received from Miss Bush and the school board. </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
