<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M02D01</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>We have some cold weather last few days, for the month of February. Mrs. John Stacy,
            Tillie and Alvin Stacy went to Greenwood yesterday, and return home same day. Mr. and
            Mrs. Simon Greyfox were in town yesterday. Indian reporter and Berand Eagle were here in
            town from water mill. Indian reporter had a letter from Hon. Peter A. Hemmy last month.
            The Indians are very glad to hear from Mr. Hemmy and we are always very glad to hear
            from him at any time, and we hope to hear some more good news from him. William McGreane
            and Chris Olson were visitors at Indian Mission yesterday, and Mr. Olson know them quite
            a few Indians but most every men, and Mr. McGreane know them put near all of Indians. He
            is working at relief office. There are 17 patients of Winnebago Indians in the Tomah
            Indian hospital last Monday as following names: Delos Yellowbank, Godfrey Mallory,
            William Blackdeer, Freeman Thompson, Peter White, Frank Pigeon, Henry Mike, Harold
            Blackdeer, Geraldine and Bemadine Decorah. These two were twins. Verna White Eagle has
            broken leg some time ago. Esther Black Hawk, Alvine Brown Eagle, Nellie Blackdeer and
            May Whitewater. The Indians has been talking about Indian hospital some time ago. They
            said they gave order, days and hours to see the doctors or get home remedies, Monday,
            Wednesday and Friday at 10 to 11:30 a. m., at 3 to 4:30 p. m. and Saturday at 10 to
            11:30 only a. m. and they would like to have at any hour enter the hospital ready to get
            anythings they want, and the order mention as above. They would like to have change,
            because some time the Indians are going to Tomah Indian hospital for nothing or just
            spent lots of gas. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
