<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M09D20</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Harris and Mrs. Frank Red Cloud
            o f Hunters Bridge, La Crosse county, came thru here on way home.
            Mr. Harris had letter from W PA office. He is going to work this
            week. He was picking cranberries. Mrs. Alice Green Fox went to To­
            mah Indian hospital two weeks ago for treatment. We are glad to hear
            she is improving on this writing. Fred King Swan and Wm. White Bear
            came back from Nebraska. Fred was there last two weeks on land bus­
            iness. Mr. Shee Noo o f Chicago, visited at Indian Mission Sunday.
            He was at Chippewa Falls as guest o f Judge Melville. The Indian
            report was invited to Eolitics meeting at Neillsville. He ear much
            talk about against New Deal. We know one thing the relief part is
            wrong. We see the office peo­ ple get more than the needy ones. One
            sight you see when you come to Indian Mission is Dick Walters
            walking around there, one house to another. Daniel Thunder Cloud is
            working on Phil Bennett cranberry marsh. He say he like it there and
            he moved to Tomah cranberry marsh. David White Decorah had one
            Deering mowing machine lost at east o f Clay some time last summer.
            They had been use to cut hay out there and leave it there for a
            while. Some­ body took it without asking. Would like to know who is
            taking. Mr. and Mrs. Willie Hall Jr. and Charles R. Lowe Cloud went
            to To­ mah Indian hospital to see Mrs. Alice Grey Fox. She has been
            there for last two weeks, and Annie Winne­ shiek too. Indian report
            went to see some In­ dian at Wood county. They had meeting out there
            to talk about their, own affairs. Hon. Merlin Hull went back to
            Washington yesterday. The Indians are not interested for any kind of
            politics but now some are having interesting talk about most every
            day. It seemed to just like wake up at near the time to elec­ tion.
            Mrs. Margaret La Mere Johnson was here most all summer. They called
            from Winnebago reservation at Nebraska. She will be cook in the
            hospital she has been working before so they sent for her, they know
            where she is. She is old Carlisle Student at same time Indian
            reporter was there. We had forgot them, those two babies were bom to
            some time ago. A baby girl was born to Mr. and Mrs. Herman Brown
            Eagle March-10, 1939, at Tomah Indian hospital. A baby boy was born
            to Mr. and Mrs. Tom Kingswan at Indian Mission July 28, 1939, and
            they are doing pretty well at present. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
