<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M05D03 part 2</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> HOUGHTONBURG Hon. P. A. Hemmy spent the week end at his home here.
            Miss Ethel Langworthy attended Prom at Osseo Saturday night. H. H.
            Nibbe of Humbird, is help­ ing Mahlon Houghton with the farm work.
            Mrs. Blanche Grush of Appleton, is here attending to business on the
            farm. Mr. and Mrs. Earl Langworthy spent Tuesday evening at Paul
            Haug- stad’s. Mr. and Mrs. J. E. Peasley of Snow Creek, were Sunday
            dinner guests of their daughter, Mrs. Paul Haugstad and family. Mr.
            and Mrs. Maeder left for Freeport, last Sunday, to attend the
            funeral of a brother-in-law of Mrs. Maeder. They returned home
            Friday. They also visited their two daughters at Freeport. Iola
            Smith is employed in the D. W. A. Holder home. Saturday eve- ning
            Mrs. Holder, Mrs. John Levis, and Mrs. Louise Holder drove out to
            call at Houghton’s and brought Iola home to spend Sunday at her home
            here. We are sorry to hear that Earl Langworthy Jr., of Hixton, was
            tak­ en seriously ill Tuesday night and underwent an operation for
            appendi- citis some time during the night at the Krohn hospital.
            Mrs. Earl Lang­ worthy sr. stayed in B. R. Falls and with her son
            part of the time until Friday when she returned home. Jun­ ior is
            getting along nicely. The Houghtonburg school attended the contest
            at the Pomroy school on Friday in which the Van Horn, Prin- dle
            Valley, Pomroy and Houghton­ burg schools took part. These peo­ ple
            won first places for us: Wini­ fred Newton, oral spelling; Virginia
            Stuve and Dale Hemmy, reading; Darle and Dale Hemmy, arithmetic. The
            Pomroy-Houghtonburg kittenball team defeated the Van Horn-Prindle
            Valley team 14-1. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
