<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M07D12</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> It is time to pick blueberries. Not much on this
            section. But some other place report have had a good crop at north.
            There are many Indians are going to North picking blueberries. Mrs.
            Tall Decorah has been sick some time ago. They took her at Tomah
            Indian hospital last week. Tom Thunder went to Wisconsin Rapids last
            week. He want come back on this week. He is hurry to get his car as
            soon as he can get here again. R. A. worker looking for their check
            since last week, has not come yet, and some are not very anxious to
            get them because not very much for this period. The word received
            from Witten­ berg, Ed Smith passed away July 4th night, 12:15, at
            his own place, and he is over sixty years, and survive his wife and
            their children and many other relatives and friends and those who
            know him is very sorrow for him and everybody know him of his age.
            The sympathy goes to his family, and some other relatives and
            friends. Hon. Merlin Hull is here last week. We always very glad to
            see him, and he is man work for his own district, the people, white
            and red skin, its make no difference to him any kind color. Henry
            Greengrass and Indian re­ porter were here in town to get order to
            cut hay at government land. Indian reporter had a letter from Mr.
            William Bumice of Fairchild, last week, and he want to see him if he
            have time to do so. Walter Luedtke spent several days in this
            community inspecting risks for the Herman Farm Underwriters and the
            Herman Mutual Insurance Co. Miss Ann Rauk writes from Columbia,
            where she is attending summer school, that she enjoys the East and
            has also taken in the World’s Fair. At the morning services at the
            Lutheran church Roger Allan, son of Mr. and Mrs. Ralph Stevens, and
            Junior Kirby, son of Mr. and Mrs. Harold Kirby, were baptized. Mr.
            and Mrs. Harley Finn and family, James Finn of Garden Valley, Mr.
            and Mrs. C. E. Olson and son Philip spent Friday at the Van Gor­ den
            cottage at Hatfield. Arthur Erickson is taking a two weeks vacation
            from his duties at the Jackson County Bank. Philip Mills, of B. R.
            Falls, is taking charge of the bank during his absence. Mrs. Lillian
            Moe and daughter Evelyn, of Independence, and Mr. and Mrs. Olaf
            Amundson and son of Blair, and Mr. and Mrs. Oscar Larson and family
            enjoyed a picnic at B. R. Falls, Tuesday. Mr. and Mrs. Ludwig Rice
            and daughter of Minneapolis, and the former’s sisters, Agnes and
            Mary, o f Madison, Minn., stopped at Ole Huseboe’s, Tuesday enroute
            to the World’s Fair at New York. On Sunday, Rev. Bringle accom­
            panied by Miss Lillian Stensby, Jer­ ome Hanson and Vernon Rauk went
            to Chetek to spend a week at the Bible camp. Others going by bus
            were Misses Mabel Fenney, Lois Smith, Vol berg Huseboe, Norma
            Bemtson, Olive Petsch, Lylah Johnson, Marjorie Berg, Verna Berg and
            Dorothy Halverson and Messrs Raymond Anderson, David Wallen, Alfred
            Waller Jr. and Ralph Loken. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
