<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M04D26</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>The Indian Mission Reform church is 60 years old
            next 14 days of May. There they are going to have celebra­ tion of
            that day. They will have big meeting and also they will have
            feastable at the same time. Rev. Ja­ cob Stucki sr., he spent 46
            years in this church to preaching Winnebago Indians and he has quite
            numbers of converted during this time and also he made a book of
            part new testa­ ment translated into Winnebago lan­ guage, still
            these books are using, those are not understand English writing.
            Rev. old man Stucki passed away about nine years ago and his son,
            Ben Stucki is Supt. of Indian Mission school Clark countv at Neills­
            ville, Wis., and Indian Mission Re­ form church is preaching by Rev.
            John Stacy, in Jackson county. This is old man Jacob Stucki’s place
            and some old members of this church they remember well all way
            through this happened. Indian reporter had received a let­ ter from
            Will B. Gipple, of Seattle, Wash. Will says he was born in Wis­
            consin nearly 61 years ago, use to live at North Bend, and at the
            time when he was 11 years moved to Galesville and he says he
            remember his father had one store at North Bend and trade with the
            Indians, and I remember him, old man Gipple. Old man Jacob Stucki
            and I, we went to see him trying to get some informa­ tion about
            that Decorah’s land, but these things, and he gave us a book he says
            he don’t know much about published by the name of Draper’s old timer
            and three or four different book. This book tell lots of Indians
            tribes Indians, when Sioux used to live at the place of citv of
            Winona, Minnesota. I thank Will B. Gipple that he wrote to me, and
            he says it is far, far away from Jackson coun­ ty, Wisconsin, but
            any way write a letter. The Minneapolis Journal, April 12, 1939 says
            part of Indian bad news— “Senators Told of Starvation Among S. D.
            Sioux Indians. Washington, April 12, 1939. Peter Bearstop and Abram
            Dogarm speaking for Sioux Indians of Cheyenne River Reserva­ tion of
            South Dakota told a senate subcommittee today there was starva­ tion
            and discrimination among their fellow tribesmen, speaking through an
            interpreter. The 78 years old Dogarm said refusal of a majority of
            the tribe to accept the Wheeler-How- ard Indian act had “Divided us
            into two hostile camps”, the act which permit self government, was
            not ac­ cepted by all the tribes, he said. Dog­ arm said some of the
            people he repre­ sented and who did not like the act were being
            starved to death. Bearstop also asked exemption from the act for the
            people. Other reservation at same state claim the Indians are now
            starving. Washington, D. C., A delegation of Sioux Indians from the
            Pine Ridge (S. D.) reservation told a senate In­ dian affair
            subcommittee Tuesday that some of their tribemen were starving and
            having trouble under the Wheeler-Howard Indian reorganiza­ tion act.
            Benjamin American Horse represented a tribal council of the Ogalala
            Sioux Indians opposed to the act, under which the Indians set up
            their own government under supervi­ sion of the Indian Bureau, urged
            that the tribe be exempt from provision of the law. “We have had
            more trou­ ble than ever before”, he said. “There should be some way
            to stop it, or some one is going to be killed on the Reservation,
            our tribal treasury now is empty.” Frank Shorthorn, another tribal
            member, urged abolition of the In­ dian Bureau he said Indian were
            han­ dicapped under the act. “For many years we were better off he
            said, now we are starving like a bunch of wild goat in a corral.
            Chil­ dren are crying for bread. We have asked for investigation but
            no action has been taken. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
