<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M10D04</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> The Indians are very busy at cranberry marsh raking berries. Herman J.
            Gebhardt commence last week 28th of Sept. They are working for Herman are as follows:
            Clarence Whitedog, Louis Johnson, Henry Stacy, Herman White and Pershing Brown Eagle.
            The ladies sewing project are going to make some men’s overall commence this week. They
            are working very hard. Mr. and Mrs. John Stacy and Mr. and Mrs. Eric W. Stephen went to
            Stevens Point last Sunday to see Miss Esther Stacy out there in the hospital. She is
            getting along very fine, but they did not say when she will be out. The pupils of the
            upper room are very busy doing safety work. They are making a poster, writing
            compsitions and giving talks. Mrs. Olson and Miss Amundson are spending the evening at
            Miss Beppenhaus home. The lower room is getting a new black board. Our reporter visited
            school on Tuesday. Too bad news- Mrs. Amanda Milner passed away last Sunday morning at
            Tomah Indian hospital, 3 o’clock, Oct. 1st, 1939. She was here at Indian Mission a few
            weeks ago. She was alright, but cause of death is she had a baby, and when she getting
            worse her husband took her in the hospital, Mr. Bill Minor. She was ill only a few days,
            and sympathy goes to her husband, her mother, Mrs. Florence Eagle, and her own three
            children. Funeral had at old Indian cemetery at Indian Mission last Monday afternoon by
            the Indian custom. Mr. and Mrs. George Bear and old Man Snyder Bear were here at Indian
            Mission yesterday. They come down to visit relatives and friend. They stop over night
            and they went back again next day. Some one enter Ladies sewing WPA project one night.
            The forelady Tillie Stacy, found one overall and a dress missing. Ruth L. Zodtner relief
            director, came yesterday and told the women that if they do not produce the missing
            things she will close the project entirely. The women can not be blamed for theft as no
            one know who stole the things. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
