<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M03D08</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Our Indian News is very brief this week. Brief as it is
            we are very ap­ preciative of the fact that Charles R. Lowe Cloud
            remembers his readers are looking for his news. He is ill in the
            hospital in Tomah. Last week he wrote that he and Henry Mike and
            Charley Smoke o f Wyeville were in a room together. That “ nurses
            are doing faithful duty and Nancy Plintz, Irene Miller and Evelyn
            Murie is tak­ ing care us all night.” Saturday we had a letter from
            Charley stating: “ Charley Smoke is died this morning after 5 hi. I
            don’t know how long I will stay here. Doc­ tor says you got to stay
            here some. I had a flu. And Charles Smoke died flu too.” Today we
            have a short news letter from Charley as follows: There are many
            Indians had bad luck, and I used to see lots of Indians back and
            forth, not todays. I would like to write Indian news, but somehow I
            can not write any more so I have to stop. There are I feel good
            every morn­ ing but today I don’t feel good, and I never been sick
            before all my life. Therefore I can not take care of my­ self but I
            am glad we have nurses too. They are taking care us. C. R. LOWE
            CLOUD .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
