<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M07D26</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Most all the Indians are going to pick berries at
            north. Mr. and Mrs. Porter Decorah and Mr. George White Bear and one
            wo­ men o f Winnebago, Nebr., were here last Friday evening, visitor
            relatives and friends, stop at Indian Mission and going to Wisconsin
            Dells and they are plan to be sure is home next Thursday at
            Winnebago, Nebraska. Mrs. Peter White Gull and her children were
            here again last Sunday morning. Mrs. White Gull received a word from
            her mother at Tomah Indian hospital and once she had a worse a day
            or two. They sent word her daughter at Winnebago, Nebraska. She was
            here last Sun­ day and Mr. Lewis Tebo was driver. Mrs. White Gull
            went to see her mother last Monday and yesterday went to Dells Dam
            to see her cousin Mrs. John Thompson. Mr. Clarence Sichler went to
            North to buy blueberries last week and Eli Young Thunder went with
            him to show the road and places. Perhaps he will return again some
            time this week or may be he is going to north already on this
            writing. There are many Indians are going away, but some are staying
            home, prepare for Winnebago Indians pow­ wow ground. They will have
            three good days, Indian report and Willie Hall Jr. went to town
            asking pole wood, for us fixing pow-wow ground shade which they will
            have next Fri­ day, July 28, 29 and 30. Indian reporter and Willie
            Hall Jr. went to Clark county last Sunday. There they meet three
            young gentle­ men and young ladies as following name given to Indian
            reporter. Mr. Adolph Zorian, Ellen Wolczok, Moo- nelyn Kobnen, G.
            James Sampson, all of Wisconsin Rapids; Ed Rutchena, Neillsville,
            Wis., C. H. Patree, Marsh­ field, Wis. Mrs. Tall Decorah is in the
            Tomah Indians hospital, has been there some time, but report
            improving gradually on this writing and she is too old, she was 82
            old last fall. Indian team play with the Disco team last Sunday.
            They said Disco boys pretty hard for them red skin team. The score
            was 10 to 3 favor the Indians. The Indians team would like to have a
            game every Sunday afternoon. Albert Johnson came down see the relief
            office and ask some groceries to relief. He refuse because he is
            sin­ gle now. His wife went to picking berries at north some where.
            Robert says I will go to soldier relief where I belong. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
