<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M08D23</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Mr. Gilbert Lowe’s boys are going back to school at
            Haskell Institute, Kansas about week from now. They were anxious to
            go back at any time. Mr. Emanuel and Myron Lowe. Jesse Stacy and
            Fred Kingswan came back from north, has been pick­ ing blueberries.
            Mrs. Whitegull and her children and Mrs. Tall Decorah she took with
            her home at Winnebago Reservation, Nebraska. She took her along with
            her mother. She is not well yet. She came out in hospital a few days
            ago. Mr. William Burnie o f Fairchild, was call at Indian Mission
            last week and Indian report with him were busy and this week too.
            Sewing project add more ladies to work this last period as
            following: Mrs. Alice Funmaker, Mrs. Alice Carl and Mrs. Frank Big
            Soldier. R. A. worker has began work yes­ terday, and last week they
            had been waiting every morning but never come the truck until
            yesterday morn­ ing but some are not here yet. The Indians some
            received oranges yesterday from relief office, and they had some
            other stuff 15th of August and they said that helps some those who
            need provision. The Indians pow-wow are all over now, and white
            people pow-wow will begin Sept. 9-10-11-12, 1939. Re­ member the
            date. Bring your part­ ner or your friends. This was last you will
            have a good time with your friend or some other your relatives. The
            Indian report planning to go visit old friends, start here to go to
            Blair and Independence, Galesville and his first teacher, Fred Sacia
            of Galesville. They will try to make a one trip, but we had not set
            the date. As soon as possible. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
