<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M05D31</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Mr. and Mrs. Gilbert Lowe went to town last
            Wednesday evening to meet their boys, Emmanuel and Myron Lowe came
            back from Haskell Institute, Kansas. This is second year to go to
            school out there. They are report everything all right and their
            parents were very glad to see them when they return to home last
            week. Mr. and Mrs. Victor Acosts and Mrs. Jesse Brown of De Soto,
            Wis., were here this week to visit relatives and friends. Mrs. Acost
            formerly Miss Beatrice Brown and she was not here for long while so.
            She came down to see at Indian Mission and Mrs. Jesse Brown always
            come down every summer when berries ripe, time to pick. Mrs. Judith
            Gilbertson was here last Monday noon train. She came from Winnebago,
            Nebraska, and she came down at Mrs. Louise Mike’s place to visit her
            again. Ladies Aid has been elected new officer some time ago as
            following: Mrs. Emma Lowe, president; Miss Matilda Stacy, vice
            president; Mrs. La Von O’Brien, secretary; Mrs. John Stacy,
            treasurer, and other members Mrs. Emma Monigar, Mrs. George Lowe,
            Mrs. Viola Young Thunder, Mrs. Thomas Kingswan, Mrs. Jesse Stacy,
            Mrs. Nancy Funmaker and Marion Stacy. They made one quilt and some
            other things to sewing, too, last Monday. The Indians had purchase
            one old Dodge tractor for 65 dollars from Mathew and Rush or Rush
            and Math­ ew. They had been plow some already since they took it
            home to the Indian Mission. Mr. and Mrs. Nathaniel Decorah, of
            Mauston, were here at Indian Mission and Mrs. Decorah visit her
            parents, Mr. and Mrs. Frank Lewis. There are many Indians do not
            expect wild berries this year. We had cold, long spring and part of
            dry killed grass and killed some by frost too. Of course it might be
            some but we don’t expect many berries this year as usual, or even
            strawberries too. We did not see any man come down trying to get
            some hand picker, or no post card to send it here notify their own a
            good hand picker. Farmer have not look for helper. Mr. William
            Greanry is going to Waupaca. Mr. Greanry is work at relief office
            and now Mr. Stewart Lathrop take his place first day of next month.
            Mr. Greanry went round with him to show the places his territory.
            Ball game at Indian Mission The Indians had two ball teams, men and
            girls teams. They are playing every Sunday afternoon and they plan
            with North Branch May 21, 1939. The first time they were defeated
            the Indian team. The score was 2 to 1 favor North Branch. Last
            Sunday playing with Springfield boys. The score was 17 to 4 favor
            Indians and they said if any team want to play with these two teams
            you can write to Jesse Stacy, Black River Falls, Wis., Route 5. If
            you have a good team or pick up team. We can play with any team
            Sunday afternoon. Mr. and Mrs. Nathaniel Decorah of Mauston, were
            here at Indian Mission and Mrs. Decorah visit to her parents Mr. and
            Mrs. Frank Lewis. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
