<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M11D29</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Miss Louise Kippenhan is going home to eat Thanksgiving dinner with her family in Appleton, she will
            return Saturday. Miss Tillie Stacy, forelady ladies sewing project she says she did not have any news this week. Henry
            E. Olson has gone to deer hunting, and season opening last Saturday in the Jackson county too. Gilbert Lowe got some
            deer hunters, some white men, as they said “no luck”. Two of them gone back home. Albert Lowe of Tomah, staying at Tom
            Kingswan since last Friday. Per­ haps he will stay with him until after deer hunting. The young people of the
            community have formed a church choir. The anthem they sang in connection with the communion service last Sunday was
            much appreciated. A group of Sunday school workers met with Ben Stucki and the consistory Saturday evening to discuss
            the plans for celebrating Christmas. Mr. and Mrs. Nathaniel Decorah of Mauston, staying with Mrs. Decorah parents Mr.
            and Mrs. Frank Lewis. They will stay during deer hunting. John Black Hawk and Deno Greengrass has been trapping at
            north, but they had no luck, too many trappers they could not find a place for trap. Mrs. Esther Peterson was here
            last week with Mr. L. G. Trowbridge of Menomonie. He is district supervisor NY A project. They said NYA boys will make
            one skating pond near the Indian Mission for the school children. John Stacy and his son Alvin Stacy are working hard
            fixing water pump taking out pipe yesterday and John is always do something, he is working fix up inside community
            house and one of make foundation and plaster too. There will be exchange to give any things for Christmas present. You
            can signed your name at Mrs. Emma Lowe this week and you can take your person’s name next Sunday so you will prepare
            for to give anythings present next Christmas day. Mrs. John Black Hawk has been gone to General Hospital at Madison
            last two months for she had two oper­ ation since she went there and she came back to Tomah Indian hospital last
            Friday. She is not very wellyet so she have to stay there for a while until she will get well. There will be no school
            Thursday or Friday. Mr. Landgray, state inspector, Miss Hanson and Mrs. Rose | the supervisors visited Hotonga school
            Tuesday. Mr. Landgraf says he has | been seen, lots different school thru the state, this Indian Mission school beat
            them all, he saw make good work and neat. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
