<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M07D05</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Everybody enjoy to attending centennial of Black River Falls people this
            week, and many are come from a far, far away from Jackson county of Wisconsin, Mr. and
            Mrs. Dan Stockwell and daughter Jeanette and Len Stockwell, all of Wibaux, Montana. Did
            you see Indian Village at Fair ground? Indian reporter he heard lots of white people say
            its worthy to see, come down see this “Indian Village” and what they had performed at
            the stage, and also they had quite lots of different days produced. We don’t expect to
            see many Indians. They come from every Indian settlement. Mrs. Margaret La Mere Johnson
            was here again yesterday. Some other Indians with her but we don’t know the names. Quite
            a few Indians come from Nebraska, and Mrs. Margaret was here all winter, went home last
            March. Dicky Walters foreman WPA, went to see his gang this morning. He told them he
            don’t know much about what they are going to do. They have report to ranger station
            tomorrow morning. I saw Mr. Hull at printing office this morning, and shake hand with
            him. He is look pretty well, always does. There are many white people would like to know
            the Indian Reporter, who he was. While many are come to see the Centennial, not the 4th
            of July but Centennial and same time they like to see Indians reporter. They are looking
            for him at fair ground last night and finally they find him. They had talk to him and
            one man gave him a dollar too, and he thank him very much. One of them come from
            Montana, he is Stockwell. He was born here between here and Tay­lor, and another party
            to look for him at Indian Mission last Monday from Iowa. R. R. Langworthy family and
            relatives from Des Moines, Iowa, and relatives from St. Mary’s Ohio, and Maurice
            Amundson from Fly Creek, Wis. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
