<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M04D19</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>John Blackhawk was here last Saturday. He brought to his wife in the
            hospital, to treat medical. Snyder Bear and his son George were here to see us one day
            last week and next day John Smoke came down to see us too. He did not know I was here
            again until he saw at Tomah newspaper. Doctor says yesterday he think I am alright, I
            can go this week at any time, only hearing not very good, but they will be all right
            after while, and if you be careful. Albert Berg stop at Tomah Indian hospital Saturday
            to see Charles R. Low Cloud in hospital. Albert says he was going thru that Highway 12
            and he saw the little ways from that so he thought stop over there to see Charles. Week
            ago last Tuesday Mrs. Harriet Noble bought some groceries for the sunshine for Lois Hull
            for the Indian report at Sechler store, and he was very glad to receive that, but he
            could not carry, so somebady to carried him into the car. One of the Frost Cloud’s boy
            cut arm by the window. They brought him in hospital yesterday to dress. Bill Carriman
            passed away Sunday at his home- in Wood county somewhere and he is over 60 years old. He
            is not feeling well since last summer. Henry Johnson of Greenwood, Ole Waukon and Able
            Looking Glass were here, come to see us yesterday. Henry Mike and I, we stay one room,
            and we thank them for that, they come to see us long distance. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
