<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M05D03 part 1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Mr. Jacob Stucki and John Stacy fixing garden
            fence. Mr. Stucki is al­ ways busy every day and he has been
            prepared to cut some posts, peel and painted both end. Indian report
            looking round where they build new houses, W PA work­ ers doing work
            and they said they had been torn down some old barn some time ago.
            They are using these old lumber and some of them working make
            foundation. They make five already finished masons work. The school
            news. Frank Johnson and John Davis have been helping the teacher and
            pnpils to clean their school yard. They appreciate this very much. A
            lot of brush has been burned. Many of the children are busy making
            May baskets for their mother and parents. Kenneth Little George
            brought Mrs. Olson two poly- wog Monday morning thinking they would
            be good company for the gold fish. Our sand table has your pansy
            flowers in it all in bloom. Our school attended the contest in Town
            Creek last Friday. They report a very good time. Frieda Stacy got
            second in arithmetic. Maurice Stack got first in art, also in a
            health poster. Our school also got first ftlace in singing. Arvina
            Lowe got second place in art. Maurice Stacy got first in three kinds
            of jumping. Lawrence Little George got second place. Mrs. Waukon has
            been making maple syrup. She also gave Mrs. Olson some of it Mrs.
            John Stacy and daughter Tillie, also Emma Olson attended the Mother
            and daughters banquet in your city. Mr. Henry Berg is going to Mil­
            waukee last Saturday, attended jew­ elry convention at Milwaukee and
            not only that, but he will have big time enjoy himself. Mr. and Mrs.
            Vanvert Dick of Wis­ consin Rapids went to Winnebago, Nebraska. They
            took it home with Mrs. Margret Johnson last Saturday. Margret came
            here last fall, she would like to go home last month so she went
            home last week. Baby boy was bom April 1, 1939 to Mr. and Mrs. Henry
            G^eengrass at Tomah Indian hospital, call the name Maynard
            Greengrass, and the boy nd mother are doing well on this writing.
            .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
