<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M10D11</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> The Indians are most came from cranberry marsh.
            They said they are all finished raking cranberry, all they want to
            clear up section or fix up cranberry marsh. Mr. and Mrs. Homer
            Snake, Mary Fisher and Mrs. Maud Brown Eagle came back from Nebraska
            last Friday afternoon and they are planning to come back last Sunday
            but pretty hard to get gas money at Nebraska Reservation. They are
            using “New Deals” and finally she got some a few dollars from her
            own leasing. William O’Brien came back from Highway 12, has been
            living on sell­ ing baskets on highway ever since last spring and he
            is here at Indian Mission now. Mr. and Mrs. Peter Pettibone are
            going to Waupaca last week to dick- ing potatoes or picking potatoes
            for 4c a bush, and they will make some money on that, big families.
            Robert Greengrass is working on Gaynor’s marsh near Wisconsin
            Rapids. He came back to Mission Sunday for only two hours. Mr. Lee
            Sam of La Crescent, Minn., stopped here at Mission. He is on way to
            Wisconsin Rapids on im­ portant business. Mr. Collins of Tomah
            Indian Ag­ ency came to Mission. The Indian report ask him why he
            promise Indi­ ans so much and he never do what he say. He say
            government is very slow in matter of Indian housing. Mrs. Esther
            Black Hawk is still in hospital at Madison. She is improv­ ing on
            this writing. RA worker will work rain or shine and they are making
            dike way on high land. It seemed never will be some water at that
            part, but they are working any way. John Black Hawk, William Hall
            Jr. and Charles R. Lowe Cloud went to Madison last Monday on
            business. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
