<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M09D27</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Many Indians are going to picking cranberries, most of did not come home
            yet. Two boys came from Winnebago Reservation at Nebraska last week, Rueben Snake and
            Ben One Horn. They went right on to Neopit Wis., to look for Waler Snake. Ladies Sewing
            project forelady said 1750 yards of material from the district office in Menomonie, Wis.
            All the ladies are busy every hours next few months, and special “cutters” Mrs. Wood,
            she can not cut all that for one month, it same some time. Mr. and Mrs. Eric W. Stephens
            came back from Wyoming, Minnesota. Mr. Eric is not working out there and came back to
            Wisconsin to stay with two John Stacy’s boys at Greenwood, Wis. Perhaps they will stay
            up there until he find job to work somewhere and his daughter will go school at
            Greenwood so Mrs. Stephens sister, brother and her parents, Mr. and Mrs. John Stacy to
            visit here last week and they took her Clarence Monigar, Jr., so of Mr. and Mrs.
            Clarence Monigar, of Indian Mission. They want him to go to school with Bonnie May
            Stephens, the daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Eric W. Stephens. I am very glad to receive a
            post card from Mrs. C. E. Button of Hixton, Wis. She says Jennie Quackenbush is a friend
            of mine and I am glad to tell you she is Mrs. A. H. Hanson now of West Salem, Wis. The
            Hotonga schoolhas had many visitors. Supt. Farmer from Tomah, Supt. Christy from
            Milwaukee, Educational Field Representative Mr. Eubank also state nurse Miss McLaughlin.
            The 7th and 8th grade are busy with their history. The 5tha nd 6th grade have been
            studying the different kinds of leaves. The school children were very happy when Eubank
            from Tomah brought them 50 coat hangers and six larger chairs. The pupils in the lower
            room are making a farm on the sand table. The 3rd and 4th graders are busy making
            colored leaves for a border in our room. Miss Louise Kippenhan of Appleton, Wis., she is
            social worker. She is here last week and she will instruct the school children lots of
            different things but they had not fix up the place. The Indian reported had lots of
            visitor from Knapp. Mr. William Whitney and daughter Mrs. Grace Whitney Larson and Mrs.
            Ida Jarrett, and Mr. Whitney says he lived here Jackson county for 60 years but never
            been here at Indian Mission until yesterday and he promised him to come here again when
            he will have time to come over, and Mrs. Grace she is one good hand writing and she said
            she onve had contest penmanship she got the first prize. Mr. and Mrs. Charley Young
            Thunder came over to see Mr. Bert F. Johnson last week. Mr. Young Thunder want him to go
            to High school this year again and he will see his record first and he will take again.
            Benjamin Young Thunder is going to high school again this year. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
