<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M10D18</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Tom Thunder is here yesterday, came back from Wood
            county on his way to home at Hunter Bridge. John Falcon was here
            last Satur­ day from Mauston and came back with Mrs. May Hunker.
            Saturday afternoon Indian report­ er was in Chris Olson restaurant
            and Moses Paquette were talking about where Moses lost one dog a few
            days ago, and if anybody gives the infor­ mation $5 reward. The
            upper room has made a “ peep show” of Columbus landing in Amer­ ica.
            Mr. Eubank called at school on Monday. There are 52 children en­
            rolled in our school now. Mrs. Olson is teaching the children how to
            play the tonettes. Miss Keppenhan is teach­ ing the children one
            hour every week in the dining room. William Hall, John Black Hawk
            and Indian report were called at Mad­ ison first part of the week
            and go from here to Endeavor Wis., and where Mr. John White Eagle
            is. He is working WPA project in that coun­ ty. His children go to
            school in that village. Henry Mike passed away last Sat­ urday
            forenoon 8 o’clock, October 14, 1939. Mrs. Mary Johnson White passed
            away yesterday morning. We will tell more about these two next week.
            “U. S. of the America” has too many missionary sent out from here to
            whole world and quite a few dif­ ferent churches or different
            nomina­ tion religion, still never use anything true and just as
            same politics they called money talking. TTiey can not use anythings
            the true. The Indians and white people most the same, they knew God
            make a man first and afterward make the woman. So therefore woman
            less than “ a man” and I am sure there is no men and no women
            Honest, and if any body says honest, that is just talk­ ing that is
            all. Old Dandy, he told them over hundred years ago. There are
            everythings we find out, its just like put somethings hide under the
            snow and when spring come you can see every things right there.
            .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
