<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M12D27</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>A Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year for all those
            Banner-Journal reader. Mr. and Mrs. Chris Winneshiek of Waupaca,
            Wis., were here Christmas day and see the Indian Mission pro­ gram
            in the evening and they all have enjoy themselves who were there to
            see them. The Indian reporter has been sick list last few weeks and
            he had receiv­ ed some Christmas present. He will expect some more
            and he had postal card but did not get the things. Christmas Program
            1939 Winnebago Indian Mission school Neillsville, Wisconsin. Silent
            Night— School Scripture Reading and Prayer— Ma. Ben Stucki It Came
            Upon the Midnight Clear — Elizabeth Christ John, Marie Ann Stucki,
            Vivian Kingswan, Madeline White Eagle, Edith Pettibone, Anna
            Pettibone, Anna Winneshiek, Ger­ maine Russell, Annabelle
            Winneshiek, Ramona Kitchkumne. Pageant scenes: The Annunciation to
            Mary. Angel Gabriel— Lillian Thunder Cloud Mary— Lena Mallory The
            Street of Bethlehem: (street scene) Mary— Dana Mallory Joseph—
            Casper Mallory Innkeeper— Harold Blackdeer Shepherd “ A ” — Herbert
            Lonetree Roman Soldier— Ruell John The Shepherd in Bethlehem Field:
            “ B” Shepherd—John Barnes “ C” Shepherd— Ernest Garvin “ D”
            Shepherd— Ray Garvin Two others— Mathew Falcon, Billy Stucki Mary
            and Joseph, Christ Child in Manger1 King Herod and the Wise Men:
            King Herod— Mr. Ben Stucki Kasper— Jacob Stucki Bolthasar— Woodrow
            Thunder Chief Melchoir— Freddie Vomholt Angel Appear to Shelherd:
            Shepherd— John Barnes, Ernest Garvin, Roy Gavin, Mathew Falcon,
            Billy Stucki. Angel— Lillian Thundercloud, Ra­ chel Lonetree,
            Genevieve Pettibone, Luveme Kitchkume, Albertain Thun­ dercloud,
            Gretchen Young Thunder, Esther Stucki Pantomime, “ Hark the Herald
            An­ gels Sing” : The Three Wise Men— Kasper, Ja­ cob Stucki;
            Malthasar, Woodrow Thunder Chief; Melchior, Freddie Vomholt.
            Shepherd Resolve to go to Bethle­ hem— All the shepherd. Adoration
            scene— All the charac­ ters. Another, our own Hotonga school in
            Jackson county at Indian Mission. Our program: Song, “ O Come All Ye
            Faithful” Welcome— Luke Snowball Song, “ So Did I” — Upper grade
            girls Christmas Wishes— Keith Snake and George Stacy, Henry Swan and
            Walter Funmaker. A Mocker’s Song and Recitation— Mary Wallace.
            Strange Gifts— Kenneth Little George, Jessie Little George and
            Fredrick Lewis. Song, “ Jolly Old Saint Nicholas” — 3rd and 4th
            grade girls. Music, “ Away in a Manger” — The girls. Christmas
            Acrostic— 3d grade. Star Drill and Song with Tonette music.
            Christmas Story— 2d grade boys. Song and Recitation, “ Bells Song” —
            Five girls. Recitation— Juanita Funmaker Tonette music, “ Come All
            Ye Faith­ ful” — 4th and 8th grades. Song, “ Away in a Manger” Song,
            “ Lesson of Christmas Can­ dles” — Girls Song, “ The First
            Christmas” — 3rd and 4th girls. “ We Trim our Christmas Tree” — 4th
            grade “ O Christmas Tree” — Lower grades Pageant 1939 and 1940—
            Upper room Recitation, “ My Dolly and I” — 1st grade girls “ An
            Appreciation” -—John Climer “ Good-bye” — The school. We will have
            another program next week. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
