<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M09D13</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>The ladies sewing project working at No. 1 new
            house, eight of them ladies and besides cutters, forelady, Miss
            Tillie Stacy. There are 45 enrolled in our school at present. Miss
            Laura Amundson is teaching in primary room. The boys have been very
            busy doing some car­ penter work for the teachers. The school
            children got some prize at the Fair. There are many big shot
            thinking, here after, what are going to say at politics. He will
            study what he will going to say when time come next election, but he
            will forget, when he get that office, what he “ promised” . The
            Indians quite a few went to the cranberry marsh to working days work
            for couple weeks vacation from RA and W PA project. Perhaps they get
            permit from their officer in the town. Mrs. John Stacy, her daughter
            Til­ lie, and her son Alvin Stacy went to see Miss Esther Stacy at
            Stevens Point, Wis., last Sunday. We had some visiting from Minne­
            sota people yesterday morning. Mr. F. J. Bowman he is to show the
            way to find Indian Mission as following: Mr. and Mrs. Leo J.
            Cardinal, Ves­ ta, Minn., and Mrs. Albert Bjelland. Some o f them
            lived in new house, Luke Snowball enter the No. 8 house, Mrs. Mary
            Whitewater enter No. 7 house and No. 9 take Nellie Wallace. WPA
            workers they tear down the tar paper camps and spoil lots of things.
            They can use them in storge. And they got order from government of­
            fice. Mrs. Harriet Noble missed the Jack­ son County Fair. She on
            vacation for two weeks and we hope she will have a good luck “
            fishing” trip. While she absent from her duty Mr. A. P. Jones take
            her place and we expect her back next a few days. There is another
            teacher came down try to see Charles R. Lowe Cloud about 47 or 48
            years ago. Miss Jennie Quackenbush. She was teach­ ing at Ox Bow
            south of Melrose, and they were in pupils at that time. Charles R.
            Lowe Cloud, Joe Thunder, late Willie Thunder and Johnnie Thunder.
            Willie and Johnnie were dead last year and Indian report want to
            know her address. If anybody know please let us know at once. Write
            Charles R. Lowe Cloud, Black River Falls, Wis., Route 5. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
