<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M01D04</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> The months of cold weather are January and February. It’s time to
            sliding now days, everywhere boys and girls, even men too. Rose Ziegler of Lebanon,
            Pennsylvania, she was here last Thursday. She came down with Mrs. Ben Stucki. She stop
            at Indian Mission school at Neillsville, and she heard about this Indian Mission in here
            Wisconsin, and now she want to see herself and to know what it was. Mr. and Mrs. James
            Yellowbank were here last Saturday evening at D. D. Decorah place and quite a few
            Indians stop here to wait newyear. Mr. and Mrs. John Stacy, Alvin and Tillie Stacy went
            to Greenwood week ago last Monday to see how they getting along those two boys working
            their own farm. Indian Mission school teacher Mrs. Emma Olson report she had forty-five
            children go to school at present. She told Indian reporter to see the children how they
            work hard to study their own lesson and every one got clean come to school, and she
            thank for their parents for these children. Miss Matilda Stacy, forelady of the sewing
            project, she went to Indian hospital last week at Tomah Indian school, and Dr. told her
            she need rest for a few days and she went there for a week to rest. She came back Monday
            evening and she is working Tuesday again. Mrs. Frank Lewis went to Tomah Indian hospital
            last Sunday night and she is going to have baby pretty soon and her daughter, Mr. and
            Mrs. Nathaniel Decorah of Mauston were here to take care of her home. Mrs. Esther Black
            Hawk underwent an operation Monday at Tomah hospital. She has not been feeling well
            since September last and Mr. Black Hawk went to see her yesterday. Mr. and Mrs. Daniel
            La Mere and Cicel Free went back to Nebraska last month and came again last Monday early
            morning and they brought back his sister, Mrs. Margaret La Mere Johnson. Too bad news—
            their brother Alex La Mere passed away a few weeks ago at Nebraska Reservation. He is
            nice old man. The sympathy goes to his family and sister and brother, and some other
            relatives and friends. His and friends. Mr. and Mrs. Ray White of Dells Dam, were here
            at Indian Mission last Monday and visit relatives and friends. A man hunting deer last
            fall had a very unusual experience. He saw a buck and he fell it with a shot. Being very
            eager he ran up to it and put his tag on the horn. He put his gun aside and began to
            take out his knife when the deer got up and ran off. In a few minutes he heard a shot
            whence the deer go. Going to the place he saw a man with rifle and at his feet laid the
            deer with his tag attached. He told the man that the deer was his as he put his tag on
            the other said “I can’t understand how you put your tag on him when he was running like
            that.” .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
