<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M06D07</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> RA worker gang are making dam and fixing up Dan its
            too. ihey said Mr. Halverson need him up there for a game.
            Strawberries is the time to picking. Quite a few Indians are going
            to picK a day, and they will return to home on evening. Mr. and Mrs.
            John Stacy went to Stevens Point again week ago last Tuesday, to see
            their daughter, Miss Esther Stacy, and they said looks al­ right,
            but they did not say when she wiii come home, and Miss Wanda De­
            corah she was going home last Fri­ day. Matilda bnowoall is report
            al­ right on this writing, at the same nospital. Bill O’Brien is
            making fence around his house. He had some small children, he could
            not keep in the house, and also road pretty close the house, pretty
            danger for them. There fore he is trying to save his children. Tom
            Thunder is here at Indian Mission waiting for another dance next few
            weeks, and also his girls are going to pick strawberries for the
            sea­ son. They are going already last Monday, and he is going with
            them too. Don’t forget that Black River Val­ ley Centennial and
            Homecoming on July 2nd, 3rd and 4th, and prepare to fix up with your
            foreman, if you are working somewhere, or be better for you, you are
            working at your own home, and 1 would like to see that because I am
            not hundred years old yet, and if you ask old man Thunder Cloud he
            can tell you most close to hundred years ago. Then some young
            people, if they tell me some thing old thing, I would not believe
            because I am older than he or she. WPA worker making house all along
            bank Dickey creek, not I mean Postmaster “Dicky” this is name of the
            creek, where you can get some trout. Mrs. James Yellowbank went to
            General hospital at Madison last Monday and she had treatment medi­
            cal again, and her son Delos Yellow­ bank was here at Indian Mission
            to see relatives and friends. The ball game between Indians and
            Pleasant View last Sunday the score was 18 to 0 in favor Indians,
            and boys will expect play with Alma Cen­ ter next Sunday but not too
            sure. We hope they will come to try our team. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
