<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M06D21</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> It's time now to pick strawberries. Only a few Indians left here at
            Indian Mission, those who are working at project and those some
            women work a sewing project. Herman Brown Eagle lost some baby
            clothes between Frank Knapp’s place and Louie Updike filling station
            and please finder return to Herman Brown Eagle and family and
            reward. Alvin Stack took in Doctor Krohn office Joe Thunderking to
            examine, he is not feeling well last few months, and he is too old
            and blind last sev­ eral years. Indians Re-selling baskets. Chair­
            man Gilbertson advised the board that he had received complaints
            some of local Indians in regards to the sale of baskets on the
            highway. He called on one of the Indians present and asked her to
            state her case. According to her statement, Indians from La Crosse
            county come in and crowd the local people off Highway 12. Motion
            made by Supervisor Millis that the Jackson county Indians pay a
            license fee of 25 cents then they will be reg­ istered and something
            can be done. Motion seconded by Supervisor Bul­ lock and carried.
            Indian reporter had received a let­ ter from Indian office nine
            years ago through Supt. Morrison office at To­ mah Indian school,
            Dec. 10, 1930 re­ garding the Indians money, and again a letter from
            Hon. Merlin Hull, Ap­ ril 2, 1939, some money was short $2676.44.
            Indian reporter wrote to Commission Indians Affairs John Sol- loir
            at Washington, D. C. Dear John Collier, Re: 28508-30, 64598-30,
            Misc. 20728-39. Dear Sir: I wish to call your attention to the
            matter of Winnebago funds supposed­ ly on deposit in the U. S.
            treasury as referred to in the correspondence from your office as
            noted above, ac­ cording to the letter dated April 27, 1939 and
            address to Hon. Merlin Hull, House of Representatives there has been
            a shrinkage of funds belong­ ing to the Winnebagoes since 1930
            amounting to $2676.44. As a Win­ nebago interested in the affairs of
            my people there are certain things I would like to know, what has
            caused this shrinkage in this fund, who were these moneys paid out
            to and for what? Also what has become of the accrued interest for it
            would seem strange that money on deposit should fail to draw
            interest. I would ap­ preciate a letter from your " office clearing
            up these matters as others besides myself wish to have this in­
            formation regarding our property. Truly yours, Charles R. Lowe Cloud
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
