<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M08D30</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>The ladies sewing project moved into one new house
            last Monday and they will move into that new build­ ing has been
            made one purpose, the squaw sewing room , and also doctor office.
            Foreman Dicky Walters says all they waiting for plasters, if they
            had they could finish before Septem­ ber. Bad news. Mr. and Mrs.
            Fred Whitewater lost one baby girl last week. Too bad. 22nd of
            August, 1939. They had funeral at Indian Mission cemetery. The
            sympathy goes to her parents and some other rela­ tives. Ben
            Potter’s marsh started last Monday, southeast of CCC camps at
            Charley Peterson’s place about five miles from there. Mr. Ben Potter
            one day came down to see Indian report­ er, told him he would like
            to have about 20 or 30 hand pickers. He want him to put advertise
            wants In­ dian pickers. Indian report told some Indians but told
            them you don’t have in advertisement, we are all here enough to hand
            pickers. Last Mon­ day Indian reporter was there, see them 76
            pickers, but soon after some more car came in, make over hun­ dred.
            Mr. Potter was very glad to have finish before some other marsh
            begin and he pay one dollar bushel. Henry Greengrass and Daniel Lowe
            had letter from Work Project Ad­ ministration district No. 8 Menomo­
            nie, Wisconsin. They will work 30th day of Aug. tom orrow. Peter
            White Gull was here again last week from W innebago, Nebras­ ka,
            visiting relative and friend. Emanuel Lowe will go back to school
            yesterday at Haskell Institute in his third year. He is bright young
            man to study everythings. W ant to learn for our use, his future
            life and we wish him successful life and use­ ful way. Mr. and Mrs.
            John Stacy went to Greenwood at his own farm, where his two boys run
            that farm, and per­ haps stay with them for a few days. They went
            last Sunday, did not re­ turn home yet. Alvin Stacy, Clifford Lowe
            and Charles R. Lowe Cloud went to cran­ berry picking last Monday.
            Alvin never pick cranberry before, all he want to learn how to hand
            pick cran­ berries, and he don’t want to go any more, he says. He
            couldn't make any things on picking berries. Hotonga school will
            begin next Monday, Sept. 4, 1989, and close end of spring 1940. The
            Indian children are very anxious, they asked when school begin, and
            some of them want to know if Emma Olson come back to teach them
            again. They told them yes she will be back. That will be fine. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
