<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M07D19</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> There are many Indians are going to North to pick
            blueberries, and the Indian Mission place are hard to find Indians
            yesterday and today. Mrs. Helen Russell of Winnebago, Nebraska, was
            here some time ago to visit her daughter, Mrs. Tom King- swan.
            Remember the date of Indian pow­wow. They will have July 28, 29 and
            30 at Indian old pow-wow ground seven mile northeast of Black River
            Falls. Don’t miss it this pow-wow. And if you do come to see you
            will see some old things you never see before, and they are all
            prepare the things. The Indian Missions are almost moved away to
            Highway 12 between Black River Falls and Merrillan. They have stand
            for sale basket. There will be a new build house near school, they
            said build for sew­ ing room and part of doctor office. The Indian
            doctor-come every month first Tuesday, and some other Indian
            settlement too, suppose visit them every Indian settlement every
            month. The Indians baseball team play with Spring Creek team last
            Sunday. The score was 7 to 5 favor for red skin. Mrs. Old Man
            Thunder Cloud has been sick some time ago and report this morning is
            improving gradually, and she is too old, she must be over 79 years
            old. Her son Adam Thunder Cloud want her to go to Tomah Indian
            hospital but she don’t want to go. Last Wednesday Mr. and Mrs. Dan
            Stockwell, their daughter Jeanette and Len Stockwell were visitor at
            Indian Mission and they come down with Mr. and Mrs. John Davis of
            Black River Falls, and Mrs. Davis she know some Indians, she use to
            go school at near Indian Mission. She remember well of Mrs. D. W.
            Decorah and Indian reporter went with around Indian Mission to see
            place and new houses to and foreman Dicky Walters too. Some Indians
            come to see the Indian reporter, want to know too many Indians came
            from the other counties, have a stand to sale basket, and Indian
            reporter says I have nothing to say about these things, you have to
            see the county board. Wm. Hall Jr. and family went to Wisconsin
            Dells to visit friends and relatives on the 13th. Also they went to
            Packwaukee to visit his sister and brother-in-law, John White Eagle.
            They witness Indian pageant at Stand Rock and return on the 15th.
            Mrs. Verna Pigeon was here today visit relatives and friends. She is
            formerly Verna Deer. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
