<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M06D14</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Mr. and Mrs. Jesse Mike of Dells Dam, were here at
            Indian Mission and come down to see Charles R. Low Cloud, want find
            out the old In­ dian name, who he was, James Shell. He passed away
            about 41 years ago. Mr. and Mrs. Peter White Gull and their family
            of Winnebago, Nebraska, and Mrs. White Gull she was working at
            sewing project, but she was lay off for a few weeks. Mrs. White Gull
            formerly Miss Grace Decorah of Black River Falls, the daughter of
            Mrs. Tall Decorah. They went to pick strawberries near Taylor,
            Relyea Dahlia Gardens. Mrs. Frank Lewis and her children went to
            pick strawberries at Relyea, and perhaps some more Indians are going
            today, and the Indians are most all going to move away for a few
            days to picking strawberries. New houses had not done much this
            week. Foreman Dick Walters says he think they could not finished
            first day of July, and he says they ought to commence two weeks
            early. He think it seemed too slow the work. Mr. Leonard Doud is
            faithfully work at Indian Mission new house, making chimney for
            them. Indian re­ port told him he would like to finished all good
            work for these chimney. Henry Greengrass had broken rear axel his
            car Monday night in front of Mr. P. L. Moe hardware store, and he
            could not get any body to haul up for him, until Flora Fun- maker’s
            boys came out from show way in night. They took him as far as Mr.
            Lewis Koran’s place, or at Airport tavern. Mr. Greengrass work WPA,
            so he could not do anything yesterday morning. Call at Dano Green
            Grass and Tomah Decorah for doctor this car. They said they are
            pretty good doctor any car. There are quite a few Indians are
            camping at Relyea Dahlia gardens waiting for the ripe of
            strawberries and his neighbor, Mr. Walter Kling, at same place. They
            will pick until Thursday. They said they got enough pickers at
            present but if they wants they can notify them at Indian Mis­ sion.
            Chief Moses Paquette he is hunt­ ing dogs, he want good watching dog
            any night. Cap Waller, he is looking for him last weeks, and they
            says they are looking for Black dog, and Chief said not too Black.
            .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
