<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M06D28</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Mr. and Mrs. Roy White were here from Wood county at
            cranberry marsh, visit relatives and friend last Sunday. Mrs. Eric
            W. Spehen of Wyoming, Minnesota, she came to visit her pa­ rents,
            Mr. and Mrs. John Stacy. Mrs. Stephen, formerly Miss Helen Stacy.
            Mr. and Mrs. M. E. Gorman, Mr. Blanchard Blekeles were here one day
            last week and last Wednesday went to Neillsville and Wisconsin
            Rapid. They had quite a few Indian probate cases. Charles R. Lowe
            Cloud went with them and help them to find where the Indians are
            located. Interpreter for old people those who can not speak English
            and return home last Friday evening on train. Mr. and Mrs. Peter
            Whitegull and their children, Agnes Whitegull, Fran- ceita
            Whitegull, Irene Whitegull and Millard Whitegull they are going home
            at Winnebago, Nebraska, yes­ terday. They came here about two weeks
            ago to visitor their relatives and friends and also Mrs. Whitegull
            visit her mother, Mrs. Tall Decorah, and its time to pick
            strawberries at Relyea Dahlia gardens and Home- acres gardens, Mr.
            Walter Kling, and they are not finished the picking but they want
            get home first day of July. Mrs. Whitegull is working project, they
            had only one month vacation and they all hope to be here again next
            summer if nothing happens to them. We are all hope to see them again
            next summer. Mr. and Mrs. Albert Johnson, Tom Decorah and Indian
            reporter went to Tomah Indian Agency office try to find one old lady
            name Emma Lowery and they could not find, and Supt. Farber was not
            there too. Only clerg Daniel was there but he could not find
            anythings, and Indians said we can not find anything what we are
            looking for last few years, and also we have been trying to get some
            medicine at Tomah Indian hospital but we can not get it. Jessie Tabo
            and Jacqueline Green- crow are going to Madison this morn­ ing and
            they will expect employment out there but they don't tell which
            company will work. We will find later on. A number of Boy Scouts
            from here are enjoying a week’s camping at Camp Decorah. Those of
            whom we have learned who went are Wayne Collum, Earl Doud, Donn
            Holder, Jimmy Schmittfranz and Hugh Trask.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
