<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M02D15</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Everybody got bad cold now a days RA and WPA workers. They have to stop
            1-two days. Mrs. Clarence Monegar and children of Greenwood are visiting for a few days
            at the home of her parents, Mr. and Mrs. John Stacy. Dr. Leo Srole staying at Tomah
            visiting the Indians all surround Tomah. He must be making two or three good size books
            by this time. The following called at our school this past week-Miss Bush from state
            department, Miss Webb, Miss Hanson and Mrs. Rose, and also Mr. George Eubank from Tomah.
            Charles R. Lowe Cloud was here yesterday, and he has been catching cold last few weeks,
            he never get things out there and he have to stay over with it, and he did not done any
            two more weeks. Indian report had several letters from three different states and they
            said they would like to have his picture, and one said he had some clipping for Indian
            News since 1933. They got one pretty good book. Mr. and Mrs. Charley Young Thunder are
            having bad cold and confine at home, and also Henry Greengrass had bad cold too, but he
            could not come to the doctor, and Mrs. went to Tomah Indian hospital too this week and
            we understand all filled up now at Tomah Indian hospital. Mrs. Victor Miner came down
            from Portage at Tomah Indian hospital last Saturday and her examined not to stay at
            hospital until later on and she went to Portage again the same evening, and Mrs. Miner
            formerly Miss Helda Smoke, the daughter of Mr. John Smoke of Watermill. Mrs. Eliza
            Johnson came back from Nebraska yesterday and she brought her daughter, Mrs. Lillian
            Harris, of Winnebago, Nebraska-Mrs. Johnson said she think it seem just same everywhere,
            everybody got cold and Winnebago hospital all filled up last week and report quite a few
            died in the hospital and outside too. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
