<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M05D10</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Ulysses White of Wisconsin Rap­ ids, was here last
            week to visit rela­ tives and friends. Mr. and Mrs. Jesse Mike of
            Dells Dam, were here last Monday to In­ dian Mission. Mr. and Mrs.
            John Stack went to Stevens Point last Sunday to see their daughter,
            Miss Esther Stacy. They said she is alright now but Doctor did not
            say when she will be out, and she is staying with Miss Wanda Decorah
            of Mauston. Both are re­ port o. k. and also Luke Snowball daughter,
            Mildland Snowball was there same hospital. John Thompson Jr. took
            him at To­ mah Indian hospital last Thursday af­ ternoon. He was
            working on WPA gang at Clark county. He catch T. B. in the country,
            at Dells Dam. Mr. Jacob Stucki went back to In­ dian Mission school
            at Neillsville, Wis. and he is now taking care of garden stuff every
            summer and he went back last Sunday afternoon. Mr. and Mrs. John
            Winneshiek of Dells Dam, they went to Black River Falls last Monday
            and when they re­ turn to home on their way, stop at D. W. Decorah
            last Monday. Mrs. Andrew Black Hawk came back from Mount Pleasant
            hospital at Wausau, Wis., and she gain some more pounds. She was
            there for 2 or 3 years at that hospital and they sid every things
            all o. k. at Dells Dam. Leonard Doud is working here at Indian
            Mission making chimney or do the mason work. “Old Dandy” he told his
            own peo­ ple before-hand, what will be hap­ pened by this time and
            he told them we will see automobile and air plane during this time
            at the same time. The Indians they will do one thing. This is work
            for the devil. The lots of Indians will be stray of their own Indian
            way or Indian custom. He did not mention these peyots but it seemed
            to be, this is one make a strays the Indian way, make fun of it, and
            these use peyots. They said they are worshiped God but it is not
            just pretend. These stray band are always looking for trouble, that
            where most come from Indian trouble everywhere, men or women, even
            their children. Indian base ball team play with Garden Valley teams
            last Sunday. The score was 9 to 6 favor red skin and also the
            Indians have girl team. If you want see them to play this team bring
            some girls regular team or pickup. The Indian reporter is right now,
            except hearing. Mr. M. E. Gorman will be here 20th of this month, at
            Indian Mission, 8 a. m. He will have quite a few case Indian land
            business, and also some other business too. Those who want to help
            them next Sunday, they will prepare for next a few days, and men and
            women. They will have big meeting next Sunday. They are all anxious
            to do these all who belong to this church, and young people are just
            for lots of people to see, but some of them they want to hear
            preaching the words of our Lord Jesus Christ. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
