<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M11D01</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> They thinking about axes by this time of season of
            the year, or chop­ ping wood, and not I mean Mr. Ho­ mer Wood. Mr.
            and Mrs. Tom Kingswan and Mrs. Kingswan mother, Mrs. Helen Rusell,
            they make quick trip last week to Winnebago Reservation, Nebras­ ka.
            A baby boy was born to Mr. and Mrs. John Smoke at Tomah Indian
            hospital, Oct. 24, 1939. There are another smoke come up Tomah
            Indian settlement. Our enrollment is now 55 pupils. Mr. Eubank from
            Tomah called at school on Thursday and Supt. Farver on Friday. The
            pupils entertained with tonettes music in the upper room and singing
            of nursery rhymes in the lower room. Exhilda Snowball is taking a
            rest in the Tomah hospital. She is on the gain, which we are pleased
            to hear. The Hotonga school is making mon­ ey. They have a “Peep
            show” of the landing of Columbus. Any one wish­ ing to take a peep
            must pay five cents. Our bank shows 30 cents for this past week. The
            pupils in Mrs. Olson’s room are putting on this pro­ ject. Miss
            Amundson and Mrs. Ol­ son gave their pupils a Hallowe’en party last
            Friday. Two witches were in the basement telling fortunes. Up­
            stairs was given to games, song, con­ tests and races. Each winner
            would receive a prize. The pupils were treat­ ed to Hallowe’en
            candy, gum and candy bars. Many balloons were fly­ ing around. Such
            a good time. Miss Keppenhan is teaching the life of Abraham in the
            one hour set aside for this instruction every week. The pupils are
            very interested, each one now has a note book. Every Satur­ day she
            had story hour at 10 o’clock. The boy scouts have been sanding Miss
            Keppenhan floor. They like the work so much. We are planning to see
            the girl scouts get organized this week. We have much to be thankful
            for. The Indian report has a letter from one of his friend at
            Galesville as fol­ lowing: Charles R. Low Cloud, Indian Report Black
            River Falls Indian Mission Dear Friend in Christ Jesus: We read in
            the Indian news what you say of “U. S. of America” has too many
            missionary sent out from here to whole world and quite a dif­ ferent
            churches or different nomina­ tion religions. Still never use any­
            thing true and just as same politics, they called money talking.
            They can not use anythings the true.” It is indeed true what you
            have said. We try to exalt ourselves instead of exalting Jesus
            Christ. He says “And if I be lifted up his name lifted high by the
            preachers of his word” “shall draw all men unto me”. People are not
            being draw to Jesus today because they look to some man instead of
            looking at Jesus. They don’t know how to look to Jesus be­ cause no
            one tells them. We must humble ourselves and confess that we are
            sinners, no matter how much or how little money or high position we
            have because God word says “If we say we have no sin we deceive our­
            selves and the truth is not in us.” If we confess our sins He is
            faithful and just to forgive us our sins, and to cleanse us from all
            unrighteousness. I John 1:8-1. Also Jesus says “This is my
            commandment, That ye love one another as I have loved you. Greater
            love hath no man than this that a man lays down life for his
            friend.” John 15:12 to 13. A man lay down his life his friends, when
            he lay down his own work or his way of making a living and spends
            all his time and strength telling others the way of eternal life
            through Jesus Christ our Lord. The lord has been calling us to leave
            our work and worldly possession and work for our heavenly Father
            helping show sinners the way of salvation for about a month we have
            felt that the lord would be pleased for us to go to the Hunter
            Bridge camps and tell the In­ dians there some of the good things
            the Holy Spirit has shown us out of the Bible. Upon seeing what you
            wrote in the news we thought per­ haps you would like to have us
            come to Indian Mission. We love the In­ dians. They are our brothers
            and sis ters. They treat us better than we do them. They show us the
            golden ruler where we do not to them. If you would like to have us
            come up there next Sunday telephone Vincent Bros, at Galesville, and
            we will pay for the call. If you would rather wait until some later
            day, write us. Ask God in prayer what would be his will for Your
            Brother and Sister in Jesus, you to do. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
