<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M01D25</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>The month of February, the Indians they have already now since we have new moon and we
            have cold spell last two days. Mrs. John Stacy, her daughter Tillie and her son Alvin
            Stacy went to Greenwood last Monday and return to home same day. Our school teacher,
            Mrs. Olson, she report the school children had examined the eye. The two eye doctors
            came and inspected the children, not one poor eye in the whole bunch. Mr. Dubank a state
            supervisor, was here at school Monday afternoon and he went from here to Indain Mission
            school at Neillsville and from there to Green Bay. Mrs. Clarence Monigar and children
            spent the week end at the home of her parents home here at Indian Mission, Mr. and Mrs.
            John Stacy. Dr. Leo Srole of Chicago was here again last Sunday night and he will be
            round here for a while to study Indian way, and he has been acquainted with the Indians
            quite a few already. We understand Tomah the Indian school is trying to get started
            Indian school again next few months from now, and we will be glad to have start at any
            time from now because they spent lots of Indians money on this Indian school and Indian
            hospital too, and Mr. Merlin Hull is one look after this thing. He is one always to push
            along with his own territory in Wisconsin. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
