<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M08D16</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Jim Maney of Winnebago, Nebraska, who here to visit
            relatives and friends, he says he like to stay here at Indian
            Mission. Those same people like to read the Indian News promised to
            pay a year, Henry Johnson o f Greenwood, Wis., Mr. and Mrs.
            Winnesheick of Wau­ paca, Wis. Indian pow-wow at Oakwood park
            Merrillan was attended by many peo­ ple white and Indians. Much was
            said about it being the best ever staged on those grounds. The Chip-
            pewas of Hayward presented our Winnebagoes a drum in view o f mut­
            ual friendship between these people. Archery contest was won by
            Winnebagoes over B. R. club by narrow margin of three points. The
            colored Brown Cubs won over North Branch 24-3. The Indian girls lost
            the soft ball game to Merrillan boys. The paid attendance was much
            lower than former years but it was a success. In work out game
            Saturday the Piney Woods Cubs beat our Indian team by 2 -0 . The
            Indians are all finished pow­ wow first of the Black River Falls
            Indians their own pow-wow ground seven miles northeast of Black
            River Falls and week after that Pittsville pow-wow and after that
            week after for Merrillan pow-wow that was last Friday, Saturday and
            Sunday, and another week after at Tama, Iowa, next Friday for three
            days. Some Indians are not com e back picking blueberries at north.
            Still some are just begin ripe now. Henry Johnson o f Greenwood,
            Wis. came down to see the pow -wow at Merrillan last Sunday and had
            car trouble so he had to stop at Indian Mission last Monday and
            Tuesday. Mrs. Old Man Thunder Cloud pass­ ed away Sunday evening,
            7:15, 1939, She has been sick last few years. She never get well.
            She was born at Bear Bluff in Jackson county, 1866. Ever since she
            lived in Jackson coun­ ty, only one year Mr. William A. Hunder
            trying to remove all o f W in­ nebago Indians at Nebraska, some o f
            them went there return to Wisconsin a year after. She went there and
            came back again. She was loving children and not only children but
            every one who met her. She never drink any liquor, even she never
            drink beer. Everybody know her and who ever com e to her place she
            is kindly w ay everybody. She had large family and her own son and
            daugh­ ter Adam Thunder Cloud, Mrs. Eliz­ abeth Thunder Cloud
            (Hall), Mrs. Florence Thunder Cloud (Funm aker) She had many
            grandchildren. The sympathy goes to her husband, Thun­ der Cloud and
            her son and daugh­ ters, nieces and nephews, and one brother, Sam
            Carly at New York somewhere. Merrillan pow -wow was report very
            good. Chippewa Indians are as following nam e: Paul Carrol, Will­
            iam Barber, George Jackey, James Hart, John Mustashe sr., John Mus-
            tashe Jr., John P. Cloud, William Bi- sonette and Louis White.
            Everybody had en joy themselves while is go­ ing on this pow-wow.
            Indian report see the Merrillan pow-wow last Sunday afternoon. He
            saw Mr. and Mrs. George Root o f Clarion, Iowa. It seemed very nice
            people and also he meets Ole Nelson of York, one of store keeper.
            The Indian reporter has a new friend of Mr. William B um ice o f
            Fairchild. They will study among Winnebago tribe Indians, make a
            his­ tory if they can. We are very glad to see him again, Hon.
            Merlin Hull com e back again from Washington, D. C. Perhaps everyone
            were very glad to see him. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
