<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M11D08</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Mr. and Mrs. John Stacy and their daughter Tillie
            went away yesterday. Mr. and Mrs. Jesse Brown came back from
            Bennett’s marsh last Mon­ day and stop at Indian Mission going back
            to De Soto, Wis., yesterday. Mrs. Trask, girl scout captain from
            Black River Falls, spoke to the girls Friday morning. We are
            planning in organized a girl scout troops. Mon­ day evening ten of
            the young women and girls meet at Mrs. Keppenhan apartment, to
            organized a girl Re­ serve Y. W. C. A. group. This pro­ gram will be
            social, educational, home and arts and service. Our community house
            will be fin­ ish in about three weeks. Then we can carry on an even
            larger program. Mrs. Trask with Kathleen Horswill and Donna Mae
            Quackenbush came out to our school and gave a talk on girl scout
            work. It was very inter­ esting and our girls plan on doing a favor
            in return. The boy scout were organized with a bang. Two men from La
            Crosse gave us a start. We meet again Wednesday afternoon. Henry
            Greengrass and Indian re­ port went to Merrillan last Satur­ day
            looking deer rifles at Merrillan. It seems cost a little bit too
            high for that old timers gun. Chief Moses Paquette has receiv­ ed a
            dog collar last Friday and some­ body got the dog, but he did not
            want dog collar. Whether you believe or not. Miss Ruth Zodtner has
            resigned her position as director of relief of­ fice in Jackson
            county. In place is Mr. William McGraene of Darling­ ton, and Miss
            Ruth Zodtner did not love her position, but instead of that she love
            a man. The congress and senate make re­ lief money is appropriation
            for the needy of the Human being, to sent out all of United States,
            from Wash­ ington D. C. and sent out to every state, and state
            officers sent out some every county, and county sent out some every
            town chairman and those chairman his district refuse relief aid to
            some that are real need. Maybe he can not see that when he has full
            stomach only his own relatives. Indian report has received one Re­
            publican paper from Galesville which he says,— The “Indian report”
            may have gone cranberrying last week or duck hunting or somethings,
            anyhow his column didn’t show up in the Black River Falls
            Banner-Joumal, From which it is clipping by the Re­ publican each
            week. This was true, was not there the Indian News Oct. 25, 1939,
            but we brought some In­ dian news too late, all filled up the paper.
            John Simplot working on plaster a new houses a few weeks ago. He is
            looking round at Indian Mission this morning or may be work. John is
            good mason work, he is old timer. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
