<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M04D12</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>There are many Indians visitor the Indian hospital
            this week and last week. George Green has been here some time ago,
            and he is going back home last Monday. Bad news Susan Smith was here
            last week. One of her daughter ser­ ious ill and she passed away
            last Fri­ day. She took her home last Sunday noon train. At
            Wittenberg, Wis. and also her husband is sick too, and this girl was
            almost full grown. She was nice girl. The sympathy is goes to her
            parents to Mr. and Mrs. Edwin Smith. The Indian Mission church is
            sixty years old. There are many Indians and whites were gather
            together here week ago last Sunday. Rev. Ben Stucki of Neillsville
            is one take charge of meeting and he is one preaching in the morning
            and some other high officer from the other city or the other state.
            There are announcement was made. There will be 14 of next months.
            They will celebration for this re­ formed church sixty years. They
            are going to have big meeting and feast- able too, and they are all
            welcome whoever come. Redskin and white. We will tell more about
            next week. The Indian report enter the hos­ pital third time in this
            winter, April 3, 1939. He had earach. He cannot hear anything about
            4 days. Pretty hard for him and April 2, Sunday, evening went to see
            Doctor Irwin Krohn, but it don’t do any good. Mr. Alvin Stacy next
            morning brought it down to the hospital. Old friend Mr. William
            Whitney of Knapp we had a letter from him and card. The letter was
            pretty good hand writing. Mr. Whitney and his daughter Grace. We
            knew him more than 30 years and when we use to live at Millston know
            him well. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
