<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M08D09</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Merrillan Indian pow-wow will commence next Friday,
            Saturday and Sunday. Some Indians are not coming back at North,
            picking blueberries. Jesse Stacy, Fred Kingswan, Daniel La Mere was
            here two days and went back again, we cannot mention all of them.
            Mrs. Grace D. White Gull went to see her mother at Tomah Indian hos­
            pital last Monday. Report is not very well, she getting worse of her
            ankle swell up and she says she afraid to get blood poison if they
            don’t use right kind of medicine. Mr. and Mrs. John Painter o f W
            in­ nebago, Nebraska, and Ruth Four Closed were here week ago last
            Mon­ day at Wisconsin Dells to see the In­ dian Pageant, and they
            come down to see Pittsville pow-wow last week and he went back to
            Wisconsin Dells yes­ terday. He says too much for him, too many
            Indians pow-wow in here this country. Henry Young of Winnebago, Neb­
            raska, was here some time ago to visit relatives and friends. There
            are many talking about pol­ itic and lots of things never think
            about them but near another election coming so they are prepare the
            things they will have a nominate paper, car license, lots of things
            license going on this country and lots of different pension.
            Pittsville pow-wow they are all en­ jo y themselves and end of that
            day some are not. The Indians pow-wow when first beginning they
            don’t call that, they used called Home com ing at Winne­ bago
            reservation, Nebraska, during Civil war 1863 at that time, our gov­
            ernment call some Indians to help white soldiers. Indian leader is
            his name Priest, at Nebraska, and when this war was over they all
            come home and they want appoint day in mid­ summer day. They will
            have a good time, play just as any things they do pleasure, during
            that and some they added in­ side some different perform , men, wo­
            men, boys and girls races, or horse race and two or three years they
            add all kinds dances, and also they brought it down here in
            Wisconsin Winnebago last 40 years ago. Mrs. Thunder Cloud passed
            away Sunday evening, 7 :15, at Indian Mis­ sion. We will have
            obituary next week. She is 73 years old. Indian report has been many
            times they come to him, ask why the Indian they don’t give them
            relief. A t present some of them need o f those who do not give a
            job. He told them what he know, or what he found some the old letter
            from Madi­ son high officer, one of district at­ torney of Sparta
            ask if they had right to the Indian relief. The following answered.
            He has been explained to them and have in publish in Banner-
            Journal. Copy July 13, 1933. William Gleiss, district attorney,
            Sparta, Wisconsin) Indian are entitled to aid under poor relief
            statutes. The question is answered in the affirmative. The statutes
            provides that every town, village and city and county where the
            county board has abolished all distinctions between county poor and
            town, village and city poor, pursuant to SKC 49.15, state, shall
            relieve and support all poor and indigent persons lawfully suited
            therein whenever they stand in need thereof.” Sec. 49.01, state, the
            word “ person” as used in the statutes is a broad term and includes
            all, whether citizens or aliens and whether belonging to the white,
            red, black, yellow or brown races, and they are entitled to relief
            under chap­ ter 49 of the statutes even though they are transients,
            Sec. 49.03, the law makes no distinctions as to races, color, age or
            sex, and is intended to provide for the relief of all such per­ sons
            found anywhere in the state who are actually indigent and in need of
            such relief. Sec. VIII op. Atty., Gen. 659, where it ruled that the
            widow o f a deceased Winnebago In­ dian was entitled to receive aid
            on account of the surviving dependent children of the decedent under
            the so-called mothers pension law. Franklin E. Bump, Asst. Atty.
            Gen. Approve Robert M. Bieser, Deputy Attorney General. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
