<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>C39M05D17</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> Chief White Wing of Dancing, was here last Sunday to
            see his relatives and friends. Henry Johnson of Greenwood, Wis., was
            here last Sunday to see the big meeting. Belle Stacy and her sister,
            Mrs. Nat Decorah of Wittenberg, Wis., were here to see sixtieth
            anniversary festival at old Winnebago Indian Mission church. Mr. and
            Mrs. Ed Wilson of Wis­ consin Rapids were here to see big meeting
            and also to see relatives and friends. Mr. and Mrs. George Lonetree
            of P ttsville, were here to see the meet­ ing and one of his girl
            baptized in this meeting. Mrs. Lena Long Thunder has been sick last
            few months and she had sore eyes, pretty bad. They took her at Tomah
            Indian hospital last Saturday evening. Indian Mission school at
            Neillsville hold 350 sit it all filled up, some 45 or 50 children
            and the tent to had 105 children and this school had all the name on
            this writing. There are many Indians and white people came over to
            see the sixtieth anniversary festival held meeting last Sunday. We
            have no room for to put standing and Rev. Benjamin Stucki some other
            says about almost 500 peo­ ple gather together to see each other,
            some had not seen for long while. Even some of them never see each
            other, they meet right here and every body had enjoy themselves,
            young or old. This mission had big time. They had dinner and supper
            too, about 500. Rev. Ben Stucki make a program, he did not put all
            name on, this pro­ gram, some of they they were here when time come,
            as following: Rev. Walter Stuckey, of La Crosse, Wis.; Rev. Victor
            Weidler, Humbird, Wis.; 'Rev. Wilson Bixler, Neillsville, Wis.; Rev.
            Jason Hoffman Waukesha, Minn, and Rev. Walter Pugh, East Peters­
            burg, Pa. Forenoon Scripture reading John 1:26-37 Alvin Stacy
            English and John Stacy read by Indian language. Prayer Sing hymn
            Address Liceatiate D. W. Decorah Evangelist John Stacy Mr. Decorah
            he take the words Mark 8-18 “Having eyes, see ye not, and having
            ears, hear ye not and do ye not remember. He says since beginning of
            this church 60 years ago and Jacob Hou­ ser was preaching to
            Winnebago In­ dian and Rev. Jacob Stucki sr. was pastor for
            Winnebago Indians and he says this 60 years they ought to know
            somethings, but they have eyes to see the things, do not know what
            it was, and they have ears to hear the things, do not remember what
            it was, and eyes, ears and heart they do not use right way, to use
            we should Mr. Stacy said 60 years ago first be­ gin to build a log
            house school. When Rev. Jacob Houser talk to the Indians he told
            them they don’t pay anythings to teacher these young people, so they
            are all agree with him to help him to this logs house. Indians come
            down with their own axe to cut the trees down and trims off. They
            cut just as long as he wished to. Mr. John Sta­ cy was there to
            witness these things were done when he was a little boy. Rev. Walter
            Pugh, East Peters­ burg, Pa., is one making picture, and he takes
            everythings while lots of In­ dians and white people. This man is
            traveling everywhere. The first Winnebago Christians as following
            name: John Stacy, Martha Stacy, David Decorah, King of Thun­ der and
            George Lowe. These are old member this reformed church, and this old
            Indian Mission church. We had Indian News last week and Winslow
            White Eagle had complained about it but is gone already, we can not
            take it back again. We will not say anything any more. This was old
            story from “Old Dandy”, he is last Winnebago Indian prophet. Last
            Sunday had some young peo­ ple baptism and confirmation the
            following: Naomi Shegonee, Jenny Mae Falcon, Alfred Oliver Stacy,
            Vi­ vian Kingswan, Freida Stacy, Rebec­ ca Lonetree, Marian Vera
            Stacy, Clifford Lowe, Marie Ann Stucki Raymond Lowe, Lillian Thunder
            Cloud, Lona Mallory, Mary Waukon Edith Pettibone, Anabelle
            Winneshiek and Germaine Russell. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
