<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M10D05</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Duck hunting pretty good and most people that go hunting get
            ducks first day. This week I want to tell white people about good job I have one time
            and all time 1926 work for Minnehaha Arrowhead Hosiery company and travel all over
            everywhere and go to Kenosha, Superior, Racine and I can’t tell all places and go to
            different town every week all time from one winter to next winter and go to just big
            towns and work all time for whole year in store window. White people come by window and
            stand long time and watch me make bow and arrow and some time make tom-tom. First time I
            go I take Ford touring car and car break down and white boss get pretty mad when I get
            there second day and not there on time and he give me tickets on railroad and tell me
            next time you take train and if I am late he get new Indian to sit in store window. I
            like job like that and meet people and everybody that time call me chief. White man beat
            Indians this year when have contest cranberry raking Wisconsin Rapids and first time for
            long time. Next year Indians make things different I bet you and Indians always best
            rakers and been that way for long time. Cranberry season just about over and only three
            four more days and all through next week. Butts and other fellows tell everybody about
            black geese that roost in three at lake and people at Wolcovasky tavern want Indian
            reporter to tell about bird white fellows call black geese and I go to lake and Indians
            call them fish ducks and Indian reporter hasn’t seen fish duck for long time. Fish duck
            is only bird Indian reporter ever know that has web foot like goose and roost in tree
            like hen. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
