<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M11D16</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Tuesday I take Indian News to town and I tell you look pretty
            much like Indian summer and every year about this time November have Indian summer and
            stay two three weeks and every time come right after new moon. In 1907 Indian reporter
            remember pretty warm Indian summer and I go to hunt deer with other Indians Jackson
            county and I hunt all time with just shirt and no coat and go bare head and I get pretty
            hot too and just like summer. That time everybody can have two deer and don’t make any
            difference which kind of deer you get and does pretty good to eat. Indian don’t have to
            have license then and go any county and shoot deer. Then only just few hunters and
            plenty deer for everybody to get deer and now just like war in woods when season open
            deer and all fellows form city come out and shoot deer and pay just same license like
            people that feed deer on their farms and Indian reporter don’t think that fair. Saturday
            I come to Tomah to give Indian news and go to newspaper and nobody there to take news
            and all go to football game and I wait long time and I get pretty mad after I come all
            way to town and can’t give news. Saturday I get mad and I tell fellow to tell Kenny I
            quit and I don’t write Indian news for him any more. Then I have car and battery no good
            and I have to have new battery and Tuesday I bring news to town and like you say I am
            Indian reporter again so I can get money to buy new battery. Kenny good fellow and when
            I get mad and I tell him I quit and he laugh and say “maybe I have to get Charley Low
            Cloud to write Indian News.” Put it in that way just like I say. Ruthe Lowe that was her
            name before she marry Jim Yellow Bank, and she was sister of Albert Lowe and last week
            she died at Madison hospital. Lots of people here know her and Friday they bury her at
            Mission. Tuesday I meet and shake hands at Cash Store with two women that used to live
            in Tomah and work in lady hat store by cash store south on corner and now they live at
            Baraboo and names Mrs. Helen Moore and Mrs. A. Hornish. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
