<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M05D25</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Last week had pretty bad time when come to town to ride Otto
            Franz horse in big parade. First place had feathers and Indian clothes and horse didn’t
            like it very much and when stop parade to let people that come slow catch up horse got
            pretty wild and don’t like to stand still and make lot of trouble. I though throw me off
            but I ride like when I was young fellow in circus and stay on horse and he go up on hind
            legs and get me over in bushes and get head feathers caught in brush and have pretty bad
            time for a while and horse go to barn and leave parade. Maybe horse go mad because band
            long way back and people didn’t know horse and Indian reporter was in parade. Everything
            too much stretch out and should have band first thing in parade – like circus parade and
            then horse hear music and like to be in parade and don’t run to barn - like Indian
            reporter have last Thursday. Next time reporter come to town early and tell Libke where
            to have band in parade and want different horse too. I told you before about no more
            frost this year and last night was outdoors and saw night hawk and that sure Indian sign
            that frost all over and never have anymore harm from frost this year. Indian always wait
            for night hawk before plant things that frost hurt and do same thing every year and
            never been fooled yet. Indian reporter want to tell folks that wet moon going to be here
            on May 25 and Indian signs show going to have plenty rain in June. Indian wet moon is
            tip like show on calendar for May 25 and white man say same thing dry moon. Indian say
            moon tip like man bend over to keep rain off face and chest like when out in rain and
            stoop over like. White man say same moon dry moon because bottom of moon tip up like and
            water can’t run out and won’t have any rain much when moon is like that. Indian reporter
            watch this for long time and pretty near every time white man wrong and May 25 moon
            going to be wet and have more rain. Joe Christman tell Indian reporter give me good suit
            of clothes if I make it rain and say other farmers do same thing because everything
            awful dry and grass all burn up. Some Indian tribe all go to one place and pray and sing
            and beat tom-tom and Winnebago just go one Indian by himself and face west on high hill
            and sing and beat tom-tom and that way make rain. Maybe Indian reporter take Joe
            Christman up on suit only one day had to have money for gas and sold tom-tom to
            Siderstrom big boss at Light and Power Company for $3 and now he have tom-tom and when I
            see Joe Christman I tell him maybe Soderstrom go out on high hill and beat tom-tom and
            sing song and make rain for farmers. Was out in woods one day just walking around and
            saw only about half different kinds of birds I used to see. Saw lots of snakes and come
            on to big pines snake and follow him and watch where he go and pretty soon he go into
            bunch of dead grass and I go up and don’t make any noise and see him take three eggs
            from bird nest and that’s one thing why we don’t have many birds anymore and only way to
            get rid of snakes that eat birds eggs and kill young birds is to have bounty and then
            people go out in woods and kill snakes. Another thing I want to tell is about poison
            that people put out to kill grasshoppers. Same year that everybody put out poison see
            lots of dead birds and pretty sure poison kill birds too. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
