<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M06D22</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Fred Stutzke not very smart fellow about moon and things like
            that when he tell about Indian reporter say in Indian News that going to have rain 25th
            May and that new moon going to be wet moon and have lots of rain in June and Stutzke say
            Indian reporter don’t know and say all humbuga. Everybody laugh in spring when I tell
            folks about no more winter and now everybody say Frisk Cloud pretty smart fellow and
            know what weather going to be some time better than fellow that tell in big newspaper
            every day like everybody read about what weather going to be. Here is some news I want
            to have put in Indian News that people give me to put in Indian News for paper. Same
            people give me news to put in Indian News for paper. Same people give me news to put in
            paper once before and girl didn’t put in paper and if not in this time I quit and don’t
            write Indian News for you. People get pretty sore when write news and then don’t put in
            paper. Winnebago Indians from all over Wisconsin are getting ready to go to Wisconsin
            Dells for the opening of Stand Rock Indian Ceremonial July 1st. Five members of the Zuni
            Tribe are driving to Wisconsin to join the Winnebago group at Stand Rock. Chief Silver
            tongue, Indian tenor, has returned from a winter in Florida to again sing at the
            Ceremonial, having been with this organization for the past ten years. Joseph Johnson,
            from Black River Falls, will also fill a singing engagement at the Dells this summer.
            Frisk Cloud, his wife and Curtis Red Bird, his grandson, are visiting his daughter, and
            son-in-law, Mr. and Mrs. Sam Frogg at Hayward. Frisk and his wife are very proud of the
            new grandson in the Frogg family. Jackson County did bad thing for Indian when county
            board make law that say Indians can’t sell baskets on highway unless get license and pay
            county 25 cents and it’s just like I tell before in Indian News about license for
            everything now times all humbug. Jackson County make Indians that live in Jackson county
            pay tax to sell baskets that they make themselves and won’t give license to Indians that
            don’t live in Jackson county. Indians that live in other counties and don’t have any big
            road like Highway 12 come to Indian reporter and tell me to tell in Indian News about
            that Indians can’t get work and try to make living making baskets and sell to tourists
            and about Jackson county say nobody but Jackson county Indians can sell baskets on
            highway in Jackson county and Indian reporter don’t think it right too. Ed Funmaker one
            fellow that come to Indian reporter and he come from La Crosse and always sell Indian
            baskets on highway 12 in Jackson county and county board tell him you can’t sell Indian
            baskets in Jackson county because he live in La Crosse county. Other Indians come to
            Indian reporter and tell same thing. This week come to town two times to give Indian
            News to newspaper. Come to town Saturday and maybe didn’t feel very good after dance all
            night at Indian dance and forgot to tell some things I want to say. First thing I want
            to tell folks about big Indian dance. Indians come from all over-Wisconsin Rapids,
            Wisconsin Dells, Mauston, Neillsville, Baraboo, Black River Falls and Melrose and maybe
            other place I don’t know where from. All come to Indian settlement between Watermill and
            Valley Junction and have big dance and feast and dance two nights all night and don’t
            sleep till morning and me and some other fellows don’t sleep next day and that make me
            pretty tired and can’t stand it and I want to tell you can’t dance like young chicken
            when 64 like I was last May. Second night, that was Saturday night, Kenny and his wife
            and Ninneman, fellow that have furniture store by Vaudell’s and his wife come out to see
            big Indian dance and want to find Indian reporter and don’t dance and just watch Indians
            dance. When Indian reporter come back to Settlement ground next day people tell me about
            them there and I want to tell folks why I go home early and don’t stay at dance. Bob
            Henry deputy sheriff at Tomah come out to Indian dance and take fellows that dance too
            much to town and lock them up in caliboose and next day turn them loose and I tell
            fellow maybe Bob Henry think I dance too much too and take me and put me in caliboose
            and they take me home and I went to bed and had good sleep. When fellow 64 dance all
            night till sun come up and roosters crow in morning and next day don’t go to bed he look
            pretty bad some time and maybe Bob Henry think I look same thing like fellow that drink
            moonshine and he never been like that and think take me to caliboose. First night two
            fellows like you call business men come out to dance and dance all night till rooster
            crow and dance same dance like Indians and have lot of fun but Indian reporter not tell
            names because they tell me don’t put this about us in Indian News or maybe our wives
            scalp us. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
