<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M09D14</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Last week Indian reporter got in pretty bad when he tell in
            Indian News about going to have medicine dance at Watermill place Saturday night and
            some Indians got pretty mad and tell Indian reporter way I put in paper look like
            everybody could come and don’t want any white people and bawl me out pretty bad.
            Government orders say only for Indians that belong to medicine lodge and no other
            Indians wanted and no white people too. They tell Indian reporter about going to put up
            big sign that tell no white people wanted and just Indian medicine lodge and it going to
            be that way next time, Saturday night Indians going to have medicine lodge dance at
            Black River Falls. War look pretty bad and everybody talk about it and some time people
            tell about America maybe have to fight too. Indian reporter remember last time have war
            and lot of people killed that time too and people come to Indian house where people live
            and put finger at young Indian fellow and say you got to go in war and go to Europe
            where they never been and don’t tell him and he don’t know what war is about and have to
            go and do same thing. Indian reporter want to say white man all time about bad Indians
            kill in war long time back and want to make Indian do same thing like smart fellow white
            man and then have war and kill people and I don’t think very smart when make young
            fellows go to war and get killed and don’t know what was is about. I want to say one
            thing pretty sure when Indian kill long time back and have war just same thing like this
            and Indian know what war is about too and white man school all time talk about make
            Indian smart like white man. Indian in this country all everybody happy and don’t want
            to have war and Indian reporter think same thing too and I want to tell it to folks like
            that. Next thing I want to tell folks pretty soon Winnebago Indians everywhere
            Wisconsin, Minnesota, Iowa go to La Crosse and have big Indian dance and help white man
            name new bridge that go over Mississippi river and same think like have name for baby
            and call it “Blackhawk” bridge and have bridge open same time and going to be 23rd
            September. Grace Redman and Herbie from Wyeville go to Indian hospital and Grace return
            to home and he stay there and doctor tell him why don’t get well pretty quick. Indians
            all over everywhere rake cranberries now and people tell Indian reporter why don’t rake
            cranberries and don’t know I have bad heart and doctor tell me not to do work like that
            and I rake cranberries when I was young fellow and every year until two three years ago.
            Curtis Redbird he is my grandson and Friday he go to Pipestone Minnesota and go to
            boarding school and leave from Indian hospital and six other boys go same time, two
            Oneida Indians and others all Winnebago. When he go away he tell me “You take care of
            yourself and if everything all o.k. I come home when have first vacation” and feel
            pretty bad and want to go to school pretty bad too. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
