<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M06D29</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>I want to say like this about how we pack up everything and
            go to Wisconsin Dells and I am part of Indian ceremonial at Stand Rock all summer and
            start on first July and don’t come home till after Labor Day. Sunday we pack up all day
            and go next day to Wisconsin Dells and just like vacation but I have to work little
            every night and get $1.50 every day for just little work at night. White man tell Indian
            reporter pretty soft for me go fishing all time every day and fishing pretty good at
            Wisconsin Dells some times when folks know where fish stay. Lots of people that come to
            ceremonial know Indian reporter and other fellows think that pretty funny when white
            people go by where I stand some time and give out papers and things like that and say
            Hello Frisk and we talk about things. There’s one thing I feel pretty bad about going
            away because maybe have trouble about getting Indian News to newspaper. I want to tell
            all you folks that I like to write Indian News and hope everyone like things I tell and
            don’t want to hurt anybody and some times tell just what I think about things and some
            time people say I don’t know and some time people get mad about things I say in Indian
            News and one fellow get pretty sore too but I tell you before and I want to say Indian
            reporter don’t want hurt anybody and just say things I think and some times just have
            joke. Maybe Indian reporter come to Tomah with fellows and give Indian News. Last summer
            I start to walk to Tomah and some time fellows give me ride and drive pretty fast and go
            by curves in road sixty seventy miles an hours and never go that fast until here few
            years ago and I get pretty scared when turn by curve and tires screech like hawk in
            night and make me think about bad wreck and people get hurt bad. Saturday Indian
            reporter had talk at Cash Store with tall fellow everybody call Fred and now live at
            Milwaukee and everybody know him when he was big boss at telephone place in Third ward.
            Fred great fisherman and sportsman and all time fish with flies and don’t use worms and
            every time catch fish and that’s what he tell every time. Now I want to tell joke about
            Fred and I want to say like this. Fred go long way up north and have camp and have
            Indian guide like I am guide some times at Dells and have guide show him where fish stay
            and Fred tell same thing himself and Indian not know he live here and fish all day and
            go lots of places and don’t catch fish. Fish long time and Fred tell Indian guide show
            me where fish bite and Indian guide say Tomah. Wisconsin best place to catch fish and
            next day come home and Indian reporter think same thing too. Fred tell Indian reporter
            at Cash Store about like Indian News and say read about Indian News first thing every
            week and other fellows tell me same time like thing I say pretty good too. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
