<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M08D17</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Tuesday come up to Tomah from Dells to give Indian News to
            newspaper and all people every place tell me want to have things I say about what
            Indians doing and like that in newspaper every week and Indian News first thing they
            read every time. If people want to see big ceremonial at Stand Rick where I work and
            part of program better come pretty soon because we only have three more weeks and them
            everything close up till summer come next year. Scott Mokey’s wife she been pretty sick
            for long time now and sometime awful bad but now she get better and pretty soon maybe be
            all o.k. again and that about all people that get sick form Tomah at Wisconsin Dells
            this summer and everybody else all feet pretty good. Hilda Smoke go to Tomah High School
            and finish school and everybody know her and three weeks ago she have operation at
            Indian hospital and get out of hospital about a week ago and all well again now. Indians
            that go to Indian hospital see Dr. Winter and people that work there and every time tell
            about get good care and pretty near every time get well too. Indian reporter make joke
            in paper one time when tell about go to hospital and just have glass rod put under my
            tongue and people don’t know I mean joke and get pretty sore and next time I make joke
            maybe I better tell like this “now folks this is joke and Indian reporter don’t want
            nobody to get mad at joke” and just want to make people have laugh about it. Philip
            Decorah little boy, been pretty sick too at Dells park and they take him to hospital at
            Tomah and he stay thee two three weeks but they tell Indian reporter that he come back
            to Dells Park and feel pretty good too and maybe be all right again now. Art Decorah go
            to Mauston one night this week and wrestle at fair grounds at Mauston. September 15
            Indians start to hand pick cranberries on Valley marsh and some going to rake too. Ben
            Cady is boss on cranberry marsh and he is good fellow and all Indians like to work for
            him. Ben Cady tell Indian reporter berry crop is going to be good and have lots of
            berries this fall and this helps Indian people too and helps them to get money to buy
            things to eat in winter time. Pretty soon I come back to Tomah to live and then I can
            write news about people everybody know and like I been at Wisconsin Dells people that I
            know about and can tell in Indian News nobody that reads paper knows and not very good
            news like I write when I stay here. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
