<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M08D24</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Last week Indian reporter drive to Tomah to give news to
            paper and everything fine on way to Tomah and have no trouble with car or anything like
            that. When two o’clock in afternoon we get car and start back to Dells because I want to
            be at Stand Rock for Indian ceremonial at night and have nine blow-outs on way home and
            just like gun go off every just few miles and flat tire all time and I got pretty mad
            after first two three times and have to stop and fix same thing. I tell that cat what I
            think in Winnebago talk and sometime don’t have right word to say in Winnebago and I use
            white man talk and I bet you I tell I am pretty mad. When we get back to Dells
            everything dark at Stand Rock and now all over and everybody sleep and 12 o’clock at
            night. This week I buy postage stamp and leave car under tree and not come to Tomah with
            news anymore. Friday night Robert Bruce who is Chippewa and play cornet and big shot
            that everybody know was at ceremonial and just about every night we have big shot people
            like that at our show and Indian reporter dance pretty good and think maybe some time
            fellow will tell me to come to Hollywood and have me dance in moving picture. Third
            September everything close up at Stand Rock and Winnebago Indians come to Tomah and
            Wisconsin Rapids and Mather and all around and help rake berries at cranberry marshes
            and Pueblo Indians return to states they come from and harvest things they raise there
            too. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
