<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M05D18</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>ndians all over country all tribes hear bad news about what
            white government talk about do with Indians. Trouble start over what Indian agency
            people call Wheeler-Howard Indian act and Indian reporter get papers and letter that
            tell all about it and say it means Indians have government by themselves and nothing to
            do with United Stated government and I want to tell folks that Wisconsin Winnebago
            Indians I talk to do not want anything to do with way that going break away from United
            States government and that Winnebago Indians like to live just same as ever and want it
            way it is now. Lots of Indians feel same way like Indian reporter but just keep still
            and don’t say anything and pretty soon maybe agency fellows come around and say
            everything all done and now you have government all own and gate to take care of
            yourself and can’t have any WPA work and can’t get any relief. Then tell all Indians you
            have to live in just few places and maybe like say Winnebagoes have to live on place
            like desert like between Tomah and Sparta or up Mather, Shennington way where no white
            people want to live. Then Indians can’t go place and kept in corral like bunch of wild
            goat and can’t move around and sell baskets and pick blueberries like Indians want to
            do. Second night frost get blueberries last week and vines all red and killed them.
            Frost killed blueberries and pretty bad for Indians that make some money in blueberry
            time. Maybe berries in matches not hurt so bad but on hills all killed. Same thing
            happen last year and about every year something happen to berries. Indian reporter was
            to Adams Saturday to see nephew and come back same night. People there never come here
            very often only when someone die or something like that and so go there to see them some
            times. Winnebagoes had big meeting at mission at Black River Falls Sunday and talk about
            own government and nothing to do with United States government. Some Indians from around
            here went but Indian reporter didn’t have license for car and too far to walk and nobody
            on highway give ride anymore. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
