<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M08D03</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Well, I tell you first thing, everybody of Tomah Indians at
            Wisconsin Dells all o.k. but Scott Mokey’s wife and she awful sick. They are down at
            Lake Delton where he work at Parson’s trading post. She been pretty sick now for about
            two weeks. Small Boy, that’s his name and I don’t mean he is little fellow from Black
            River Falls and he turn car quick and roll car over two three times and break his arm
            pretty close to elbow and hurt pretty bad. He go way up north and that’s when it
            happened. Tourists now going pretty good and lot more people than last year. Indians
            tell reporter that sell more baskets and people don’t say “too much money” every time
            squaw say basket $1.50. Indian Reporter and Chief Rain-in-the-face Soderstrom fix up
            rain pretty good last Thursday night. I didn’t talk to him but I put in Indian News
            about have him beat tom=tom and make rain and paper come out Thursday morning and
            Thursday night big rain that farmers like. Indian reporter was in Tomah Saturday and two
            fellows buy me drink for way I fix up rain and tell me next time don’t wait for such
            long time before fix up rain. I tell them tom-tom right here in Tomah and next time want
            rain go to Power company place and let him know about it and he fi it up all right, and
            have big joke and everybody laugh about beat tom-tom and shake rain out of clouds. This
            two times now we make rain like that and both times farmers need pretty bad. Indian
            reporter was in Cash Store Saturday and Arnold Schueler like what you call manager of
            boxing show Friday night at Fair tell me two Indians going to fight in show and one of
            them Myron Lowe of Black River. He tell me suppose I am going to be here for fight but I
            have to work at Dells that night and coming to fair Saturday night and broadcast to
            people that come to fair. People that run fair tell me lot of people want to see Indian
            reporter that write news in Tomah Journal every week, and I want to see all my friends
            and have talk to them. Friday night Indian Reporter have joke with people and talk like
            southerner right in middle of 250 people that come from Louisiana and they laugh and
            think big joke. That pretty long way to come to Dells. White Bear who is good singer and
            drummer at Stand Rock have bad news from home at Winnebago, Nebraska and have to go to
            home today because somebody pretty sick. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
