<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M12D28</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Everybody ask Indian reporter why I don’t have Indian news in
            paper two weeks and I get letters and say same thing. I was like what you call strike
            and don’t write news because newspaper boss all time want news and don’t give me enough
            money and I have to drive car to town and cost me money every time. Thursday we settled
            strike and here I am Indian News again this week and maybe after while I get more money.
            Kenny good fellow and we are friends and I help him out and write news about what
            Indians do like what people want to read in paper. Everybody tell Indian reporter about
            what I write best news in paper. Other day fellow ask me, I don’t know his name but he
            know me and always say Hi Frisk like that when I see him in town, and he ask me Frisk
            you are pretty smart fellow and maybe toy can tell me who got birthday last Monday
            Christ or Santa Claus. I tell you same thing like I tell him and I say I don’t know too
            sure. Churches all say Christ and store and everybody talk about Santa Claus and maybe
            he got birthday too same time. I think maybe he is adopt child and grow to old man long
            time back and everybody think he is same as Christmas and family have to moved into one
            of the Spooner houses in this neighborhood. Mr. and Mrs. Adolph Schultz or Adrian were
            visitors at the Sooner and Snowberry homes on a Sunday recently. Charles Spooner missed
            a few days of high school recently on account of a bad cold and sore throat. John Dennis
            called at the Rolls Vanervort home Sunday morning. The Madson family of Catarnet
            attended the school program and were accompanied home by their daughter, Marie, of
            Kirby. Mett Rose and daughter Marie of Kirby also attended the program. Several other
            from outside communities were there also, but the writer did not get their names. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
