<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M11D23</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Indian reporter get two letters today and one letter from Ben
            Cady who was boss at cranberry marsh Valley Corporation and tell about want to have
            paper go to Rockford where he now live and moved there. Everybody that work for Ben Cady
            think he is pretty good fellow and all Indian like to work for him and sorry when they
            hear he leave cranberry marsh. Other letter I got from Minneapolis fellow and his name
            Andrew Senerson and he want big picture of Indian reporter to have in frame and hang on
            wall and tell about have room in his house Minneapolis all about Indian and want picture
            of me to hang on wall. I have to write to him and tell Mr. Senerson I don’t have big
            picture like what he want and I send him little picture and maybe he can make it big
            picture like he want. Saturday first day to hunt deer and lot of Indian just same like
            me and don’t have any money to buy license and can’t hunt deer. Young Indian fellow tell
            me other day about he want to get license so he can shoot deer but don’t have money and
            take everything he make to buy things for family to eat and now can’t get job and nobody
            hire Indian to do work and pretty bad when good Indian young fellow can’t shoot deer to
            eat and all whole country was Indian S and all deer was Indian’s before white man come
            over here Europe and take all away from him and now when he don’t have white man money
            to buy license with tell him “you can’t kill deer or put you in jail.” Other day when
            Indian reporter over by rock cut between Tomah and Valley Junction on old railroad I see
            big track that look like cow track and I know deer track and two three days I go there
            and I see big buck but he wasn’t in same place but pretty sure same deer. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
