<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M10D26</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Girl at Wilton write to Indian reporter on post card and want
            me to tell about what happen to Indians today so she can tell same thing in school when
            teacher want to know about for school. Letters and cards come every week for Indian
            reporter and maybe I have to have girl and typewriter to write letters for me. I am
            Indian and I know what Indians think and I write letter and tell girl at Wilton about
            way we don’t like how things are fixed by white man and won’t let Indian live like he
            want to live. Indians long time ago used to have pretty good times and hunt and fish and
            nobody ever tell us you have to have license and same thing trap too. Indian man trap
            animals and squaw make things to wear to keep warm and all time have plenty to eat and
            nobody go hungry them times. Now white man have a law for everything and I used to make
            my own flying and now I can’t make living and have to get relief and other Indians too
            and lots of white people can’t make living and have relief. Pretty soon be season open
            for buck and maybe I get deer and then we have meat at our house. Last year I got no
            deer an when I go to get deer every time I just get skunk. Saturday I was in Cash Store
            and Fred Pietz stop on my foot and I tell him get off my foot and he say he have to step
            somewhere and when he step on my foot feel like elephant walk on me. Paper tell about
            government going to give Indian school to state and that make me feel pretty bad and do
            same thing with Hayward school and just same like they always do to Indian and take
            everything he have away from him and give to white man. When Compton run school at Tomah
            all Indian kids go to school and everybody happy and have good time and learn things
            that help them make living. Indian kids don’t like to go to white man school and want
            own school and then happy and have good time and play together. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
