<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M09D28</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>First thing I tell folks this week about big time we have at
            La Crosse Saturday and Winnebago Indians help have program when bridge open. Reporter
            for LA Crosse Tribune look me up Indian reporter and he ask me about what to call bridge
            and we have talk and I tell him best thing call bridge Winnebago bridge and he say
            that’s fine and going to tell people in La Crosse Tribune to call it that. Reporters for
            La Crosse paper and St. Paul papers and Minneapolis and another place in Iowa all come
            around where I am and everybody joke and have big laugh with Indian reporter. They tell
            me Indian reporter know all over United States and people go by and reporters say Hey!
            George, or Henry and like that and come over and meet Tomah Indian reporter and pretty
            soon everybody come around where I am and all people everybody tell me I am good
            reporter and lot of fellows write down name of paper where I write Indian news for and
            say they want to take paper to read Indian news I write. Reporter for Minneapolis paper
            tell Indian reporter he is coming here to see me and have talk with Kenny that I write
            news for and see if maybe I can write same thing for Minneapolis paper. I tell folks
            once before maybe some time I have desk in office like big shot white reporters and I go
            around places in airplane like fellows that come to La Crosse when bridge open. Duck
            season look pretty good for hunters this year and I want to tell about today Indian
            reporter see ducks on swamp and they stay around same place and I stand long time and
            watch them and I know pretty sure they not going to stay just little while and fly up
            and go away and when they do like that I know because I have been hunter long time duck
            hunting going to be pretty good. I tell you how I sneak up in weeds just like skunk go
            through weeds and don’t make noise and I get right up to where decks sit on water when I
            go way wind come from. I stay in swamp long time and kneel like and watch what ducks are
            doing and maybe white man fame warden pretty near too and all time watch Frisk Cloud and
            think maybe just when I sneak up on ducks in swamp and stay long time in swamp maybe I
            am going to shoot one to eat. I fool game warden and I wait until season open and then I
            tell you one thing pretty sure I get my share and I know good places to hunt and I have
            been hunter for long time. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
