<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M05D11</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Indian reporter have talk with Ranney, big fellow at ice
            cream factory, Saturday and talk it over about way water is not kept in new lake and let
            a water go over dam until weeds and snake grass get growing and make lake look pretty
            bad. Same thing last year and lake all full of weeds because let water out too long.
            Indian reporter walk out to lake and see water all stopped by dam and see lots of weeds
            and snake grass on south end of lake too. I know something myself and other fellows can
            tell same thing that if lake was filled up soon as ice melts, weeds and stuff like that
            won’t grow in water and won’t have swamp and march lake. Everybody talk about big party
            in Tomah on May 18 and fellows at Cash Store tell Indian reporter that Libke, manager of
            parade, want reporter to ride white horse and wear costume. I talk to Claude Dietzman in
            town Wednesday and can get white pony and everything fixed up all O. K. Monday fishing
            season going to open and all people around here going to see if they can catch fish.
            Indian reporter been fishing around her for long time back and I know myself fishing was
            pretty good till Oh about 10 years ago and now fisherman has to have own pond with signs
            everywhere that tell people “I am big rich fellow and I own pond and you can’t fish on
            my land: or can’t get any trout. Build dams in crick that belong to all people and hold
            fish on land and keep all fish for themselves and let other people catch just suckers.
            Indian reporter going to tell folks why cricks don’t have trout in like they used to
            have when everybody could go and catch fish and I going to them that four five years ago
            when everything dry and no rain cricks all get low and fish won’t hatch out eggs and
            fish die and lots of little ones too. Lots of people say it’s funny that people can’t
            catch trout anymore and Indian reporter tell them try summer like we have all them years
            spoil fishing. Maybe take long time to have lots of trout in cricks like there was long
            time back. Other day had talk with Indian fellow that worked with Indian reporter long
            time back for Herb Tuttle at cranberry marsh at Watermill and tell about work 10 hours
            every day and get $1.25. We work that time and get along fine and everything and save
            some money too and nobody ever get hungry. That time everybody work and have good time
            and government never send big truck to town and have big load of pears for people and
            everybody get relief. Today everything pretty bad and nobody feel very good. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
