<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M06D08</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>One of letters other day from farmer at Kendall and he tell
            about Indian reporter all wrong about when tell about grasshopper poison kill all birds
            and say bait for grasshopper all sawdust and only just little bit of poison and say
            birds won’t eat dead grasshoppers tat been poisoned and tell in letter that poison for
            gopher sand things like that do kill birds. Maybe Indian reporter wrong sometimes but
            not very many times but find lots of dead birds in woods. People tell Indian reporter
            about a baby girl born to Guy Redeagle and his wife at Indian hospital. I think Guy
            Redeagle pretty proud fellow to have baby girl. 25th June all Tomah Indians that dance
            at Wisconsin Dells in summer time go downs and do things and get ready for big
            ceremonial at Stand Rock and other places in summer and season start July 1. Some
            Indians stay at Stand Rock all summer and others return to home to help do things
            Indians all tribes do same dances together and come from all over country, Mexico, Texas
            and everywhere. Every summer people everybody know like Bing Crosby and movie people
            come to see Indians dance and hear Indian angers like Chief Silvertongue and maybe some
            time people come from long way off to hear Lavern Carimon and he one of singers there
            now last two years. Jim Smoke that everybody in Tomah know tell people all about it at
            show. Fred Stutzke tell about Indian reporter all humbug when tell in Indian News about
            moon and tell when going to be wet and what white man say same thing going to be dry
            moon. Indians know about rain by what moon look like long time back and maybe Mr.
            Stutzke know somethings about moon but Indian reporter show he was all right when he
            tell about going to have rain about 25th June and everybody tell you he was right too.
            Winnebagoes going to have some kind of dance at Hatfield sometime this month for Indians
            that were in war and hear people around Tomah talk about going to big dance. Always have
            big time at dance like that. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
