<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M10D12</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>This week letter come from Minneapolis and tell Indian
            reporter about woman want picture and want to know things about Winnebago Indians and
            tell about friends read in Tomah paper every week what Indian reporter say and like
            Indian News. Letters come pretty near every week and every time want same thing and
            Indian reporter pretty busy and grandson go away to school and don’t have time to write
            letter back. First news I want to tell this week about close season on mink, muskrat and
            skunk and just shoot and trap coon when season open this month 28th. I want season
            closed on coon too because we don’t have any coon around here and white man that make
            open season on coon don’t know it and he tell in book about go out and get coon at open
            season and look pretty foolish when tell you you can go out and get coon and fame warden
            not arrest you and take you to jail and take gun and traps and Indians know they don’t
            have coon around here. When have open season on coon I don’t stay here and get fooled
            and I go to 31st Street Chicago and get two-legged coon. Indian reporter want open
            season on skunk and mink and muskrat so poor Indians can make little money to live on in
            winter time and not so many people on relief when don’t have so many laws that tell
            hunters and trappers and everybody what they can’t do all time. If I can’t make living I
            go to poor house and white man that make foolish law make him keep me. My grandson
            Curtis Redbird come home room school at Pipestone, Minnesota, at Indian school for
            little awhile and pretty glad to see us too. Other day I talk to fellow at Sparts and he
            tell me pretty soon this country be in war too and all young fellows and all Indians too
            have to go and fight in war. Indians don’t’ want to have war and at meeting two three
            weeks ago all Indians ask about what is war about and nobody know what war is about and
            pretty soon they come around and put finger at young Indian fellow and tell him he have
            to go out and get killed for war he don’t know what is about. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
