<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M12D07</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Well Folks Indian reporter not such bad hunter and I get my
            deer too but I don’t get him with bow and arrow. I have to use rifle and I get nice deer
            with four wings on horn and I told people pretty sure I get my deer this year. After I
            shoot deer I see great big buck but I can’t shoot him because saw tell hunter he can’t
            shoot more than one deer, but I bet pretty sure on thing white fellow shoot deer I see
            before season open. Fellows in town tell Indian reporter pretty good joke and want me to
            put in Indian news. They tell me like this. Chet Burnstad he is tall fellow that work at
            Shitter store and August Schamens he now at barber shop and other fellow I don’t
            remember his name go deer hunting. Burnstad work at store so he is going to take lunch
            and tell other fellows you don’t need to take lunch and he will have some for everybody.
            Day before go hunting Burnstad’s wife go down town and get cornflakes and coffee and
            shirt for boy or things like that and have in basket and leave by door of house and next
            morning Burnstad get up early and think basket is lunch and put it in car and everybody
            go hunting. Noon fellow get pretty hungry and want to have some of lunch and Burnstad
            say “come and get it” like that and open basket and don’t know he have just package of
            coffee and cornflakes and boy shirt. I have to laugh pretty good when I heard that
            story. Same time they all tell me about Indian hunter and everybody want to tell me what
            I put in Indian News. They tell me his name but I can’t remember and I tell story like
            they tell me. Indian go out in woods to get buck and he shoot him and buck fall down and
            he run up and think he is dead and he tie on tag on him. They tell deer not dead and
            jump up and run through woods and Indian follow him and pretty soon hear gun go off and
            white man city fellow shoot his deer. Indian tell him about that is his deer and show
            him tag and white fellow say if you can run as fast as deer and put tag on him when he
            is running Indian should have buck. Woman at Wyeville write to Indian reporter and want
            to know things about Indian religion long time back and I tell he like I am going to
            say. Long time back Winnebago Indians like around Oshkosh and lots of red bank clay
            there and Indians think then that Great Spirit like we call God take red clay and make
            Indian. Same think with white man too only Great Spirit take white foam from lake there
            and make white man. Jess and Steve and Leo Brown all brothers and come from Desota to
            hunt deer and they all good friends of Indian reporter. Some more Indians come from La
            Crosse and they come to see Indian reporter too. Furs going to be pretty good for this
            winter and I think Indians that trap make pretty good money. Everybody tell me better
            trapping than other years. This week Indian reporter don’t hear much news and nobody die
            or get sick or have baby and like what you call news like other people write. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
