<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M09D21</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>First thing I want to tell this time is about all Indians go
            to La Crosse 23rd September to be at big pow wow when big bridge that go over
            Mississippi river open. Indian reporter want to go down to that and everybody tell me
            going to have good program and good time and Indians and white people go there. Mayme
            Frogg, she is my daughter, she come down to see us. She live on Hayward Chippewa
            reservation and come to our place Friday and go back to home this week some time. Her
            oldest boy going to school and her man go back to work WPA next week and have to return
            to home. She tell me lots of white people come to Hayward from Chicago and like that and
            have good time and fish in summer. Everybody catch lots of fish and I go there myself
            and every time catch fish. Not like fish like pollywogs and lizzards like people here
            think good fish- great big fish that fight pretty bad and pretty bad time to get out of
            water some time too. Pretty soon time to go hunting again and I go through woods last
            week and I tell you one thing quite a few pheasants and look like pretty good for
            hunters this year. Indian reporter know now where to find birds when white man law tell
            Indian he can shoot pheasant and I know pretty sure I won’t get skunked. Phil Bennett
            and Guy Potter have lot of Indians raking cranberries at marshes. Sunday Indian reporter
            at Guy Potter place and all time Indians pull in and come from all over Wisconsin
            Rapids, Melrose, Wisconsin Dells, and all around every place. Cranberries look good and
            white fellows that own marsh make some money and Indians that rake cranberries make
            money. Robert Big Thunder brought my brother’s girl to Indian hospital Sunday. She from
            Wittenberg and doctor tell her better come to hospital. She is my brother George girl
            and he is dead now and everybody around here knew him one time. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
