<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M06D15</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Indian reporter have to leave pretty soon and work at Indian
            ceremonial at Stand Rock at Wisconsin Dells and can’t write Indian News any more for
            Tomah paper for folks until after Dells close up after Labor Day. Maybe some time get
            ride to Tomah in day times and then tell girl at newspaper office things about Indians
            and then have Indian News in paper same like before go away. Go fishing last week two
            three times but fish don’t bite very good but mosquitoes they bit all time on neck and
            hands and not very much fun fishing and other fellow say same thing. Indians going to
            have another medicine dance at Dells Dam above Hatfield Saturday night all night and
            Sunday in day same as church medicine lodge. Old folks tell me anybody sick take him
            down there and get cured and believe that for long time back. Call it medicine dance and
            all clans meet there and talk together and have mumbler talk and just about same thing
            like white man call church. Now I going to tell about Indian medicine man and Indian
            peyote man. Winnebago not many don’t have anything to do with peyote man and all believe
            medicine man all right. Peyote man take what white man call whiskey bean that grow in
            Mexico and in that country and chew peyote and then act like drunk after drink strong
            moonshine and sometime make soup from peyote and drink soup and act same way. Then
            peyote man can see things other Indians don’t see and can tell what make him sick. Then
            maybe chew more peyote and tell him other things about get well and like that. Other
            people not only peyote man chew peyote and drink peyote soup and make them feel good and
            everybody feet nappy and think peyote man pretty good fellow until next day and then
            sometimes people come here and sell same thing to Indians and change one cent for bean.
            People tell about Indians in west about eat peyote and never sleep and most Indians kind
            of afraid to chew it. Strawberries don’t grow good this year and Indian reporter pick
            for Carl Jansen all day for eight hours and only pick 13 trays and make $1.17 and Jansen
            berries better berries than I see on other farms too. Indian reporter walk to town by
            Indian school today and make me think about time when I go to school there in 1893. Just
            go to school from February to April and Supt. Simmons kick me out. Then every Sunday let
            all boys and girls go down town to go to church and every Sunday me and other fellow and
            two girls go out long walk and never go to church and one Sunday when get back to school
            Supt. Simmons say did you go to church and I tell him no we went to Indian settlement
            along tracks near Tunnel City and he say Frisk you’re all done with school and you get
            out and don’t come back and Indian reporter never go to school anymore. First building
            at Indian school was what you call boy dormitory and then boys and girls all live in
            same building and first built in 1892 year before I go to school and get kicked out
            pretty soon. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
