<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M07D27</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>When Indians come through Wisconsin Dells always stop at
            Stand Rock and talk with friends and people stop this week and tell about pick
            blueberries up by Fairchild, Washburn, Iron River and tell Indian reporter season all
            over and pretty good berries there. I want to tell you one thing sure blueberries pretty
            good to have in winter time and another thing want to say when eat blueberries help
            rheumatism like people have and when Indian reporter eat them he dance just as good
            Indian dance as young buck and make him want to do things just like young fellow. Game
            warden around here don’t bother Indian when he fish and just catch fish to eat and up by
            Tomah every time Indian go near where people fish game warden jump out of brush and say
            “where your license” and then have to go to Sparta and judge tell you go to jail for 90
            days. Yesterday Indian reporter get three big fish and that night we have big fish feed.
            Tomah people come up to Indian reporter Sunday night at Indian ceremonial where I hand
            out cards and tell about have no rain since I come down here and want me to come back
            Tomah and make big rain like I do 25th May. I tell folks about how I sell Tom-tom to
            Soderstrom at Power Co. place and tell them I put it in paper this week about have
            Soderstrom beat tom-tom and sing song on high hill and make rain. In camp woman name
            Good Star Woman and been pretty sick. Yesterday she go out in woods to get some tobacco
            and over 80 years old and blind. She go out in woods with daughter and tells them what
            kind of trees when touch with hands and get one she wants for her tobacco. White man
            call tree willow and Indian call same thing Kinnikinnie. She take rough bark off tree
            and scrape stick and make pile of shavings and dry them and mix with tobacco for pipe.
            Good Star Woman come from Winnebago, Nebraska but she is Sioux Indian. Indian reporter
            glad to come back to Wisconsin Dells every year and see country that was Indian country
            long time back. Long time back my people make mounds all around Dells and Portage and
            Devil’s Lake. Indian reporter camp with father when young boy and one time father catch
            big muskeilunge just below dam here. It free country then and Indians could take game
            they want to eat and now when Indian do same thing get 90 days in jail and too many
            white men game wardens. People tell Indian reporter Myron Lowe who is Indian from Black
            River Falls going to box at big fight show at Tomah Fair 4th August and too bad Indians
            at Stand Rock can’t come to fair and see Myron Lowe box. Next night Indian reporter
            maybe go to fair at Tomah and talk to people and be part of program and see boss at
            Stand Rock and see if I can go. That’s enough. Too hot day to write Indian News. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
