<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M05D04</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>I have that flu like everybody been having and don’t feel
            very good and was pretty bad last night. Everybody ask why I don’t go to hospital but I
            don’t want to go to hospital because I have been and didn’t make me well and had to go
            home and mix up own Indian medicine dope before get over it. When at hospital just lay
            down in bed all day and nurse come in some time two three times every day and put little
            glass rod under tongue and say you keep that right there and after long time come and
            take it out and that’s all. Do same thing two three times every day and never five any
            medicine and I get pretty sore. I tell nurse can’t get well with just glass rod under
            tongue. I get pretty mad and get up and go home and mix up medicine dope with roots and
            things and after take dope feel pretty good and pretty soon same as ever. Glass rod
            under tongue never made Indian get well and I know Indian medicine dope better than
            stuff white man use some times. Well first place I want to tell again something I know
            pretty well myself. Long time back maybe 15 years back everything get along good but now
            whole country like what everybody talk about refuge. Can’t go no where and can’t do
            anything without license. When Indian reporter was young fellow pick blueberries
            anywhere we want to and everybody make living and nobody get relief. Now can’t pick
            blueberries in good patches because big shot white government fellows put up signs and
            have fellow out looking for poor Indian or poor white people that might pick berry in
            wrong place and taken to jail and make pay big fine and maybe keep in jail for 90 days
            like I stay once. Everybody try to make living and got food from family before
            everything have to have license and so much refuge and now government say can’t do
            anything without license and everybody all and get relief and don’t try to pick
            blueberries or hunt or fish and just wait for truck to bring food that government buy.
            One time got laid off at Stand Rock at Wisconsin Dells and go for long walk and between
            Mather and Necedah white fellow warden jump on my neck and say “Where your license?” and
            I tell him I just stop for few berries to eat and maybe if I find good patch to pick
            maybe if I find good patch to pick maybe I buy license like that. He tell me you write
            to Juneau County and get license and now you go on and get out of here. Indian reporter
            tell him that pretty funny thing if poor Indian can’t pick few berries to eat and whole
            country was Indian’s before white man come over here from Europe and take everything
            away. Make me pretty mad every time I think about that fellow. George Lonetree he come
            over here last week and visit Indian reporter from Wisconsin Rapids and tell about
            Indians going to get money from government sometime maybe pretty soon. One other time
            government give money to Winnebagoes and money all spent for big hospital at Tomah and
            now Oneidas come from all over and fill up hospital and no room for Winnebagoes. Every
            Oneida that going to have papoose now have to come to hospital for some times two three
            weeks and no room for Winnebagoe that break leg or like that. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
