<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M02D16</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Oscar Pigeon was visitor last week from Wittenberg. Him and
            wife and mother stay with Indian reported dinner time and return back same day. Oscar’s
            brother came here to Indian hospital. Wednesday pretty cold day and I think Indian
            reporter was a humbug when I say last week no more bad winter here this winter. People
            make fun with Indian reporter about tell there won’t be bad winter. Ray Whitewing been
            at Indian hospital get out Saturday. His brother going to prize fight at Milwaukee and
            Ray go there to see him in prize fight. White friends at Valley Junction say like Indian
            News. Maybe some time have desk in office like Fuller big talk noise man at newspaper
            office, and loaf around and get big check Saturday night just like worker fellow. Last
            week forgot to tell about big game all killed off. Indians know used to be lots big game
            here bear, moose, elk, and white man kill them all off. Long time back but Indian
            stories that come long way back know bear, moose, elk here. White man killed for
            tin-didn’t want to eat. Indians got skunked. White man come over here and make
            everything a law and make guns that shoot long way and Indian have just bow and arrow
            and can shoot long way and don’t need laws to keep from killing off all big game. White
            man make laws for everything and can’t kill bull frog but get 90 days in jail. I know I
            got 90 days in Sparta jail once. Jail good jail and plenty to eat but don’t like being
            cooped in jail and don’t like white man laws for 90 days and don’t like take traps too.
            Another thing pretty bad about money people pay for baskets Indians make. Pietz and
            people at stores that buy baskets from Indians only give 50 or 60 cents for big basket
            and cost that much for things to make baskets. When sell baskets on highway same baskets
            get you $1.50. Lots of people tell Indian reporter should have big pow-wow at Tomah lake
            in fall. Big pow-wows here long time back every year and people come long way off. After
            Labor Day after close up at Wisconsin Dells be good time for pow-wow. All big performers
            from Wisconsin Dells come here maybe after Dells close up. Indians come from all over
            and camp at lake. September 10 good time. Indian reporter think have two-day pow-wow.
            After September 10 some Indians raking cranberries and can’t be at pow-wow and no good
            if many Indians can’t come. Lawrence Marksman of Chipewa tribe from Ashland is new man
            at Tomah Indian Agency. He is junior clerk at agency office. Editor’s Note: In last
            week’s Indian hospital news it was stated that a baby girl was born to Mr. and Mrs.
            Andrew Funmaker of La Crosse at the hospital. We have been informed that this them was
            incorrect and that the child was born to Mr. and Mrs. James Funmaker of Black River
            Falls. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
