<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M06D01</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Indian News By Frisk Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Everybody laugh and have big joke about Indian reporter this
            spring when tell folks all about what weather going to be when I tell them no more cold
            weather and then have bad winter, but nobody laugh very much when tell in Indian News
            last week that moon sign tell going to have rain about 25th May when moon change and
            everybody tell Frisk Cloud Saturday you’re all right Frisk and buy me drink and say
            think I am pretty smart fellow. People at tavern at depot tell about hear something that
            sound like drum Friday night and one fellow tell maybe Soderstrom go out on high hill
            and beat tom-tom and sing song and try to get suit that Joe Christman want to give
            Indian reporter to make it rain and can’t because I sold tom-tom to Soderstrom. Fellows
            at Cash Store say going to ask Soderstrom about it if he beat tom-tom and sing song to
            make big rain and maybe have Winnebagoes make him chief at pow-wow at lake and name him
            “Chief Rain-In-The-Face”. Indian tribes all good friends and like to have visit with
            Indians other tribes. Tuesday Indian reporter was in Tomah and got acquainted with
            Chippewa Indian soldier camped in Tomah. Private Nelson H. Hamlin, Company G. 2nd
            Infantry, stationed at Fort Wayne, Detroit, Michigan. He is fine fellow and had good
            talk with Indian reporter and tell me that Indians in every army camp he has been in and
            white men think they are good soldiers. All Indian soldiers ready to fight for country
            same as white man and Indian reporter tell Chippewa soldier that Indians should be
            soldiers and fight for country because this more their country than white man’s because
            country was their’s first and white man come over here from Europe and take land away
            from them. Indian reporter get letter every week about people that like Indian News and
            this week got letter from La Crosse and tell about Indian News beat thing in paper and
            tell about three people that want to subscribe for Tomah Journal to read about what
            Indian reporter say. Man that write letter tell about neighbor take paper and he go to
            his house and get paper every week to read Indian News. Two three fellow want to know
            from Indian reporter in Tomah Saturday how are blueberries going to be this year. I tell
            them I don’t know because haven’t been looking for blueberries but went out in my woods
            Sunday and look around and Monday go to another place and don’t find much blueberries
            and think they are all shot by big frost and lost dry weather and won’t be many
            blueberries this year. Found lots of places that look like going to be lots of
            blackberries and they good too when don’t have blueberries. Indian friends come down
            here from Black River Falls to fish and when comeback tell about all good fishing places
            posted and have signs that say you can’t fish here ad trespass and mean same thing. All
            good fishing place shut up by government or white man own land and just fish himself on
            land and lot of good cricks spoil for fishing because rich white fellows build dams and
            don’t have right kind of way for fish to go up crick and get trapped and have to stay in
            pond or can’t go up stream to like what you call spawn. Indian reporter think good thing
            to have government man go to rich man’s dam and see if have place that fish can go up
            crick without have to be leap frog and break neck. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
