<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M11D09</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>This time I tell them about trapping business and I tell some
            things I know myself about white fellows that trap skunk and mink and like that when
            season closed worse than Indians. White fellow game warden just watch Indian and when he
            catch poor Indian think he is big guy and take him jail and try to make him pay fine by
            judge and Indian don’t have money and can’t pay fine and stay in jail. I am trapper and
            I am hunter too and I know myself white fellows just as bad as Indian and lots of time I
            find white man trap without tag and lots of time too I hear gun shot and I know he don’t
            shoot at squirrel. I am not game warden and I am Indian reporter and just like farmer
            and I don’t say anything when I find trap that don’t have tag and when I see hunter I
            just walk by and I don’t even speak to him. Game warden meet me in woods two three years
            ago and he walk up to me and say “Hey Frisk did you see fellow hunting over on other
            side?” and I tell him “No I don’t see nobody,” and every time I tell them same thing.
            Lots of Indians now work at sort cranberries at marshes and give work to quite a few
            fellows and get pretty good pay too. Everybody need work now so can buy heavy clothes
            for winter and every time Indian get job sorting cranberries he feel pretty good. Some
            marshes pay Indian workers 15 cents an hour. Fred Sam from Wittenberg he come to Indian
            hospital four five days and have swell up his hand and arm and doctors try to fix it and
            he tell Indian reporter he maybe get better now. Joe Green and Herschel Thompson they
            are two young Indian fellows from Neillsville and Saturday they come to Tomah to see
            Indian reporter. I just see Frank Rehberg go by and everybody all Indians know him and
            call him fish king and he come through by our way and sell fish and meat to Indians and
            white people too. Indian reporter always have joke and big laugh with fish king. I eat
            his sausage he sell and I think pretty good and don’t kill me yet. Indian reporter have
            girl friend just young girl over in Michigan and I meet her at Wisconsin Dells and this
            week I get letter from her. Everybody say I am too old buck to have young girl friend.
            Whenever I get money I want to go Michigan and see her. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
