<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M11D02</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Well first thing I want to tell about what white fellow tell
            me at Wyeville about friend that go fishing up Onalaska and go fishing no one else with
            him and catch three big fish and bring them home. When he got home like fellow say he
            have big feast with his family and then take other fish over to neighbor and neighbor
            fellow laugh and tell him that is dog fish and nobody eat dog fish get pretty pale and
            look pretty sick. Lots of Indians and I know white people too eat dog fish and make them
            in big stew and dog fish taste pretty good fish and pretty good to eat. Indians some
            people think not as smart as white fellows but I tell you one thing pretty sure Indian
            know when he catch what kind of fish he has. Now I tell you what I know about how people
            don’t have enough to eat and times with all people get pretty bad. Two three year ago
            everybody talk about pretty soon we have good times again and everybody have plenty to
            eat and like that and white fellows that run government going to fix things up all o.k.
            Indian reporter been here long time and I know myself young Indian man that have family
            always have plenty to eat for family and have warm clothes in winter. When Indian
            reporter was young fellow have work all time and everybody work and get two dollars two
            dollars and half a day and take his money to town and get lots of things and money go
            pretty good. Now when go to store and have money to buy and fellow in store say first
            thing “How much money you got?” and only give you just few things that you want and
            money pretty soon all gone and I don’t think that very good times. And another thing I
            want to tell about all farmers around where I live and other places same thing have own
            farms few years back and now farmers don’t own farms and somebody else now have place
            and he work for them and that pretty bad too and nobody very happy. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
