<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>F39M10D19</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Henry Mike everybody know him Indian Saturday he die at
            Indian Hospital. Henry Mike was pretty old and they tell me 84 years old and when get
            that old have to die and everybody have to do same thing and can’t go farther and have
            to die. All people, white man, black man, and Indian all have to die when get old and
            big strong fellow like prize fighter die too when he get old just same like weak squaw.
            I don’t know about what people tell about what going to happen after Indian die and
            every time friend die make me feel pretty bad. Rex Gondrezick is judge now and tell
            Indian reporter about don’t go hunting prairie chicken and pheasant because he is big
            fellow and can’t get between trees in woods and stay home and don’t go hunting and just
            eat tame chicken. Now I want to tell white folks about it make pretty bad for Indians to
            have to buy license to kill things to eat. Indian been here long time and when he want
            meat to eat he go out and kill and everything all right and Indians never get hungry and
            been that way for long time and then white man come over here and take land away from
            Indians and tell Indians he can’t kill his own game and have to go to white man at court
            house and buy license and nobody want to hire Indian to work and he don’t have money to
            buy license for everything like white man want and some time get pretty hungry and
            Indian want to do same like he used to and kill game when he want meat to eat and don’t
            have license for everything. Some Indians tell about better give Indians back some land
            and let them do like they like to live and ten don’t need to have everybody get relief
            and be better that way. Friday Indian reporter saw geese fly south and that pretty bad
            sign about winter and maybe get cold now and have to chop wood to keep house warm. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
