<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M12D27</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>HEAP TEPEE TALK By Smoke Signal Redcloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>The season’s greetings of a very Happy
            Christmas and a Very Happy Prosperous New Year to all our readers of the B-J and to its
            correspondents. It’s really hard to understand why the old world being the cradle of
            Christianity should forever be the battle-ground of nations whose ideals and principles
            are directly opposite to the doctrines so strongly exemplified by the Saviour whose
            birthday we have just celebrated. It is so pleasingly strange that our nation so far
            removed from the stamping ground of the great teacher should be the bulwark of the
            Christian doctrine. Be it as it may, we should all be thankful not only for ourselves
            and our children but for those nations who look to our shores from which “good will
            towards all men” should emanate. Therefore we should all the more enjoy the Christmas
            and New Year holidays. Wars may come and wars may go, but human nature remains the same.
            Wars cannot be fought to end all wars and wars do not just happen. The human element
            enters into the picture somewhere. The human element of vicious and ambitious greed or
            ambitious viciousness or greeditious ambition, any way you want to take it. Wars could
            be brought to an end if only these adverse human traits could be eliminated. To
            eliminate them there should be no moral embargo. Yes! There should be no embargo on
            morals, instead these warring nations should be bombed with Christian and American
            morals. In these modem warfares everything is streamlined. Bombing and pursuit planes,
            battleships and submarines and even bombs are scream-lined. Two great factors seem
            always to be clashing in this great country of ours. To the men representing the long
            arm of the law, every individual is a potential criminal, while to the pulpit every
            individual is a potential saint. And if we can go by the Christmas spirit of giving so
            much manifested by the people the pulpit seems to have the edge. Speaking of wars and
            Christmas, wars have killed only their thousands while peace has killed its hundred
            thousands. Speak as much as we want of war and its horrors but the above is the truth.
            It takes all kinds of people to make a world and one of the meanest kind is one who
            scuttles his pocketbook so the wife can’t capture it during the Christmas shopping
            season. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
