<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M01D18</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>B-J SMOKE SIGNALS By Red Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Last Friday all one heard on the radio programs was the fact that it was Friday the 13th, but none were aware that December being the 12th month, last Friday the 13th was of the
            13th month. Even if one is superstitious is no reason to believe in signs. Remember a few days ago it thundered and rained and there was lighting? Those were signs of spring, but one can’t believe them. Some
            time we drove along the road south of Morrison Creek camp and we were thirsty, and presently we saw a sign, telling all way-farers ‘Spring here”. We stopped to quench our thirst. My companion said “I guess
            ‘spring is here’ alright, look at the frogs.” We did not drink. According to the B-J there were two horse meetings in the country last week. Quite probable the Dobbins discuss the dangerousness of being
            hauled in trucks over slippery roads, after the catastrophy of last week north of Merrillan in which a number of horses were killed. Quite probable, too, the matter will be brought to the animal supreme
            court, the S. P. C. A. Now is the time for all car owners to buy their license, but if one would wait till later in the spring when the license numbers are large, one would get more for his money. This mild
            winter was foretold by the animals of the Jackson county wilds especially the deer. The deer were not as fat as they would have been if a cold hard winter was ahead. Besides that they are traveling in small
            herds. Probably only immediate families are going around together as usual the mother-in-law being left behind. The squirrels too were not prepared for a cold winter being that they were not coated with a
            thick layer of fat. The field mice are not dragging their tails in the snow. When their “tall track” does not show there will not be a heavy snow-fall. One day last week a fellow luncher and myself sat
            lunching. My friend dropped a piece of butter. Presently be sorted in disgust, “look at the little cuss, will you. Who said chicka-dees were friends of the farmer? But look! he is a friend of the poultry
            men”, I looked. The little bird had completely ignored the butter and was so ravenously picking on the remains of a chicken drumstick. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
