<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M01D04</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>B-J SMOKE SIGNALS By Red Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>A Happy New Year to everyone. So many
            have inquired of me who it was that “ played” Santa Claus at the
            Clay school this year and did so well. “Played” get that. Imagine
            some people can’t believe there is a Santa Claus. Why it was Santa
            Claus him­ self, of course. They must be like Santa Claus’ children.
            They don’t believe there is a Santa. They “know” it’s the “old man”
            who plays it. Reminds one of the stork when he came home from making
            a call and found Mrs. Stork eyeing proudly a brood of gangling
            long-legged stork- lings wrapped in swaddling twigs and weeds lying
            in a chimney flue. “What is all this?” he roared. “Why”, the stork
            was here while you were away,” the Mrs. S. replied. The Christmas
            trees of yesteryear shorn of all tinsel trimmings and fra­ gile
            glittering and glistening oran- ments are thrown away, like empty
            bottles, no more to brighten the home and gladden the hearts of
            children. No earthly use whatever it lays dis­ carded awaiting to be
            carted o ff to the dump. But no! They still can be of ser­ vice to
            someone as the writer found out. Placed conveniently in two rows,
            tree alternating, they make the best kind of a snow fence if enough
            of them can be gotten together. We saw white whiskered 1938 go out
            leaning heavily on his cane look­ ing like his life started long
            before he was forty. We saw the new year come in but couldn’t tell
            whether it was a boy or a girl. I’d hate to be a year because one
            gets old too quick long before he has any fun. For the people of the
            old country the new year started with a “ bang”. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
