<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M03D15</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>HEAP TEPEE TALK (By Smoke Signal Red Cloud) </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>How! He-chalk-kolo! meaning, Hello, friend! “Hump-day-a, Hump-la-pin” meaning “ Today is a fine day.” Learn to talk Winnebago Indian language by following this column each week? Why not? The whites have taught us Redskins their language so turnabout is fair play. Every white reader should talk to some extent the Indian language of their
            community, not that it will get you anywhere in the world, but merely for the fun of it. The English language is not my mother tongue, so 1 have lots of fun juggling the English words and arranging them in such a way that it sounds like something. John Marsh, our recent retired business man, talks very good Indian and knows the meaning of many Indian names for different kinds of dry
            goods. “Pale face” Carish of the I. G. A. store, talks fairly good Indian too. But when it comes to talking the Winnebago language, the late Werner brothers, Art and Bob, of this city, were way above the average. And then there were and are many great friends of the Winnebagoes who do not speak a word of Indian. Take the late surgeon and physician, Eugene Krohn, and Judge Frank
            Johnson, for examples. It is quite probable these true friends of the Redmen never had the leisure time to learn. Now there are County Judge Harry Perry and Mr. Berg of the jewelry store, and many others who do not talk one word of Indian except to say How! Next week we’ll have the first part of Scout law of the Boy Scouts in Winnebago language. Sometime in the latter part of January,
            the Wisconsin Winnebago Claim committee, of which the writer is president, received a letter from their tribal attorney in Washington, stating that Senator “ Bob” La Follette had introduced the Winnebago Jurisdictional bill on the 16th of that month, in Congress. This bill, if it passes Congress, will open the doors of the Court of Claims to the Winnebago tribe that they may present
            what claims they may have against the U. S. Government. Proving claims against Uncle Sam is what we would call a task colossal. This Winnebago claim committee, representing the Winnebago tribe, of Wisconsin, is represented in Washington by the tribal attorney Ralph H. Case.' The committee is also working in conjunction with the state’s attorney general’s office. A law was passed about
            four years ago in the state legislature conferring on the state the authority to secure or work out some means of securing satisfactory recompense for the Indians of Wisconsin from the U. S. government, for long neglected benefits from unfulfilled treaties. Providing that this jurisdictional bill introduced in Congress by Senator La Follette should pass and the Winnebagoes receive a
            favorable decision from the Court of Claims and the Indians receive satisfactory adjustments from Uncle Sam, the state will have benefitted by having the living standards Of its Indians greatly lifted and will have benefitted largely also from the monetary viewpoint. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
