<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M03D08</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>B-J SMOKE SIGNELS By Red Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>March came in like a cute little pet lamb with lots of
            wooly white snow and probably will go out like a female lioness without the shaggy mane.
            They say Ferdinand the bull likes to smell flowers which may account for our steak
            having such sweet flavor. Week ago Monday while walking through the woods to the mail
            box I ran across tracks of field mice and what do you suppose I saw? Well, this
            prophetic little mouse was dragging its tail in the snow. I said to myself, “ Oh! oh!
            we’re going to get some snow” . And Tuesday you all know what happened. Roads were
            drifted so high in places it took me five hours from B. R. Falls to home, a distance of
            13 miles, and then I had to leave the car and walk five miles to home. Who then is to
            blame for the storm? The field mice or the weather man? It’s “hiyo, Silver!” twice a
            month when the pay checks come. And it shall come to pass that Disney will take a rib
            from Ferdinand’s side and make a bovine Eve who will in time offer Ferdiand the
            forbidden apple. Believe it or not, that’s bull! The trend of thought of the human race
            is hard to follow and even more difficult to understand. The Indians of the earlier
            times fought for their rights as rightful owners of this county and they were called
            savages. Today men fight for greed, power and wealth through means of aggression,
            oppression and "trick laws” , and this current existence is called Advanced
            Civilization. In another two weeks youthful beautiful spring will be fighting for its
            rightful place and I hope we will not call her a savage. The Smoke Signals predicted a
            mild winter not thru use of scientific instruments but thru observance of nature’s own
            trees, shrubs and animals and we all know we had a very comparatively mild winter
            season. Ail well and good but we should give all credit to these “dumb animals” and
            lifeless trees for they alone know what we as thinking human beings do not know. Now
            altogether, let us shout— “Hats off, the snow plow is passing by!” .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
