<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M11D22</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>HEAP TEPEE TALK By Smoke Signal Redcloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>“Clean out your barred and have a barrel of
            fun. Clean out your barrel and shoot your buck on the run” might be the theme song for
            all the hunters. The seven days beginning Saturday. Be careful and not let your white
            socks protrude over your boot tops. Carry a blue or a red handkerchief for your snozzle
            because anything white will draw fire from any one nearby who might be afflicted with
            buck fever. As for the whites of your eyes, if you’ve got something on your hip to keep
            them blood shot, well, that’s alright, too. I’ve heard many a story of how one hunter
            shot another hunter but the best I ever heard was of a young Indian who, while standing
            on a high windfall near a point of land where bears usually came up on dry high land
            after browsing in the marshes during the night, shot what he took for a bear and shot
            his own father- in-law. After the old man was gotten home he confessed that he was
            trying to frighten the young man into thinking that he was seeing a member of an enemy
            war party and then watch his run for home. But it just happened that he was not the kind
            of young man that would run. I can just imagine the young man standing there, shot and
            wad bag slung over one shoulder and the powder horn slung over the other shoulder
            leaning on his trusty muzzle loading shotgun patiently waiting for any sign of big game
            whereby he could prove his mettle to the tribesmen of the village. Then suddenly, barely
            discernable in heavy fog he sees something going on all fours, and never thinking it
            could be a human being he blazes away with both barrels. Imagine his discomforture when
            reaching the place to see his wife’s father lying there with a mortal body wound. I
            myself have hunted with muzzle- loading shot guns (my great-grand­father’s) and I know
            how hard hitting they can be. Well, anyway, the young man was cleared of all blame and
            in later years became one of the great leaders of the tribe. I know not who wrote the
            following very enlightening and strengthening words, but I do know this. Anyone who
            feels down and out and feels everything is working against him and feels there are too
            many obstacles impossible to overcome one hindering him from reaching his goal in life,
            would read these words and ponder over the circumstances under which these words might
            have been written he would soon see a different slant on life and his morale restored.
            “It matters not how hard the scroll, I am the master of my fate and the captain of my
            soul.” Maybe that I haven’t just got the right wording but anyway I’ve always thought
            that he must have been a Progressive. A man who believed in fair and square dealing,
            whether it be in politics or individuals. A man who was a credit to the state, a man who
            was not daunted by anything, not even big party coalitions. A man beloved and believed
            in by people of the government, for the government and by the government. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
