<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M06D14</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>HEAP TEPEE TALK By Smoke Signal Red Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Friends, Womans and Countrymen a worthy and notable movement has been launched by the
            various fraternal organizations of the city of Black River Falls and leading towns of
            the county, to have Centennial to celebrate the founding of the first white settlement
            on the Black river a hundred years ago. I want to tell the boys and girls that I will be
            there with the fiercest warriors and the best dancers of the tribe. So write to your
            friends, here there and everywhere, and tell them to be there. Much will be written
            about the early history of Jackson county, the activities of the Indians and white
            settlers and pioneers of those early trying times. Next week I am writing a few short
            stories that took place about the time this county was first being developed. These will
            depict the humorous side of that life, just everyday happenings of the Indians when
            firearms first became a part of their hunting equipment instead of the good old bow and
            arrow. George Zahrte, who has employment with a construction company at Owen, spent the
            week end at home. He has been on the job at Owen for the past couple of weeks. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
