<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M03D22-Heap Tepee Talk</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>HEAP TEPEE TALK By Smoke Signal Redcloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>“How! He chalk-kolo!” Well, my good people, another week has passed and we are that much
            closer to spring and when it does come I hope we will all make good use of it by doing
            for others more than we expect others to do for us. The Boy Scouts have got the right
            idea of the fundamental structure of the true human relationship in the following scout
            oath which 1 will translate into the Winnebago language. "On my honor I will do my best”
            “Woysh-sliak-ha-nee-nay-kee, J a w -shay-l'ee-iia-na-kee-zhay-skay-hock- nay-n.” “To do
            my duty to God and my country” ‘ ‘W oe-lay-J ay-koo-wa-kee- ook-Jaw-nay-kee, Ma-oo-la,
            a-kee- ma-hanee-la.” To help other people at all times” “ wa-k ee-gee-day-kchay,
            he-jaw-nay-ia, hoy-ship-gee.” The other part of this Scout oath we will have next week.
            Just a few words in reference to the Wisconsin Winnebago Claim committee mentioned in
            this column last week. This committee is the official organ of the Winnebago tribe here
            in Wisconsin and it is composed of members of the tribe representing six different
            districts of Indian settlements. Black River Falls district is represented by the writer
            as president of the committee, and Fred King- swan, counselor. The Tomah district is
            represented by James Smoke, secretary of the committee and Scott Mokey, treasurer.
            Mauston district is represented by Kay Goodbear, as counselor, Wittenberg district being
            represented by Albert Big Thunder and Nathaniel Decorah. Wisconsin Rapids district is
            represented by Frank Lincoln and the late Chief A. White. The La Crosse district
            including the Minnesota settlement has Gilbert Lowe as representative and the late
            William Hopinkah was also a representative of this district. The committee was organized
            back in 1928. The committee men being elected by the tribal members present at the
            general meetings called by the Indian agent at the Tomah school auditorium. The Indian
            agency at Tomah thru which the U.S. Government is to take care of its wards, has done
            very little to bring about better living conditions for the Indians under its
            jurisdiction. Years back when there was an agency for each tribe very little was
            accomplished for the Indians. Today the Tomah Agency has under its jurisdiction other
            reservation Indians besides the Winnebagoes of central Wisconsin. What can the agent
            accomplish now going from one tribe to another? Nothing much to be sure. Thinking
            seriously over the situation one comes to the conclusion that the relative combination
            of the Indian agency and the different counties in which the Indians reside can be very
            much likened to the monkey and the cat in the kindergarten story. The cat was burning
            its paws pulling chestnuts out of the red hot bed of coals while the monkey sat back
            eating the nutritious kernels. In the last 2 0 years what has the agency done for the
            Indians. What has the Indian Bureau done for the Indians? Very little, if anything at
            all. What were the Indian Bureau officials and semi-officials doing at the outset of the
            disastrous depression of the last six or so years when the various women’s clubs of this
            city and surrounding towns were doing the best they could to meet “difficult situation?”
            What did the Indian Bureau officials do when the American Legion Post of Alma Center was
            distributing fresh meat and other supplies. The Indian Bureau continued to receive
            appropriations from Congress and the Indian Bureau officials and employees continued to
            receive their monthly salaries while doing nothing to help the Indians who were under
            their guardianship. The state and the counties, women’s clubs and the American Red Cross
            were staggering under a prodigious labod load getting nothing in return for all their
            troubles and sacrifices. How much more these charitable institutions could have
            accomplished if they had all the money that was expended for the maintenance of the
            agency and its employees salaries. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
