<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M12D06</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>HEAP TEPEE TALK By Smoke Signal Redcloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Again as in years past the deer season opened with a bang! Every one we meet querys “get
            your buck?”, with down cast glance we reply “No, no luck” . But I do not worry for it
            makes no difference now. The first morning of the deer season we arrived in the deer
            country about 6:30 C. S. T. The air was a bit frosty, not unpleasantly nippy, but more
            exhilarating than anything else. The atmosphere was quiet. It was so quiet you could her
            a dew drop about ten feet away. I kept wondering from what direction shooting would
            first take place. About ten minutes to seven there came a terrier-like bark o f a 25-20,
            over to my right about a mile away. That was the first shot I heard in the country where
            I was. Something like three minutes passed when again to my right about three-quarters
            of a mile away came the business-like “buck- o-o! buck-o-o! o f a hi-powered rifle. It
            buckoed five times and then silence. A neighbor boy got his buck. Four misses and the
            fifth a fatal shoulder shot at 35 rods. From then on the heavy artillery kept up a
            steady fusillade punctuated now and then by sharp yaps of small calibred rifles. Every
            so often came the usual doe-o-o! doe-o-o! of rifled slug splitting shotguns. Well, men,
            how do you like April hunting in November? I am of the opinion that more venison have
            spoiled on the hand of hunters than at any time within the last five years. The second
            and third mornings of the deer season were the most beautiful mornings a hunter have
            ever seen. A grayish-white hoary frost blanketed all the trees and shrubs, and when the
            sunlight struck them, Ah! it was just like a scene within a dream, unreal, beautiful
            beyond description. No thought or desire to kill should have entered into the mind of
            anyone. But just the one trigger-finger itched and kept itching whenever a herd of deer
            came running by over frozen runways. Their drumming hoofs reminded one very much of the
            riding of the lone ranger. America and Americans sit today on the ringside closely
            observing great nations at war. What will be the ultimate outcome of all this? The last
            world’s war was fought to end all wars in order to start new and bigger and not better
            wars. One never thought that things like these could ever happen in a civilized world
            like ours. Reading the newspapers and listening in on the news commentators is like
            reading one of Edgar Rice Burrough’s novels such as Mars, The Warlord of Mars, or The
            Princess of Mars. But they do say— Truth is stranger than fiction. The administrative
            and supervisory end of the Soil Conservation Service of this city was well represented
            among the lucky deer hunters who got their buck the first day. The lucky representatives
            are Richard (Dicky) Nelson, Stanley De Boer, Gust Spiering and Brownie O’Brien. If there
            are any others, raise your right hands. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
