<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M01D11</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>B-J SMOKE SIGNALS By Red Cloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>By Red Cloud The family’s provisions were gone and
            not a cent did they have to buy food. But they just laughed and
            laughed because they had plenty of “Jack” pine on the back “forty”.
            We’re having real nice spring weather now but we’re due for some
            real cold spells before long, and from all indications we’ll have a
            late spring. The country has been in the throes of a very disastrous
            depression for a good many years, from which we are just emerging
            and the next two years there will be prosperity and good times for
            every one and the years after that we may run into a worse business
            than the one we have just witnessed. Roosevelt really speaking,
            “take good notice.” Many startling changes in our na­ tional life
            come and go, but what is more startling than that dead men come back
            to rally weakening politi­ cal forces. “Look here, young fella, we
            believe what we want to believe, and if you believe you are
            weakening you’re bound to weaken”. So again “take good notice.” In
            driving over these slippery roads and driving in town where there
            are children ever crossing streets, “Take good notice.” In these
            days of disastrous winter fires and subsequent sales when you see a
            friend with good clothes, before you come to a conclusion “take good
            notice.” As far as we are concerned there will be this year,
            centennial celebra­ tions or expositions in three of the most
            important cities in the U. S. A. — New York City, San Francisco and
            Black River Falls. The old Indian had after many days of laborious
            work, made a neat “No Trespassing” sign which he nail­ ed to a tree
            at the corner of his homestead. Lately when he looked pretty glum
            one morning, when asked the reason why he said “Somebody ‘take good
            notice’.” .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
