<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M04D05</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>HEAP TEPEE TALK By Smoke Signal Redcloud </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Well boys and girls, and readers of the B-J,
            here is the last part of the Boy Scout oath in Winnebago language. To keep myself
            physically strong (Lo-ha-nee-la, Lush-shay, ha-kaw,la- neek-Jay); mentally awake
            (wo-way- we-la-nee-ump chee-la-key, ka-la-neek jay), and morally straight (ay-ki-woy nak
            sawb-la-lo-chaw). Next week we’ll count up to 10. Headlines in Komensky News:
            “Constitutionality of U. S. Constitution challenged.” “Efforts made to deprive
            Winnebagoes the Right to Vote.” “Winnebagoes meet force with force.” “First Time in
            History Winnebagoes stand together.” “No statesmanship, no forsight, no diplomacy among
            white populace of Komensky.” “No denial that all whites were on relief thru acceptance
            of Red Cross flour.” “Indian vote break ring of advicates for depriving the Winnebagoes
            the privilege to enjoy the rights of citizenship.” “Theoretically, Winnebagoes have more
            right to challenge the whites their eligibility to vote.” “Winnebagoes score a devisive
            victory.” “Democracy wins over Fascism.” “Chas. Marek defeats Frank Hryz for chairman by
            34 to 41 vote.” “Fred Kingswan and Frank Roush elected supervisors over Frank Marek and
            Otto Wagner. Fred Kingswan ..................51 votes Frank
            Roush......................... 48 votes Frank Marek........................27 votes Otto
            Wagner ........................ 26 votes .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
