<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>M39M06D28</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>HEAP TEPEE TALK By Red Cloud</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Do not say “Fourth of July”, say instead “Centennial and
            homecoming”. Indians never run when a shower catches up with them. They never run during
            a storm no matter how hard it rains. It is strictly against their belief. When a person
            runs he runs into more raindrops than if he walks so it’s better to go slow. The
            horse-flies went crazy with the heat last few days and couldn’t tell the difference
            between a horse and a cow and cows had a hard time of it. It takes a jack to raise a
            car, and it also takes a jack to raise a family. A couple of weeks back a bit of Smoke
            Signals appeared in the Cookie Jar. Will wonders never cease. “Vacation with pay, even
            for a day” sounds alright on paper and mothers may believe in it in theory, in actual
            practice, nothing doing. Even if mothers did receive “pay” it’s more than likely they’d
            buy things for their children. But for fathers they are very much against it in theory.
            They think it is an extreme new deal policy. In actual practice they are for it, heart
            and soul, and will use the “pay” to buy more fishing tackle. I didn’t think the “Heap
            Tepee Talk” was read by such distinguished people. Thanks just the same, Marcella. The
            thunder showers of last week were said to be million dollar rain storms. I can’t say
            that I know any about a million dollar rain. As far as I concerned there can be only
            forty dollar rains. That’s the biggest amount of money I know anything about. May we all
            meet happily at the Centennial and Homecoming. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
