<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>R39M04D13- Violet Big Thunder</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>The Wausau visitors the past week were:
            Mrs. Thomas Little Bear and son, Thomas, of Wisconsin Dells, visited the home of Mrs.
            Robt. Big Thunder; Mrs. Eli White, Mrs. Frank Storm, Mrs. Eugene Wabashagain and Mrs.
            Sam Little George were also at the Big Thunder home. Miss Katherine White Wing was a
            week-end visitor at her aunt’s home. Mr. and Mrs. Nat Long and family and Mr. and Mrs.
            Alfred Big Thunder and family attended a Easter dinner at the home of Lena Big Thunder.
            Mrs. Robt. Big Thunder and Violet went to Tomah on business. On the way back they
            visited at the Wisconsin Dells Indian Settlement. Their trip was rather a fair one, but
            a little too cold. Quite a number of Indians attended an Easter gathering at the home of
            Nat Decorah where dinner was served. Mr. and Mrs. Annie Ruben and family returned to
            Madison April 4 after spending the winter in Florida. George White Wing spent a week at
            his home in Wittenberg, but has returned to his aunt’s home in Wausau. Miss Isabel
            Smith, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Edward Smith, died Friday at the Tomah Indian Hospital
            after a lingering illness. The funeral was held at the Indian church and burial followed
            in the church cemetery. Mr. and Mrs. Joe Smith of Mauston attended the funeral services.
            Two of our Indian boys, Melvin Decorah and Leroy Brown, have entered the Rib Mountain C.
            C. camp in Wausau. Emerson Thundercloud, who finished his term there, has returned home.
            He is ill with a cold. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
