<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>R39M03D09</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Mr. and Mrs. Albert Big Thunder are now staying in Wisconsin
            Dells. Mrs. Albert Big Thunder has a sister there who is sick and is taking care of her.
            They were taken there last Thursday night by Mrs. Robt. Big Thunder and daughter, also
            George White Wing and Elmer Big Thunder. Emerson Thunder Cloud of Rib Mountain C. C. C.
            camp at Wausau was a Sunday visitor at Mrs. Robt. Big Thunder’s home in Wausau. Mrs.
            Minnie White Wing and son George White Wing of Dancy were at Wausau at her daughter’s
            home. Mr. and Mrs. John Stacy are visiting at the Indian settlement. They were staying
            at Mrs. Houghton’s in Schofield. Peter White, who was at the Tomah Indian Hospital and
            who returned home quite a while ago, passed away at the home of Mr. and Mrs. Tom
            Prescott where his folks were living. We would like to extend our heartfelt sympathy to
            his surviving mother, Mrs. Theodore Niconish. Mrs. Eli White Wing and two sons, George
            and Raymond, also youngest daughter Caroline and Herman Wabashagain were in Shawano on
            business. Mr. and Mrs. John Dickson were last week-end visitors at the Nat Long home in
            Schofield. Mrs. Robt. Big Thunder and daughter Violet took H. L. Mumm of Wausau to the
            Indian settlement on business. Mr. and Mrs. Esau Prescott were week-end visitors at Mrs.
            Big Thunder’s home in Wausau. George White Wing who is staying at his aunt’s place in
            Wausau was a week-end visitor at his mother’s home in Wittenberg. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
