<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>R39M03D23-Violet Big Thunder</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Miss Isabell Smith, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Ed. Smith, was taken to the Tomah Indian
            Hospital where she will receive treatments. Esau Prescott and Oscar Pigeon left Tuesday
            for Tomah hospital where Oscar’s youngest brother, Frank Pigeon, has been all winter.
            Frank will come home with his brother Oscar. Mr. and Mrs. John Storm, town of Elderon,
            were in Wausau on business Tuesday. Mrs. Joe Eagle, former resident of the town of
            Elderon, passed away on March 9. Mrs. and Mrs. Joe Eagle had been living in Winnebago,
            Nebraska. They had been there a long time. Mr. and Mrs. Eli White Wing of Wittenberg
            were in Wausau last Saturday. With them was Mrs. Eugene Wabashagain also of Wittenberg.
            Mrs. Robert Big Thunder and her nephew, Little George, visited at the home of Mrs.
            Minnie White Wing of Dancy. Miss Violet Big Thunder visited her aunt’s and uncle’s home
            in Schofield last Sunday. She reports that everyone there is getting along fine. Nat H.
            Long had a heart attack and almost passed away last Wednesday night. He is now in fine
            condition. Albert Big Thunder has written to his son in Schofield telling how his wife’s
            sister is getting along. It is said that she is improving, but very slowly. Andrew Black
            Hawk has returned to his home in Neillsville. He had been staying at the home of Mrs.
            Minnie White Wing of Dancy. John Stacy has returned to Schofield from Wittenberg where
            he had been working for the past week. Robert Big Thunder, who has been staying in the
            Veterans Hospital, is coming home for only a few days and will return to Milwaukee. Mr.
            Big Thunder wrote and said that people who heard a Robin, know that Spring has come; but
            he said he went walking on National Avenue where he heard a pig grunt, and said that the
            pig had brought the cold weather. Christ Wilson has found himself a bride. The lucky
            bride was Miss Bertha Johnson of Chicago. They are now making their home in Portage,
            Wis. Miss Lois Marie Brown of Schofield visited at the home of Mrs. Robt. Big Thunder in
            Wausau last Sunday night. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
