<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>R39M12D28</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Once again Christmas found us all well together in our little
            church in the country. Our usual Christmas program was well attended and it was very
            well appreciated as understood from many sources. The program in clued the singing of
            several well known Christmas songs and recitations given by our young people of the
            community. It was evident that the speeches and songs by our little ones were well
            executed with feeling. A solo was given by one of our ladies, Susie Smith, and also one
            by the Rev. Sihler. We wish to thank all those who took part in it and especially to
            Miss Anna Mathison, our associate mission teacher, who had much to do with the
            arrangement of the splendid program. Many wonderful and helpful gifts were distributed
            among the various families which were donated by our church friends and supporters of
            the Mission work throughout the country. The many beautiful quilts, needless to mention
            the many colorful, framed Bible story pictures for our homes, the many toys and school
            supplies for our many toys and school supplies for our children. We appreciate these
            gifts greatly and certainly our Christmas was a merry one. We deeply express our thanks
            to you all. Vacationists over Christmas include Miss Florence Wabshagain of Whitefish
            Bay, Joseph Monegar, Milwaukee, and Sammy Cloud, Lake Tomahawk. Greetings came to many
            of our families with apples and honey from Martin’s Cherry Orchard Inc., Sturgeon Bay,
            which greatly added to the making of our Christmas season a merry one. We wish
            profoundly to express our thanks. Bertha and Dells Wabshagain were very proud to be
            recipients of an attractive fur clothed Eskimo doll and a pair of arctic mittens. These
            gifts were sent to the girls by Miss Helen Frost, Igloo, Alaska. Until again I wish the
            readers of this column a very Happy New Year. -S.C. .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
