<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>R39M03D16</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Mrs. Eli White Wing of Wittenberg was at
            Wausau doing some business of her own. She returned Saturday. Alpheus Long visited at
            Robert Big Thunder’s home Monday night. He is attending the Wausau Vocational School.
            Mrs. Robt. Big Thunder and daughter Violet also (Little) George White Wing and Emmerson
            Thunder Cloud of Rib Mountain C.C. C. camp in Wausau visited at Mes. Robert Big
            Thunder’s mother’s home in Dancy, Wis. They sure enjoyed the visit. Charles Smoke of
            Tomah passed away last week at the Tomah Indian Hospital. Robert Big Thunder, who is now
            at the Veteran’s Hspital near Milwaukee, has written to his family telling them that the
            snow is all gone round there. He said they had rain and that helper a grat deal to melt
            the snow. George White Wing has returned to his home in Wittenberg. He had been staying
            at his aunt’s place in Wausau. Nat H. Long was ill in bed last week, but now he is well
            and is working. Now for a smile! It is said that a government man or a case worker came
            to see Ed. Little Wolfe, and asked “Little Wolfe” various questions. When he got all the
            information he wanted, he asked “Little Wolfe” this question: “Mr. Little Wolfe, when
            was your wife born?” Then “Little Wolfe” sat and thought for a while. Finally he said:
            “Well, my wife was born when she was a baby.” .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
