<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W39M05D04</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p> VILLAGE TO CURB STREETS Fluid Milk W hile department o f
            agriculture officials prepared to issue further price reduction
            orders, cheesemakers, consumers, and other dairy interests appeared
            before the assembly comm ittee on agriculture last week to register
            vigorous opposition to the Bichler bill which would re-enact the
            milk price control law on a permanent basis. Originally passed in
            1933, the milk price control law has been re-enacted by successive
            legislatures as emergency legislation. It allows the department o f
            agriculture and markets, in those urban areas where producers and
            distributors agree, to fix prices fo r fluid milk and cream in order
            to stabilize the market and to prevent unfair marketing practices
            which existed prior to 1933. Opponents o f the bill claimed that the
            statute m erely built a “ fence around the cities fo r a favored
            circle o f producers,” that it failed to alleviate thc distress o f
            the great m ajority o f dairy farm ers who are outside the city
            market areas, that it tended in some cases to accentuate their
            troubles by decreasing consumption and increasing the flow o f
            surplus milk to the creamery, cheese factory and condensery outlets,
            and that it worked a hardship on the workmen ll» the eities who
            cannot afford to pay the high retail prices fo r the milk which his
            family needs fo r health. Producers and distributors who are now
            protected under the law argued that failure to reenact it would
            result in a return to the chaotic conditions which existed before
            1933, and denied the claims that the price-fixing statute has
            decreased consumption. Budget The members o f the Wisconsin assembly
            this week went to work on the biggest piece o f legislation which
            will confront them this session, the biennial budget bill. After
            weeks o f revising and adjustment, the finance comm ittee has
            reported out fo r passage the fourth version o f the budget, called
            “ Substitute Amendment No. 2,” which calls for an appropriation o f
            approximately $70,000,000 for the next two years. With legislative
            floor leaders con ceding that a $4,000,000 to $5,000,000 relief bill
            in addition to the budget appropriations is likely, predictions that
            the Heil administration’s expenditures will reach $75,000,000 seemed
            likely o f realization this week. For purposes o f comparison here
            is the record o f expenditure o f other administrations in the
            present decadi Kohler (Republican) . . . $54,098,848 La Follette
            (Progressive) 59,181,172 Schmedi man (Democrat) 49,941,490 La
            Follette (Progressive) 00,362,993 La Follette (Progressive)
            71,405,257 Heil (Republican )............ 75,000,000 (probable) The
            village board at its meeting Monday night decided to curb the
            streets in four downtown business blocks, namely, two on Webb and
            two on Vinal, one block in each direction from the bank corner. The
            work will come under a WPA project and will start within a few days.
            It is estimated that about 20 men w ill be employed in laying the
            forms and pouring the concrete. Another W P A project under
            consideration is one fo r building a band shell in the local park.
            The proposed shell will be 40x20 feet in size and it is planned to
            have it built on the north end of the park, facing toward town.
            SCHOOL NEWS € hutd Two One act palys Two one-act plays will be
            presented in St. Paul’s church parlors on May 5 at 8:00 p. m. The
            plays are: “ T H K R O A R OF T H E T W IS T ” J o h n
            ................................ Roger Hanke Evelyn
            ......................... Doris Y aeger C ly d e
            .......................Herman Hoffman B e n n y
            ......................... Roland Zeinert E m i l
            ............................ W ilm er W'erth A n n a
            .......................... Anna Jannusch N e l l
            ............................ Geraldine Black “ H IS JU S T D E S SE
            R TS’’ K it ................................ Arlene Black Oscar
            .......................Clifford Brunner David
            ............................ Ted Hoekstra Max
            ......................... Donald Schmidt Miss L o i s
            ................... Eunice Brunner Mrs. T w in e fo r d .........
            Elaine Brunner T rio “ The S trife O ’er’’ “ Kentucky Babe Evelyn
            Jannusch, Doris Yaeger, and Marie Flemming. Admission 10 and 15
            cents. Candy sale. You are cordially invited to attend. N otice to
            Farmers W’e have just received a shipment o f field seeds and Hybrid
            seed corn from the well-known and reliable La Crosse seed company.
            The best there is in the line o f seeds. Gjermundson Hardware Co.,
            Wittenberg. Vaccination o f Horses Through arrangements made by the
            county soils committee, o f which O. B. Hagen is chairman, horses
            may be vaccinated fo r sleeping sickness at the special rate o f
            $2.50 a head, providing a number o f horses are brought to one place
            for this purpose. An agreement to this effect on a cash basis has
            been made with Dr. F. W. Hansen, local veterinary surgeon. Church o
            f the Holy Fam ily N o mass Sunday. Henry Schmitt, Pastor. First
            Lutheran Church Sunday services: 10:45 a. m. Worship. 9:30 a. m.
            Sunday school. 9 a. m. Worship, Morris. Saturday 9:00 a. m.
            Confirmands. Thursday 8:00 p. m. Choir practice. Tuesday, May 9. W.
            M. F. convention at Iola. Palmer A . Wahl, Pastor. St. John's
            Lutheran Church Sunday, May 7. English services at 9:00 a. m. Sunday
            school at 10:00 a. m. Thursday, May 11. Ladies Aid. jCarl Musall,
            Pastor. St. Paul’s Evang. Lutheran Church Services in the American
            language at 9:30 a. m. Services in the German language at 10:45 a.
            m. Sunday School at 10:30 a. m. No services or Sunday school at
            Shepley. G. F. Fierke, Pastor. Methodist Episcopal Church Sunday
            school 9:45 a. m. Morning worship 11:00 a. m. Women’s Home
            Missionary Society meets with Mrs. C. A. Thoreson Tuesday, May 9, at
            7:30 p. m. Union Sewing Circle meets W'ednesday, May 10, at Lutheran
            Home Mission church, Mrs. Grover Meisner entertaining. Confirmation
            class Saturday 1. p m. Choir rehearsal Saturday 7 p. m. Ralph W .
            Hawkins, Pastor. The Evangelical Free Church (Services in Town H
            all.) Sunday school 9:45 a. m. Norwegian services 10:45 a. m.
            English evening service 8:00 o’clock. Topic: “ W’ hat it Means to be
            Lost.” Wednesday evening at 8:00 o’clock, mid-week prayer meeting at
            the home o f Gunder Gunderson. C. Kjeldgaard, Pastor. Lutheran Home
            MisNion English Sunday service 2:30 p. m. Prayer meeting Wednesday,
            8:00 o’clock at the pastor’s home. H. E. Engebretson, Pastor.
            Bethany Indian Mission Services Sunday morning at 10:30 in the
            Winnebago Indian church. Sunday school and service 7 p. m. in
            Tigerton chapel. In d ies’ Aid at the Winnebago Indian church
            Wednesday afternoon, May 10. Oneida Ladies’ Aid at Tigerton,
            Thursday afternoon, May 11. Reading Room will be open this Saturday.
            E. W. Sihler, Supt. Our Saviors Lutheran Church, Elderon Class
            Thursdays at 4:00 p. m. Services Sunday, May 7, 11:00 a. m. W. A .
            Johnson, Pastor, H onor R o ll— 5-6 W eeks S en io rs : C a rl V o e
            lz , 15 points; D o ro th y B rehm er 13, H erm a n H o ffman 13, W
            'ilm er W e rth 13, E th el P a n ko 12, A le x D erro w 11, V ir g
            in ia S c h ly tte r 11, G erald in e B lack 10, C la ra Schulz 10,
            G la d ys G ra cy a ln y 9, V io la H eg ew a ld 9, E v e ly n
            Jannusch 9, O rton Lunde 9, A n g e lin e C a se tta 8, Ruth Z e in
            ert 8. Ju n iors: Jean G a tes 15, R obert H e istad 12, Joyce Th
            orson 12, Donald Schm idt 12, B ern hard t A nd erson 11, D o ro th
            y S p ra n gers 11, T h elm a G underson 9, M a rjo rie H itz k e 8.
            S oph om ores: D elores C arlson 11, M arth a F itz g e ra ld 10, A
            nn a H eista d 10, M ae S ieb ert 10, D o ro th y P le s s e r 9, M
            iriam S ch ly tte r 8. F resh m en : M a rjo rie W e s tg o r 12,
            June W o lff 12, S h irley B e rg 10, A lic e M cC on ley 9, B ern
            ice Schum acher 9, A rle n e Black 8, J o y c e T im m 8. * # * R u
            ral School D ay Th u rsday. M ay 18 Due to c o n flic tin g a
            ctivities the date fo r R u ral School D ay has been postponed from
            F rid a y , M a y 12, to T h u rsda y, M a y 18. Plans a re bein g
            fo rm u la ted to m ake the day both en jo y a b le and educational
            fo r the 8th gra d e gradu ates. T h e rural students b ein g asked
            to m eet at the h igh school at 9 a. m. and spend the foren oon in v
            is itin g classes. A fr e e lunch w ill be served a t noon and the a
            ftern o on w ill be -pent in p la y in g so ftb a ll, v o lle y
            ball, contests, and o th er recrea tion a l a ctivities. T lv eigh
            th gra d ers from a num ber oS chools have been contacted and tht
            response s in dicate th at a la rg e n um ber w ill be on hand fo r
            the occasion. * * # I ocal B oxers T r im Oconto F a lls 6-4 W itte
            n b e r g H igh concluded its b o x in g season by o u tclassin g
            the O conto F a lls boys. H o w a rd T im m , M erton F a n n e r
            and O rton Lunde outpoin ted th ir opponents, w h ile Jim R in gsta
            d lost a close decision. C la y to n L in d land and F lo y d
            Schofield, o f E lderon, took p a rt in exh ib ition m atches. It w
            as u n fortu n a te th at a com p lete p ro gra m w as not ca rreid
            out but tw o O conto boys and Ed. Thom son o f the local team fa
            iled to pass th e ph ysical exam in ation Im cause o f recen t
            illness. C on sequ ently th ree bouts w ere fo r fe it ed by each
            school. C on sid erin g the late s ta rt in th e ir firs t y e a r o
            f b o xin g the W itte n b e r g boys made a good sh ow in g w in n
            in g fr o m O conto F a lls and M arath on w h ile losin g to tw o e
            x perienced team s, M arion and S tr a tfo rd . C a rl V o elz, Ed.
            Thom son, O rton Lunde and M erton F a rm e r w ill be lo st to th e
            team n ext y e a r but th e re s t o f the bo^s w ill m ake up a
            nucleus w ith which to sta rt another season. # * # ( ’lass P la y
            Th u rsday. M ay 18 T h e sen ior class play, “ B ig H ea rted H e
            rb e rt,” a com ed y in 3 acts by Sophie K e r r and A n n a S teese
            R ich ardson, w ill be presented Th u raday eve n in g. M ay 18, in
            the high school gym n asiu m . T h e ch aracters a re as fo llo w s
            : H e r b e rt K aln ess ............ O rton Lunde R ob ert K a l n
            e s s ............ Gordon Laude E liza b eth K a l n e s s
            .......... C la ra Schulz M arth a .................... A n g e lin
            e C a setta H e rb e rt K aln ess Jr. . .. L y m a n Laude A lic e K
            aln ess ............ G erald in e Black A n d rew Goodrich . . .D
            elm a r T re p to w A m y L au ren ce . . . .V ir g in ia S c h ly
            tte r Jim L a u r e n c e .......................C a rl V o e lz Mr.
            G oodrich ........ A lex a n d er D erro w M rs. G oodrich ........
            D oroth y B rehm er M r. H aven s .................. R oya l H a rv
            e y M rs. H a v e n s .................D ella C an nady * * *
            Baseball N e w s L a s t w eek T h u rsd a y W itte n b e r g lo st
            a w ell-p la ye d ball gam e, despite the cold, w in d y w ea th er,
            to M arion 4-3. M arion w as held w ell in check by M ason, the
            local pitch er, until the last in ning, when th e y g o t to him fo
            r 3 h its and 2 runs. Th e M aroons w ere not able to push a run o v
            e r to tie it up w hen th e y took th eir turn at bat. W 'itten b
            erg box score: A B R H M ason, p ...................................
            3 0 0 Lau de, lb ................................... 4 0 0 R in
            gstad, ss .............................4 1 1 A . D errow , c
            ............................. 2 1 1 K. Johnson, 3b
            .........................3 0 1 B. Johnson, r f
            ...........................1 0 0 Jolin. I f
            ....................................... 3 0 1 H eistad, c f
            .................................3 0 0 T. D errow . 2b
            ...........................2 1 1 F a rm e r
            .......................................1 0 1 T o ta ls Runs H its M
            arion ....................................... 4 0 W itte n b e r g
            ............................... 3 5 B ow ler 9. W itte n b e r g 5
            In a v ery p o orly played b all gam e, fea tu red by its m any erro
            rs, the local H E L P F IG H T C A N C E R W IT H K N O W LE D G E
            Enlist in the Woffcen’s Field Arm y, the American Society for the
            Control o f Cancer. The month o f April was set aside as Cancer
            Control month, hut let ua continue. Let us all ufiite in a concerted
            effort to impress upon the people o f the nation the necessity for
            this program and the importance o f constant vigilance in this fight
            fo r humanity. Enlist now in this humanitarian Campaign. Read the
            bulletins and pamphlets which have been made possible through the
            funds raised by our organization during the annual “ Enlistment
            month’’ campaign o f the Women’s Field Army. W ill you volunteer in
            this w ar? It is necessary to have funds in order to continue the
            educational work. Any donation in this worthy cause may be given to
            Mrs. W\ I). Haseltine. local lieutenant, not later than on Monday,
            which is the limit set for the gathering o f these contributions.
            Cancer’a Danger Signals Here are the danger signals that may mean
            cancer: A lump in the breast or other part o f the body. 80' '* of
            cancers o f the breast may be cured when diagnosed and treated
            early. Any chronic skin trouble, especially any sore that does not
            heal. A ll skin cancers can be recognized early and 90' r are
            curable by known methods. Any chronic discharge, or irregular
            bleeding. These disorders often constitute the first indication o f
            cancer o f the bowels, stomach, bladder ami uterus. Persistent
            indige fcion, loss o f appetite or irregular ix>wel movement. Loss o
            f weight— progressive general weakness without obvious cause. high
            school team last Tuesday lost to the Bowler aggregation 9-5.
            Although W’ ittenberg outhit the Bowler boys 7- 6, the visitors made
            good use o f the many errors to score enough unearned runs to make
            sure o f victory. W'ittenberg box score: AB I*aude, lb Mason, ss . .
            . . Ringstad, p . . A. Derrow, c . Jolin, If ....... Farmer, I f . .
            . B. Johnson, rf Heistad, c f . . T. Derrow, 2b Totals * Bowler
            ......... W'ittenberg . .. Runs Hits .9 fi . . .5 7 Early Norrie
            Settler Died on Saturday Funeral services for Peter Paulson, one o f
            the earliest settlers in N o rrie .' who passed away at his home at
            that place on Saturday, were held Tuesday afternoon. The Rev. T.
            Aug. Lillehei, | o f this village, officiated, and burial took place
            in the N orrie cemetery. The pallbearers were Louis Larson, Ben
            Larson, Martin Johnson, Wallace Thorson, Erick Erickson and L.
            Konkol. Mr. Paulson was born in Norway October 3, 1R58, and came to
            this country 58 years ago. He spent one year in W ittenberg before
            moving to Norrie, where he lived the past 57 years. His w ife
            preceded him in death five years ago. Eight children, lfi
            grandchildren and three greatgrandchildren survive him. Relatives
            and friends from a distance pit sent at the funeral were Mr. and
            Mrs. Charles Paulson, William Paulson and daughter, Margie Ann, and
            Mr. and Mrs. Dan Mikkclson and children, Jean and Mary, o f
            Minneapolis, Mrs. James Ganyeau and son, James, Mrs. G. W. Prescott
            and Emerson and Milton Miller, o f Detroit, Mr. and Mrs. Arnold
            Paulson and Mrs. Henry McCornb, o f Chicago, Mrs. Herman Gilbertson,
            of Shepley, Mr. and Mrs. Matt Fox, of Eland, Mr. and Mrs. Frank
            Suick, of A ntigo, Mr. and Mrs. Charles Erickson and son, Edwin, o f
            H atley, Mrs. Ole Erickson and Mr. and Mrs. Erick Erickson, o f
            Birnamwood, and Mrs. Conrad Verpoorten, o f Wittenberg. Brother o f
            Mrs. Herhaum Dies Mrs. Herman Berbaum received the sad message that
            her brother, Gustav Wiegandt, town of H ew itt farmer, passed away
            Saturday. Funeral services were held on Tuesday at a fu neral home
            in Wausau and at Zion Lutheran church in the town o f Easton, the
            Rev. Zimmerman officiating. He was 58 years old. Seven children
            survive him, and three sisters, including Mrs. Berbaum, and three
            brothers. GENERAL CLEAN -lIP OP ENTIRE VILLAGE PLA N N E D FOR NEXT
            WEEK M AY 6 TO 13 The week o f May 6 to 13 has been officially
            designated as Clean-Up Week here. A notice to the effect will be
            found elsewhere in this issue o f The Enter- _________ , __________
            j prise. A s in years past the o » » • a. annual observance o f the
            week is S p i ing Music Concei t expected to producc g ra tify in g
            Wednesday Night at results here in W ittenberg. W. H. S. Gymnasium
            ------- ----------- # * Track A ctivities A number o f boys are
            taking an interest in track and field activities with Mr.
            Christenson teaching them the fine points. Entrance in two meets are
            being planned, the W o lf R iver Conference track meet at Wittenberg
            May 24, with competition in the foi lowing events: 100 yd. dash, 220
            yd. dash, 440 yd. run, 880 yd, run, mile, high jump, broad jump,
            shot put, pole vault, discus, and 880 yd, relay. The state district
            meet w ill be held at W isconsin Rapids May 12, and if the boys are
            in shape by that time a Witten berg team will be entered. First and
            second place winners o f this meet enter the state meet at Madison
            May 27. * » * Kindergarten News W e are making a bird book. W e
            colored a Cardinal Blue Jay, Bluebird, and a Red Headed Woodpecker,
            and put them in our books. We are going to make a Red Winged
            Blackbird, Baltimore Oriole and a Robin to put in our books. W e
            learned the names of the King Bird, Chipping Sparrow, Flicker and
            the Downy Woodpecker. Yesterday we went fo r a walk to the park. W’e
            looked at the trees and learned the poplar and pine tree and maple
            tree. W e went to the stock yard to see Roger’s little calf. Then we
            played games outdoors. * * * 71 h and nth Grade News Honor Roll:
            Dorothy Olsen, 21 points, P eggy Turecek lfi, James U r sin 16,
            Willard Hartleben lfi, Donald Iverson lfi, Mary Jane Christensen 15,
            Dorothy Sutheimer 15, Hai old Bessette 15, George Leo Voelz 15. The
            7th and Kth gimders have completed their text books and have begun
            review books. W e a're preparing fo r the county tests which are
            scheduled for May 15, lfi and 17. Our room gave a candy sale and
            fish pond. W’e made about $4.00. This we plan on using for our
            picnic. W e have fompleted our final unit booklets on agriculture,
            civics, and hygiene for grade 8, and history and geography fo r
            grade 7. John Ostenson John Ostenson died A p ril 14 at thc age of
            92 years after a residence of 10 years at the Homme Home fo r the
            Aged. He was a native of Hadcland, Norway, where he was born on
            August 22, 1846. He came to the United States as a youth and later
            settled on a farm near Blue River in the southern part o f the
            state. The funeral was held on A pril 18, the Rev. H. M. Mason
            officiating, and burial was in the cemetery o f the institution. One
            son survives him. “ Home T alen t" The Ladies' A id o f St. Matthews
            church o f Bowler are presenting a 3- act comedy entitled, “ His
            Women Folks” Friday, May 5, at 8:00 p. m. at the Bowler club house.
            Characters: Mrs. Martha Lewis, his grandmother— Gladys Goddake; Mrs.
            Lucinda Lewis Breckenridge, his mother- -Meta Marquardt; Miss Jane
            Lewis, his aunt— Florence Kriuwalt; Miss Edith Breckenridge, his
            sister Lizzie Bartelme; Miss Polly Breckenridge, his sister— Theresa
            Fuhrman; Mrs. W illiam Breckenridge. his second w ife— Elsie
            Kucksdorf; Mammy, his cook— Stella Radun; Liza, his maid — Anna
            Kassube; Patience Trent, his neighbor— Emma Zdrosky. Boy Scouts
            Monday evening the Scouts went on a hike instead o f holding their
            regular meeting in Scout headquarters. Thr evning meal was prepared
            by each patrol over their own fire, started by two scouts who passed
            their fire build ing test. They were Donald Iverson and Johnnie
            I^arson. The meal con sisted o f kabobs (m eat broiled on a stick)
            and twist, (bread baked on a stick.) A fte r supper patrol meetings
            were held to prepare a stunt for the camp fire service. Games were
            then played. A t the campfire service the stuntwere presen ted by
            each patrol and songs were sung. An add-a-line story was told, which
            turned out to be a tragedy for Raymond Mickelson and Lyman Laude.
            Taps were sung as a closing, thc fire was put out and the gang
            returned to town singing. Those who participated: Edward Plesser,
            Raymond Mickelson, Carl Voelz, George Leo Voelz, Lyman Laude,
            Johnnie Larson, Bernhardt Anderson, Raymond Oestreich, Donald
            Iverson, Melvin W agner, Teddy Derrow, Byron Johnson, Rolland
            //♦•inert, W'illard Hartleben. Robert Cappel joined the Hawk patrol.
            — i ■ ♦ ---------------- T o Purchase Roofing The purchase o f at
            least 150 squares o f roofing will be acted upon at a meeting o f a
            committee representing the Homme institutions and the First Lutheran
            church to Ih* held in the church basement Monday evening, May 8, at
            8:00 o ’clock. A ll bids presented at this meeting will receive doe
            consideration, — Committee A program o f music is to be given at the
            gymnasium next W'ednesday J evening, beginning at 8:00 o’clock.
            There will be many selections by the i school band and sections o f
            the band, instrumental solos, selections by the glee club, male
            double quartet, girls’ i sextet anti mixed chorus, musical reading.
            and entertainment by the German Band during the intermission. About
            a hundred students and pupils will take part in the presentation of
            the program. Your attendance is respectfully in- j vitod. Official
            Minutes of the Village Board V illage Hull. A pril 17, I0:IU. The
            board o f trustees met this evening in regular session. Present:
            Trustees Y aeger, Hanson, Haufe, Gates and Brehmer. Absent:
            President Evinson and Trustee Kersten. Motion made by Trustee Yaeger
            and seconded by Trustee Haufe that Trustee Gates act as chairman o f
            the meeting. Motion carried. The minutes o f the meeting o f April
            10 were read and approved. The finance committee audited the
            following bills: Cities Service Oil Co., kerosene nnd gas
            .................................. $12.75 Joe Komp, pair rubber
            boots . . . 2.39 Motion made by Trustee Hanson and seconded by
            Trustee Haufe that the above bills be allowed as read. Motion
            carried. Motion made by Trustee Yaeger and seconded by Trustee
            Hanson that Dr. Evenson be appointed health officer. Motion carried.
            Motion made by Trustee Haufe and seconded by Trustee Brehmer that
            Dr. Evenson, Dr. Gates and the clerk be appointed to the board o f
            health. Motion carried. The appointments o f President Evenson to
            the various committees were presented to the board as foi lows:
            Finance— Gates, Yaeger, Brehmer. Streets and Walks— Haufe, Brehmer,
            Kersten. Sewer and W ater— Yaeger, Hanson Gates. Ordinance— Hanson,
            Kersten, Haufe. Public Property— Brehmer, Yaeger, Gates. Bonds—
            Kersten, Haufe, Hanson. Poor— Dr. Evenson, Luther Englund, G. A.
            Meisner. Motion made by Trustee Brehmer and seconded by Trustee Y
            aeger that the committee appointments be con firmed as read. Motion
            carried. Motion made by Trustee Brehmer arul seconded by Trustee
            Haufe that the village continue to retain its membership in the
            Laegue o f Wisconsin Municipalities and pay the yearly dues o f
            $23.00. Motion carried. Motion made by Trustee Brehmer and seconded
            by Trustee Y aeger that the wages o f village man labor be set at
            35c an hour and wages fo r man and t am be set at fiOc an hour.
            Motion carried. Trustee Brehmer introduced a resolution that Aug.
            Benz be permitted to connect at any time to the village water and
            sewer mains at his own expense, plus the regular added connection
            charge of $25.00. Resolution carried. Motion made by Trustee Haufe
            and econdcd by Trustee Hanson that John Y aeger be appointed village
            marshal, water and sewer superintendent and street and weed
            commissioner at the monthly salary o f $85.00, and that Harold
            Danback be appointed his assistant at $70.00 per month. Motion
            carried. Upon motion the board then adjourned. L U T H E R E N G L U
            N D , Clerk. Smallpox Vaccination Clinics Two smallpox vaccination
            clinics will be held in Shawano County next Monday, May 8. The first
            om will be held at the Bowler School at 9:00 to 10:00 and the other
            at the Eland State Graded School from 11:00 to 12:00. The
            vaccinations will be given by local physicians and assisted by Miss
            Laura Gollnick, county nurse. All parents are urged to have their
            children vaccinated from nine months o f age and up. Large Audience
            Enjoys Operetta I “ Melinka of Astrakan,” a Russian operetta by
            Charles Ross Chaney, pleased a large crowd in the high school
            auditorium last Friday evening. Lyrics anti music were under the
            direction o f E. W’ . Born. I/»uise W estlund furnished the piano
            accompaniment.. The cast »neluded: Kerm it Johnson as General
            Ivanoff, Virginia Schlytter as Melinka. his daughter, Gordon Laude,
            U. S. salesman, Ruth Zeinert, an aviatrix; Jean Gates, American
            college girl; Marcella Bloecher, an American novelist; Lyman Laude,
            as Captain Arensky; Kenneth Denn, as Corporal Zuiski; Luther Mason,
            a Bolshevik; Delmar Treptow, Jewish salesman; Herman Hoffman,
            Chinese business man; Florence Fitzgerald and Lois Johnson,
            Melinka’s body guards; Kenneth Gunderson, messenger. Those taking
            part in the chorus as Cossacks were Harold Bessette, John Derrow,
            Paul Graber, Robert Haupt, Theodore Hoekstra, Donald Iverson,
            Willard Hartleben, James Ursin, Rodney Wincentsen, Robert Hoekstra.
            Chorus Soldierettes: Dorthea Brunner, Naomi Boerger, Violet Iverson,
            Elaine Brunner, Angeline Casetta, Beatrice Gunderson Thelma
            Gunderson. Mildred Benson, Martha F itzgerald, Miriam Schlytter,
            Joyce Thorson, Shirley Berg, Marilyn Maack, Leota Treptow, Lucille
            Hoffman, Mildred Stewart, Agatha Erickson, Mildred Jensen, Alice
            Ursin, Mary Ellen Warner. American girls: Lorraine Bessette, Annette
            Johnson, Eunice Brunner, Dorothy Sprangers, Joyce Timm, Juanita
            Vandenburg, Marjorie W estgor, Ardel Kersten, Mae Siebert. Dancer:
            Ruth Christensen. Chinese girls: Mary Jane Christensen, Dorothy
            Olsen, Margaret Turecek. Scouts: Ted Derrow, Ray Oestreich, Carl
            Voelz, George Leo Voelz. The following comprised the production
            staff: Business manager, Alex Derrow; scenery builder, Ray H
            alverson; scenery painter, Ray Oestreich; ■’posters made, Thelma
            Gunderson, Martha Fitzgerald; stage managers, | Ronald Hempel, Ray
            Oestreich and Ray Halverson; electrician, Ray Halverson. The
            costumes were made by Mrs. Mark Hitzke. The school orchestra made
            its first appearance with the following members: Louise Westlund,
            Clara Schulz, Alice McConley, Harold Sundet, Bruno Johnson, Joyce
            Timm, George Leo Voelz, Geraldine Black, Ray Halver- I son, Lucille
            Ackerman, Carl Voelz, Arline Black, Johnny Larson, Evelyn Jannusch,
            Dorothy Plesser, Wilmer Wi rth, Charles Behnke, Marjorie Hitzke.
            Johnny Yaeger, Bernhardt Anderson, Royal Harvey. Talent Show
            Arrangements were completed during the past week b ythe Morris
            Farmers Club to stage a new kind o f ing the past week by the Morris
            community talent show, called “ A Hillgiven for two nights at the
            Morris I Fanners Club House on Thursday and Friday, June 1 and 2. “
            A Hillbilly Wedding,” is described as a hilarious evening of
            laughter and gaiety in which the country people from this entire
            vicinity will be invited to participate. T H E W IT T E N B E R G
            ENTERPRISE. W ITTEN BER G . WIS. ------ W e e k ly N e w s A n a ly
            s is --------------------------- C.O.P. Frowns on Early Booms While
            Wooing Insurgent Dems -B y J o s e p h W . L a B in e - EDITOR S
            NOTE—When opinions are expressed in these columns, they are those of
            the news analyst, and not necessarily ot the newspaper. Politics To
            stand a chance of winning 1940’s presidential election,
            Republicanism ’s two biggest jobs fo r 1939 ore (1 ) stopping any
            prem ature boom which might shatter party unity, and (2) win support
            from D em ocratic leaders who have abandoned the N ew Deal. These ob
            jectives clash because few D em ocrats w ill desert their
            traditional political faction for nothing m ore stable than the hope
            that a suitable candidate can be found. But the G. O. P. is tackling
            both jobs with fingers crossed : Candidates. Most favored
            presidential nominee is youthful N ew Y o rk District Attorney Thom
            as D ew ey, whose sensational racketbusting record is offset in
            veteran political minds by the realization S E N A T O R T A F T . .
            . uelcom ed an “ insultinn ultimatum." that he has no adm
            inistrative experience. Second choice is M ichigan’s able Sen.
            Arthur Vandenberg. T r a iling fa r behind are Ohio’s ambitious Sen.
            R obert T a ft, his home sta te’s G ov. John W. B ricker, and ex- P
            residen t H erbert Hoover. Since m ost danger of a premature boom
            centers in Washington, m inority leaders in both houses (O regon ’ s
            Sen. Charles M cN ary, Massachusetts’ Rep. Joseph M artin ) are
            reportedly urging their colleagues to avoid com m itm ents. On the
            G. O. P . calendar are party dinners, each o f which w ill hear a
            potential candidate. One such affair, originally scheduled to hear
            both Candidates T a ft and B ricker, was split two w ays when G
            overnor B rick er’ s c a m e took grea ter importance. Coalition.
            Possibility o f D em ocratic support for a Republican candidate
            started during last autumn’s “ pu rge” and grew when President R
            oosevelt plumped for liberalism o ver partisanship. This season's
            reb el congress gave it m ore impetus, and in late A pril Mr. Roosev
            e lt told junior Jackson day celebrants via letter that the D em
            ocratic party must uphold N ew Dt principles to win next year.
            Seizing the cudgel, 'Ohio's T a ft labeled the letter an “ insulting
            ultim atu m .’ ' Said he at a “ Republicans- on-the-March” banquet:
            “ To the President, anyone who disagrees with him is m oved only by
            prejudice and . . . is disloyal to his lord and m aster. The
            Republican party . welcom es them (anti-adm inistration D em ocrats)
            to our party councils. Th ere is no fundamental differen ce between
            us which cannot be reconciled.” M eanwhile N ew Dealers on Capitol H
            ill thought the President's letter w as highly significant.
            Louisiana’s Sen. Allen J. E llender thought Mr. R oosevelt was
            asserting aggressive leadership to block a “ reactionary candidate”
            in 1940. Pennsylvania’s Sen. Joseph GufFey thought w hat he had
            believed all along—that Mr. R oosevelt should seek a third term .
            Europe F rom his Pa ris office, thc Chicago D a ily N ew s' E d gar
            Ansel M ow rer apparently sent first word o f Der F u eh rer's cra
            fty schem e to devalua te President R oosevelt's peace appeal. The
            schem e: G erm any asked individual nations whose peace Mr. R
            oosevelt said is threatened, whether they felt m enaced by Germ any.
            Said Mr. M ow rer: ' " I t is the old tto ry of the w olf asking the
            lam b w hether it really believes that w olves som etim es eat lam
            bs.” Though Mr. M o w r e r 'i revelations ■nd subsequent diplom
            atic maneuv e rs took the edge of Herr H itler's plan, dem ocracies
            had little reason fo r glee. In the w eek preceding D er F u eh
            rer's Reichstag answer to M r. R ooseveli, both dictators and d em
            ocra cies m ade frantic efforts to line up E urope's few rem aining
            neutra ls, all of them located in the Balkans. A t negotiations’
            end, the R om e-B erlin axis had won a signal v ic to ry by the sim
            ple procedure of je rk in g a keystone—Jugoslavia— from under the
            tottering Balkan entente. H em m ed in north and south by H ungary
            and Italy respectiv e ly , the B elgrad e governm ent Joined G erm
            any, Ita ly , Spain. Hung a ry , Japan and Manchukuo in the •nti-C
            om m unist alliance, fram ed a mutual defense pact with H ungary and
            began leading a new pro-Fascist Balkan entente in which B ulgaria w
            ill be a m em ber. S trategica lly located Rum ania now becom es the
            focal point, wooed desp erately by dem ocracies as the last hope o f
            stopping a solid dictator front in southeast Europe, y et inclined
            to conform with N azi demands on pain of invasion from land-hungry
            Jugoslavia, Hungary and Bulgaria. Deeper in the Balkans, British- F
            rench alliances with G reece and Tu rkey m ay m eet sim ilar fate.
            Though expressing gratitude to the dem ocracies for guaranteeing her
            integrity, G reece has announced she seeks to rem ain on a friendly
            basis w ith the Axis powers who now threaten her entire northern
            front v ia Albania, Jugoslavia and Bulgaria. M eanwhile Turkey has
            given G erm any a contract to build her $12,000,000 new naval base
            and granted Lufthansa, Germ an airline, an operating concession. W
            ith the Balkans apparently lost j to N aziism . B ritain's last
            chance for anything like a parity o f European j power lies in the
            last-resort m ilita ry i treaty with Russia. The unexpected return
            to Berlin of Ambassador Sir | N e v ile Henderson has given rise to
            | b elief that Britain m ay seek peace 1 with the Reich rather than
            accept a Russian pact. Furtherm ore, J F ra n c e's m ove to return
            her Ger- [ m an ambassador, coupled with ru- ; m ors o f U. S. trade
            concessions to a peaceful H itler, produces a world- I w ide atm
            osphere suspiciously like the long-since discredited instrum ent o f
            "ap peasem ent.” Relief W orkers A lliance is a W P A union ! which
            thrives m ainly on contribu- j tions from a reputed 400,000 (out of
            2,756,000) U. S. reliefers. F rom its 1 Washington headquarters go
            fre- [ quent m im eographed statements for newspaper men and
            persistent lob- | byists to plague Capitol Hill. O f the latter, m
            ost famous is Theodgre Oz- | m an who had his face slapped by ; G eo
            rg ia ’s fie ry Rep. E. E. Cox during debate on the $150,000,000
            deficiency relie f bill. Workers Alliance's most famous officer is P
            re sident D avid Lasser, who last yea r drew from Aubrey W illiam s,
            then deputy W P A adm inistrator, a terrible pre-election statem ent
            for W P A consumption: “ W e’ ve got to keep our friends in pow er .
            . . The men you are going to (e le c t) should be those who stand fo
            r projects such as W P A sponsored.’ * Though H arry Hopkins
            squelched further W illiam s outbursts, David L asses’ s reliefers
            no doubt took the W illiam s advice. Whether their vote w as big
            enough rem ains to be DATE BOOK M A Y I I — M other's day, with
            Golden Rule foundation honoring Mrs. Ilia s Compton o f W ooster,
            Ohio, as "A m e r ic a n M other for 1939.” M A Y 15— K in g G eo
            rge and Queen Elizabeth of B ritain arrjve at Quebec fo r N orth A m
            e rican tour. M A Y 17— G erm any to conduct one-day census with
            750,000 voluntary workers, expected to show a ccu rately for first
            tim e the e x tent o f Jew ish em igration, M A Y SO— G en eralissim
            o F ran cisco F ran co's trium phal entry into M adrid, accom panied
            by Italian and G erm an troops. Ita lian Count G aleazzo Ciano and G
            erm an F ield M arshal Herm an G oering expected to participate.
            Asia P rim a rily an exporter o f cheap substitutes, Japan's foreign
            trade is. norm ally unbalanced on the debit side since total valu e
            o f exports falls short o f total im ports. B iggest single export,
            h ow ever, has been precious silk to the U. S., a $100,- 000,000
            annual trade which brings an a vera g e o f $50 to each of 1,815,-
            246 Jap fa m ilies raising cocoons as a sideline. But recently U. S.
            chem ists perfected nylon, a synthetic substance which threatens to
            replace Japanese silk. An im portant discovery in itself, nylon has
            upset Nippon’s business applecart fa r enough to precipitate a m a
            jo r industria l revolution. With cotton imports curtailed and its
            U. S. m arket disappearing, Jap silk production w ill becom e sm
            aller and sale restricted to dom estic m arkets. Thus forced into
            even g rea te r selfsufficiency, Japan has launched a three-year
            program o f industrial e x pansion with the double purpose of givin
            g its people hope and inform ing other nations of its strength.
            Sample production increases: M agnesium, 1.000 per cent; artificial
            gasoline, 800 per cent: dehydrated alcohol, 1.200: wool. 200: steel,
            pig iron, m achine tools, 100. N otew orthy is the heavy em phasis
            on iron ore and gasoline, both o f which have been purchased en
            tirely abroad, and both o f vrtiich w ill be needed the day Japan
            tackles Russia in a g rea t A sia tic w ar. Sam pling its first
            fruits o f conquest, Tokyo w ill depend la rg e ly on Chinese and
            Manchukuoan resources. NATIONAL AFFAIRS R e v ie w e d b y CARTER
            FIELD Taft’s G rid iro n d in n e r speech didn’t do much for his
            presidential ambitions . , . Two schools of thought on the subject
            of a European war . . . Sabre shaking here might help to keep peace
            there . . . Neu> Dealers present another of their brilliant ideas in
            the new job fixed for Edward J, Noble. T ransportation D A V ID L A
            S S E R Congress /ears Am union. seen, fo r now pending in congress
            are m easures to toss re lie f back into the states’ lap, to junk
            all present agencies for a new federal unit, and take politics out
            of relief. Wcrrkers A lliance is prim a rily interested in the
            latter. C hief puzzle facing West V irg in ia 's Rep. Clifton
            Woodrum and his re lie f subcom m ittee is whether reliefers should
            or can be denied the right to organize for a patently political
            purpose. A lread y on record are several disturbing facts. Sam ples:
            (1) Though D avid Lasser denied he is a Communist, most offlcial
            Washingtonians rate him distinctly pinkish. Workers A lliance
            Secretary- Treasu rer Herm an Benjamin boasted to com m itteem en
            that he has been a Communist for 20 years, also that he reported
            personally to Moscow last y ea r on the A lliance's activities. (2 )
            A lliancers have threatened and m ay some day exert pressure on
            congress. When President Roosevelt asked an $875,000,000 deficiency
            relie f appropriation, the A lliance asked $1,000,000,000. Congress
            coughed up $725,000,000. When thc White House asked restoration of
            the $150,000,000 cut, Mr. Lasser turned on heat and threatened to
            ballot all reliefers on a protest m arch to Washington. Probable
            outcome w ill not be an attem pt to dissolve the Alliance, but a
            hastening o f back-to-the-states legislation in the hope that
            Individual ized relie f setups w ill g ive the union less chance for
            a unified national front. On some future date all U. S. m otorists m
            ay be forced to insure against public lia bility and property dam
            age, a co vera g e at once most essential (to protect fellow m
            otorists) and m ost ignored (because o f high ra tes ). O rigin ally
            a rich m an’s insurance, “ P . L. and P . D ." was offered m ainly
            by 37 m em ber com panies of the N ational Bureau o f Casualty and
            Surety U nderw riters, who eventu#.ly began losing business to
            newer, low er priced com panies. T o recover business, bureau firm s
            have just effected new low prices in 30 states, cutting 20 to 25 per
            cent from rates charged p rivate m otorists. Thus a downw ard price
            trend has been stim ulated, which m ay eventually place liability
            rates at a point w here state legislatures can m ake this co vera ge
            m andatory without suffering undue criticism . Aviation U. S.
            isolationists to the contrary, each European dictator encroachm ent
            apparently has its repercussions on this side o f the Atlantic.
            Looking ahead, observers are now sizing up the results-to-be o f a v
            e ry likely dictator coup, the unification of Portu gal with Spain
            through an extern ally inspired revolution. T w o Portuguese landm
            arks, the A zore Islands and Lisbon, are vital stopping points on
            the southern route of P a n -A m erican ’s transatlantic air service
            which is scheduled to start this spring. O ver nearby routes from
            Europe to South A m e rica fly G erm an and Italian lines which
            would like a slice of lu crative U. S.-to-Europe a ir business.
            Since Spain’s puppet Dictator Francisco Franco would share P o
            rtugal's spoils with his two friends, G erm any and Ita ly, those
            two nations would gain aviation rights at Lisbon and the Azores,
            thereby holding a monopoly over south A tlantic airlanes. Still open
            to U. S. boats would be the northern route from N ew Y ork to
            Southampton, excellent in sum m er but risky in winter. T re m l H
            ow th e w in d is b low in g . . . C E N S O R S H IP ?— E ffe ctive
            June 7, thc British governm ent w ill assume com plete control o ver
            the British B roadcasting corporation, strictly supervising all news
            bulletins and launching an arm y-recruiting cam paign. IM M IG RA
            TIO N—Influx of aliens to the U. S., at low ebb during the
            depression, is on increase with Jew s leading the pack. F ig ures:
            35.000 Jew s have entered in the past three years. . W E A T H E R -
            U. S winters have grown m ilder since 1900, but trend w ill soon be
            to cooler, w etter phase of w eather with more rain in sum m er and
            low er tem peratures in winter. Authority: J. B. K incer, ch ief of
            U. S. w eather bureau's clim ate and crop w eather division. W A S H
            IN G T O N .— It is not perm itted to rep eat anything said in a
            speech m ad e at a Gridiron dinner, though from tim e to tim e
            history has actually been m ade by speeches at the gatherings o f
            that organ ization. But there is no ban on the com m ents o f guests
            follow ing the dinner. Consensus i««th a t Sen. R obert A. T a ft
            did not do his presidential am bitions any good by his speech at thc
            recent dinner. As a m atter of fact, one diner actually congratulat-
            ! ed Thom as E . D ew ey on T a ft's sp eech ! D ew ey,
            incidentally, who spoke at the D ecem ber G ridiron dinner, had a
            much better break all around than Taft. In the flrst place,
            President Roosevelt did not reply to D ew ey. He did not rea lly m
            ake a speech at all, just a fe w pleasant rem arks at the end o f
            the dinner. A fter T a ft's speech, h ow ever, the President m ade a
            real speech, which, according to com m ents of guests a fterw ards,
            w as a v e r y good one. In the case o f D ew ey the club follow ed
            its cu stom ary p ractice o f having one speaker from each o f the m
            a jo r parties, but, the President not wishing to m ake a regu lar
            talk, Jam es A. F a rle y had to ca rry the load for the D em
            ocrats. F a rle y was in a tough spot. H e had to m ake a speech to
            which the President would listen, which m eant that he had to be v e
            ry ca refu l about w hat he said. G en eral opinion a fterw a rd was
            that Jim did not do h im self justice, which m ade D ew ey s spot
            all the m ore a ttractive. A curious phase o f all this is that ;
            the President actually feels rather friendly, personally, tow ard T
            a ft, and dislikes D ew ey v e ry much indeed, yet as a result o f
            his own actions D ew ey w as helped and T a ft w as hurt before
            gatherings o f tre- ; mendous political im portance. Taft's Economic
            Views Anathema to Mete Dealers R oosevelt is so politically minded
            that it is just possible he "planned it that w a y .” T a ft m a y
            be personally m ore a greea ble to the N ew D ealers than D ew ey,
            but his econom ic view s are anathema. It is v e ry obvious that m
            ost o f the N ew D ealers have been m ovin g heaven and earth to
            discredit the Ohio senator for months. T a ft in the White House,
            with a sym pathetic congress, is just the last thing th e N ew D
            ealers would want to see. It might, as they sec it, bring about a
            reaction in their fa vor, w hich would sw eep them back into pow er
            four yea rs later, but they sh iver at what he would do to their
            social and economic “ refo rm s '' in the m eantim e. Many of the
            tycoons present at the Gridiron dinner w ere terribly disappointed.
            Th ey h a ve been agreeing with so much that T a ft has been saying,
            in his speeches, statem ents and radio talks, that the Ohio senator
            had obtained a considerable follow ing for his candidacy in downtown
            N ew Y ork, and in the financial districts o f most o f the big
            cities o f the country. Th ey not only liked his view s, Out his m
            agnificent showing in Ohio against N ew Deal Sen. R obert J.
            Bulkley. But since the G ridiron dinner they are rem em b ering A
            lfred M . Landon, whose view s also they a greed with. In fa ct they
            rem em b er sadly the points the Kansas governor m ade in his 1936
            speeches. But they also rem em b er the deadly dullness o f his
            speeches— how he drove a w a y votes e v e r y tim e the radio ca
            rried his voice. Which is not so good at the m om ent for M r. T a
            ft's chances. Two Schools of Thought As to a Euro/wan It ar
            President R oosevelt is being sharply criticized for his w arlik e
            utterances, even attacked fo r ‘ 'g a m b lin g " on getting this
            nation involved in casualty lists. But there is a school of thought,
            to which m any friends and m an y opponents o f the N ew Deal
            subscribe 100 per cent, that the m ore certain Mr. Roosevelt can m
            ake H itler and Mussolini that the United States w ill enter the w
            ar on the side o f Britain and France, if and when w a r comes, the
            less chance there w ill be of a big European war. Even m ore im
            portant, those holding this view believe that if the opposite is
            done— that is if H itler and Mussolini can be convinced that the
            United States w ill rem ain neutral, the probability of w ar is
            increased, and the probability that the United Stales w ill
            eventually be sucked into it w ill becom e much grea ter. The theory
            behind the support that [♦resident Roosevelt gets on this issue, on
            which he is being opposed by most Republic an leaders and by a great
            many D em ocrats, is very sim ple. We start with the assumption that
            w a r is not absolutely c e rtain— that it m ay be that a sufficient
            number o f fa ctors can prevent it— that H itler and Mussolini are
            not absolutely determ in ed to keep on until they fo rc e a g en e
            ra l conflict. I f th ii assumption is not correct, then nothing m
            atters v e r y much. Th ere w ill be w ar, and eventu ally the
            United States w ill be draw n into it. In that case nothing said at
            this tim e by P residen t R o ose velt or anybody else is im
            portant. O nly what is done by w ay o f preparation is im portant.
            But if the assumption is correct, then it would seem obvious that
            the m ore strength H itler and Mussolini know is going to be thrown
            to their enem ies the m ore chance there is that they m ay decid e
            not to risk the consequences o f w ar. Sabre Rattling in V. S. Might
            Help Keep the Peace T h ere are se ve ra l theories which seem to
            rein force the argum ent. F o r exam ple, it is believed by most arm
            y officers here that if w a r com es the pow er o f H itler w ill at
            once becom e v e ry much curtailed. T h e G erman a rm y does not
            recogn ize H itler as a m ilita ry genius. It has been backing him
            right along because o f his dem onstrated hold on the people, and
            because o f his d em onstrated pow er as a blu ffer in international
            negotiations. But with the com in g o f w ar, it is held, he would
            be sidetracked and ignored. The prestige resulting from the ear- j
            ly victories — most a rm y officers j think the e a rly conflicts
            would be G erm an victo ries— would g o to the m en who directed the
            troop m ovements. P re tty soon a new H indenburg or a new Lu
            dendorf would be the popular hero o f G erm any. Th e thought is
            that H itler must know this, and would be scarcely human if he
            relished the idea. Hence the longer he can win victories by sabre ra
            ttling, instead o f actual m ilita ry encounters, the longer he rem
            ains No. 1 man in G erm any and retains practica lly d ictatorial
            powers. Noble’s Mew Job Another Bright New Deal Idea N o one is ev e
            r going to say that the N ew D ealers do not have ideas. T h ey reek
            with them . One o f the m ost interesting involves the rea sons for
            the sudden eleva tio n o f E dw ard J. N oble, adm inistrator o f
            the c iv il aeronautics authority, to assist in adm inistration's
            program for the promotion o f business re c o ve ry as u
            ndersecretary o f the departm en t o f com m erce, a new position
            which congress w ill be asked to create. T h e answ er, it is
            explained, can be found in a public statem ent m ade by M r. N ob le
            the d a y b efore his appointment. In b rief, M r. N oble, in the
            eyes o f President R oosevelt and S ecretary o f C gm m erce H a rry
            L. Hopkins, has m ade a huge success in applying governm en t regu
            lation to one industry— the a ir lines —which a re highly com p
            etitive and a live with individual initiative. So the theory is that
            M r. N oble, having accom plished this with air lines, can spread
            out o v e r a ll lines o f business his supervision and
            coordination, and bring about the ideal econom ic state visualized
            by Rooseve lt and Hopkins— no m onopoly, plenty of com petition,
            plenty o f individual initiative, and y et com plete regulation and
            control by a beneficient governm ent! In the public statem ent in
            question, M r. N oble dw elt at length on the record m ade by the a
            ir lines during the last winter. Th e lines, he pointed out, flew m
            ore than 64,000,- 000 passenger m iles for each passenger fa tality
            betw een D ecem ber 21 last and M arch 20. T h ere was but one fatal
            accident in that period, during which the lines flew 17,863,270
            plane m iles. Th e statem ent also pdftited out that the three
            transcontinental lines and the principal north-south line flew
            50,000,000 passenger m iles this w inter without a sin gle forced
            landing. A fter recounting this record M r. N oble said: Turns It
            Into Boost for Government Regulation "T h e s e figures present a
            striking exam ple ot the w ay a highly com p etitive business, in a
            sta ge ot highly individual initiative, can co-operate with governm
            ent regulation and get results.” Much further down in the sam e
            statem ent Mr. N oble said: “ It seem s to m e that the lesson is
            obvious. Sane and w ise application o f our regu latory laws not
            only protects the public but at the sam e tim e enhances the profit
            o f the business. L ong experience has shown— and it is shown
            strikingly in the a ir transport industry— that only through the
            co-operative services o f the govern- J m ent can this kind of
            regulation pro- : duce a result that protects e v e r y body, both
            the en terprise and the citizen. I wish other business men I in this
            new day m ight learn that the I a ir transport industry has learned
            so w ell, nnd applied so w ell, on thc record it presents here tod a
            y.” A critica l exam ination o f all this m ight produce just a
            little skepti- , cism . In the first place, it is pointed out, the
            railroads also can m ak e a m agnificent showing so fa r as
            passenger m iles per fa tality are concerned. But this “ proof” that
            gov ernm ent regulation o f highly com- I p etitive enterprises is
            not ca lcu la ted to appeal to investors. Th e finan- | c ia l
            situation o f the railroads, to put it m ildly, is not bright. Also
            critics are inclined to think ] that fate had m ore to do with the j
            sm all number of fa talities in the air service this w inter that)
            govcrn m en ' j regulation. £ BcU Syndicate.—WNU Scrvicc. W isconsin
            News « Briefly Told » sa s a s ra a s A rb o r Day M ay 5— A
            proclamation Issued b y G ov. H eil set Friday, M ay 5, as A rb o r
            Day. Face* Sheriff’s Sale — A sheriff's sale o f properties o f the
            Oconto Falls P u lp Paper company has been ordered to satisfy liens
            totaling about $14,000. Properties include a dam on the Oconto
            river. Cuts Game Penalty — Minimum penalty fo r violation o f the
            hunting law s on all gam e and fish except bear, deer and sturgeon
            would be reduced from $50 to $10 by a bill that has passed the state
            senate, 13 to 14. Banking Commission Change — G ov. H eil has
            appointed A lle n G. Pflugradt, M ilw aukee building and loan
            association executive, a m em ber of the state banking commission to
            succeed P e te r J. C leary, whose term expired A p ril 1. Signs H
            ighw ay Fund B ill— Counties, towns and villages became assured o f
            an additional $2 666.904 for local roads and streets during each o f
            the next tw o years w hen Gov. H e il attached his signature to the
            b ill increasing highw ay allotments. Canning Plant Burns — Loss
            estim ated at $100,000 resulted from burning o f the office building
            and warehouse o f the Fredonia Canning fom pany at Fredonia. Ozaukee
            county. One hundred volunteer firemen fought the blaze, w hich
            destroyed 50.000 cases o f canned goods. Rosenberry W on 2 to 1— Th
            e official canvass o f the vote fo r supreme court justice shows
            that C hief Justice M arvin B. Rosenberry was r e elected b y a plu
            rality o f m ore than 2 to 1. Rosenberry received 369,176 votes, W
            illiam H. Markham had 169.819 and Gerhard A . Hagedorn 94.201. M ay
            K eep Rail Branch— Plans o f the Soo Lin e railroad to file an
            application for abandonment o f its 80- m ile branch line between
            Stevens Point and Portage have been delayed fo r 90 days. I f action
            by communities along the route point to sufficient revenue increase,
            the abandonment proposal w ill be dropped. Postmasters Named —
            President Roosevelt has sent the fo llow in g Wisconsin postmaster
            nominations to the senate fo r confirmation: Bonduel. A. W. K a
            llies; Markesan, C. G. Lockw ood: Neshkoro, B. J. Rabbltt; Osceola.
            C. E. M cC arty: R ib Lake, J. J. Voemastek: St. C roix Falls. H
            elen T. Donalds: Shell Lake. J. S. K ennedy: Siren, J. S. Dodson.
            State A rm ory Planned— Construction o f a $1,000,000 m emorial arm
            ory on the shore o f Lake Michigan at M ilw aukee was advocated by
            Adjt. Gen. Ralph M . Im m el at a conference with the M ilw aukee
            county board highw ay committee. Tentative plans for such a
            structure have been draw n by the state m ilita ry architect in
            preparation fo r the tim e when financing can be arranged. Labor B
            ejin s Battle — T w o suits filed in circuit court at M ilw aukee m
            arked the beginning o f a fight by the Wisconsin Federation o f
            Labor to have the Catlin “ anti-stranger” picketing law declared
            unconstitutional. One suit sought declaratory re lie f judgm ent
            finding*!ho la w unconstitutional and the other asked tem porary and
            permanent injunctions to restrain authorities from enforcin g the
            new law. Fight Proposed Pay Cut— Assemb lin g at Madison,
            representatives of nine state teachers’ colleges organized a lobby
            to fight pay cuts o f 8 to 10 per cent threatened for faculty
            members if the legislature sets up the appropriation recommended for
            the colleges by the join t finance committee. Protest meetings had
            been held at the schools after it was announced that the state em
            ergency board had cut facu lty salaries 5 per cent fo r A pril, M ay
            and June o f this year. T ria l Witness Suicides — When Herm an
            Bergmann, 49, failed to appear as a witness at the trial o f Joseph
            W oeful, charged w ith slaying Patrick and Maurice Healey, bachelor
            brothers, near Baraboo, thc Sauk county district attorney sent
            messengers to remind Bergmann to be in court the fo llo w in g day.
            G oing to Bergman's cabin in the “ Coon H o llo w ” district, the
            messengers I looked through a w indow and saw his body suspended
            from a beam by a rope. Acquaintances said that Bergmann had been
            brooding over the case. La b or B ill Passes—The labor bill
            tponsored by the Wisconsin Council o f A gricu ltu re received final
            passage in the legislature when the senate voted concurrence. 22 to
            11, Th e vote was along strict party lines. M cD er- I mid o f
            Ladysm ith being the only Progressive senator to line up with the m
            ajority. Th e bill sent to Gov. H eil for his signature repeals thc
            “ little W agner act" enacted by thc 1937 legislature, from which it
            d iffers vastly in defining “ u nfair" prac- | tices. The measure
            has been called a “ fascist straitjacket" by labor leaders. It
            provides for abolishment o f the present labor relations board i and
            creation o f a new quasi-judicial | em ploym ent relations board o f
            three | m em bers to be appointed by the governor and confirmed by
            thc senate. Th c board is em powered to conduct hearings, order
            election*, deter- \ m ire collective bargaining agents and make
            findings in labor disputes, j but it m ay do no investigating. W H O
            ’S N EW S T H IS . W E E K B y LE M U E L F. P A R T O N Y O R K .—
            P ro g res siv e education has been pushed around a lot lately. The
            B ellw ether Lincoln school o f N ew Y ork has been back- S . . H T
            , . , C - Of Leaving Chap other D a n i e l With$2Camera Boones o f
            t h e educational w ilderness. F rom the rig h t-c am e the ch arge
            that they just let the youngsters fool around with toys and tools,
            without rubbing in any rea l education. H ere’* a field goal for the
            other side. A t the som ewhat ultra Fountain V a lley, progressive
            school of C olorado Springs, the boy, D avid H a re, scion o f a
            highly placed N ew Y o rk fa m ily , was given ca rte blanche to
            build his education around a $2 cam era . Th e idea, as in all p
            rogressive schools of those fe w y ea rs back, was to g iv e the
            green light to any crea tive impulse. But, at 22, here is M r. H are
            w ith a N ew Y ork exhibit o f cam era portraitu re, with President
            R o osevelt am ong his subjects, and with fam ous artists and
            photographers, including Arnold Genthe, cheering him as the "L e o n
            a rd o da Vinci of the cam e r a .” Specifically, they agree that
            young M r. H are has proved indisputably that the cam era not only m
            ay be, but now is an Instrum ent o f tbe highest artistic
            expression, and that he demonstrates an absolutely new m ethod and m
            edium o f color portra it photography. H is three-lens cam era allow
            s the superim posing of color im ages, in the m anner o f the
            color-printing process, and m akes possible shading and em phasis in
            the se rvice o f m ood. His is the first and only color p o rtrait
            exhibit in the country. A rtists and prom inent society folk are
            boiling with enthusiasm o v er M r. H a re 's achievem ent. H e is a
            tall, shy, personable young man, somewhat inarticula te, as he
            filters life through a lens, and hesitant in any other fo rm of
            expression. A s was the young Lindbergh. Th ere is the sam e “ W e”
            combination here. W hether he knows the prepositions used with the
            ablative or w hether he stumbled across the " B r id g e o f A sses”
            is not revealed. U T of the lim bo of the past rises '~ , “ 01e B
            ill,” Bruce B airnsfath er’ s fam ous walrus-mustached cartoon ch
            ara cter o f World w ar days, to . . . .. . adorn recruit- * A t t r
            i t i o n jng p o s t e r be. M a rk s ‘O le B ill’ ing displayed A
            n d H is C rea tor throughout the United K in g dom . B aim sfa th
            er says his revised ch ara cter revea ls signs o f age, but, fo r
            that m atter, so does the c a rtoonist. The slow attrition o f 20
            yea rs since a slender youngster created “ Ole B ill,” in a trench
            in Flanders, has added to his bulk, had taken toll o f his thatch o
            f w avy black hair. B itterness cam e, too, as when he returned all
            his w ar m edals to the B ritish governm ent in protest against its
            treatm ent o f veterans. Somehow, despite the w ide and va ried
            exploitation of B ill— books, lectures, a play, “ The B etter O le,”
            a syndicated piece and so forth— Bruce seem ed to g e t the short
            end of it all. He is said to have received som e $10,000 out o f
            $300,000 earned by his black and white creation. Pu tting on his own
            rev iew , “ I'llo ,” he lost $40,000, and a fter that events led him
            straight to bankruptcy, liabilities $75,000, assets negligible. H e
            w as born in India o f a long line o f a rm y forebears and began
            life as an electrica l engineer. O f recen t years, what with
            lecturing, w ritin g and draw in g, life is said to have dealt m ore
            am iably by him. ----• ---- C E L E C T E D for transfer from his
            post as ambassador to Argentina to the governm ent of Gen. Francisco
            F ran co in Spain, A lexander W. Wed- O u r Ambassador * “• « * * »
            • T o Spain Packs him such assets D ip lo m a tic Bag as are im
            plied in the long experience o f a ca ree r diplom at, a m an of
            tact and diplom atic deftness, com bined with broad humanitarian
            sympathies. M r. W eddell was educated at G eo rge Washington
            university la w school and the U niversity of Catania in Ita ly.
            Appointed p rivate secretary to the m inister to Denmark in 1908, he
            entered the consular service two yea rs later as consul at Zanzibar.
            He spent two years, 1912- 14, as consul at Catania, going thence to
            Athens as consul general. R etirin g from the diplom atic service in
            1928, he returned six yea rs ago, filling various consular posts
            until V 'S appointment as am bassador to the Argentine. «■ Conjoint
            itfd NVw s Features. wMJ Scrvice. TH E W IT T E N B E R G
            ENTERPRISE. W ITTENBERG. W IS. T H E L I F E O F T H E P A R T Y BT
            ELIZABETH JORDAN B u y W a s h F a b r i c s T h a t A r e F a s t C
            o l o r , N o n - S h r i n k a b l e C H A P T E R I X —Continued H
            a le was pondering the resolution and finding additional grounds for
            it when he re-entered the Cam p a fter midnight. He had w alked
            further, been ayuay longer, than he realized. Th e house was v e ry
            quiet. H e glanced into the living-room and study. Both room s w ere
            dark. In the low er hall the sole rem aining light was that which
            burned all night in a single amber-tinted bulb. Approaching the
            staircase he rea lized that the upper hall w as sim ila rly dim. The
            m em bers o f the fa m ily w ere all in bed, or at least w ere shut
            away in their rooms. Joan and B ert must have returned long ago. His
            foot w as on the low est step when the telephone bell in the hall
            closet rang insistently. Its shrillness w as stifled by the closet's
            closed door. He doubted if Banks o r anyone else would hear it. H e
            went to the closet, closing the door behind him in an instinctive
            consideration for the sleeping household. The voice of an operator
            csm e to him. “ N ew Y ork wants M r. H a le,” it said. “ H a le is
            speaking.” " A ll right, M r. H ale. P lease hold the line.” During
            the instant that he w aited H a le glanced at his w rist watch. T w
            en ty minutes to one. H e could not im agine who had called him up
            at that hour, unless it w as K n eeland. What could Kneeland want,
            unless there had been some accident But the voice he heard next w as
            not Kneeland’s. It was a m an's voice, anxious, yet apologetic. “
            Mr. H ale,” it said, “ this is K a u fman. I ’m sorry to disturb you
            at this hour. But did you get the teleg ram I sent you today?” F o r
            an instant H a le could not rem em ber who Kau fm an was. His
            thoughts had been fa r rem oved from anyone named Kaufm an. His mind
            busy with that problem he answered autom atically, “ N o, I haven’ t
            rece ive d any teleg ra m .” T h e voice becam e m ore urgent, less
            apologetic. I t said: “ T h at’ s what I w as afraid of. I ’ ve been
            pretty busy e v e r since I sent the telegram this noon. But a fter
            I got to bed I rem em bered that you told m e you w ere several m
            iles from a telegraph office. You said m essages w eren ’t alw ays
            delivered prom ptly, or even telephoned. When I began to think that
            over, I decided to call you up.” " Y e s ? ” H a le’ s scalp was
            prick ling. H e had rem em bered now who K au fm an was. “ What w as
            in that te le g r a m ? '1 he jerk ed out. ' “ I told you in it that
            the analysis o f the m ilk you sent m e showed a sm all quantity of
            bichloride of m ercu ry. It w asn't much. I t w asn’t anyw here near
            a killing dose. But, you see, I rem em bered that w ater you sent m
            e for analysis. Th at w as p retty serious and— ” “ N ev er mind the
            w ater,” H ale interrupted. " T e ll m e about the m ilk. B
            ichloride o f m ercu ry is a deadly poison, isn't it? ” H e did not
            recog nize his own voice. “ Y es , it is. T h at’s w hy I
            telegraphed. It w as a sm all quantity, but it has no place in m
            ilk. A fte r that w ater analysis— ” A t an e x clam ation from H
            ale the vo ice went on hurriedly, “ W ell, it’s the sort of thing
            that suggests to a suspicious mind like m ine— taken in connection w
            ith the w ater analysis—that som eone who doesn’ t like you is givin
            g you ve ry sm all doses o f poison. T h e y ’ re so sm all they m
            ay not show any serious effects fo r som e tim e. Y ou looked pretty
            husky the day I saw you. Still, if th ey 're kept up long enough— ”
            " T h e y ’ll kill in the end? I see.” “ T h ere’s no im m ediate d
            an ger,” the vo ice went on, “ unless the doses a re increased. But
            I telegraphed you at once. Then when I thought it o v er I got
            fussy.” “ Thank God you did. Thank you, too, Kaufm an. I wpn’ t fo
            rg e t it. Is there anything else you ought to tell m e about it? ”
            “ Only to la y off m ilk fo r a while, and keep both eyes op en ." K
            a u fm an's voice w as now quite ch eerful. H aving done his duty as
            he saw it he was ready to drop the m atter and g et hack to bed. “ W
            ait a minute. T h ere’s one thing m ore on m y m in d ." H ale asked
            his next question in a voice that was not quite steady. “ You say
            there w as only a little poison in that m ilk. Mow many such doses
            could a person take before— ” “ B efore it killed? Oh, quite a lot.
            I f I'm right in m y guess, the plan w as to give it In such sm all
            doses, o v er a long period, as to cause a v e ry gradual fa ilin g
            in the patient; something that would look like what used to be
            called 'a slow d eclin e.’ T h e effects va ry in differen t
            patients, but th ey 're the sam e as those ot any slow poison—
            gastric disturbance, indigestion, lassitude, that sort of thing. T h
            e special efTect i i on the kidneys. It m ight go on for w eeks or
            even months before an acute m arasm us developed. T h « plan in such
            cases is to have the patient die a seem ingly natural death by
            gradual stages. H ave you had m any doses?" “ No. Thanks again,
            Kaufman. Good-night." H ale hung up the receiver. He seem ed to be
            in a dream — a nightm are. Th e whole situation had unfolded before
            him and he w as numbed by it. He put it to him se lf in
            unconsciously m elodram atic term s; “ M y God, there’s a killer am
            ong u s !” Th e words echoed in his brain like a refrain, w hile his
            hurrying feet carried him to Joan’ s door. H e rem em bered the
            strange visitor to that room — the visitor who had seem ed a nightm
            are. He rem em bered Joan’ s sym ptom s, the seen Joan sit up in bed
            as she herself leaned over the sm all table at the head o f that
            bed. She had e x pected recognition, discovery. Then, as now, her
            distorted face must have shown not so much fe a r as frenzy, even
            fury, at the interruption. She tried to push past Hale, but he held
            her firm ly. “ What have you got in your hand?” he asked in a low
            voice. It was something she was trying to conceal by twisting her
            right arm out o f his grasp and hiding her right hand behind her
            back. Taking a stronger grip on her left arm he seized that
            struggling left hand and wrenched from it the bottle it held. A
            glance at the label was Looking back at her, trying to grasp the
            incredible fact that it w a* rea lly Miss Hosanna who sat opposite
            him, Miss Hosanna from whom he had taken that bottle, H ale told him
            self the tableau was grotesque. Miss Hosanna's plump form was
            encased in a dark dressing-gown, shapeless and rather heavy for so w
            arm a night. On her head was a g ray net, evidently designed to keep
            in position a ring of curling pini in her hair. H er face shone with
            the rem ains of a coating of retiring cream , which had not been
            wholly wiped off. The purplish color that had suffused it during her
            brief struggle had faded almost to its norm al hue She would have
            looked as harmless as the oink sofa cush- “ Isn 't it a fa r stran
            ger thing tbat you are doing. Miss Hosanna?” asked Hale. doctor’ s
            uneasiness. H e rem em bered everyth in g . . . H e did not know
            what he w as to do when he reached her door. He stood before it,
            considering the question. W ake her up and ask her if she w as all
            right? Idiotic. He had no reason to b elieve she had drunk any m ilk
            that night. Indeed, now that he considered the m atter, he had e v e
            r y reason to feel that she had not done so. His w arning to her had
            been im perative, and she had prom ised to heed it. F rom tom orrow
            she would be safe. He would take her to Doctor Crosby ea rly in the
            morning. Both would h ave to know what he had learned. Th at much
            was certain. In the m eantim e, she was safe. O r was she? H e could
            not lea ve the door. H is fe e t would not ca rry him away. His
            brain would not direct him to m ove. H e could not stir until he
            knew that all was w ell with her. H ow could he get that knowledge
            without disturbing her? His hand closed on the door-knob, turned it
            softly. He did not expect that the door would open. She had prom
            ised to lock it regu larly, and the m em ory o f thst nightm are she
            had dw elt on would surely m ake her do so. But, incredibly, the
            door opened. He widened the opening slightly and noiselessly, and
            peered in, looking toward Joan's bed. He g a v e no thought to the
            possibility of being discovered in such a situation, but he did not
            cross the threshold. Indeed, the narrow opening did not allow that.
            He would m erely m ake sure that Joan w as sleeping, and go back to
            his quarters with an easier mind. C H A P T E R X Th e room was so
            dark that fo r a m om ent he could see nothing. Then, as his eyes
            becam e accustomed to the blackness, he saw the dim outlines o f the
            two windows opposite him. He glanced toward the bed. It w as
            occupied and he heard quiet breathing. It was not until then that he
            saw something else. Something ve ry close to him, at his right,
            between him and the head of the bed. It turned with a low gasp, cam
            e tow ard him with a little rush, w renched the door-knob from his
            hand by a strong pull on the inside, and slid through the opening,
            closing the door behind it. It had m oved with such rapidity that it
            struck against him as it cam e. He recoiled a step, then caught its
            arm and held it. F or an instant it struggled fra n tica lly but in
            silence. Then, under his unyielding grip, it collapsed. In the
            hall's dim light H ale stared down into the convulsed face of M iss
            Hosanna. H e knew now what fa ce Joan had seen in her nightm
            are—that face fa m ilia r, y et terrible, whose identity she would
            not confide to him. Then, as now, Miss Hosanna had been startled
            during her visit. She bad enough. H e dropped the bottle into his
            pocket, kept his hold on her w rist, and drew Miss Hosanna along the
            hall toward his own quarters. When they had reached his room he
            stopped, opened the door, and m otioned her to precede him. She held
            back. “ What do you w ant?” Th e question was almost inaudible. She
            had trouble in form ing the words with her stiff lips; but her head
            was erect and her pale eyes burned into his. H e answered under his
            breath. “ A little talk with you. Miss Hosanna. W e can't talk here
            in the hall, you know.” She hesitated another second, then crosscd
            the threshold. When they w ere inside the room he closed and locked
            the door. H e drew fo rward a chair for her, and seated him self
            facing her. "N o w ,” he said ve ry quietly, “ w e 'll get to the
            bottom o f this. What does it m ean?” Miss Hosanna was already
            getting herself in hand. She straightened in her chair, and stared
            at him with icy resentment. ion to which her brother had com pared
            her, if it had not been for her burning eyes. Her manner had
            something o f its usual dignity. He had a lw ays known that she had
            courage. N ow she proved that, aside from her mom ent of panic, she
            also had self-control. She took the aggressive at once. "T h is is a
            strange thing for you to do, M r. H a le,'' she said between
            straight lips. “ Isn’t it a far stranger thing that you are doing,
            Miss Hosanna?” H ale asked the question very quietly, holding her
            eyes. He sat facin g her like a gray rock, but he w as inw ardly
            shaken and appalled. Miss Hosanna! Miss Hosanna! “ I suppose I was
            walking in my sleep .” H er head was erect now, her shoulders back.
            She radiated defiance. “ I guess you’ ve heard of sleep-walking
            before,” she ended. " I have. But I don’t rem em ber hearing of
            anybody who went about poisoning others in their sleep.” I T O BK C
            O N T IN U E D ) M ilk Churned by Lurching o f ‘Ship o f Desert,’ W
            a s E a rly W a y o f M ak in g Butter Cam els m ay be ugly and
            ill-tem pered, but those of us who like plenty of butter on our
            bread ow e them a debt o f gratitude nonetheless, asserts M artha
            Harm on in the Ph ila delphia Record. M ore than 20 centuries ago,
            men used goat and sheep m ilk butter. According to tradition, the
            Arabs m ade the first butter accidentally aided by the aforesaid cam
            els. Milk was carried in skin bags on jou rneys across the desert
            and the jo lting o f the cam els as they lurched along churned the
            liquid into a buttery mass. N ot the sort of butter w e are
            accustomed to use, w e’ ll adm it, for it was fluid enough to be
            poured slow ly from the skin*. Th e people o f India still m ake
            butter by shaking m ilk in bottles, producing a d a y’ s supply at a
            tim e, because the poorer folk there have no m eans of keeping foods
            fresh in refrigera tors or even in running stream s o f cold w ater,
            as do our cam pers. Just because Am erican s have a prejudice in fa
            vo r of butter made from cow ’s m ilk, with m argarin e or oleom
            argarine as substitute when the fa m ily purse grows lean, doesn’t
            im ply that the rest o f the world shares our taste. Even in this
            country there is considerable im portation of goats’ m ilk butter fo
            r persons o f G reek or Italian origin, as w ell as others from the
            M editerranean regions. O live oil is another fa vorite for a bread
            “ sp rea d " in lands where i olives grow. Many vegetarians ini sist
            on nut butters. U p in the A rctic the Eskim os have a decided
            penchant for blubber as the fam ily fat supply. W here butter is m
            ade in quantity fo r com m ercial purposes, the separator has
            superseded the old method of allowing m ilk to stand in shallow pans
            in a cool place until the cream rises and then putting the latter
            into a hand churn to worn and stir about in a modern version of the
            original cam el method. B y C H E R IE N IC H O L A S C L A S S I F
            I E D D EPARTM ENT R E M E D Y IINATION I M l n i i u m , f is t u l
            a , a ii ■ i l l f c V Other RECTAL TROUBLES I I k b V and Varicose
            VtiuCorrtel«4 WITHOUT OPERATION K T / n m ? * " * 00 I f S * / f r r
            * - WrxU Today It WiU I'ay You D r.G .F . M ESSER D a y - E v e n i
            n g B o l e r o D o n e i n J i f f y K n i t I T IS no wonder that
            sm art cot- * tons and other wash m aterials have attained to dizzy
            heights of style prestige, which is especially true this season, for
            they are am azingly lovely and versatile, and tune to e v ery
            occasion, form al or informal. H ow ever, their attractiveness is by
            no means their ch ief lure, for the really grand and glorious thing
            about most modern washables is the promise they ca rry of being both
            fast color and non-shrinkable. Modern science has worked m iracles
            in this particular. Which should be particularly encouraging to
            mothers who are outfitting little daughter with pretty new dresses
            for spring and summer. F or peace o f mind it is only necessary to
            demand, when buying wash m aterials, the kinds that carry non-fade
            and non-shrink assurance. The m aterials that go to make up the
            charm ing dresses pictured take on added interest when you know they
            w ill not fade neither w ill they shrink. F or everyd a y w ear in
            classroom and happy ca refre e hours of the day the shirtm aker
            dirndl type dress shown to the right couldn't help but satisfy the
            pride of most any little style-alert girl. It is made of a
            sanforized-shrunk slub broadcloth in a sm art triple stripe design,
            with white collar and trim on the sleeves. Shopping in wash-fabric
            sections these days is as refreshing an experience as walking
            through gardens abloom with spring flowers. The Swiss voile florals
            especially make you feel just like that, thev are so realistically
            flower-patterned in colors that are breathtaking in beauty. I f
            there is one sort of frock more than another that w ill m ake a
            dainty little maiden look her prettiest it is a dress o f
            flower-printed sheer and to prove it the adorable child to the left
            in the picture says invitingly, "look at m e !" She is w earing a
            dress of fairyspun lawn, which, being pre-shrunk, w ill wash like a
            dream , and w hat’s m ore the beautiful print is fast color, assured
            by the use of vat-dye. You can get these dainty, sheer lawns in the
            newest color schemes, both in flowered and conventional patternings.
            Th e shops show dresses made up that are surprisingly inexpensive,
            and so pretty you w ill want several. Which all goes to show the
            chic, the charm and the dependable w earableness of the wash m
            aterials that go to make up the new showings. By the w ay, had you
            heard that ging ham is making style-high fashion news for spring and
            summer? Not only are little girls wearing it with their usual
            enthusiasm for this ever attractive and colorful wash w eave, but
            mother and big sister are ordering tailored suits made o f it, for
            fashion decrees gingham as fashionable to w ear about town, at the
            club and to bridge parties or wherev er you go during the active
            rounds of the day. Gingham a'.so is the “ p e t" of the teen age for
            party and prom evening frocks. Speaking of frocks for party w ear,
            when you go fabric-seeking be sure to look over the showings o f
            cloque organdies. C W estern N ew sp a p e r Union. Pattern No. 6149
            This bolero’s got what it takes— to m ake you the star. Pu ff
            sleeves (so fem in in e!) and a lacy stitch that rolls off your hook
            with am azing speed! Use two strands of cotton. Pattern 6149
            contains directions for m aking the bolero, also illustrations of it
            and of stitches; m aterial requirements. T o obtain this pattern,
            send 15 cents in coins to Th e Sewing C ircle, Household Arts Dept.,
            259 W. 14th St., New Y ork, N. Y. P lease w rite your name, address
            and pattern number plainly. G o o d Counsel N o man is so foolish
            but he m ay g ive another good counsel som etimes, and nr. man so w
            ise but he m av easily err, if he takes no other counsel than his
            own. He that was taught only by him self had a fool for a m aster.—
            Ben Jonson. How Women in Their 40’s Can Attract Men Here's good
            sdvlce for a woman during change (usually from 38 to 62), who fi her
            ___ _______ __________ __. Tura ■ha'll I**••• her appeal to men, who
            worries about hot Sashas, loss of pro. d l « y spalls, upset nerves
            and n o o d y spells. G et more fresh air, 8 hrs. sh-ep and if you
            need a icood general system tonic take L y d ia K. Pinkham’ s
            Vegetable Compound, made for yomrn. I t helps Nature build re. thus
            hei. _ to enjoy life snd assist rslm ing snd disturbing symptoms t
            hat Y o k e a n d P l e a t s They H ave Teeth Pulled In Finland,
            and Like It! A h ! One spot under the sun w here there is pcace
            between the sexes. The men don't beef when the ladies take their
            jobs. They don’ t w rite to the newspapers. In (act, they rather
            like it. This strange state of affairs exists in Finland and the
            profession the wom en have taken over is dentistry. Wom en have
            practically a monopoly on the dental offices in Finland, it is said
            It's a country where you don't need an advertising cam paign to get
            you to see your dentist at least tw ice a year. But the girls don't
            stop at dentistry in Finland. Most of the banking jobs are held by
            women. They are also stenographers and secretaries. And politics has
            attracted m any women. M ore and m ore Am ericans are com ing to
            Finland as tourists. And a lot o f them like Lapland, where you can
            play golf 24 hour* a l a y in Ui* sunshine. R i b b o n R u f f l e
            s t o T r i m C h a n e l S u i t I Chanel trims a superb dressy
            suit i with applique o f tiny ribbon ruffles, around the collar,
            down the front, and around the low er edge o f the 1 jacket and
            sleeves. The jacket doesn’t meet, so a sparkling white gilet shows
            at the front. Th e skirt is slightly gathered and has a row of
            ribbon applique down the front. From Molyneaux comes a suit that j
            combines a rose-colored box jacket with a skirt of soft brown. The
            jacket has revers and pockets of brown. uifphysfral resistance,
            helps give more T in d t jr ‘ - — * — jittery m often accompany cl W
            O K T li T R Y I N G ! Firm Foundation Constancy is the foundation
            of virtues.— Francis Bacon. HiWAfiiji? iiu a u '« H Bowela r you
            think all Uxatlrss , . ct alike. }us» try tbla ' ell vegetable
            lasetbre. (to mlid. thorough. Dependable rettsC sick headschst M M
            speOfc tired tesllag when assnetated with eonetlpntion. ______ W i t
            h o u t Make* th e * u e t^ lb ig If not delighted, return tbe bo*
            to us. Ws wil* refund th e purchase QUICK REUEF FOR MID /INDIGESTION
            Prom pt Prudence Prudence is of no service unless It be prompt.—
            Francis Bacon. H a t S h a p e s M o s t I m p o r t a n t I t e m
            This spring the shape of a hat will be m ore important than its trim
            ming. Straws are spreading out, enormous brims in odd
            shapes—palettes, or shovels or fans. Others, halo style, are tied on
            with bandanas, m am m y style. Doll hats— if you still like ’em —in
            straw with stiffly starched veils; the inevitable * hool girl
            sailor; felts, their crowns blocked in odd shapes; straws with brims
            like royal crowns, w ill ali be good. mKILLS MANY INSECTS O N F I O
            W t R S • V R U IT S V IG E T A I'.E S k S H R U I S Demand original
            iM l«d koltlM, from your dtalor WNU—S 18—39 Pleating continues to
            add infinite charm to the m ajority o f print silk dresses. H ere is
            a fashionable P e r sian design silk print in bayadere striped
            treatment. The silk for this attractive afternoon frock has cool lim
            e green and black as its color scheme. N ovel pleating lends
            interest to the skirt front. The patent leather belt o f corselet
            interpretation repeats the colors o f the print. Notice the waist is
            made with a yoke which i i a styling greatly em phasized this
            season. R e c e n t A r r i v a l i n M i l l i n e r y R e a l m ;
            One of the latest arrivals in the i domain of hats is the black felt
            sail* j or with rolled brim —the padre styli with very flat crown
            and slightly up- j turned brim on each side. To re- i lieve its
            severity and give it a dis tinctly feminine touch, it is draped j
            with a cyclamen-pink mesh veil I gathered at the shallow crown tc
            fall loosely over the face. a d v e r t i s i n g I I V Is u
            essential K to business as is rain to K growing crops. It is the T■
            keystone in the arch of ■ H successful merchandising. 1 Let us show
            you how to N apply it to your business. O PAGE FOUR THE WITTENBERG
            ENTERPRISE. WITTENBERG, WIS. _______ Thursday. May 4, 1939 T h «
            Wittenberg Enterprise JOHN E N G LU N D . Editor I'uhlixhrd Every
            Week On Thursday $2.00 Per Year. Cask In Advance. T e l e p h o n e
            6 3 - 2 National Advertising Representative A M E R IC A N PRESS A S
            S O C IA T IO N Member Wisconsin Pfess Association Entered as matter
            o f the second class at the Wittenberg:. Wis., postoffice November
            23, 1893. C o n trib u te Hu ‘Spud* on “ A T o w n F o rest” A
            certain eccentric character earned fame and the name of Johnny
            Appleseed hy traveling over western Pensylvania and Ohio scattering
            apple seeds. Whenever he came upon a fertile, well-watered spot,
            there he planted his seed, und the little orchards which sprang up
            he tended on his later visits. Fantastic as were his methods,
            certain parts o f Ohio look upon him as a benefactor. Wm. Seatyook
            writes in a recent magazine an article on Town forests that pay. I
            quote: “ When the children of Russell, Mass., grow up. they will
            live in their town tax free. Town costs will he borne by Russell’s
            tewn forest which was begun only 15 years ago with less than 100
            acres and an appropriation o f $100. Russell is just one of 1800
            American towns that own forests. These forests cover 3.000,000 acres
            in 27 states, and their number has more than doubled since 1933. W
            hy? Because they pay. And almost aay town can have one.” How did
            Russell acquire its town forest ? Fifteen years ago there were many!
            farms near Russell whose taxes were a burden to the owners. It was
            costing the town plenty to keep roads open in winter and get the
            kids to school fo r the few' struggling families that remained. So
            the town fathers used the money to move the backwoods J families to
            good land nearer town, i Everybody was happy and the aban- \ doned
            farms became the town forest. Most o f it was already wooded. Thej
            open fields were planted with 246,000 J young pines. The forest is
            already paying, ^aid Mr. Parks, and when his grandchildren grow up.
            after the lum-. ber comes in, thev will live tax-free in Russell.”
            "P ro f. R. R. Holds worth exclaimed: “ W hy. man. I could preach a
            whol«*j sermon on town forests.’ ‘What would i your text b e?’ I
            asked. T h e y pay.’ he 1 replied.” “ They pay,” he said, not m
            erely in j dollars and cents but in a deep socialj and spiritual
            way. In run-down rural communities what was once a source j o f
            wealth can be made so again. When town forests are managed as cropj
            units, they can produce annual yields] o f fire wood, and yields o f
            lumber* every fiw years. . . . A town forest j insures the
            permanence of an industry | dependent on a permanent supply of wood.
            “ More and more states are coming! to realize the importance o f
            small j community-owned forests and are passing laws to encourage
            them. Your | own *tate forester can probably tell j you how to start
            one in your town. I f j he can’t, the U. S. Forest Service, in j
            Washington, can. T «u r town could not make a better investment for
            its j future. I f humanity survives, trees' too must survive. Our
            destinies arei interlocked, and parallel.” How about a town forest
            for W ittenberg? Surely we have enough lanl sold for taxes . . .
            surely we have need j o f a tree planting program . . . surely | it
            would be a fine thing if in the next I few decades we could look
            forw ard to reduced taxes. A town forest is something the village
            board might well j consider seriously planting. They might
            incidentally enjoy the esteem ofj posterity that Johnny Appleseed is
            accorded. BR UH N SCHOOL Mr. and Mrs. John Bamke o f M ilwaukee
            visited relatives and friends in this community Sunday. Mr. and Mrs.
            Leo Wojciehowski and daughter Verna and Mrs. Verna Buss spent Monday
            afternoon at Antigo. Mr. and Mrs. Albin Ostrowski and children spent
            Sunday afternoon visiting relatives in the Town of Reid. Mrs.
            Bertina Olsen and Belma and John Olsen visited at Bowler Sunday. Mr.
            and Mrs. Louis Balthazor, Mr. and Mrs. B**n Omernick. Grace and
            Elaine Seefeldt and Beverly Hansen spent Monday evening with Lester
            and Mabel Balthazor at Tigerton. Mr. and Mrs. Leo Wojciehowski and
            daughters, June and Verna, and Mrs. Verna Buss were dinner guests at
            the Paul Buss home at Eland. Mr. and Mrs. Wojciehowski were sponsors
            for the latter’s infant daughter, Mary Ellen. Mr. and Mrs. Jonas
            Halverson and children, Roy and June, spent Sunday afternoon with
            Mrs. I^ouis Johnson at Elderon. Mr. and Mrs. Paul Seefeldt and
            children visited relatives at Split Renk and Shawano Sunday. Miss
            Constance Carmody, rural nurse, examined the children at school
            Tuesday morning. WHITCOMB Mr. and Mrs. Frank Montabaum and daughter
            o f Tomahawk were visitors at the T. W. Treptow home F r iday. M r.
            and Mrs. John Cook of Oshkosh, Mr. and Mrs. A rvil Low and son
            Leland o f Tigerton were Sunday visitors at the Harriet Becker home.
            Mr. and Mrs. Otto Boerger and fam ily. Mr. and Mrs. Adolph Tra tz
            and fam ily o f Shawano were Sunday visitors at the H arry Soper
            home. T. W. Treptow and son Teddy visited the form er’s daughter,
            Mrs. Max Garman, at Forreston, 111., over the week-end. Mr. and Mrs.
            Clarence Hille, Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Bushen o f Clintonville were
            Sunday visitors at the Mason Buck home. Mr. and Mrs.' Louis Joubert
            and daughter Lois Jean were Sunday visitors at the W alter Mortenson
            home Tuesday evening. Mr. and Mrs. Carl Denn and son Kenneth visited
            at the Allan McAuly home Tuesday evening. Mr. and Mrs. Louis Joubert
            and daughter Lois Jean were Sunday visitors at the W alter Mortonsen
            home at Birnamwood. John Howe o f Elcho is spending a few days at
            the Wm. Schoening home. The Birthday Club met with Mrs. Clarence
            Stai Wednesday afternoon. Mrs. James Stewart returned home last
            Friday from North Dakota where she helped care for her father up to
            the time o f his death. Mrs. Andrew Peterson has returned home from
            the Madison Hospital where she received treatments. Fern Quick.
            Francis Stewart. Roselene Van Dorn. Raymond Becker, Wayne Joflbert,
            Erman Treptow and Mrs. E. Berglund were supper guests at the H arry
            Soper home Tuesday in honor o f Harold’s birthday. F ifty friends
            and neighbors surprised Leo Joubert on his birthday Saturday
            evening. Bunco and cards was the evening’s entertainment after which
            lunch was served. The George Quick house, better known as the C. L.
            Just house, caught fire Sunday evening. Quite a little damage was
            done to the attic and roof before the fire was put out. Mr. Korting.
            a teacher at the W’ ittenberg High School, was a visitor at the
            Whitcomb School Tuesday. Creditors Take O ver Garage Certain
            creditors recently took steps to take over the garage operated for
            the past several years by Karl H. Burke by reason o f his inability
            to meet in full certain pressing obligations. Mr. Burke is o f the
            opinion that it is very doubtful whether or not he will be able to
            make satisfactory arrangements so as to obtain possession! o f the
            property again. He has, however, made a la r g e ; number o f
            friends during his stay here and has met with so many assurances by
            local patrons that they would continue to patronize him in case he
            continues that it is his intention to continue work as a mechanic in
            this field and is at the present time considering making a new
            connection in this village. (F irs t pub. A pril 20; last May 25.)
            Notice o f Foreclosure Sale L A W N M OW ERS sharpened and repaired
            at Albert Hartleben’s shop, Wittenberg. All work guaranteed. (F ir s
            t pub. A pril 13; last May 18.) Notice o f Foreclosure Sale State o
            f Wisconsin, in Circuit Court Branch o f Shawano County Court, for
            Shawano County. The Federal Farm M ortgage Corpora-1 tion, a
            corporation. Plaintiff, vs. Ervin Maas and F. C. Maas, Defendants.
            Notice is hereby given, that under and by virtue o f a judgment o f
            fo reclosure and sale made in the above entitled action on the 25th
            day o f March, 1938, the undersigned. Sheriff j o f Shawano County,
            State o f Wiscon- j sin, will sell at the sheriff’ s office in ! the
            Courthouse, in the C ity of Shawano, Shawano County, Wisconsin, on
            the 27th day o f May, 1939, at 10:00' o’clock in the forenoon o f
            that day, the real estate and mortgaged prem- 1 ises directed by
            said judgment to be sold and therein described as follows: j The
            North One-half (N V i) o f the Northwest Quarter (N W 1* ) o f
            Section Number Twenty-six (2 6 ), Township Number Twentyseven (2 7
            ), Range Number Th irteen (13 ) East, in Shawano County, Wisconsin.
            Terms of Sale: Cash. Dated this 4th day of April, 1939. C A R L D R
            U C K R E Y . Sheriff. Shawano County. Wisconsin. Aik, Kresky A
            Cohen, Attorneys, Green Bay, Wisconsin. (F irst pub. April 20; last
            May 4.) N O TIC E OF A P P L IC A T IO N FOR PR O B A T E OF W IL L
            A N I) N O T IC E T O C R E D ITO R S State o f Wisconsin, in
            Circuit Court Branch o f County Court for Shawano County.
            The*Federal Farm M ortgage C o r p o r ation, a corporation,
            Plaintiff, vs. Joe M ayef and Helen Mayer, his w ife, and William
            Wudtke, Defendants. Notice is hereby given, that under! and by
            virtue o f a judgm ent o f fo re closure and sale made in the above
            entitled action on the 6th day o f April. 1938, the undersigned,
            Sheriff o f Shawano County, State o f Wisconsin, will sell at the
            sheriff’s office in the Court House, in the C ity o f Shawano.
            Shawano County, Wisconsin, on the 10th day of June, 1939, at 10:00
            o’clock in the forenoon o f that day, the real estate and mortgaged
            premises directed by said judgment to be sold and therein described
            as follow s: Southwest Quarter o f the Southeast Quarter (SW V 4 o f
            S E 1* ) o f Section Tw enty-four (2 4 ), Township Tw enty- seven (2
            7 ) N orth o f Range Seventeen (1 7 ) East, subject to an easement
            to Wisconsin-Michigan Power Co. fo r power line as recorded in
            V’olume One Hundred Ninetynine (199), Page One Hundred F orty- six
            (14 6 ); all o f the above described premises containing F orty (40
            ) acres, more or less, in Shawano County. Wisconsin. Terms o f Sale:
            Cash. Dated this 14th day o f A pril, 1939. C A R L D R U C K R E Y
            , Sheriff. Shawano County. Wisconsin. (F ir s t pub. A p ril 20;
            last May 4.) N O T IC E O F A P P L IC A T IO N FOR P R O B A T E O
            F W IL L A N D NOTIC E T O C R E D IT O R S State o f Wisconsin,
            County Court, Shawano County. In the M atter o f the Estate of
            George Gable, deceased. Notice is hereby given that at a term o f
            said Court to be held on T 1.m i iv. the 10th day >f May. tfltta at
            10 o’clock in the forenoon o f said day at the Court House in the C
            ity o f Shawano, in said County, there w ill be heard and
            considered: The application o f Mrs. Bertha Gable for the probate o
            f the W ill o f George Gable, deceased, and for the appointment o f
            an executrix or an administratrix with the w ill annexed o f the
            estate o f George Gable, deceased, late o f the Town o f Fairbanks,
            in said County; N otice is further given that all claims against the
            said George Gable, deceased, late o f the Town o f F a irbanks, in
            Shawano County, Wisconsin, must be presented to said County Court at
            Shawano, in said County, on or before the 19th day o f August, 1939,
            or be barred; and that all such claims and demands w ill be examined
            and adjusted at a term o f said Court to be held at the Court House
            in the C ity o f Shawano, in said County, on Tuesday, the 29th day o
            f August, 1939, at 10 o’clock in the forenoon o f said day. Dated A
            pril 18th, 1939. By Order o f the Court, C. B. D IL L E T T . Judge.
            E. J. M A D L E R , Attorney. Mr. and Mrs. Earl Cowles and Juanita
            Vandenberg visited at the J. j W. Maas home Sunday afternoon and at
            the Wm. Uecker home in Caroline in the evening. (F ir s t pub. A
            pril 13; last May 18.) N otice o f Foreclosure Sale State o f
            Wisconsin, in Circuit Court Branch o f Shawano County Court, fo r
            Shawano County. The Federal Land Bank o f Saint Paul, a body
            corporate, Plaintiff, vs. L etter O. W estgor, also known as Lester
            W estgor, and Emma Westgor, his w ife, the W ittenberg National Farm
            Loan Association, a corporation, Leona W estgor Johnson, Mabel W
            estgor Kaufman, Stanley W estgor, and Esther W estgor Hanson,
            Defendants. N otice is hereby given, tbat under and by virtue o f a
            judgment o f fo reclosure and sale made in the above entitled action
            on the 25th day of March, 1938, the undersigned, Sheriff o f Shawano
            County, State o f Wisconsin, will sell at the sheriff’s office in
            the Courthouse, in the C ity o f Shawano, Shawano County, Wisconsin,
            on the 31st day o f May, 1939, at 10:00 o’clock in the forenoon o f
            that day, the real estate and m ortgaged premises directed by said
            judgment to be sold and therein described as follows: Term s o f
            Sale: Cash. The Southeast Quarter o f N ortheast Quarter (S E ‘ 4 o
            f N E 14); also the Northeast Quarter of Southeast Quarter (N E * i
            of S E 1* ) o f Section Number Tw enty- tw o (2 2 ), Township Tw
            entynine (2 9 ) North, Range Tw elve East, containing E ighty (80)
            acres, more or less, according to government survey thereof, in
            Shawano County, Wisconsin. Terms o f Sale: Cash. Dated this 4th day
            o f A pril, 1939. C A R L D R U C K R E Y , Sheriff, Shawano County,
            Wisconsin. A ik, Kresky Cohen, Attorneys, Green Bay, Wisconsin. T O
            W N S E N D P IE S O C IA L A pie social, similar to a basket
            social, will be held at the Town Hall Wednesday evening, May 10.
            Ladies please bring pie, cups and forks. Everyone welcome. A speaker
            will come fo r this occasioh. Lydia Stone, Secretary. (F ir s t pub.
            A pril 13; last May 18.) N otice o f Foreclosure Sale State o f
            Wisconsin, in Circuit Court Branch o f Shawano County Court, fo r
            Shawano County. The Federal Farm MoLtgage C orporation, a
            corporation. Plaintiff, vs. Josephine Fuller, Defendant. Notice is
            hereby given, that under and by virtue o f a judgment o f fo
            reclosure ami sale made in the above entitled action on the 25th day
            o f March, 1938, the undersigned, Sheriff o f Shawano County, State
            o f Wisconsin, will sell at the sheriff’s office in the Courthouse,
            in the C ity / o f Shawano, Shawano County, Wisconsin, on the 27th
            day o f May, 1939, at 10:00 o’clock in the forenoon o f that day,
            the real estate and m ortgaged premises directed by said judgm ent
            to be sold and therein described as follow s: Southeast Quarter o f
            Northeast Quarter (S E 1* o f N E 1* ) , South H a lf o f Southwest
            Quarter of Northeast Quarter (S H of S W 1* o f N E 1* ) , and the
            Northeast Quarter o f Southeast Quarter (X F .1* »f S E '*> . Set
            1.1on Th irtytwo (3 2 ), Township Tw entyseven (27 ) North, Range
            Eleven (11 ) East, containing One Hundred (100) acres, more or less,
            in Shawano County, Wisconsin. Terms o f Sale: Cash. Dated this 4th
            day o f April, 1939. C A R L D R U C K R E Y , Sheriff, Shawano
            County, Wisconsin. A ik, Kresky A Cohen, Attorneys, Green Bay, W’
            isconsin. T U R E C E K ’ S U B E S E E S t o r e and MODERN M EAT M
            ARKET SOME OF THIS W EEK 'S SPECIALS: F I.O t'R — Harvest Gold:
            guaranteed: try 19 lb s ............ 98c F I.O l’ R— Gold Medal—
            Special fo r 49 ths. n o w ..........$1.19 C H O C O L A T E — I ’
            BC B akin *; Ih. f o r .......................... 10c D E E RW O O D
            C O F F E E — Vacuum packed; per th .......... 29c W H E A T IE S —
            Regular 8 oz. package, now o n ly .............. 10c C A K E F L O U
            R — Deerwood feath erw eigh t. 41 oz. pkg. .191- T O M A T O E S — U
            B C; 19 oz. can s.......... :{ f o r ................... 25c I’ E A
            S — UBC No. :t size; 19 oz. cans; :t f o r ......................
            25c SO U P— UBC tall. 21 oz. cans; now 2 f o r
            .......................... 19c M IL K — Deerwood. 11*2 oz. tall: now
            4 f o r ...................... 25c S A N D W IC H S P R E A D —
            Flodlight. large 2 Ih. j a r ........ 25c C O O KIES— Rutter ('ream
            Sandwich; 2 Ihs. f o r .............. 25c P E A N U T B U T T E R —
            U B C ; a 2 Ih. ja r f o r ...................... 23c G E L A T IN D
            E S S E R T— Deerwood. .‘It , oz. pkg.. 3 fo r. .13c C A N D Y —
            Tiny, fresh Jellies, per pound o n iy ................ 10c R IN S O
            — L arge 2 3 '2 oz. pkg. fo r o n ly ..............................
            23c L U X F L A K E S — I.arge 1212 oz. pkg. fo r o n lv
            ..............23c L U X T O IL E T S O A P — Buy 3 hars fo r only
            20c L IF E B U O Y S O A P — N ow 3 hars for o n ly
            ........................ 20c O R A N G E S — 341 size, juicy Cal.
            navels; 2 dozen fo r ...2 5 c Special prices on those fine pink meat
            Grape F ru it; also on Cabbage, Pineapple, Onions. Apples, Etc. See
            our hand bills at store, and extra list o f new Specials, each and
            every week. — Subscribe for The Knlerpriae. State o f Wisconsin,
            County Court, Shawano County. In the M atter o f the Estate o f Ole
            Nelson, deceased. Notice is hereby given that at a term o f said
            Court to be held on Tuesday, the 23rd day of May, 1939, at 10
            o’clock in the forenoon o f said day. at the office of the County
            Judge, in the V illage of W ittenberg, in said County, there will be
            heard and considered: The application of W. D. Haseltine for the
            probate of the W ill of Ole Nelson, deceased, and for the
            appointment of an executor or administrator with the will annexed of
            the estate of said Ob* Nelson, deceased, late o f the Town o f
            Wittenberg, in said County; Notice is further given that all claims
            against the said Ole Nelson, deceased, late of the Town o f W
            ittenberg, in Shawano County, Wisconsin, must be presented to said
            County Court at the C ity of Shawano, in said County, on or before
            the 21st day of August, 1939, or be barred; and that all such claims
            and demands will be examined and adjusted at a term of said Court to
            be held at the Court House in the C ity of Shawano, in said County,
            on Tuesday, the 22nd day of August, 1939, at 10 o’clock in the
            forenoon of said day. Dated A pril 7th, 1939. By Order o f the
            Court, C. B D IL L E T T . Judge. W. D. H A S E L T IN E . Attorney.
            AVOID THIS with the new C U S H IO N LOCK Rubber Lined Mounting. No
            metal touches the glass. Sold by licensed dealers only. See it
            demon- strated by being dropped on the floor at the office of DR. A.
            B. SCHULTZ OPTOMETRIST N E W LO C A T IO N 310 Third St., Wausau
            First door north o f W’ inkelmans. A t W'ittenberg First Saturday o
            f Each Month. Office at Gauerke’s. M. C. CRANK Physician and Surgeon
            Office O ver Gamble Store W IT T E N B E R G , W IS. E yes Tested —
            Glasses Fitted H ow W ill Your Woodwork Look Twenty Years from Now?
            I f i Far Cheaper to Buy the Best Whether You Are Building or
            Remodeling W TO O D W O R K IS something that you buy just once. And
            tbe valuation o f your home can be greatly increased or reduced— all
            depending upon what kind you buy. 3 af Before you decide let us tell
            you about Curtis Woodwork. Let us show you doors, windows, moldings
            and trim designed ind construc ted with all the care you'd expect to
            find in the finest furniture. You will never realize how convenient
            and distinctive your home can be made until you’ve seen the wide
            variety of built-in features which Curtis has created. Regard less
            of the type af heme you plan, there areitemsofCirtisWood' work
            especially designed for that style of home. By specify ing Curtis
            Woodwork you getthchenefitof thefinest designs and choicest
            materials— at final cost no greater than ordinary millwork Ask for a
            copy of “ Curtis Woodwork” — free to interested builders. J o h n s
            o n - B u r t L b r . C o . W IT T E N B E R G , W IS. Colonial E n
            tra n ce C -lO O Pure Colonial m dtngn with a quaintness that
            attracts most favorable attention There ore many other entrances
            from which to mah/t your selections CurtiS See chat the utxxWr^ you
            buy bears this trademark — tht Curtis guarantee of FREE 2 5 * Pkg.
            OLD FASHIONED FLOWER SEEDS wilh s SOc purchw. ol v«..U bl*
            [FlwwMMure F A R I B A U L T S E E D C A S E Larson’s Food Store W
            IT T E N B E R G , W IS. D A N C E ! MAYFLOWER LAKE Sunday, N ay 7 M
            U SIC B Y B O B M A L C O L M A D M IS S IO N : G E N T S 10c; L A D
            IE S 25c BIRNAM W O O D PROM— Friday, May 12 JOE G IJM IN A N D H IS
            O R C H E S TR A SU N D A Y , M A Y 14—Joe Gumin * m v \ i\ S p « c
            i. ls foe W e e k M a y 5 T h ru 1 1 B i l l I T C a r n a tio n J m
            i L A ! 4 V i M . 4 25c T h a T r ip la C r .o m a d S h o rte n in
            g S P R Y 3 49c B A C O N TT. u. R o th 's T e n d e r 'd PICNIC S ‘
            :,tb C O R N F L A K E S S W * 2,„ F LO U R 49 N A V Y B E A N S S 3
            V « B ag 5lbs. 17c » L F ru it D apt. S » t 0RAN8ES Seedless N avels
            D o , I4c Large Ripe each P in a a p p lo . . . . 14 c ■ N ew Texas
            M ■ O n ion s . . 6 lbs. 2 5 c ■ B i Large. Crisp Stalk m ■ C E L E
            R Y ............. 8 c J S GRAPEFRUIT ■ ■ Jumbo sb e ■ i 6 23c ■ I k
            i i i i i i n n PINEAPPLE ST. N ic o le t P u re Egg COFFEESNBC
            Marshmallow Blossom C O O K I E S ............... Ib. 19c NBC
            Premium C R A C K E R S . . . Ib. box 15c Butter Cream Cookey S A N
            D W IC H E S . 2 lbs. 2 3 c Chocolate Nut C O O K I E S
            ............... Ib. 17c Chocolate Fruit C O O K I E S
            ............... Ib. 17c Lemon Fruit S Q U A R E S .......... 2 lbs.
            19c Fresh Roasted P E A N U T S .......... 2 Ibt. 19c Stanby— Pink S
            a lm o n . 2— 1 Ib. c a n t 2 5 c Schilco 38 oz. can M O L A S S E S
            .................. 17c NOODLES 14 0 s . . . . C o n Lb. C e llo . .
            . B ag Lb. 10c 10c 18c Ohio Blue Tip M A T C H E S 6 box carton
            .............2 5 c Nicolet 31 Oz. Can P O R K b B E A N S 2 fo r 25
            c Tiny. Whole. Ungraded 19 oz. W A X B E A N S . 2 c o m 29 c
            Nicolet Fancy T O M A T O E S 19 Oz. Can .......... 10c Heinz or G
            erber’s 4% oz. B A B Y F O O D S . 3 c a n t 2 5 c Keeps Drains Open
            D R A N O . . . la r g e ca n 19c My Lady Helen T O IL E T S O A P 4
            b o rt 19c Automatic 5 Lb. Box S O A P F L A K E S .............6 5
            c Kirk's Coco Hardwater S O A P ............... 3 b o rt 13c
            Schilling's Special 55c Value B R O O M S .............o n ly 4 9 c
            C A S H W A Y S T O R E S Thursday. May 4, 1939 THE WITTENBERG
            ENTERPRISE, WITTENBERG, WIS. PAGE FIVE LOCAL NEW S NOTES Raymond
            Oestreich spent the weekend at Wausau. The W alter Hubert fam ily
            moved into the Brunner house. Mis? Mildred Hartleben made a visit in
            Madison early last week. Miss Marion Van Gilder made a week-end
            visit in Goodman. Harold Olsen and Edward Guerin were in Wausau on
            Wednesday. Mrs. Frank Turecek, o f Pickerel, visited in W ittenberg
            on Friday. A gn ar Rolfson, o f Minneapolis, was a week-end visitor
            with his folks here. Mr. and Mrs. A rt Schoepke moved into the
            Cleveland house this week. Mr. and Mrs. Ervin Hanson visited at the
            Russell H ager home in Wausau Friday night. The W illard Bricco fam
            ily moved from the Gust Krueger store to the Barker house. Mrs. R.
            S. Budahl, o f Omro, was a visitor in the G. N. Holm green home on
            Wednesday. Mrs. A very Vose and children left Monday for Waukegan,
            111., for a visit with relatives. Mr. and Mrs. Roy Mech made a
            Sunday afternoon visit with his parents at Clintonville. Miss
            Bernice and Luther Christianson, o f Oshkosh, visited at their home
            near Elderon last week. Miss Lucille Kersten attended a child w
            elfare conference at Wausau on Friday and Saturday. Mr. and Mrs.
            Raymond Schulz and daughter,' Ruth, of Wausau, spent Saturday in
            Wittenberg. Mrs. Rud. Beck, o f Green Bay, visited with Miss Lejna
            Szutkowski at the Netzel restaurant yesterday. Albert and Donald
            Gunderson and Ehardt Liesch made a brief visit in Minneapolis during
            the week-end. Stanley Feuerpfeil and fam ily, of New Richmond,
            visited with relatives here from Saturday until Monday. Miss Martha
            Budahn is spending a w eik with friends and relatives in Hartford, M
            ayville and Theresa, Wis. Miss Mildred H ager and Charlotte Jacquot,
            o f Sheboygan Falls, spent the week-end with Mrs. M argaret Hag «
            r.M rs. Con Verpoorten returned home Saturday a fter spending
            several days as a nurse in the Paulson home in Norrie. A tty. W .
            I). Hpseltine was a professional visitor in Madison on Tuesday,
            attending to a Dane county probate matter. Mrs. Beatrice Dav is and
            children, of Stevens Point, were visitors in the home o f her
            parents, Mr. and Mrs. Charles Koeppen. Misses Ramona Hubert and
            Leona Szutkowski made a visit with the latter’s sister, Mrs. Myron
            Owen, at Eland last Thursday. S. Thorson has returned to his farm in
            the town o f W ittenberg after spending tw o months with his son and
            fam ily at Lake Geneva. Mr. and Mrs. Mont Walsh, o f B irnamwood,
            have moved into the Art Olson house on the east side o f town. This
            house was recently purchased by Mr. and Mrs. Walsh and has been
            redecorated. ENTERPRISE W A N T AD DEPARTMENT FOR S A L E — New
            Eureka vacuum cleaner, $12; sauerkraut shredder, boudoir lamp, Roth
            iron piano stand, medicine cabinet, rocking chair, 2 fish baskets,
            2-burner gas stove, and other household goods; also piano at $20.
            Phone S6R2, W ittenberg. 25-ltc H O U SE FOR R E N T On Elm street.
            A. B. Larson. Tel. R20-Rfi. 25 -ltfc F O U N D — A new ladies’ hat;
            found near the Feuerpfeil garage. Owner pleaFC call The Enterprise
            fo r further particulars. Mrs. M. E. Schneider visited with her
            sister, Miss Martine Cleveland, in Stevens Point during the
            week-end. Mrs. Ellen Thorson, a resident at the Homme Home for the
            Aged, left Tuesday night fo r Waseca, Minnesota, where she w ill
            spend several weeks with relatives and friends. Mr. and Mrs. E. W .
            Klaus and two daughters, o f Minot, North Dakota, are now living on
            the old George Long farm a few miles east o f W ittenberg which they
            recently bought. Mr. and Mrs. Eugene Feuerpfeil and daughter, Nancy,
            o f Shiocton, and Mr. and Mrs. Alois Kuhlman and fam ily, o f New
            London, were week-end visitors in the William Feuerpfeil home. Mr.
            and Mrs. Edwin Anderson spent the week-end in Appleton. Mrs. Mollie
            Glass, her mother, and Miss Ruby Hull returned here with them fo r a
            v ifit in the Anderson home until today. M iss Helen Budahn, who
            will graduate from the two-year course at the Langlade Normal School
            in June, has been announced Salutatorian o f her class. Miss Frances
            Banczak, o f A n tigo, is Valedictorian. Bernadine Marquardt, who
            attends the Oshkosh State Teachers College, was in charge o f the
            information committee at the Wisconsin Rural Conference Meet which
            was held at that school A pril 28 and 21). Mr. and Mrs. Eric Plautz,
            o f M ilwaukee, Mr. and Mrs. Stanley Zastiow and fam ily, o f Green
            Bay, and Mr. and Mrs. Robt. Feavel, o f Elderon, Were visitors at
            the Mrs. Peter Bessette home cn Friday and Saturday. Sunday visitors
            in the Gustave Budahn home were: Mr. and Mrs. IL Weber, o f
            Cherokee; Mr. and Mrs. Louis Boldt and son, of Unity, and Mrs. Henry
            Hoppenworth and Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Backhous and fam ily, o f
            Bonduel. John Larson and Merton Farm er left on Monday by automobile
            for upper Michigan, where they are doing Kome canvassing. In
            Larson’s ab-1 sence from his barber shop, Frank Sell is looking a
            fter the patrons’ tonsorial needs. W’e just learn that Esther
            Margaret Hermanson passed away Thursday, April 27, at Gresham,
            Oregon, a fter an illness o f eight months. She was a form er
            resident o f this community and we shall publish her obituary in a
            later issue. Mr. and Mrs. Earl Cowles, Juanita Vandenberg and Bette
            Peterson attended a play, “ The Queen’s Husband,” fciven by the
            English division of Central State in Stevens Point Thursday evening.
            Gordon Cowles was a member o f the cast. Mrs. A rthu r Olsen and
            sons, Lyle, Robert and Donald and Mrs. Gogolin left Friday fo r
            Milwaukee. Lyle and Mrs. Gogolin went on to Chicago where Lyle
            visited for a few days. Mrs. Gogolin returned to her home in
            Cleveland, Ohio. The others returned here on Monday. Mrs. Carl
            Jacobson returned here Saturday night a fter an absence o f three
            months. Most o f the time was spent in Miami, Florida, as the guest
            o f her sister, Mrs. Haabestad. o f Philadelphia. Enroute home she
            made a visit in Chicago with her daughter, Mrs. J. B. Arneson, and
            fam ily. Extensive alterations are being made on the ground flo or o
            f the Schlytter building on Webb street. About ten feet in front is
            being partitioned off fo r the insurance office. All the rest o f
            the floor space is to be made into livin g rooms, which will be
            occupied by the Mrs. Selmer Schlytter family. Gordon Cowles spent a
            few days in Oshkosh and Milwaukee with Central State Men’s Glee
            club. While in M ilwaukee they attended the annual convention o f
            the Federated music clubs o f Wisconsin with which they are a
            ffiliated. While there, they w ere entertained at the Mrs. John Le
            Feber home. A concert was given at Berlin high school, and in
            Oshkosh the quartet and mixed chorus o f Central State entertained
            at Oshkosh State. Gordon is a member o f the quartet and directs the
            mixed chorus, composed of students in the rural state graded divi- H
            E L L O , W O R L D ! Born to Mr. and Mrs. Paul Bengert (fo rm e rly
            Ann K lovdahl) o f Wisconsin Rapids, a daughter, Pauline Ann,
            Saturday, A pril 22. Born to Mr. and Mrs. Leo Schuttenberg, town o f
            Bevent, on A p ril 28, a daughter, Yvonne. Mr. and Mrs. Frank
            Westphal and Mr. and Mrs. Adolph Lorenz helped Charles Malitz, o f
            Bowler, celebrate his birthday on Sunday. Friends and relativea
            helped Mrs. August W egner celebrate her birthday Sunday afternoon.
            Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Korth came from Crandon for the occasion. H a lf
            a hundred friends and relatives helped Mr. and Mrs. Ed. Wendler
            celebrate their silver wedding at their home on Sunday. It was an
            informal affair and greatly enjoyed by all present. And the table
            was loaded down with many appetizing dishes when it came time to
            eat. Mr. and Mrs. William Hoppe entertained four tables at
            schafskopf W ednesday evening, the occasion being Mr. Hoppe’s
            birthday. Prizes went to Mrs. Otto Frederick, Mrs. "M ark Hitzke,
            Mrs. Charles Huebner, George Turecek and Herbert Haufe. Mr. Hoppe
            received several nice birthday gifts. The follow ing helped Edwin
            Cowles celebrate his birthday Monday evening: Mr. and Mrs. Henry
            Schoepke, Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Wendler and girls, Mr. and Mrs.
            Cleve Guerin, Mr. and Mrs. Oscar Smestad, Mrs. Stanley W estgor,
            George Cowles, Frank Lang, Mr. and Mrs. Earl Cowles. Mr. and Mrs.
            Wm. O. Johnson, Bette Pederson, Mr. and Mrs. Gabe Overen, Mrs. Adon
            Falstad and Mr. and Mrs Ted W olff and son. Balance o f Madison
            Letter \ GOOD S U G G E STIO N “ Spud” offers a fine suggestion in
            the uOz ’n ’im ” column this week. | which might well be given
            consideration by the village board or the Lions i club or some other
            civic organization. “ Spud” believes that a “ town forest” (som
            ething new in civic ventures in several states) planted in W
            ittenberg by the present generation would in time be a blessing fo r
            posterity. Not a bed idea. Youth Killed Near Hiles Harold Kedftc,
            13-year-old son o f Mr. a*id M s. Robert Keune, former Birnamwood
            residents, was accidental1 v killed on A pril 20 near Hiles when a
            shotgun he was carrying disc h a rg e^ sending a charge o f shot
            into his head. Kenturkv Derby Is Thrilling Climax lo Technicolor
            Film C on in g I«» Badger Theatre May 7, 8, 9 For the first time in
            the history o f tht motion picture, the Kentucky Derby will be seen
            on the screen in full natural color. In the many years that newsreel
            companies have been filming the running o f the Derby, no shots have
            been made in anything but black and white. The huge technicolor
            cameras have now captured every glint o f brilliant color to be
            found in Am erica’s premier tu rf classic. “ Kentucky,” a romance o
            f the Blue Grass country, is said to have captured the glorious
            tradition o f that state, and a love all fire and pride is the
            glamorous theme o f the story. Loretta Young and Richard Greene are
            seen as the tw o young lovers who are born to the traditional enmity
            between their fam ilies which has carried over since the Civil War.
            W alter Brennan, Academy Award winner, also has a sizable role in
            the film. Political Activity A fte r several months o f comparative
            quiet, Wisconsin’s political organizations are beginning to break
            into the news more frequently. Most prominent currently is the
            Democratic party, which reached a new low in voting power last fall
            when it polled only about 80,000 votes for its state ticket headed
            by Senator H arry W. Bolens fo r governor. C riticizing the regular
            state organization headed by W illiam D. Carroll, party chairman, fo
            r inactivity and conservatism, a new group which has called itself “
            The Democratic party Organization o f Wisconsin” has set about the
            job o f rebuilding the Democratic party in the state in preparation
            fo r the 1940 campaigns. The new organization is headed by Gustave
            J. Keller, o f Appleton, chairman o f the Outagamie county
            committee, and has the apparent support of the two national
            committeemen from Wisconsin, C. E. Broughton, o f Sheboygan, and
            Mrs. George Givan, of Milwaukee, in addition to form er Senator F.
            Ryan Duffy. It belabors the Democrats who are sympathetic to
            Coalition with Republicans, and avows loyalty to the N ew Deal and
            the candidate who will carry the New Deal standard in 1940.
            Formation o f the new group has given rise to some speculation on
            the possibility o f an alliance with the P rogressives fo r the
            purpose o f reelecting Senator Robert M. La Follette next year.
            Bolens, one o f the leaders o f the Republican-Democratic Coalition
            in the Wisconsin senate, charged publicly that it was a move started
            by La Follette politicians to gain control o f the Democratic
            machinery in W isconsin. Others, including Assemblyman E lmer
            Genzer, o f Mayville, a leader of the assembly Democrats, have said
            that the Oshkosh rally which gave birth to the new organization was
            sponsort d by persons interested in promoting the candidacy of Paul
            V. McNutt, o f Indiana, for president on the Democratic ticket.
            Republican state headquarters in Madison, in charge of Dr. T. F.
            Gullickson, o f West Salem, party chairman. reports continued
            organization activity throughout the state, and this week it was
            announced that the W isconsin Young Democrats will hold their annual
            convention in Sheboygan late in August. Progressives, who have kept
            extrem ely quiet during the first months o f this year a fter their
            decisive defeat in the election last November by the Republicans,
            are *1*o reviving their activities with the return o f former
            Governor Philip F. I.a Follette from Europe and the selection of J.
            K. Kyle o f W’ hitewater as the new chairman o f the state central
            committee. K yle has announced the intention of the committee to
            launch an immediate campaign o f organization and education. A form
            er secretary of the state labor board who resigned early in the H
            eil administration, K y le has been prominently identified with
            Progressive activity for many years. As party leader he succeeds
            John Reynolds, of Green Bay, who resigned after the last campaign.
            Reorganizing Republican majorities in rapid fire fashion last week
            continued their job o f reshaping the pattern of the state capitol
            administ rative depart ments. Th eir aim is two-fold: to repeal many
            o f the departments and changes made by the form er La Follette
            administration, and to install their own ideas for governmental
            organization. Most recent actions o f the legislature included
            approval o f a new department o f agriculture and markets, with a
            seven member advisory board which will choose a director and set up
            such divisions as are found necessary, and passage of a bill setting
            up a new securities division for the administration of the “ blue
            sky” laws in the governor’s office. Wayside Gleanings The world w
            ill little care or long remember what is written in this column.
            Somewhere in the Archives of Poetry, is one of the beautiful
            expressions o f human love and sympathy portrayed by the poet in the
            story o f a feeble old man, perishing from hunger and thirst in a
            lonely mountain trail, and found by a young virgin fa r from water
            and food. Unable to bring him down from this lonely retreat, she
            pillowed his head on her bosom with an inspired prayer to heaven,
            that from those virgin breasts might flow the nourishment that would
            give life to a dying old man. A beautiful symbol of the crying need
            o f a confused and war-torn civilization o f today, seeking in the
            midst o f the most advanced enlightenment in history’s records, a
            way to succor a dying civilization. W ill, like the milk that flowed
            from those virgin breasts, the milk o f human kindness and
            understanding, again flow forth and stem the tide o f hate and
            destruction, that threatens to destroy our Democracies o f today,
            and if not abated w ill in turn destroy its creators. As the glad
            message that each Easter season brings to the world, both in the
            visible resurrection o f renewed growth in the Vegetable kin gdom,
            it also brings to us the great message o f the resurrection and the
            life hereafter. While the forces o f Science and destruction
            seemingly today are w orking harmoniously together to add to w ar’s
            hellishness, let us hope that in the hearts of our sanctified
            motherhood, sanctified to us by the birth and tesurrection o f a
            Saviour, that by a woman’s great mission, like the maiden’s prayer,
            written fo r us by the beautiful lines o f the poet, so will again
            woman’s prayers rescue the world from the mad plung* into thc
            darkness o f despair and selfish ambition. Let us honor our
            motherhood again in thought and prayer. Waldemar A. Ilansen. N o t i
            c e ! TO THK RESIDENTS A N D PROPERTY OWNERS OF WITTENBERO The week
            o f May 6 to May 13 has heen officially designated as “ C L E A N -U
            P W E E K " in W ittenberg. Property owners and residents are
            requested to see that all ruhhish. papers, leaves and loose brush,
            etc.. are removed from their premises. Out buildings should he
            cleaned and disinfected. All questionable lire hazards should be
            removed. Ashes and oily rags should be removed from basements.
            W’ittenberg citizens are urged to cooperate with the V illage Hoard
            in this campaign to make W ittenberg a cleaner, safer village in
            which to live. Village Board, VILLAGE OF WITTENBERG. — Subscribe for
            The Enterprise. ARTH UR DOEDE . Livestock and Farm Sale A U C T IO N
            E E R IO L A , W IS C O N S IN . R TE . 1. For Mutual Insurance F IR
            E . W IN D . A C C ID E N T , A l T O M O H ILE W rite or Call H OW
            ARD ERICKSON Phone 2dii2 Tigertj»n, R. 1 FARM AUCTIONS A T R E A S O
            N A B L E H A T E S Antigo Finance Corp. 723 5th Ave.. Antigo. Wis.
            NOTICE OF SALE N O TIC E IS H E R E B Y G IV E N that in pursuance o
            f the authority o f the Banking Commission o f the State o f
            Wisconsin as Statutory receiver fo r the Eland State Bank. Eland,
            Wisconsin, the undersigned will, on the 10th day o f May, 1939, at
            11:00 in the forenoon, sell the follow ing described real estate,
            to-w it: Lot No. Five (5 ) in Block No. Ten (1(1) of the I'lat o f
            the Village o f Eland Shawano County, Wisconsin, (located in the
            Southeast Quarter o f the Southwest Quarter (S E 1, o f S W 1, ) o f
            Section N o. Thirty (3 0 ) and the Northeast Quarter o f the
            Northwest Quarter ( N E 1, o f N W 1, ) o f Section No. Thirty-one
            (M l) all in Tow nship No. Tw enty-eight (2 8 ) North, o f Range No.
            Eleven (1 1 ) East. Shawano County, W isconsin), more commonly known
            as the Hotel Woodland located in the V illage o f Eland. Wisconsin.
            Said sale to be made at Pubic Auction and to be held on the
            premises. The highest bid received will be accepted subject to the
            approval o f the Circuit Court fo r Shawano County. Wis. Term s o f
            Sale: CASH. Dated A pril 2G, 1939. Banking Commission, State of
            Wisconsin, By N. W. H A H N . Special Deputy Comnmaioner in charge*
            o f the Eland State Hank. Kland, Wisconsin. Enterprise Want Ads
            Bring Results. FOR S A L E — Several good used light tractors and
            farm machines, also new I. H. C. tractors and farm implements.
            Cities Service Garage, Elderon. FO R S A L K — 8 ««d cot n. two
            varieties. No. 12 Golden Glow and a larger 130-day silage corn,
            price, $2.00 per bushel; also No. 38 velvet barley at 80c per
            bushel. Frank Harvey, Route 1, Tigerton. . 24-3tp FOR S A L E — One
            1937 Terra plane De Luxe, like new, at a nice price. Several cheap
            used cars. Cities Service Garage, Elderon. 24-2tf S E E George
            Bricco fo r pickle contracts. 28‘ lt p FOR S A L E — Cobbler seed
            potatoes and see*d barley. See Frank Liesch, Route 2, Wittenberg.
            FOR S A L K — Pure maple syrup; $1.50 a gallon, without containers.
            Edwin Cowles, phone 508-R9, Wittenberg. 21-4tp S E L L your old
            horses direct to a fur farm er and get higher prices. W e also buy
            cows lost through freshening, accidents, etc. Graves Mink Ranch.
            Eland, Wis. 48-eow H E A V Y D R A F T HORSES for *alc 01» trade. N
            o Sunday calls. G erritt Bultman, Route 3, Birnamwood, Wis. 18-lStp
            A N T IG O R E N D E R IN G W O R K S— w ill call fo r your dead and
            disabled horses ami cattle free o f charge (w ith hides on).
            Telephone A ntigo 744. W e pay telephone charges. Where To Q o . * a
            The W itU n berg Band Mothers will hold their regular monthly
            meeting Monday, May 8, at 3:30 in Miss Byse’s BIG D A N C E at J.
            D.’s Saturday, May 0, highway 29, 4 miles west o f Wittenberg. Music
            by Wisconsin Nightingales. Gents 25c, ladies free. Come here fo r a
            good time. DR. A. B. S C H U LTZ , O P T O M E T R IS T C O M IN G S
            A T U R D A Y E V E N IN G at Gauerke’s Jewelry Store, W ittenberg,
            from 7 to 9 p. m. Eyes tested and glasses fitted. FISH F R Y F R ID
            A Y N IG H T Chicken fr y Saturday and Sunday.! Lunches and
            sandwiches at all times. 1 Larry lla rry. GLASSES FITTED p r i c e s
            r h ; h t : GEO. H. W ILK E O P T O M E T R IS T 506 Third St.
            Opposite Heineman’s Open Friday until 9 P. M. Phone 5S75. W A U S A
            U i *ta« tun* to *anu*h you* floors, woodwork. staira. table top*
            boats and many othar article* with Nufcnamel Spar Varnish It *
            durable tha regular Nu Ec.ama! Spai Vareifh Com* in and g # youi
            abate A c m U N u Emo*1 Spa/ V u a itL -O m b W S M I T H ’ S S t a
            r V a l u e s ! FRIDAY’ A N D SATURDAY, M AY 5th and 6th C O RN—
            Cloverland Sweet Four 20 oz. cans.................... C O RN—
            Cloverland Gold. Hantam Three 20 oz. cans.................. P E A S—
            Cloverland No. 3 sieve Three 20 oz. cans.................. T O M A T
            O E S— Cloverland Tw o large 28 oz. cans.......... G IN G E R S N A
            P S 3 tbs......................................... C H EE S E— Fancy
            American Per pound ............................ B O L O G N A —
            Saturday Only Per pound .............. . 25c 23c 23c 19c 25c 16c l l
            i e N O O D LE S— Pure E gg 1 It), package...................... R
            IC E— 5 Ihs................................. C O RN F L A K E S —
            Ernst 13 oz. pkgs. 3 f o r .......... I.A R I)— 2 Ih.
            package.............. S A I.A D D R E SSIN G — Miracle W h ip; Q u a
            rt.................. IE L L O — V/i oz. pkt?s. 3 for
            .................................... O R A N G E S— GikkI size 2
            dozen .............................. B A N A N A S — 5
            Ihs..................... 13c ........ 22c 13c ........15c 37c 14c
            23c ........2!>c P E R C A L E S — L arge selection o f new patterns
            ................................ L A D IE S W A S H D R E SSE S -
            real value $.198, $1.37 an d ............ J / O C M E N 'S S H IR T
            S OR SHORTS A real v a l u e ............................ !>KY GOODS
            SPECIALS 12c ■Every one a *”144c 15c RIG Y A N K W O R K S H IR TS
            Special (ffi ................................ O V E R A L L S — Vou
            can’t beat this value a t ............................ SHOES— A
            complete lino >f Men’s Work Shoes in 6 and 8 inch © - i and up.
            tops; Special priced Co “ A * 69c 89c G R A N D O P E N IN G S A L E
            O F D R Y GOODS IS S T IL L IN E F F E C T U N T IL S A T U R D A Y
            N IG H T . W e also offer our usual Volunteer week-end Grocery
            Specials. Don’t forget that we handle Sacco Fertilizer and
            McCormick-Deering Farm Machinery. C A P P E L ’ S T H E W ITTE N B E
            R G ENTERPRISE. W ITTEN BER G . WIS. Bi" Top Hits Trail Once More
            With Bigger Bundle of Thrills R o u M l n b o ii l t It ta d in g u
            p f o r I h e o v e r n i g h t t r i p , “ How do you like living
            in country in the w inter tim e? ” "G re a t. E very tim e there's a
            snowstorm 1 have a good excuse tor staying home from the office.' A
            M atter (or Washington A Swedish fa rm er .who wanted to m ake his
            permanent hom e in this country appeared for his naturalization
            papers. " A r e you satisfied with the general conditions of this
            country?’ ’ he w as asked. " Y a h , su re," answered the hopeful
            one. "A n d does this governm ent of ours suit you ?" "W e ll, yah,
            m ostly,” stam m ered the man. "on ly I lak see m ore rain ." W hat
            to Eat and W h y C . H ouston G oudiss C onsiders th e Q uestio n: H
            o w O fte n Shall W e Eat? Suggests That Som e People M a y B enefit
            by M o re Than Three M eals By C. H O USTO N GOUDISS ON E o f the
            questions 1 am frequ ently asked is whether or not it’ s advisable
            to eat between m eals. Any answ er must take into consideration a
            number o f factors. It is true that m any people experien ce a
            desire for food *n mid-m orning, m id-afterhoon or before going to
            bed. Some begin to nibble as soon as they feel hungry, and often
            they continue to eat in excess of their needs. Others, trained to m
            ore selfrestraint, refrain from eating, because they have been
            brought up with the idea that no f o o d ________________________
            should be eaten except at regular meals. Unfortunately, it
            frequently occurs that neither procedure is based upon actual food
            requirements. C om ider the Day's Food Needs In a rrivin g at any
            decision concerning between-meal eating, the da y's ration should be
            regarded as a whole. I f the foods served at breakfast, dinner and
            lunch or supper are ca refu lly chosen, with a view to m eeting
            bodily requirem ents, there should be no need for m any adults to
            eat between meals. O n t h e o t h e r hand, it should be borne in
            mind that dividing the d a y 's food into what we Am ericans so
            often call "th re e square m ea ls," is prim arily a convenient
            custom. One rea son that it has grow n up o ver a period o f years
            is because it allows the m axim um fre e tim e to pursue our various
            occupations. In a number o f countries, a fourth meal is an accepted
            part of the day's routine. No Englishman, for exam ple, would
            consider going without his afternoon tea ; and w orkers pause in
            offices, stores and factories, as w ell as at home, for a brief rest
            and w elcom e refreshment. H ow Many Meals? In recent years, several
            scientists have advanced the idea that some of us m ay benefit by
            eating more than three m eals. At a leading university > few yea rs
            ago, two distinguished investigators concluded that sm aller and m
            ore frequent m eals would promote general health and w ell-being for
            many types of individuals. They suggested lighter m eals, but
            proposed as many as four, five, or even six feedings a day. Another
            well-known authority has perform ed various experiments which effe
            ctively demonstrate that a light additional meal in mid-afternoon,
            consisting principally of a milk beverage, increased the efficiency
            of workers and helped to reduce fatigue. Relieving Late Afternoon
            Fatigue Many people experience a tired feeling about four o’ clock
            in the afternoon. During the working day, they gradually utilize a
            va ila ble food en ergy, so that by late aftem oou, the supply m ay
            be greatly reduced—along with both mental and physical en ergy. H
            ere is a case where eating between m eals is regarded as a decided
            advantage, provided the food is carefu lly chosen. A glass of milk
            and a few crackers, or some other carbohydrate food, w ill help to
            renew en ergy, relie ve the feeling o l fatigu e and bridge the gap
            to dinner. It must he rem em bered, how ever, that the extra m eal
            should be composed ol light, easily-digested foods so as not to
            destroy appetite for the following meal. m id-m orning feeding o f
            orange juice, or a mid-afternoon cup o f milk with one or two
            crackers. And some school children also make better w eight gains if
            they pause in the m iddle o f the morning, or take an after-school
            snack, o f fruit juice, or m ilk, and crackers. A ged persons often
            require m ore than three m eals. That is because large, heavy meals
            might overtax their digestions, and three light m eals do not
            usually provide adequate nourishment. F or this reason,
            nutritionists advise that they have a light, mid-afternoon pickup of
            a hot beverage and crack ers; and perhaps a cup o f hot bouilloo
            before going to bed. Don’t O vereat Thus, it is evident that there
            are numerous instances when there ia justification for departing
            from the accepted routine. But it must be rem em bered that as the
            number of m eals is increased, the amount of food taken at each one
            should be decreased. Otherwise, an undue strain m ay be placed upon
            the digestive organs. Then, too, no m atter how the d a y ’s food is
            divided, it must provid e all the substances required for sound
            nutrition. Otherwise, the body w ill be im properly nourished, no m
            atter how many meals a re consumed. Th e diet should be built first
            of all around the protective foods— m ilk, eggs, fruits and
            vegetables, which a re such an important source o f necessary m
            inerals and vitamins. It must also supply protein for growth and
            repair, carbohydrates and fats for adequate ene rg y , and
            sufficient bulk or cellulose to prom ote normal elim ination. Keep
            the Diet Balanced Whether you serve three hearty m eals and forego
            eating between times, or follow the plan of providing a mid-morning
            or midafternoon pickup, you should m eet the requirements for a
            balanced diet. This, you w ill rem em b er from previous
            discussions, includes a pint of milk for each adult, a quart for
            every child; an egg for each m em ber of the fam ily, or at least
            three or four w eekly ; one serving o f a whole grain ce rea l; one
            serving of m eat, fish or chicken plus a second source of protein,
            such as m eat, nuts or dried beans or peas; two vegeta bles besides
            potatoes, one of which should be o f the leafy green va rie ty ; two
            fruits or one fruit and one fruit juice. O -W NU-C. Houston
            GoudlM—1838—«1. B O Y S ! I t ’ s R e a l S p o r t to finish yoar
            own Archery Set Spaciaf Off f t , COMPUTE ARC MERY $ *0 0 SET only -
            ■ - - O A'rprM* ColUet tSe •'»n>l.hln«JQ k tel worth O Young
            Children and Elderly People Children of certain ages, as well as
            adult*, m ay benefit by a schedule that includes an extra meal. V
            ery young children— in the toddler stage— are frequently given a A R
            O U N D TH E HOUSE r ~ft TLemonwood Bow (el* miwt finished) F •
            Arrow* Kenthered - Tipped ft How String ft Leatherette Grip Cover
            Set of finishing instruction*. Iitra - 1 Regulation Target Faco Not
            a Toy, but real Archery Equipment. For your Sot toad $3.00 today to
            L .C . WHIFFEN CO., Inc. §28 W. Clybourn St. Milwaukee. Wis. •
            Maker* of Hang* T—Ud Archer* Kju\pm*nt C o m f o r t "Y o u look
            very despondent.” “ How can I help it? A in 't I blue fish?” Wash
            Chamois Often.—Chamois I in which silv er is stored away j should be
            frequently washed, if j the silver is to be kept bright. e e e
            Lustrous G lassw are.— Laundry, ! blue added to the w ater in which
            I glassw are is washed w ill g iv e the | glass an added luster. * e
            e Washing Hint.— N ev er use soap on white silk. The soap should
            first be dissolved in w ater before laundering is begun. e e • Fresh
            Doughnuts.— Put freshly m ade doughnuts into a covered dish while
            they are still w arm and they w ill stay fresh longer. e e e rt'hrn
            Buying Garm ents.— Look at the seams to see that they have a
            generous width and firm finish. e e e Adding Height to Room .—
            Height can be added to a low-ceilinged room by using striped w
            allpaper and long window draperies. j f l * " H O T E L CL ARK in
            Downtown L O S A N G E L E S Convenience io another offering of this
            hotel. Whether on business or pleasure bent, the Hotel Clark makes
            an ideal "base of operations," as well as a restful "billet" at tha
            end of the day’s “campaign.” Good Food, naturally. And moderate
            charges, as well asf or room accom* modations, give final
            significance to assuring word —COMFORT. ftin g la from % 2 .% 0 D
            ouble from $ 3 .SO F i f t h a n d H i l l P. 0. • M O tllli. M a n
            a t" ROOMS 555 BATHS T H E W ITTE N B E R G ENTERPRISE. W ITTENBERG.
            WIS. Tiotfd (}M64+£ ADVENTURERS’ CLUB H K A D I I N K S P R OM T HE
            L I V E S OP P E O P L E L I K E Y O U R S E L P I “ The K ille r
            Ship” He l l o , e v e r y b o d y : I ’ ve told you stories about
            human killers, and I ’ v e spun you tales about an im al killers.
            This is the story of a killer ship. C arl L. Rynning o f Brooklyn,
            N. Y ., told m e this story. It happened to him in 1902, when he
            found him self broke and out o f a job in South A fr ic a and signed
            on a w in djam m er for a trip to South Am erica. The w in djam m er
            was the bark Albatross, which had just brought a load of corn over
            fro m Buenos A ires and w as going back to the sam e port in
            ballast. T h ere it would pick up a load o f wheat and return to E
            ast London, Cape Colony. Th at suited C arl’ s plans, so he sailed
            aw ay one m orning at daybreak, and six weeks later, after an
            uneventful trip, the Albatross entered the P la ta river and docked
            at Buenos Aires. So far, everyth in g had gone smoothly, but they
            had no sooner begun loading grain for the return trip than it becam
            e evident that the Albatross was none too seaworthy a craft. When
            the sand ballast had been taken out o f the hold, w ater began com
            ing in through the s e a m s . That didn’ t bother the captain any
            to speak of. H e just let the ship settle in the mud, and when the
            mud got into the seam s and closed them up, he began loading again.
            M any a sailor would have quit that ship then and there. But C arl
            wanted to get back to South A frica . H e stayed on for the return
            trip, but the ship was hardly out o f the riv e r again before he
            began to reg ret it. Huge Sw arm s of Rats Had Boarded the Ship. The
            w eather w as fa ir enough at the m om ent. It w as late June and
            the old tub w as w allow ing along before a fa ir breeze. But it w
            as the rats that bothered C arl. Sw arm s of them had com e aboard w
            hile the ship was loading grain, and now they w ere threatening to
            take o v er the ship. " W e must have had half the The Dark ages
            extended, roughly speaking, from the fa ll of the western Roman em
            pire in 475 A. D. to the rev iva l of learning on the disco very o f
            the pandects at Am alfi, Ita ly, in 1150—altogether about seven
            centuries. The period extending from the fall of the Roman em p ire
            to the capture of Constantinople in 1533 by the Turks is known as
            the M iddle ages. The pandects w ere a collection ol laws sytem
            atically arranged from Roman writings on ADVENTUROUS AMERICANS By
            Elmo Scott Watson H C W Tq S E W 4 ^ " R u th W y e th Spears A
            heavy gale blew up and quickly mounted to hurricane fo rce. rats in
            the A rgen tin e with us,” C arl says. "T h e y w ere e v e r y w
            here. W e found them in the pockets of our clothes— in our bunks—
            and in shortk every w h ere w e looked. While w e w ere lyin g
            asleep, w e w ere awakened by the anim als craw lin g across our
            faces, and w e had to lie p erfectly still w hile w e fe lt their
            cold feet and tails ticklin g our noses. Many a tim e I stepped on
            one when I got out o f m y bunk to go on w atch.” The rats w ere bad
            enough, but as they neared A frica , things becam e worse. A h eavy
            gale blew up, and it quickly increased to hurricane force. The seas
            mounted until they seem ed to be fifty fe e t high, and the old
            ship, with nothing but a storm trisail up, was plunging ahead at
            half again her usual speed. F o r a day, the ship withstood the
            buffeting of the gale, but that night, along about eight bells, the
            carpenter sounded the bilges and reported to the captain that there
            was four feet of w ater in the hold. The captain ordered all hands
            to the pumps. The crew w orked g rim ly at those pumps— because they
            knew they w ere w orking for their lives. “ Four feet of w ater,”
            says C arl, “ is bad in any ship in a storm . It was especially bad
            in this rotten old tub. W e had no life preservers and the life
            boats w ere so rotten that they would fa ll apart if any attem pt
            was m ade to raise them off their cra d le s." Captain Asks fo r M
            en's Opinions. The men pumped for two hours, and the carpenter
            sounded the bilges again. This tim e, there w as five feet of w ater
            in the bilges. In spite of all the men could do, it had gained a
            foot. T h ey kept on pumping, but the captain w as w orried. At
            three o’clock in the morning, when the crew w as so exhausted that
            hardly a one of them could stand up to the pumps, he called them all
            into his cabin. W et and hungry, they trooped in, and the captain
            told them bluntly that he didn't know w hat to do and wanted to get
            the m en’s opinions. Th ere w ere tw o courses they could follow .
            Land w asn't fa r distant. In the sky they could see the reflection
            of the Cape of Good Hope Ligh t. They could keep on pumping and try
            to m ake port, or they could run the ship on the rocks, g iv in g
            the men a chance to be washed ashore, if they escaped being killed
            by w reck age, or pulled to their deaths by the undertow. T h ere
            wasn’ t a chance of keeping the ship afloat until they reached port.
            The men all knew it. The ch ief m ate was for piling the boat on the
            rocks, and the men agreed with him. Th e ship was turned about and
            headed for the shore. "A n d w e w ere a silent crew as we w o rk ed
            ," says C arl, “ for w e knew that in a fe w hours w e would
            crash—and then w h at?" V oyage o f the Albatross Ends. But suddenly
            the m ate m ade a d iscovery. B efore the bark had been turned tow
            ard shore, she had been running on her starboard tack, with the port
            side deep down in tbe w ater. When they cam e about, the wind and
            the seas w ere astern, and she cam e up on an even keel. And now.
            the m ate, looking over the port side, saw a stream of w ater com
            ing out of a great gap in the hull of the ship at a point which had
            heen submerged a fe w m oments before. It w as the cause of all
            their troubles. A piece of floating tim ber had struck the side of
            the ship and ram m ed a hole in the rotten planking. The wind w as
            dying out by that tim e. Th e carpenter rigged a scaffold over the
            side, filled the hole with bags o f oakum and nailed a heavy canvas
            o ver it. “ W e hove to,” says C arl, "a n d it was with a different
            feeling that w e manned those pumps again. It was six in the m
            orning now, and we pumped until eleven, when the pumps began sucking
            air and w e knew she w as em pty. W e w ere all tired, but w e w ere
            happy. Six days after that w e entered the harbor of East London, w
            here the whole town turned out to view the battered looking w reck
            as it cam e lim ping in. And thus ended that never-to-be-forgotten
            vo ya ge of the bark A lbatross.” Copyright.—WNU Service. Roman
            Writings on Jurisprudence Enacted Into Law jurisprudence. Th ey w
            ere enacted into law by the E m p eror Justinian in 533 A. D. T h
            eir discovery at A m alfi stim ulated a general study o f Rom an and
            G reek literature, which led to what is known as the classic age.
            During the Dark ages learning was at its low est ebb in Europe and
            civilization seem ed to retrograde, ow ing to the masses of
            barbarians who em erged from northern Europe and overran the fo rm
            er seats of learning. An American Spahi C E W Am erican s have e v e
            r heard 1 o f M arius Van de W eghe. He stays pretty close to his
            tallow and caustics, test tubes and chem icals and other scientific
            apparatus in his laboratory at a soap com pany in Chicago. You
            wouldn’ t suspect that Marius, a young man o f less than 40 years,
            is an Ouissam Alaouite Cherifien. But that is what you are when the
            Sultan o f M orocco gives you a m edal and says that’ s what you
            are. Because Van de W eghe, w hile a soldier in M orocco, displayed
            unusual bra very under fire, the sultan knighted him. Van de W eghe
            was a spahi in the Moroccan arm y right a fter the World w ar. A
            spahi is a cavalrym an . During a fierce engagem ent with rebel
            natives. Van de Weghe rode back two m iles *into enem y territory to
            bring back the body of his slain com m anding officer. Th e kind of
            men the soldiers w ere fighting w ere those who tortured their live
            captives and m utilated those who w ere killed. Van de W egh e’s
            heroism prevented the natives from burying the body of his com m
            ander with his head protruding to be eaten by insects. But there is
            nothing of the hero in Van de W egh e's present dem eanor, now that
            he is an A m erican citizen and the head o f a fam ily. Whenev e r
            anyone expresses am azem ent that he would risk his life to retrie
            ve a dead body he adds his own am azem ent, stating that neither can
            he understand how he happened to do it. * • • ‘Prince of Trinidad’
            «* I A M E S 1, P R IN C E O F TRIN1- ** D A D ,” is an im pressive
            title Th e holder o f it was an Am erican who m arried the daughter
            of a Standard Oil com pany magnate. He presented her with the entire
            kingdom of Trinidad which they ruled together with a firm hand.
            Trinidad w as easy to rule, of course, because Mr. and Mrs. Jam es
            Harden-Hickey, the A m erican names of the rulers, w ere the only
            human inhabitants. T h eir subjects w ere the land crabs, sea fowl
            and snakes with which the place w as infested. Trinidad is an island
            700 m iles east o f B razil in the South Atlantic. D iscovered by
            the Portuguese and visited by the British, no power had exercised a
            ctive possession of it at the tim e “ M r. and Mrs. Jam es I ” went
            there and proclaim ed them selves rulers in 1894. But their reign
            over this sm all dom ain that reeked with the odor of dead fish,
            ended in January of the follow ing yea r when the British sent the
            warship B arracouta there to take o ver possession. Th is w asn’t
            the first tim e Jam es H arden-H ickey w as thrown out of a country.
            He established a newspaper, Le Triboulet, in P a ris in 1878, and
            was so obnoxious in his criticism o f the republican governm ent
            that he was expelled from France in 1880. H e died a suicide in E l
            Paso, T e x as, in 1898, just pla^n Jam es Harden- H ickey, A m
            erican citizen. • • • Audacious Robert Stobo L I OUDIN1 w as fam ous
            for his 1 ■* ability to escape from almost a nyw here; Sergeant Y
            ork w as noted for his ability to capture enem ies by the w
            holesale; but in pre-R evolu tionary days, M aj. R obert Stobo was
            fam ous fo r both. Th e French from Canada w ere constantly
            arresting Stobo for supplying Washington with confidential
            information about their plans. But regardless o f w hete he was im
            prisoned he alw ays m anaged to escape. A fter breaking out o f a
            cell in Quebec, he paddled up the St. L a w rence rive r with three
            companions. Cam ping one day on the bank, he noticed a sm all boat
            lea ve a French ship and m ake toward them. He could easily have
            retreated into the woods until they g a v e up the search. Instead
            he and his companions surprised the party when it landed and
            captured the group that had been sent out to capture h im ! Then, a
            fter waiting for darkness, he had the further audacity to order them
            all into the boat and with guns at their backs, row back to their
            ship as if he and his party w ere captives. Th ey w ere all aboard
            the vessel before the crew realized that it was Stobo's party, not
            theirs, that held the guns Once aboard, he had the upper hand and
            forced the entire cre w of 18 to surrender. But this was only a good
            beginning In com m and of the ship, he set sail and pulled alongside
            another French vessel a m ile down the river. Without w arning, he
            fired a broadside against the unsuspect- | ing vessel and forced its
            surrender I too. Then he set fire to it. Prou dly he set sail up the
            St Law ren ce and relu m ed triumphant ly to Colonial territory,
            having per form ed one of the most adventurous feats o f his time. *
            WHtcrn Newaoaoer Union. SOON F IN D O U T A stranger was talking to
            a fa rm er and said to him: “ This (e e m i to be a healthful
            country. You say you are nearly 70 and can still do a full d a y ’s
            work. Th at's pretty good.” " Y e s , but my old dad, who is 97, is
            even a harder w orker than I am ,” said the farm er. “ His health
            must be wonderfully good,” rem arked the stranger. "N o , it a in
            't,” replied the fa rm er. " F o r the last several years he ain’t
            had quite his old-time pep. Sometim es I kinda think farm in' don’t
            a gre e with him.” Substitute ■ The teacher had forbidden the
            children to eat candy or chew gum during school time. One day she
            becam e suspicious o f a lump in Jim m ie ’s cheek “ J im m ie ,"
            she said reprovingly, " a r e you eating candy or chewing g u m ? "
            “ N either on e," replied Jim m ie, [ “ I ’m soaking a prune to eat
            at recess.” _ TIPS to (jardeners C h a n g in g M e th o d s P ocket
            for dish towels. L E T DOWN Maiden— Can you drive with one hand, M
            r. Corntossel? Aged Suitor (e a g e r ly )— Wall, I I should say. M
            aiden—Then 1 wish you would take your whiskers off my face. First
            Round H e— R em em ber when we first met in that revolving door at
            the post j office? She—That wasn’t the first time j we met. He— Yes,
            but it was the first tim e w e started going around together.
            Inheritance " B illy ,” Said his father sternly, "1 want you to
            learn better table manners*. Y ou 're a regu lar little pig at the
            table. I suppose you know what a pig is?” B illy m eekly replied: "
            Y e s , s ir; it*s a hog’s little boy.” In M ovie Land F irst F ilm
            Star—How do you like I your new father? Second F ilm Star—Oh, he’s
            quite ! nice. Firs* F ilm Star— Yes, isn’t he? We had him last year.
            All Things Equal Old Lady (a s husband fails to help her up the
            steps of railw ay co a ch )— H enry, you ain’ t so gallant as when I
            was a gal. Husband—No, Lettie, and you ain’t so buoyant as when 1
            was a boy. Too Tru e! A girl was asked to explain why men never kiss
            each other, while women do. She replied: “ Men have something better
            to kiss; women haven’t.” A ll Depends A xel—S elm a’s husband has
            been a sufferer for years, hasn’t he? T re e — I don’t know. How
            long have they been m arried? N o Hurry His P a l—I f you know who
            stole your car why don’ t you go after it? Freshman— I ’ m just
            waiting for him to put on a new set of tires. Colorful Story Teacher
            — F redd y, haven’ t you read anything? F reddy— Y es, teacher. 1
            have red hair. A G A IN S T T H E R U LE S T W O pockets on the
            inside of 4 this pantry door are used for dish tow els—the upper for
            clean tow els; the low er for soiled ones. Th e pockets them selves
            are m ade from four dish towels with bright red borders and are
            hooked onto the door with brass rings. A ll the dimensions for
            cutting, and d ire ctions for m aking are given here in the sketch.
            I f toweling by the yard is used, 3*4 yard s w ill be required. Th
            ese directions are not in e ither Book 1 or Book 2, so be sure to
            cut them out for reference E ach of the books contains com plete
            directions for m aking dozens o f other useful things for yourself,
            your home and to use fo r gifts and bazaars. Many readers are also m
            aking scrap books of these articles and when they are com bined with
            the two books, they have a treasure house of ideas that have been
            tested by thousands of hom emakers. Book 2, G ifts, N ovelties and E
            m broideries, contains 48 pages of step-by-step directions which
            have Jlsk Me Jlnother A A General Quiz 1. What is m eant by the R o
            a ring 40’s? 2. Who had the ‘ ‘fa ce that launched a thousand ships”
            ? 3. How fast could W alter Johnson throw a ball? 4. Is there such a
            thing as a double-jointed person? 5. Has anyone ev e r seen the
            other side of the moon? 6. What is the difference between a thief
            and a robber? T he Answ ers 1. The streets of N ew York be tween
            Fortieth and Fiftieth, especia lly relating to the Tim es Square
            district. 2. Helen of T ro y had the " fa c e that launched a
            tnousand ships.” 3. A test m ade at the R em in gton A rm s Co.,
            showed that W alter Johnson threw a ball at the rate of 122 feet per
            second. 4. No. Loose or stretched lig a m ents give the appearance.
            5. Inhabitants of the earth cannot see the other side of the moon,
            because the moon rotates on its axis at the sam e rate that it
            revolves around the earth. T h erefore, it alw ays keeps the sam e
            fa ce towards the earth. 6. A thief is one who deprived another of
            property secretly or without open force, as opposed to a robber who
            uses open fo rc e or violence. helped thousands of women. If your
            home is your hobby you will also want Book 1—S E W IN G , for the H
            om e Decorator. O rder by number, enclosing 25 cents for each. With
            orders for two books we include F R E E , a leaflet of 36 authentic
            patchwork stitches. Address, Mrs. Spears, 210 S. Desplaines St.,
            Chicago, 111. / ^ E R T A IN garden p r a c t i c e s ^ w idely
            followed a generation ago have now been proved unwise. G ardeners fo
            rm e rly allowed vegetables to grow as la rg e as possible. A
            ccording to H arold N. Coulter, vegetab le expert o f the F e rry
            Seed B reeding Station, thia p ractice gave a higher y ield in
            pounds, but ve ry often low ered the quality o f the vegetables. Som
            e vegetables, of course, lika tomato, must be m ature to be pala
            table; but carrots, cucumbers, beets, sum m er squash, turnips,
            radishes and others are m ore tender and tasty when not much mora
            than half grown. T o keep a regu lar supply o f vegetables o f
            proper eating size, gardeners are finding also that it is advisable
            to plant oftener than once or tw ice a year. Gardens prove m ore
            enjoyable and m ore profitable when successive plantings of fa vo
            rite crops are m ade e very two or three weeks, providing
            garden-fresh vegetables for the table o ver a long season. F ew
            gardeners nowadays save flower seeds. Fine flowers grow ing in the
            home garden often are cross-pollinated by others of the sam e
            species, m aking flowers grown ftom their seed inferior and untrue.
            . I A T T E R N > JUST see how much playtim e fashion this one
            design (1557) gives you. The backless, slimwaisted play suit is
            perfect for sum m er sports. W ear the skirt with it, and you have a
            sm art daytim e dress. Add the bolero, too, and you have a charm ing
            little suit. Make this of linen, broadcloth, sharkskin or percale,
            and trim it with gay ricra c braid. B olero Ensem ble With Bows. The
            bolero dress with princess skirt (1731) is one thing you sim ply
            must have. It ’s so useful for street and afternoon w ear both, ond
            extrem ely becom ing, with its slim -waisted silhouette, wide revers
            and bow trim s. F lat crepe, silk print, georgette and street
            cottons are good choices fo r this. The Patterns. No. 1557 is
            designed for sizes 12, 14, 16, 18 and 20. Size 14 requires A R T M E
            N T 55h yards of 35-inch m a teria l; 10 yards of ricrac braid to
            trim . No. 1731 is designed for sizes 12, 14, 16, 18 and 20. 'S iz e
            14 requires 5% yards of 39-inch m ateria l; 2lb yards of ribbon for
            bows. New Spring-Summer Pattern Book Send 15 cents for B arbara B
            ell’s Spring • Sum mer Pattern Book! Make sm art new frocks for
            street, daytim e and afternoon, with these sim ple, carefu lly
            planned designsl It’ s chic, it’ s easy, it’ s econom ical, to sew
            your own. Each pattern includes a step-by-step sew chart to guide
            beginners. Send your order to The Sewing C ircle Pattern Dept., Room
            1324, 211 W. W acker Dr., Chicago, 111. P ric e of patterns, 15
            cents (in coins) each. © Bell Syndicate.—WNU Service DICKINSON'S I H
            ’.****?, H S * * * I sb»t»ty •• is in tne I I ™ In Anticipation
            Looking forw ard to a pleasure is also a pleasure.—Lessing. NEW YORK
            W S FID) W e have trelnrd C oll*** Men and Women (ChrUiian*i to arom
            pany V l»l tor* through oat New ToiH City end the W o rld * Kelt, el
            * rurjr modem tun May 1 » n d detella bow thia Individual!***
            personal aen lc e w ill aere yoo nonalderable money, time. e ffo rt
            end am lety JOSEPH A.LEWIS,S21 Prfih An ie,New Ywk Bunny Cop—-H ey!
            Mr. Possum, didn’t I tell you 1 didn’t want to see you hanging
            around here again? P ra ctica l Suggestion Prospective Buyer — Th
            ere sre eight in my fam ily, and we have • lot of friends. Auto
            Salesm an— Let me sell you this second-hand patrol wagon. If has
            held 20—in a pinch.” F irst Consideration Miss M u ltir o y — I ’ m
            s o rr y to hurt you, but our e n g a g e m e n t m ust end. I tru
            st you w ill not feel too badly about it ’ Lord S to n ib ro k e—
            Don t think of m e. Th in k o f m y c red ito rs. PAGE EIGHT THE
            WITTENBERG ENTERPRISE. WITTENBERG, WIS. Thursday. May 4, 1939 E L A
            N D M rs. J. Baird and son Tom o f A n tijfo spent S atu rd ay w ith
            her mother, M rs. G. La gest. M r. and M rs. Burke and Bob Burke w
            en t to Oshkosh S atu rd ay to visit Mrs. B u rke’s sister, M rs. E
            arl P u ttrow . Th e M isses E sth er D ivin e, A gn es S tron g, Em
            m a B ottin and G ertru de Zuch, all teach ers at Shaw ano, spent
            the w eek-end in the Zuch home at Eland. M rs. E n g el drove to A n
            tig o T u esday a ftern oon . Mr. Olm and Ben Bell o f A n tig o
            called on Eland frien d s M onday. Mrs. W m . F ra n k w en t to
            Ashland W edn esday night to v is it her daugh ters, Lo is and Lorra
            in e. .John R e t t ig was at W'ausau M on da y on business. O tto M
            ey er retu rned fro m C h icago w here he spent a w eek w ith his
            sons and daughters. M rs. H. T e itz o f S u gar Bush visited her
            dau gh ter, M rs. C. W estfa h l, Sunday. M r. and M rs. Rud. Beck o
            f Green Bay and grandd au ghter, M a ry Olson, o f M ilw au kee
            visited in the H en ry Schwalbach hom e o ver the week-end. Mrs. C
            la re Babcock returned to her hom e at M ilw au kee a ft e r spend
            in g a fe w w eeks w ith relatives. M r. and Mrs. Em erson C o
            ttrell d rove to Crandon W ednesday. M rs. W a rn e r Schoepke is
            vis itin g her parents at O akfield, her fa th e r bein g qu ite
            ill. Chas. W e s tfa h l spent T u esd ay at Shaw ano on business. M
            elvin S trtm g plays his first gam e Thu rsday. Mr. and M rs. F rank
            R o g ers o f M a rion are spendin g a w eek w ith th eir dau gh
            ter, M rs. L. Larson. Mr. and M rs. H a ro ld S atre o f L e o polis
            spent Sunday w ith his brother, A I Satre. M rs. Sam p and Mrs. S
            tro n g w ere at Birnam w ood Tuesday. M rs. R. Beck o f G reen B ay
            spent T u esd ay a t the hom e o f h er parents, M r. and M rs. H.
            Schwalbach. Ir v in W estfa h l spent the week-end in the Chas. W e
            s tfa h l home. B ert B ig fo rd o f W ausau spent a fe w days w ith
            his fa m ily . M r. and M rs. E rnest G ra bb ert re turned from M a
            rq u ette, M ichigan, w here he is em ployed. T h e G eo rg e N a g
            e l fa m ily o f M a ttoon have m oved in to the Rud. Beck home. M
            r. and Mrs. Rolland W e s tfa h l and children o f Neenah spent
            Sunday w ith his parents. M r. and M rs. M. T . F o x and Louis
            Larson attended the fu n era l o f Mr. Paulson at N o rr ie Tu
            esday. ELDERON M r. and M rs. P a b le v isited at the W m . M oore
            hom e Sunday. M rs. P a b le rem ained fo r a tw o w eek s’ v is it
            w ith her parents. Dr. A lla n H a ffn er, o f O tta w a , C a n a
            da, is v is itin g a t the E. J. Benson home. H is w ife , the fo rm
            e r M arion Benson, w ho has been v is itin g here fo r several
            months, w ill retu rn hom e w ith 4iim. M rs. W m . Peterson is v is
            itin g at the A rth u r K lin e and G ordon P eterson homes in G
            reen Bay. M r. and M rs. B ert Bu tton w ere W au paca visito rs F
            rid a y. M r. and M rs. H arold Jam es o f W a u sau w ere E lderon
            vis ito rs Sunday. M ayn ard Z w irch itz retu rned home from the
            St. M a ry ’ s H o sp ita l in W a u sau W edn esday. M r. and M rs.
            G eo rg e K a rsch n ey and da u gh ters, E m ily, E th el and Jean
            ette, w ere W ey a u w eg a visito rs Sunday. Ed. Thom son le ft M
            onday fo r Park F a lls w here he w ill take up residence fo r the
            summer. M em bers o f the B rid g e Club e n jo y ed a din ner and
            th eatre p a rty at W au- -au T u esd ay evenin g. T h e ninth gra d
            e students made a trip to M ilw au kee Th u rsday. NORRIE FOREST
            VIEW Jane N e llis returned to her home in C h ica go S atu rd ay a
            fte r spendin g a w eek ’ s vacation in the S ta n ley W e s tg o r
            home. G ertru de Zuch, county school supervisor, visited the school
            on Tu esday m orning. S tan ley W e s tg o r le ft M onday fo r a fe
            w d a ys’ business trip to Bessem er, M ichigan. Mr. and Mrs. L e v
            i Johnson visited i t the «ullik M atson home on Sunday •ifternoon.
            M r. and Mrs. W illia m Sense and fa m ily o f M arqu ette. M ich
            igan , spent the week-end at the C le ve Guerin home. M r. and M rs.
            L e v i Johnson attended f he fa re w e ll p a rty on M r. and Mrs.
            E dw in Matson g iv en T u esd ay evenin g. M r. and M rs. C leve G
            u erin spent Sunday a ftern oon a t the B e rt S ta rr home. W . J.
            Hansen retu rned M onday from a w eek-end trip to C h icago. B lue
            Goose School d efea ted Forest V ie w 12-9 in a s o ft hall ga m e
            played on F rid a y a ftern oon . M r. and M rs. W illia m Sense and
            fa m ily and M a ry Jean G u erin spent Sunday a t the W 'illiam
            Sense Sr. home at W’ ausau. N o te : A n y on e in this d istrict w
            ho w ish es to have new s printed in these columns, send it alo*ig w
            ith the ch ildren a tte n d in g school. Mrs. II* i man G ilbertson
            o f Shepley visited her d a u gh ter, M rs. A n d rew C h ristian
            son, on W ednesday. M rs. G u st S p itze r spent M onday at W
            ausau. Miss C ora K in n e y returned from E a g le R iv e r w h ere
            she spent the last tw o w eeks w ith old frien d s in E a g le R
            iver. M rs. Chas. Pau lson and M rs. O. H. Paulson and son Branch
            visited a t A n- »ig ". Th* Misses J o yce and M arian K a r a i t e
            , M iss C a rolin e Rasm ussen, and he Bulson fa m ily all o f E a g
            le R iv e r •ment the w eek-end w ith M rs. A . R. Bucknam. C h rist
            C h ristian son was called back o w ork on the h igh w a y. H u b e
            r t H u m b lrt o f N e w London visited at the A n d rew C
            hristianson home M onday nigh t. Ralph Bucknam le ft Sunday fo r
            sprin g w ork at E a g le R iver. Ruth B e rn itt, E dw ard Brunner,
            Fames G o w ell, C h ester P ierzch a lsk i, L es te r Stone, R ose
            M a rie B e rn itt, Jean E asker, R osella F red rick , G ladys H o
            ltz, G e o rg e L ieth en , C h arles P a u lson, pupils o f the
            fifth and sixth gra d e o f the N o r r ie P u blic School, a ft e r
            stu dyin g unit on p rin tin g in social studies, vis ite d the W
            itte n b e r g E n te rprise o ffice W ed n esd a y a ftern oon .
            BLUE GOOSE SCHOOLl ___________ Mr. and M rs. Ed. W a n ta o f
            W'ausau | visited at the home o f M r. and Mrs. A n to n D u d zig
            Sunday. Mr. and M rs. E dw in E rb rech t and fa m ily and A lm on d
            Sm ith visited w ith Mr. and M rs. H erm an Schroeder at A n tig o
            Sunday. M r. and Mrs. F e lix R ek ow sk i andj dau gh ters, S h
            irley and P a tricia , v is ited at the C h arles Bronk hom e in | R
            osh olt Th u rsday. Julian S troik was a business caller at T ig e
            rto n F rid a y. H e rb e rt B orch a rd t visited at the R ich ard
            B orchardt home Sunday. M iss G ertru de Zuch, the county su
            pervisor, visited our school M onday m orning. E lm er H ellesta d
            was a W itte n b e rg c a ller Satu rday. W e all had our pictu re
            taken M on day aftern o on . T h ese w ill be shown in a m ovie a t
            G a llo w a y n ext Tu esd ay n igh t. T h e Blue Goose School w on
            its third stra ig h t ball gam e F rid a y by d e fe a tin g the F
            orest V ie w School by a score o f 12 to 9 on th e ir grounds. M r.
            and M rs. Ben W a n ta o f N orsk visited at the hom e o f M r. and
            M rs. Paul Yach Sunday. M iss E sth er S troik w ho is em ployed a t
            W'ausau. visited w ith her parents, M r. and M rs. Julian S troik ,
            F rid a y. IC E D E L IV E R Y S E R V IC E W'e a re now d e liv e
            rin g ice to cu stom ers. Th e ra te fo r residences is $2 a m onth.
            D ependable service gu a ra n teed and you r patron a e g w ould be
            appreciated. Henry F. Kersten, W’ itte n b e rg , Phone 15-R2. W A
            YSID E SCHOOL M r. and M rs. Rudolph S choepke and loan and Ju nior
            v isited at the A rth u r T u lb e rg hom e Sunday a ftern oon . M
            r. and M rs. John Borchardt and fa m ily w ere Sunday even in g vis
            ito rs at the A r t Aanonsen home. V is ito rs a t th e A u g u st B
            orchardt home Sunday a ftern o o n w ere : H a rold, Trma and N o rm
            a n Aanonsen and Mr. nnd M rs. O scar F a lsta d and fa m ily . M r.
            and M rs. A . R. A g g e n and A r v illa attended the silv e r w ed
            d in g an n ivers a ry o f M r. and M rs. Ed. W end- V r Sundav. M
            rs. A lt a L ys n e, A lfr e d L ys n e and •hildren w e re a t the
            S an ford Iverso n home Sunday aftern o on . M rs. John E n glu n d
            and d au gh ter, Ruth, o f W itte n b e r g visited w ith M rs. M.
            G. Simonson and M am ie Simonson Sunday aftern o on . A rth u r and
            T ed S chaar spent Sunday a ftern o on a t the Jake B ern arde home.
            M r. and M rs. E a rl N elson and child- j ren called at the M a
            rtin A lb e r g hom e near M a ttoo n Sunday a ftern oon . M r. and
            M rs. F ra n k D e x te r o f M e n - ; asha v isited a t the Ed. K
            a u fm a n hom e I M onday. M r. and M rs. A r t C arlson and ch
            il-j dren w ere F r id a y ca llers a t the Ed. K a u fm a n home.
            Rich ard and R obert Simonson v is ited at the S lotten hom e
            Sunday. Rich ard and R o b ert Simonson v is ited a l th e S lotten
            hom e Sunday. M r. and M rs. L a w ren ce Buck and d a u gh ter
            spent Sunday a t th e Ed. K a u fm a n home. Klderon Club Plans P
            rojects Mr». A. E. Formella en terta in ed Ih e E ld eron W om en ’s
            Club at h er hom e in Elderon T h u rsd a y aftern o on , A p r il
            27. Th e business p o rtio n o f the m e etin g was conducted b y M
            rs. E. J. Benson, presiden t. A donation o f $1.00 w ill be sent to
            th e D isabled V e te ra n ’s H om e. A f t e r the usual business
            was taken care o f the fo llo w in g w ere decided on as p ro je c
            ts f o r th e sum m er: P la n tin g hollyhocks as a liv in g m em
            orial to Dr. Babcock, o f M a d iso n ; p la n tin g flo w e r s
            around the new club house in th e r»ark; the annual flo w e r show
            to be held som e tim e in A u gu st. M rs. K a rs ch n ey , ga rd en
            ch airm an , had ch a rg e o f th e fo llo w in g p ro g ra m : Mrs.
            A . J. P eterso n g a v e a v e r y in te re s tin g and in stru
            ctive ta lk on the p la n tin g and cu ltu re o f ro ses; M rs. W h
            itn ey read w “ A n In te rv ie w W ith Bob Burns in H is H o lly w
            o o d G a rd en ” ; Mrs. K a rs ch n ey read th e h isto ry and rom
            ance o f A n n ie Lau rie, a ft e r which M rs. M a rio n H a ffn e
            r sang th e song, “ A n n ie L a u rie .” A f t e r a ga m e o f jum
            bled nam es o f flo w e rs and v e g e ta b le , each con testa n t
            received a p o tte d plant fr o m M rs. K arsch n ey. A deliciou s
            lunch was served b y the hostess. O ut o f tow n gu ests w ere M rs.
            M a rio n H a ffn e r, o f O tta w a , Can ada, and M rs. M y rtle
            Biekle, o f A m h erst. Conservation Picture T h e W’ itte n b e rg
            Fish and G am e club is sp on sorin g a fine conservation ta lk in g
            p ictu re w h ich is to be show n at the B a d g e r T h e a tre
            here n ext F r id a y , S atu rd ay and Sunday, M ay 5, 6 and 7. T h
            e n am e o f th e pictu re is “ T h e W’ h ite T a ile d D eer,” and
            w ill be show n a lo n g w ith th e re g u la r p ro g ra m those
            nigh ts. DR. A B. S C H U LT Z , O P T O M E T R IS T . C O M IN G S
            A T U R D A Y E V E N IN G a t G a u erk e’s J e w e lr y S tore, W
            itt e n b erg, from 7 to 9 p. m. E y es tested and gla s s e s
            fitted. D A N C E Konkol’s Hall Room H A T L E Y . W IS. EVER Y SU N
            D A Y GOOD M USIC B A D G E R T H E A T R E W IT T E N B E R G , W
            IS C O N S IN S h o w in g e v e ry n igh t at 7:00 and 9:00 A D M
            IS S IO N 25c-15e-10c F R I. S A T. M A Y 5-6 L iv e aga in this m
            ig h ties t o f t h r ills ., o u t-lea pin g the m addest im a g in
            in g s! “KING KONG” A p e -lik e creatu re b ig as a ba ttlesh ip, h
            oldin g in his hands a trem b lin g g ir l, ra cin g thru streets,
            sm ashin g autos, crash in g w alls, sn atchin g a irplan es fr o m
            th e sk y! C O M E D Y : “ W estern W e lc o m e ” S P O R T S R E E
            L : “ Bird D o g s ” T E R R Y T O N E : “ V illa g e B la ck sm ith
            ” W A N T E D — Old and disabled horses j fo r m ink feed. A r th u
            r Larson , W i t ten berg. 2 4 -tf | PIA N O T U N IN G J A C K S O
            N M cC O N L E Y T IG E R T O N , W IS. P h on e: W itte n b e r g
            502R5 G ra d u a te o f N ile s B rya n t School o f P ia n o T u n
            in g CITIES SERVICE GARAGE E LD E R O N W IS C O N S IN INSION $1.11
            RIVERVIEW M r. and M rs. Rich ard Zander, sons Richard and M a rvin
            , M rs. Geo. M atz and d a u gh ter Joyce, M iss Frances L ip k e o
            f B o w ler visited in the Paul H anke home Sunday a ftern oon . L u
            cille H offm a n spent Sunday at the Rudolph E rickson home. M r.
            and M rs. O estreich o f W ausau visited in the Reynolds S ick ler
            home Sunday. M r. and M rs. A dolph D rew s and fa m ily , M rs. W’
            m. D rew s w ere ca llers in the H a rv e y Behn home in B irn am
            wood Sunday. M rs. E lm er M aahs and children and M rs. A n ton T r
            a t z spent F rid a y a ft e r noon in the A m e lia Buser home. M
            r. and M rs. O tto D ra eg er and •lau ghter S y lv ia and M rs. A m
            elia Buser visited in T ig e rto n Sunday. L a V on n e D ra e g e r
            attended a leagu e ra lly a t A n tig o Sunday. M r. and M rs. M y
            ro n P ik e visited w ith M r. and M rs. Louis S alzm an on Sunday.
            M r. and M rs. M y ro n P ik e and fa m ily spent S atu rd ay ev e n
            in g w ith M r and M rs. E. A sh on brenn er. SU N., MON., TU ES., M
            A Y 7, 8 9 Th e sp o rtin g blue gra ss tra d itio n o f noble
            thorou gh breds, ra cin g r iv a lr y , and the fam ed K en tu ck y
            D erb y in all th e splendor o f T ec h n ico lor L o retta R ich
            ard Y O U N G G R E E N E “KENTUCKY” w ith W A L T E R B R E N N A N
            T O P IC C A R T O O N N P .W S POCKET A N D WRIST WATCHES • 1 . 0 0
            t o * 3 . 9 5 ALARM C L O C K S 1 .0 0 t o 2 .9 5 L O O K FO R •
            ***?. O N THE D IA l W ED . T H U R S . M A Y 10-11 Sm ash ing rom
            an tic m elodram a o f adven tu re w ith wom en o f the sky A lic e
            Const ence N an cy F A Y E B E N N E T K E L L Y Joan D A V IS Jane
            W Y M A N “T A IL SPIN” w ith C H A R L E S F A R R E L C o m e d y:
            "Plum b C r a iy ” Terry Tone: “ Frozen Feet” Lew Lehr Topic: "W hat
            Every Girl Should Know” C h a p ter 11 o f “Custer’s Last Stand” 153
            HEAD OF LIVESTOCK A U C T IO N S A L E W ED NESD AY, M A Y 10
            Beginning at 12:30 P. M. Sharp CURTIS BLACK Farm Located l J/« miles
            N o f Shawano on State H ighw ay 55 17 I am leaving fo r the W est
            on an extended visit June 1 and for that reason I am selling all my
            high grade live stock. 10 H E A D O F GOOD F A R M W O R K H O R SE
            S 22 H E A D H IG H G R A D E H O L S T E IN D A IR Y C A T T L E -
            22 milk cows; all fresh and producing good. These cattle made more
            butterfat per cow than any other herd in this county; also negative
            to blood test. 1 ilig h G rade Holstein Sire. 11 yrs. old. 20 H igh
            Grade H ereford 1 yr. old Bulls. 100 Fancy Feeding W H IT E FAC ED H
            E R E F O R D S T E E R S : 1 year old; one of the best selections
            of steers to be found in this state. Thoroughly acclimated to this
            climate. T E R M S — All sums 14 down, balance 6 months credit- with
            monthly payments at 6 '. interest. Wisconsin Sales Corporation.
            Clerk. Col. A . L . Schoenike. Auctioneer. Clintonville. Wis. S top
            in and Shop FR ID A Y -SA T U R D A Y SPECIALS C O RN F L A K E S —
            Joannes brand A L arge 13 ounce package; 2 f o r
            ........................ 1/C GLO SS OR C O R N S T A R C H 4
            Joannes; 16 oz. packages; 2 f o r .................... XdC P O R K B
            E A N S — Joannes A B _ L a rge 30 ounce cans; 2 f o r
            .............................. J . / C P E A S — Cloverland, No. 3
            sieve E xtra fa n c y ; 20 ounce cans; 2 f o r .................. A
            M B R O S IA COCOA A n _ 2 lb. tin s; Special @
            ........................................ IO C G E N U IN E J E L L O
            A M _ In six delicious flavors; 3 f o r .......................... D
            IL L P IC K L E S — Cloverland n j > . E xtra fan cy; 101 oz.
            (gallon siz^e j u g ) .............. U U V C R E A M S A N D W IC H
            C O O KIE S A f . Thin shell, cream filled; 2 pounds f o r
            ............ A w v A M B R O S IA M IL K C H O C O L A T E . 4 m F
            or fu dge and icing; 8 oz. cakes; 2 f o r ........ 1 / C T O IL E T
            TIS S U E . Sanisorb a n . Wrapped, w hite ; 6 f o r
            ...................................... 2 u l > M A T C H E S —
            Diamond Brand 4 Q _ L arge blue tip ; 6 box carton
            ............................ I v v R U T A B A G A S — Real choice 4
            A . Firm and sw eet; 5 tbs. f o r .............................. IO
            C COFFEE SALE H O F F M A N ’S B R O W N IE 1 lb. packages 29c 2
            packages f o r . . . , H O F F M A N ’S O L D T IM E 24c Fancy
            blended Pound .................. C H A M P IO N Vaccum T in ; tb 24c
            L A W N GRASS Parkview , N o rth rup King, fo r shady lawn, *95.
            test; Per lb. 29c Evergreen, HunkePs Best, M ilwaukee Park m ix; 95.
            test. Per lb. 27c W hite Clover, N orth King d w a rf variety; 99.
            test; Per lb. 48c POTATOES N e w Y o rk Rurals, extra choice, for
            seed or table; Per Bu. 75c E arly Red Triumphs, a real early
            variety; Per Bu. 75c P . H . K U S S E R O W S O N 'ALU ES 'A F IE T
            Y A L L STEEL COASTER Full size, speedy, sturdy, heavy one-piece
            steel body. B ig 10-inch disc wheels — Congo roller bearings —
            |.-inch rubber tires — Usually sells fo r $3.55. Specially priced fo
            r Natonal H ardw are W eek ............ *2.49 CHROME PLATED SKILLET
            H eavy Steel skillet, with a lustrous, easyto- clean, chrome plate
            finish. No. O Q a 8, 104 in. size. Cool, wood h a n d le O J F x *
            HOUSE BROOM A good quality five-sewed broom. Usual 45c quality.
            Specially priced for National H ardw are W e e k .. DE LUXE L A W N
            MOWER Five blade; 16-inch c u t; Ball bearin gs; 10- inch W h eels;
            R ubber tires. A precision built mower that will give you many years
            of service.. The solid rubber tires give it better traction. The
            self-adjustin g ball bearings keep it easy running. A djustable bed
            knife. Varnished hard *7 ^ ? maple roller. Special price ^ ■ • I V G
            E N U I N E U N I V E R S A L FOOD CHOPPER Capacity 2 lbs. per
            minute. H eavily tinned. Complete with 4 knives C 4 / * Q A usual
            $1.95 va lu e .............. E N A M E L E D COLD PACK C A N N E R A
            big 17-quart kettle with an enameled cover and a canning rack that
            will hold seven quarts or pints. Speckled blue finish. N e ver
            before have we Q Q f * offered such a value! Only EN AM ELED STOVE P
            A N Size 9 x l3 :!4x2 23c W h ite with Black Trim, inches. Usual 40c
            value. W hile our supply lasts . T H R E E -P IE C E S T A R GARDEN
            SET A ll pieces fitte with attractive colored handles. A set you
            would expect to pay much more fo r! m 1 * * Special p r i c e
            .................. iu ytty $1.49 G . N . H a r d w a r e C o .</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
