<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>W39M08D31</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p>

W it t e n b e r g
T H K
I N E S S E N T I A L S . U N I T Y ; I N D O U B T F U L P O I N T S . L I B E R T Y ; I N A L L T H I N (J 8 . C H A R I T Y * *—M e l i n e t h t h o n
F O R T Y -S IX T H Y E A R . W IT T E N B E R G , S H A W A N O C O U N T Y . W IS C O N S IN . T H U R S D A Y , A U G U S T 31, 1939 N U M B E R 42
T a x Bill— Guess Again
Wisconsin citizens who wonder just
how they w ill be taxed in order that
the state m ight balance its budget or
who may have guessed which o f the
many tax proposals their legislative
representatives would choose, might
as w ell guess again. The parliamentary
entanglements and inconsistent
roll calls o f the past week indicate
that any guess is still a good one.
A s this week began, the senate had
tw o proposals before it. In the orig inal
tax revenue bill sent to it by the
assembly there remained the two cent
per package cigarette tax expected to
raise 6 million dollars, earmarked fo r
relief, and a re-enactment o f the 60
per cent surtax on incomes estimated
to bring in $4,800,000. Stricken from
the bill are the increased liquor and
wine taxes, the reduced exemptions
fo r the teacher’s retirement fund, and
the fla t 6 per cent tax on corporations.
The senate in its final action before
adjourning fo r the week end also refused
to kill by a 14-13 vote the substitute
amendment o f Senator Jess
Peters o f H artford, which proposed to
divert 7Vfe million dollars during the
biennium from the highway fund. The
Peters substitute also includes the
cigarette tax, the 60 per cent surtax
and the 6 per cent corporations tax.
Then, too, still pending and on which
no vote has yet been taken is the sales
tax substitute offered by Senator
W hite which provides fo r a general 3
per cent sales tax with rebates to local
governments fo r relie f o f general
property taxes.
Th e Income Tax Increase
When the senate convened a week
ago it appeared as though they would
pass the increased income tax bill as
offered in an amendment by Senator
Otto Mueller, the finance committee
chairman. The increased surtax on
income was expected to raise 14 m illions
and would have made Wisconsin
income taxes the highest in the nation.
The amendment which grew out
o f a series o f conferences between
Democrats and Republicans was rumored
to have full support of the
coalition. Even Progressives, some o f
tJiem, admitted that it was the best
tax plan that had been offered.
The upper house promply set to
work on the new amendment, but then
things began to happen. Milwaukee
senators aided by Progressives and
Democrats amended the amendment
to guarantee payment by the state of
30 per cent o f all local relie f costs.
Another amendment offered by G ettleman
to the amendment reduced the
suggested increased surtax 25 per cent
cutting the estimated revenue down to
10*^ millions and earmarked the entire
amount fo r old age pensions.
As that Tuesday ended the tax bill
was a mess. I t contained a cigarette
tax and an income surtax with nearly
all o f it earmarked fo r relief and pensions
and practically nothing fo r the
general state fund.
On Thursday again the senate
changed its mind. Previous actions
were reconsidered and the income tax
surtax amendment was withdrawn.
By Friday they had patched up the
original tax revenue bill to where it
included the cigarette tax and 60 per
cent surtax which will raise about
lO ^ million dollars. By a compromise
the state’s share o f local relie f payments
was le ft at 15 per cen t As the
week ended they w ere considering
highway monies diversion.
Highw ay Diversion
Even though the assembly months
ago by an almost unanimous vote rejected
a highw ay diversion proposal,
the senate’s action in refusing to kill
the Peters substitute indicates that
there are still legislators who believe
that it would be better to use highway
funds than to levy new taxes.
Senator Peters, author o f the
amendment, told fellow senators that
in these times of financial stress it is
“ foolish to build super-highways.” He
maintained that the state’s roads are
good enough for another two years
and that with the exception o f needed
repair work, highway construction
could be delayed.
Senator Conners, Rice Lake, opposed
the highway money plan. He told
Peters that he was glad that highways
were in good shape in southern W isconsin,
but that in Barron county they
did not have a single through concrete
road. Senator Nelson, Maple, mad*-
sim ilar statements for W’ ashburn and
Bayfield counties.
Asked by Senator Ingram if highw
ay diversion would not result in the
loss o f federal aid, Peters admitted
that the state m ight lose 3 million
dollars from the federal department.
However, he pointed out that if thi*
state had to assess 14 million dollars
Groh-Diestler Nuptial**
The Rev. George Groh, pastor of
Bethlehem Lutheran church in Milan,
officiated at the m arriage o f his
daughter, Ellen, to Adolph Diestler,
son o f Mrs. William Diestler, town of
Birnamwood, which was solemnized
Saturday afternoon at the church parsonage.
The bride wore a stone-blue crepe
afternoon frock and a corsage of
gardenias, and her sister, Miss Marguerite
E. Groh. Sparta, who was her
only attendant, wore an antique rose
afternoon frock and a corsage o f
mixed flowers. The bridegroom was
attended by the bride’s brother,
G. Edwin Groh, Milwaukee.
A buffet supper was served at the
home o f the bride’s parents to 25
guests, a fter which the couple departed
fo r a wedding trip to the
Pacific coast and a tour o f western
states. A fte r September 15, they will
be at home to friends on the groom’s
farm home.
The out-of-town guests at the wedding
included Miss Sadie Espeseth,
Eagle River, Mr. and Mrs. Vern Naset,
Portage. Miss Laura Butter, Mayville,
Miss Florence Schaumberger and
George Groh, Plymouth, Mr. and Mrs. j
A. J. Groh and fam ily, Milwaukee,
Miss Dorothy Groh, Long Beach, Cal.,
Mrs. William Diestler, Wittenberg,
Mrs. Edna Berkhahn and sons, ClintoQville,
Mr. and Mrs. George H illary
and daughter, o f Waukesha, and Miss
Ruth Sisson, o f Greenville.
worth o f taxes to save the 3 million
dollars federal aid, he still believed it
would be sound business.
The diversion o f highway money
was to receive further consideration
early this week.
Long SeasmnH
Lengthy Wisconsin legislative sessions
would become a thing o f the
(Continued on Page 4)
School O p e n s M o n d a y
M o r n in g , Septem ber 4
( S h t t t c l n f a i t o ! — ' ■■ 1 ■ ——r— — —. ■ i ■
Church o f the Holy Family
N o mass on Sunday.
Henry Schmitt, Pastor.
First Lutheran Church
Sunday Services:
10:45 a. m. Divine worship.
9:30 a. m. Sunday school.
On Sunday, Sept. 10, our Sunday
school w ill have a rally day.
Tuesday: Luther League entertained
at the home o f Ruth and Gerhard
Johnson.
Thursday: Ladies A id entertained
by Mrs. H arry Briggs, Mrs. N. B.
Ursin, and Miss Anna Reinert.
Confirmation instruction on Saturday
at 9 a. m. You are welcome to
join our confirmation class. W e will
have a junior and senior class.
Palmer A. Wahl, Pastor.
St. John’s Lutheran Church
Sunday, Sept. 3. English services
at 9 a. m. A class o f 5 adults w ill be
received into membership by confirmation.
Carl Musall, Pastor.
St- Paul’s Evang. Lutheran Church
Services in the American language
at 9:30 a. m. This service will be
dedicated to thechildren o f the church.
Sunday school at 10:30 a. m.
Services and Sunday school at Shepley
at 10:45 a. m.
G. F. Fierke, Pastor.
Methodist Church
Sunday school 9:45 a. m.
Morning worship 11:00.
Union C ircle’s annual business meeting
September 13.
Annual Conference at Green Bay on
September 5th to 10th.
There w ill be no services on Conference
Sunday, September 10.
Ralph W. Hawkins, Pastor.
Lutheran Home Mission
Young people’s meeting Sunday 8:00
p. m.
Prayer meeting Wednesday 8 p. m.
H. E. Engebretson, Pastor.
The Evangelical Free Church
(Services in Town H all.)
Sunday school 9:45 a. m.
Norwegian services 10:45. Topic:
“ A Church, which had le ft its first
Love.”
English evening service 8 p. m.
Wednesday evening at 8 o’clock midweek
prayer service.
Saturday 10 a. m. The confirmation
class will meet.
C. Kjeldgaard, Pastor.
Elderon Methodist Church
There w ill be no services on C onference
Sunday, September 10. Our next
services w ill be Sunday, Sept. 24.
Confirmation class meets Saturday
2 p. m.
R. W. Hawkins, Pastor.
Registration Monday
A ll grade children w ill assemble in
their respective rooms at 9:00 o’clock
Monday morning to enroll, check on j
textbook needs and receive first assignments.
The high school students
will also meet at 9:00 o’clock and will
register between 9:00 and 9:30. From
9:30 to 10:00 textbooks will be distributed
a fter which all classes will meet
fo r assignments. The afternoon will
be devoted to faculty meetings and
arranging classes.
Grace Byse Resigns Teaching Position
Another teaching vacancy was
created in the local teaching staff this
week when Grace Byse, 1st and 2nd
grade teacher fo r the past two years,
resigned to accept a similar position
in the Rhinelander school system.
Miss Marcelline Warbelton, o f Stevens
Poin t*w h o recently received her
Bachelors Degree in Prim ary Education
from the State Teachers College
in the same city, has been signed to
teach the 1st and 2nd grades during
the coming year.
I t has been the aim o f the local
Board to employ, whenever possible,
teachers with college degrees. A t the
present time all teachers employed in
the W ittenberg school have bachelors
degrees, representing at least four
years o f college training preparing
them fo r their profession. The
local school is one o f few schools of its
size that have attained that goal.
Grade Textbook Changes
A fe w texts w ill be replaced by later
editions. Copyrights o f some books
now in use are from 10 to 20 years
old. Changes already decided upon
are 8th grade Reading, Health and
Agriculture. 7t.h grade History, Geo-1
graphy and Reading.
Rand Notice
One year ago when Mr. Born took j
over the band work o f the school he
was very enthusiastic about giving thc ;
community a good school band. To do j
this he used part o f the school day
as well as much o f his own time forj
individual instruction free o f charge.
Tbis year Mr. Born will make a charge
o f twenty-five cents fo r individual lessons
given outside o f the school day, 1
which is from 8:30 to 4:30. Mr. j
Born’s erades w ill require more o f his 1
time this pear as the enrollment will j
be almost again as large. Further- •
more only a limited number o f stu- 1
dents seek musical instruction a n d ,
those benefiting directly should pay,
for the privilege.
Student A id Program
The National Youth Administration j
provides part time employment o f ,
needy students between the ages o f 16,
and 24 inclusive, in regular school
attendance in order to enable them to
continue their education. Monthly
allotments are made available for
payment to eligible students. W’ ittenberg
high school w ill have a monthly
allotment of $30.00 which will provide
work for from 5 to 10 students. The
monthly payment to each student will
be established within the maximum o f
$6.00 and a minimum o f $3.00. Students
feeling the need of this assistance
shall make application with the
Principal o f the school.
C O N F E R E N C E IN G RE EN B A Y
Methodist Annual Conference will
be held at First Methodist church in
Green Bay starting Tuesday, Sept. 5.
Mrs. Arthur Olsen is the lay delegate.
A very interesting program has been
arranged for this year’s conference,
some o f the speakers being Bishop
Ralph S. Cushman, St. Paul archbishop;
Bishop Edwin Lee, Singapore;
Edgar G. Doudna, secretary of the
board o f regents o f state teachers’ college;
Dr. Ralph Stockman, o f Christ
Episcopal church. New York C ity; Dr.
Nathaniel Forsythe, board of education;
Prof. G eorge Teter; Miss Edna
Hutchins, Girls* High School, Cawnpore,
India; Steven A. Habaush.
There will be music on Thursday
evening by the Oneida Indian Mission
Choir.
District Attorney
Directs Clean-un of
Disorderly Houses
A L L P L E A D G U IL T Y A N D F IN E S
A N D COSTS ASSESSED T O T A L
A L M O S T *2.000
W IT T E N B E R G TO D IS P L A Y
BOOTH A T C O U N T Y F A IR
The township o f W ittenberg will
have a display booth at the county fa ir
again this year. A ll persons livin g in
either the city or town o f W ittenberg
are invited to display their products.
The products displayed in the booth
are entered in competition in the open
classes and are eligible for prizes.
Last year a number o f folks from
W ittenberg won prize money on the
products displayed in the booth.
A committee composed o f O. B.
Hagen, Clarence Loken and Karl E.
K orting are in charge of the booth
this year. I f you have any flowers,
fruits, vegetables, grains, or other
crops of good quality, don’t miss this
opportunity o f showing them. Get in
touch with any member o f the committee
so arrangements can be made
fo r gettin g the exhibits to Shawano.
I f the committee is notified, it will
see that the exhibits are gotten to the
F air and properly entered. In case
you are doubtful as to how your product
should be prepared fo r F air display,
get in touch with any booth
committee member. He will be glad
to give you this information and will
even help you select the best specimens
fo r display. Most prizes in these
classes range from seventy-five cents
to three dollars. For a complete list
o f entries and prizes see a premium
list. Tuesday, September 5th, is entry
day at the Fair so all products must
be ready by ta b o r Day.
Help advertise W’ ittenberg by par
ticipating in a good booth display!
A quiert and efficient investigation of
vice conditions in Shawano county
ended Tuesday night when five disorderly
houses w ere raided and a total
o f 22 people, including five operators
and 17 inmates, 15 o f whom were
women, were arrested and brought
into Shawano county court.
The raid occurred at 10:30 o’clock
and was planned and conducted with
a special force o f deputies working
under direction o f District Attorney
James A. Larson and the sheriff’s department.
Places raided included
Blondie’s Inn in the town o f Belle
Plaine, Sam F avia’s bar at Pine Lake,
the Brick House jit Eland, the E vergreen
Inn near P tfA v and Slab C ity
tavern near Bonduel.
Operators and inmates arrested
were Vivian Roberts, Ed. Co-ttingham.
Sam Favia, Leonard Roberta. Frank
Licurse, Mildred Meyer, Sylvia W illiams,
Lou Connor, Fern Dean, Joan
Fields, F ay McKayne, Mrs. Sam F avia,
Judy Blaine, Bonnie O ’Brien.
Margaret O’Donnell, Antoinette P eltier,
June McCormick, John Roberta.
Earl Brown and Francis Roberts.
A thorough investigation of the
conduct o f such places in Shawano
county had been going on under cover
fo r the past several weeks by Otis
Gomillion, an undercover man of Milwaukee,
and two assistants, under
direction o f District A ttorney James
Larson o f Shawano county. Besides
the five places raided, many others
w ere checked, but were found to be
living up to promises made by them
to their respective town boards. Last
January District Attorney Larson, by
letter, requested 13 places in this
county to cease operating under vice
conditions.— Shawano Journal.
Anna Lee Is Bride o f Professor
Announcement is made of the
m arriage o f Miss Anna Olivia Lee.
Milwaukee musician and composer,
and Dr. Frank E. Ross, o f Williams
Bay, Wis., professor o f astronomy at
Yerkes observatory and the University
o f Chicago, on Monday, August 21, at
Dubuque, Iowa.
Only a few intimate friends of the
couple attended the ceremony, performed
by Dr. C. H. Buell in the First
Presbyterian church in Dubuque.
Prof. 01iv«v J. Lee. director o f N orthwestern
observatory, was best man.
Miss Florence Schiller, o f Milwauke
Mrs. Helen Hamlin, o f Evanston, and
Victor Heiser, of Williams Bay, wen
among the guests.
The bride, who is w idely known as
a pianist, has been active in the Mac-
Dowell club and the Walrus club. Dr
Ross, nationally known for his studies
in the variation o f latitude and
planetary and stellar photography, is
a member of the national academy to
the American Astronomical society
Previous to coming to Yerkes in 1924.
he had taught astronomy at several
universities, done research for thi
Carnegie institute, and served as research
head for a large photography
supplies concern.
Shawano County
Opens Three-Day
Fair Next Tuesday
Louis W. Cattau. Secretary o f the
Shawano County Fair, announces a
big and varied program fo r this year’s
Fair which w ill open on Sept. 5, entry
day, and continue for two big days and
nights, Sept. 6th and 7th. N o effort
has been spared to make this year’s
Fair outstanding both from the standpoint
o f larger and better exhibits and
a program o f entertainment which will
be pleasing to both old and young.
The huge barns will be filled with exhibits
o f the best livestock o f different
breeds and classes, the exhibition halls
w'ill be filled with the finest products
o f the farm and field, inviting your
inspection and interest. The Shawano
County F air prides itself in the exhibits
and in the fact that it is an
agricultural Fair in the true sense of
the word, promoting agriculture as its
first and final purpose, and combining
the educational advantages o f an agricultural
Fair with good clean wholesome
entertainment and good-fellow ship.
One may go to a carnival any
time during the summer, or see a
show, but you have not “ taken in” the
Shawano County F a ir until you have
seen the great display of agricultural
products and other exhibits, fo r which
after all, a F air is sponsored. So see
the F air in its entirety, meet your
friends and neighbors and old acquantances
there, get away fo r two days
from the work and w orry: the
Shawano County F air extends its invitation
to you.
Attractions
By popular request we have secured
W L S with Lulu Belle and Skyland
Scotty fo r Thursday night, Sept. 7.
With her on the platform will be a
full cast of the W L S Barn Dance
Show featuring the Prairie Sweethearts,
Georgie Goebel, H ayloft
Fiddlers, Miss Pauline, and Ralph and
Helen Sternard; an hour and one half
show o f good clean fun, comedy and
music. Lulu Belle, since appearing at
the Shawano County Fair several
years ago, has become a famous movie
star in her own right and has appeared
in a number o f pictures in Holly
wood. W e are indeed fortunate in securing
this nationally known movie
and radio star to appear in person at
the Shawano County Fair.
“ Happy Harrison” with her troupe
of merrymakers, offers a modern animal
circus, in a feast o f fast fun and
feature tricks. H er animals are her
friends, her pets, and business partner.
Miss Harrison has always been
tremendously popular with her circus.
The Gasca Trio offers one o f the
most unique type o f acts in show
business. Three Mexican boys working
on rolling balls, doing outstanding
acrobatic routines. This is the one and
only act o f its kind and this is their
first appearance at any Fair. Senor
Pedro, the wonder o f the wire, one of
the m o*l outstanding wire acts ever
seen in this country. The tricks accomplished
by Senor Pedro on the wire
are almost unbelievable.
The Fair also presents the Stuart
Roberts Trio, three finished artists
performing exciting feats o f hairraising
calibre combined with astonishingly
clever comedy.
Another entirely new and different
act is Fenwick and Cook late stars of
the W hite Horse Tavern.
On the night of September 6th, the
Farm Hands will entertain before the
grandstand.
Baseball
An extremely strong baseball schedule
has been arranged on Sept. 6 th. A
big double-header will be played with
Shawano opposing Gresham and T ille da
playing Krakow. On September 7
Fierke Hurls No-Hit, No-Run
Game As Pilots Win Pennant
Improvements
Albert Smith last week put in a new
concrete walk in front o f his place of
business after putting in a wood shute
at the front o f the building and a retaining
wall in the basement.
The fronts of the Wittenberg Cooperative
store buildings have been
given new coats of paint and present
a much improved appearance.
John iA rson has been busy for several
days repainting and renovating
the interior o f his barber shop.
A county road crew began this morning
the work of removing the surplus
gravel and stone dust from the
main business streets, follow ing recent
application o f a tarred surfacing. To
allay the remaining dust, the fire department
this evening used lengths of
hose fo r flushing the streets with
water from the hydrants.
LOCAL NEWS NOTES
Mr. and Mrs. Louis Glaubitz and
son Hugo, o f Milwaukee, made a visit j
in the Glaubitz home early this week j
while on their way fo r an outing a t !
Pelican take.
Mrs. August Zietlow, of Neenah, and j
daughter Lena and her husband, of
Gillett, were week-end visitors in thej
O. B. Hagen and William Spargo;
homes.
Miss Carolyn Rolfson enjoyed a 3-!
weeks vacation from duties as secretary
to the president at Central State
Teachers College in Stevens Point, and |
spent it at her home here.
Mrs. J. R. Carmany o f Newberry,
Michigan, and her son, Burton, and
his w ife, o f Flint, Michigan, spent the
week-end in the home o f her brotherin-
law, G. H. Carmany, and family.
Mr. and Mrs. Carl Nelson and
daughters, Clarisse Mae and Laverne
Joan, of Minneaipolis, visited in the!
“limnp csf STVs.* NelsJVnVi "parents. Mr.
and Mrs. O. B. Hagen, from Friday
until Sunday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Otto Wendler and
children. Alma and Margaret, and Mr.
and Mrs. Clarence Wendler and son, I
Roger, spent Sunday in the Herman
Schwartzkopf home in Neenah. Mrs. j
Otto Wendler remained there fo r a
longer visit. Miss Sadie Wendler, who
had been making a six-weeks visit in !
the Schwartzkopf home, returned here j
on Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. W alter Puchner and i
son, Richard, and Mrs. Bamford, of
Santa Rosa, California, departed today
after a week’s visit here. They |
expect to visit in New Holstein and J
other places in Wisconsin before
going back to California. W alter has j
a good job in a mercantile establishment
in Santa Rosa, a fine city not far
from San Francisco.
Mrs. Mark Hitzke and daughter
Rosemary returned home Monday evening
a fter a visit of two weeks in the
liee C raig home in Rockford. Ill , and
with Donald Hitzke, who is employed
in Rockford. Donald was one o f the
many who took an airplane ride with
Mr. Chamberbin, noted world war
aviat r, while he was at the Rockford
airport several weeks ago.
Dr. arul Mrs. E. E. Evenson and
daughter Ann returned on Wednesday
from their trip to the West. They
were gone four weeks. Their tour included
the Pacific coast states and
they got as fa r south as San Francisco.
From there thev headed home by
A no hit game put the Wittenberg
Pilots’ pitcher into the hall o f fame
last Sunday when Kelly was the victim
o f one o f the best hurling exhibitions
seen in this part o f the country in a
long time.
Had it not been for a few walks
the game would have been written
into the history books as the first and
only perfectly pitched game. Others
have hurled no-hitters, but someone
has yet to turn in a perfect game.
Fierke struck out twelve batters.
Fierke is the second pitcher to pitch
a no hitter in the Shawano-Marathon
League since its existence. The other
was pitched by Joe McKlosky for
K elly in 1937.
The game rang down the curtain
on the Shawano-Marathon league season,
which was declared by W. H.
Yaeger, secretary, to be the best
since the league was organized several
years ago. W ittenberg won the pennant
with a full game margin over
their closest rival, Wausau.
The Athletics put on a valiant fight
throughout the year, keeping ahead
o f the pack, but they weakened in the
stretch and the Pilots pulled out in
front to win.
Scores Sunday. August 27
W IT T E N B E R G
Gunderson, ss .
Hubert, 2b . . . .
* Mason, 2b
Arnold, 3b . . . .
Vance, r f .......
Fierke, p ..........
Storm, If .......
Cowles, cf . . . .
Pukall. l b ............... 4
Derrow, c .........
Totals .........
K E L L Y
Karl, 2b ...........
A. La Porte, cf .
Messerknecht, If
Green, I f ...........
Russ, lb ...........
Young, 3b .......
Gusman, r f .......
E. La Porte, ss .
Sickler, c .........
Jolin, p .............
Totals .........
* Mason hat.U*d for Hubert in 9th.
Team Standings (F in a l)
AR R H PO A E
4 1 0 3 8 2
.3 0 2 1 1 1
.1 0 0 1 0 0
4 0 1 0 2 0
.4 0 1 0 0 0
4 0 2 0 1 0
.4 0 1 ft 0 0
4 0 0 2 0 0
4 1 2 7 1 0
0 1 IS 2 1
35 2 10 27 9 4
AB R H PO A E
.3 0 0 3 4 0
4 0 0 0 0 0
.2 0 0 1 0 0
.1 0 0 2 0 0
.3 0 0 17 0 0
4 0 0 1 6 0
.3 0 0 1 0 0
.2 0 0 1 3 0
2 0 0 1 0 0
.3 0 0 0 5 1
27 0 0 27 18 1
Won Lost Pet.
Wittenberg ............12 2 .857
Wausau ........... ........... 11 3 .786
Edgar ............... ............ 9 5 .643
Elderon ........... ........... 8 6 .571
Eland ............... ........... 8 6 .571
A n iw a ............... ........... 4 10 .286
K e l l y ................. ........... 4 10 .286
Birnamwood . . ........... 0 14 .000
They
th- F «,r m .n w m e n t b u book.dIS. r(.)a
mour t o Play Clm tonv,lle. Both o f ,m h h a (,k
t h n * team., . r e ,t nut for mu-h
first place in t.h ei.r le*a gu, e an■ d have.1 uibiv A«*a av f n/« M luuii
been natural rivals during the past
summer. In addition to the baseball
Band Concert
Friday Night
Free Band Concert a t Washington
Park, Wittenberg, by Wittenberg
Concert Band tomorrow (F r id a y ) nite
at 8:00 o’clock.
program there will be a Kittenball
Championship, contest fo r the champion
o f the entire county.
Racing
Already many entries have been received
for the big race program Sept.
6th and 7th. There will be three big
races each day, featuring an extrem ely
fast race September 7th in the 2.09
pace with 2.07 trotters eligible.
Dance Program
The three big dances will be held in
the Dance Pavilion. The floor of this
huge hall has been sanded and put into
! first class shape. On September 5th,
entry night, Lawrence Duchow and hi**
Red Ravens w ill be at the Fair.
The next night, September 6th, the
I Farm Hands will play for the dance.
| On the last night o f the Fair. Sept.
7th, a modern dance band will play for
the dance. The F air has engaged Bob
Malcolm for this dance which promises
to be a drawing card fo r the last night
o f the Fair.
Bands
Recent visitors at the Mission were:
Dr. and Mrs. Wm. Bernstein, o f New
Richland, Minn., and Miss Bernice
Goldberg, o f Minneapolis; Dr. Harold
Tolo, of Stevens Point, and Rev. and
Mrs. G. W. Tolo and fam ily, o f Fertile,
Minn.; Fred Lier, o f Green Bay; Rev.
W. Johnson, of Rosholt; Rev. and Mrs.
T. J. Tanner and family, o f Ulen,
Minn.; Miss Bertha Berg, o f Chetek.
Carl W o lf came from Highland Park
Friday for a few days’ stay in W ittenberg.
He was accompanied home
on Sunday by his w ife and daughter
Margie, who had come earlier for
visit with Mrs. W olf’s parents, Mr.
and Mrs. William Berbaum. The Enterprise
acknowledges a pleasant call
by Mr. W olf, who is the secretarytreasurer
(rf the Western Printers
Supply company in Chicago.
EXTRA
T O W IT T E N B E R G F R IE N D S
Mrs. Anna Netzel has a lunch stand
at the Shawano County Fair and
would be glad to serve Wittenberg
Bands and music will be in evidence friends who may feel hungry or thirsover
the grounds, W ittenberg playing ty while taking in the sights of the
j on September 7th and Shawano High fair. She invites you to look her up
School band on Sept. 6th. while there.— Adv.
W A R SA W BOMBED!
W A S H IN G T O N . I) C— A P Radio
Dispatch — President Roosevelt received
official word this morning at
2:f>0 o’clock from the I 7. S. ambassadors
at Paris and London that Poland
had been invaded by German troop*
nnd that fleets o f planes had dropped
bombs on Warsaw and three other
large cities in Poland. Poland has
officially notified France and England
o f Ihe events, so the reports stated,
and begged for immediate aid.
TKe cabinet* and parliaments! o f
France, Germany and England are
meeting this morning in emergency
sessions.
* # *
A M S T E R D A M — ( I N S )— A Reuters
dispatch, unconfirmed, state that German
and Polish troops are engaged in
heavy fighting along the entire frontiers.
Leases Feuerpfeil Garage
Eldred Hull has leased the Feuerpfeil
garage in this village and will be
ready to serve customers on September
1. The son of Mr. and Mrs Wm.
Hull, former residents of the town of
Morris now living in Bowler, Eldred
has had 15 years o f experience in automobile
repair work. He expects to
carry a complete line o f Cities Service
Co. products in oils and automobile accessories.
Elsewhere in this issue is
an announcement by Mr. Hull.
W e understand that Mr. Feuerpfeil
will continue in business at the same
place as the local Chevrolet agent.
• ♦ ■> ..... .—
N o Business I>ahor Day
As usual, the business places of
W ittenberg will not be open on Labor
Day, September 4.
The postoffice will be open for a
few hours during the day for the dispatch
and distribution o f mail.
THE W ITTENBERG ENTERPRISE. W ITTENBERG. W IS
W EEKLY NEWS ANALYSIS HY HENRY W. PORTER
New Crisis Looms as Germany
And Poland Mobilize Troops;
Chamberlain Summons Aides
(E D I T O R 'S N O T E — W h en o p in io n * a r e e x p r e s s e d In th e s e c o lu m n s , th e y
a r e th ose o f th e n e w s a n a ly s t a n d n o t n e c e s s a r ily o f th is n e w s p a p e r .)
R e lea se d bv W estern N e w s p a p e r Union
World aUeuuua w as lucused early this week on me In lie town of
Zilina (shown a b o v e), strategic railw ay center of Slovakia where 50.000
Germ an troops w ere reported to be concentrated a fter the Keich had
taken m ilita ry possession of the Slovak republic which was already under
Germ an “ protection." From Zilina m ore than a quarter of a m illion w ere
deploying: along a 100-mile front facin g the Polish border.
E U R O P E :
Week of Crisis
P eace or w ar?
Renew ed a ctivity, both m ilitary
and diplom atic, indicated that this
question m ay be answered one w ay
or the other before this w eek of
crisis ends.
Concentration of m ore than a
quarter o f m illion Germ an troops,
fully equipped for w ar, along Slova
k ia 's border with Poland followed
closely upon a conference between
H itler and Count Stephen Csaky,
Hungarian foreign minister, after
which it was announced that Hunga
ry and tha Reich had become
firm ly allied. Both o f these moves
w ere regarded as a part o f the G erman
plan to “ en circle” Poland and
as a buildup for H itler’ s m aking a
“ final o ffe r” to Poland on his demands
for D anzig and a link with
East Prussia through Pom o rze (the
Polish C orridor).
T o m eet this arm ed threat, Poland
began sending troop reinforcem ents
toward her frontiers facin g G erm any
and Slovakia as a “ precautionary
m easure against any eventu ality.’ *
H ow ever, there w ere indications
that Poland, feelin g this m ilitary
pressure, m ight advance some plan
fo r settlem ent o f the Danzig question
by negotiation.
Th ere w ere equ ally strong indications
that she would resist arm ed
fo rce with arm ed fo rce and count
upon Great B ritain to back her up.
Whether o r not her confidence in
that backing is w ell-placed w ill becom
e apparent if P r im e M inister
Chamberlain, who interrupted a va cation
in Scotland to return to London.
issues a statem ent after his
conference with F oreign Secretary
Lord H alifax, W ar M inister Leslie
Hore-Belisha, Sir John Simon, chancellor
of the exchequer. Sir Samuel
Hoare, home secretary, and M alcolm
M acDonald, colonial secietary.
Significant was an editorial
in the London Tim es, which often
reflects the view s of the British government.
It said that G reat Britain
had given Poland " a specific pledge
from which it w ill not and can not
recede. It had given no such
pledge to Czecho-Slovakia.”
Meanwhile, if negotiation, rather .
than arm ed force, is used to solve .
t h e D a n z i g i
question, the |
impetus for it
m a y c o m e
f r o m R o m e .
A fte r his conference
with
H itler, Count
Csaky flew to
t h e I t a l i a n
c a p i t a l f o r
co n ve rs a tio n s
with Mussolini
and his foreign
m i n i s t e r .
Count Ciano,
a fter which he returned to Budapest.
ernment has invited the m inisters
o f six sm all powers to rush to Brussels
by airplane and join with Belgium
in a peace plea to the larger
nations. Those who w ere invited
and who are said to have accepted
the invitation w ere the Netherlands,
Luxem burg, Sweden, N orw ay, Denm
ark and Finland.
LABOR:
‘Onft' on Ford?
Th e Ford M otor company has notified
the National Labor Relations
board that it would not com ply with
an order which the board had issued
against it reaffirm in g its earli-
I er ruling that the com pany was
guilty of violating the W agner act
; by refusing to reinstate 24 men, said
j to have been discharged for union
activity.
The new labor board decision re-
| tained the disputed section o f the
e a rlier ruling which required the j
firm to “ cease and desist from . . .
interfering writh . . . its em ployees |
in the exercise of rights guaranteed
in Section 7 of the act by circulating,
distributing, or otherw ise dissem
inating among its em ployees
statem ent o f propaganda which dis-
POLITICS:
1Stop Spending!'
Calling upon the Roosevelt adm inistration
to take the lead in a cooperative
effort by business, labor,
farm ers and ethers to stimulate production,
the A m erican F ederation of
Labor in its monthly survey of business
declared that an expansion of
industry is necessary to forestall “ a
further demand for governm ent
spending, with its danger o f inflation
and consequent losses to w age
earn ers."
It said experts contended that production
increases could be planned
for the country as a whole, but that
businessmen w ere not likely to lead
in the expansion because business
risks w ere grea ter and profits sm aller
than in predepression years.
D efeat of the adm inistration’s
lending bill w as cited as evidence
that congress had rejected the
“ pump-priming’ ’ theory of stim ulating
recovery and by so doing had
placed the responsibility on business.
This suggestion o f a farm er-laborbusiness-
government get-together,
following close upon the heels of a
sim ilar suggestion by Philip M urray,
C. I. O. vice president, is regarded
as evidence that the A. F.
o f L. is not only trying to bring a
labor peace but w ill probably side
with business in the 1940 cam paign
against a Roosevelt-backed candidate,
unless he discards his philosophy
of spending as a method o f recovery.
DOMESTIC:
llund 'Immorality
Back from Washington, w here she
had told the Dies com m ittee that
she had quit as a G erm an-Am erican
Bund Youth leader because of
“ im m orality’ ’ in their cam ps, went
19-year-old H elen Vooros to her
home in Brooklyn. As she sat in a
restaurant an eight-year-old boy
handed her an iodine bottle label,
on the back o f which was penciled,
in shorthand, “ Goodbye, life .” The
boy who d elivered this death threat
C O U N T C S A K Y
A go-betueen?
H E N R Y F O R D
Denied “free ipeech"?
parages or criticizes labor organ ization
. .
The board referred m ainly to the
fam ous “ F ordism s’ * as w ritten by
H en ry Ford. The quotations contained
anti-union sentiments.
In replying to the labor board, P.
E. Martin, Ford vic e president, denied
that the com pany had discharged
m em bers of the United Autom
obile W orkers o f A m erica or otherw
ise intim idated them and
charged that the right o f fre e speech
was being denied Ford.
A G R ICU L TU R E :
M ilk Parley
As the result of renewed violence
in upstate N ew Y ork, m arked by
m ore milk-dumping and some skullcracking
when police and state
troopers clashed with m ilk plant
pickets, M ayor F iorello LaG uardia
NATIONAL
AFFAIRS
Rtvitwtd by
C ARTER FIELD
Cynics suspect President
would be pleased if business
slumped a little thereby justifying
his remarks on failure
of congress to pass the spendlend
bill . . . Now Senator
Wheeler looms as possibility
for the Democratic nomination
for President. . . Roosevelt
seeks a way to make the
administration the leader in
the improvement in business.
N o official announcement o f he re- ; of N ew Y ork cU h k
suit of this conference w as forthcom - f a rm er and distributor representam
g but it is considered likely that the tlves lnt0 a conference £
axis powers hope to m ake Csaky *
go-between for negotiations between
B erlin and W arsaw. Since Hungary
has been on friendly terms
with Poland and with the axis powers.
especially Ita ly, the Hungarian
foreign m inister would fit w ell into
this role.
What effect the recently proclaim
ed trade agreem ent between
G erm any and Russia w ill have upon
the resumption of negotiations for a
three-power mutual asistance
a greem ent between G rea t Britain,
F ran ce and the Soviet is still undeterm
ined. Th is agreem ent, which
w ill probably g iv e G erm any access
to much-needed raw m aterials, m ay
so strengthen her hand in Europe's
pow er politics that it m ay have a
v e r y decisive effect upon negotiations
over Danzig, if that problem
is to be settled by negotiation.
Th e latest m ove tow ard m aintaining
peace by negotiation was made
by Belgium. K in g Leopold 's govseek
peaceful solution of their dispute.
The m ayor's action cam e a fter the
dairym en's strike had cut the usual
supply available to the m etropolitan
area from 4,400,000 quarts to 2.300.-
000 quarts, although both sides had
given assurance that hospitals, public
institutions and other needy custom
ers would receive an adequate
supply.
The F a rm ers’ D airy union, which
claim s a m em bership of 15,000 dairy
fa rm ers and which is supported by
the C. I. O., called the strike in an
effort to force distributors to pay
them $2 35 a hundredweight (o r 47
quarts) for all classes o f m ilk. Thc
present price for such “ blended"
m ilk, which is used for m anufacturing
as w ell as drinking purposes—
is $1.60 a hundredweight.
Hearings in Syracuse and New
Y ork city to discuss thc price structure
have been ordered for this
w eek by the United States departm
ent of agriculture.
H F.LE N VOOROS
"C fW ftw , life.’*
is said to have identified a photograph
o f a prominent Bund m em ber
as the one who handed the label to
him with instructions to g iv e it to
“ the girl in the black dress.”
Most im portant witness thus far
has been Bundmaster F ritz Kuhn.
A fter hearing his life story, R e p resentative
Starnes o f the com m ittee
asked Kuhn if his organization
w asn’t intended to establish a N azi
governm ent in the United States.
“ Th at's an absolute he— a flat
lie !” shouted Kuhn.
F lam in g with anger, Joe Starnes
jum ped to his feet. Shoving reporters
and photographers aside he
strode toward the witness cry in g :
“ Don’t call m e a lia r !”
When capitol policem en had put
an end to these fighting words, the
com m ittee got down to m ore serious
work. With calm deliberation, I llinois
Rep. Noah Mason drew enough
inform ation from the witness to
m ake G erm an-Am erican bundism
distasteful. When faced with the accusation
that his bund is “ a m oneym
aking racket based on the credu lity
of the Am erican people,” Kuhn
countered by listing these strange
o b jectives: (1 ) T o unite the Ger*
m an-Am erican elem ent, (2 ) to flght
communism, (3 ) to give the G erm an
elem ent “ political background."
ARMY:
'Iron Horses' to Front!
W hile a group of foreign ob servers,
including m ilitary attaches from
G erm any, France, G reat Britain
and half a dozen other European
countries looked on, the crack m echanized
Seventh C avalry from Fort
Knox, K y., swung into action for the
first tim e in two “ battles” in which
52,000 regular soldiers and National
Guardsmen w ere engaged this week
in the w ar gam es near Plattsburg.
N. Y . A day of rain that soaked
fields and highways gave Uncle
Sam ’ s “ iron horses” a real test, of
their usefulness in modern war.
B efore the second ‘ phase o f the
gam es began, Lieut. Gen. Hugh A.
Drum, commander-in-chief, assem bled
3,000 officers on the parade
ground to present a few facts. Publicly
scorned was the suggestion that
his troops fight at “ paper strength,”
i. #., with im aginary arm am ent the
arm y hopes some day to secure
The general demanded a cam paign
of reality, “ to bring home the actualities
of our state of preparedness.”
Only in tanks, he said, is the arm y
up to strength. Other deficiencies
m anpower, 77 per cent; machine
guns, 67 per cent; trucks, 83; autom
atic rifles. 57.
Said he: “ I do not intend to belittle
the advantages of speed. But
m obility of! the battlefield cannot
compensate for inefficiency in the
conduct of a fight. What w e need
to learn is how to fight.”
W A S H IN G T O N .—Th ere are som e
people so cy n ical that they suspect
P resid en t R oosevelt would be
pleased if business did slump a little,
or at least fa il to continue the
pickup which has been in progress,
so as to ju stify his sharp com m ents
on the fa ilu re o f congress to pass the
spend-lend bill.
Perhaps the w orst feature o f the
situation is that there are plenty of
business m en and investors who
a gree heartily with the President as
to the effects on the country’s buying
pow er o f this eleventh hour retrenchm
ent d riv e by congress.
P len ty o f argum ent is being m ade
on the other side, those holding this
v ie w citin g tw o im portant factors.
Th e first is that actually the appropriations
o f the session o f cong
ress just closed w ere not sm all.
A ctu a lly they w e re m ore than a billion
dollars in excess of those o f the
previous session. The second fa cto r
is som e recent reports, one fro m the
N ew Y o rk em ploym ent agency, indicating
that despite this feelin g on
the part o f the President, and the
gloom y a greem en t with his vie w s on
the part of m an y business m en, em ploym
ent by p rivate capital is on
the increase, w hether it is sufficient
to take up the slack or not.
This last fa ctor was rather cu riously
dem onstrated by a H a rry Hopkins
departm en t of com m erce report
showing business im provem ent.
Th e tim in g o f this report caused
considerable amusem ent in W ashington,
as it w'as published on the
front pages o f m any newspapers in
ju xta position w ith the gloom y statem
ents o f the President.
Should Stop Feeding Out
Pessimistic Propaganda
But assuming that M r. R oosevelt
does w ant business re c o ve ry to continue,
and that he would be distressed
to have his gloom y fo re bodings
sustained, there is one thing
he certa in ly ought to do. This is to
g iv e perem ptory orders to the fe d e
ra l reserve board to stop feeding
out pessim istic propaganda by the
back door.
Various lieutenants o f M a rrin er
S. E ccles have caused much m ore
pessim ism in N ew Y o rk and W ashington
by their “ confidential” com m
ents to their personal friends
am ong stock brokers and m ark et
operators than did the Presid en t’s
ow n statement. Th e trouble here is
that these reserve board attaches
convince the v e ry people who are
gen e ra lly disposed to “ copper” anything
the President says.
A s a result a g rea t m an y persons
w ho m igh t be m aking investm ents
or buying securities have been holding
off. There is no doubt about
the accu racy of this. A canvass
eith er in N ew Y o rk or any other
i city boasting a financial center w ill
disclose fears of the business situation
which can be traced d irectly to
pessim istic view s expressed p riv a tely
to this or that banker or broker
by som e official o f the fed era l res
e rv e board.
W heeler a Possibility as
N om inee jo r President
I f candidates fo r the D em ocratic
nom ination for P residen t w ere going
to run like horses in the derby, it
w ould not be a bad idea to put a
little m oney on Sen. Burton K.
W h eeler o f Montana, fo r “ show.”
F or the D em ocratic sweepstakes
next June the odds-on fa vo rite is
still Franklin D.
! R oosevelt, the second
choice is John
Nance G a m e r and
the horse that didn’t
even look as if it
w ere going to get
aw'ay from the starting
post, just a little
w hile back, W heeler,
is now in third
position and going
strong. The rea lly
im portant point is
that this recent
spurt o f W’heeler has resulted in his
passing Paul V. M cN utt, and for
significant reasons.
Six months ago W h eeler scoffed
at the idea he m ight be nom inated
and would ca refu lly explain to adm
irers just w hy the then political
setup m ade it im possible. Th e key
log in this setup, as W h eeler’s
friends then understood it. w as that
R oosevelt would n ever accept
W heeler as a “ com p rom ise” candidate.
Since that tim e R oosevelt has
poured a lot of oil on the Montana
senator. He has sent for him again
and again, first on the railroad leg islation
but gradually on other
things. Exam ination of the list o f
W hite House appointments— which
a re m ade public e v e ry d a y—for the
period from F eb ru a ry to the adjournm
ent o f congress, w ill show a
p e rfec tly astonishing number o f
talks betw een the two.
Montana Senator Playt
B all and Keeps His W ord
M any o f us in Washington have
b elieved since the fight to en large
the Su prem e court, in which W heele
r w as m ad e the lea der against the
P residen t, that R oosevelt would neve
r fo rg iv e him. Som e o f us still belie
v e that. W e sim p ly cannot rem
em b er any other m an who has
fought R o osevelt and been forgiven
and w e find it difficult to conceive
o f his doing it in W h eeler’ s case.
But w e m ay be w rong. W hatever
one m a y think of W heeler, he is
v e r y likable personally as wrell as
a fo rcefu l ch aracter. He plays bail
and keeps his word. H e seldom
prom ises anything that he cannot
d e live r. H is ju dgm ent as to what
can or cannot be done is excellent.
R o ose velt has not found m any
am ong those whom he has a ctively
liked since he entered the White
House who have possessed all those
qualities. F o r instance, Senators
Sherman Minton o f Indiana, and Joe
G u ffey o f Pennsylvan ia, who w ere
as enthusiastic about the “ pu rge”
as T o m m y C orcoran and Ben Cohen.
F o r instance, the g rea t M arathon
orator, w hom the President m ade
D em ocratic leader o f the senate,
A lben W. B arkley o f Kentucky.
So it just m ay be that next June,
if the Presiden t discovers he cannot
nom inate a m an who agrees with
him 100 per cent, he m ight turn to
W'heeler rather than see 4he nom ination
o f someone ea g er to tear
down m ore o f the N ew D eal than
W heeler. A lw a y s assum ing o f course
that R oosevelt is not nom inated him self.
It must be rem em b ered that
W’ heeler has been so liberal for
y ea rs that some have called him a
Com m unist, that he w as one o f the
m ost a ctive o f the “ F o r R oosevelt
B efore C h ica go” club, and that despite
the fa c t that the White House
ignored him on patronage in fa vo r
o f his bitter political enem y, J.
B ruce K rem e r. W heeler n ever opposed
the P residen t on any im portant
issue until the Suprem e court
battle.
In cid en tally both G a m e r and Jim
F a r le y a re frie n d ly to W heeler.
President Seeks C redit fo r
Im provem ent in Business
Im p rovem en t o f business despite
defeat o f the spend-lend bill, bumper
crops on top of ca rry-o vers and
big crops abroad, and the obvious
intention o f the G. O. P.-C onservative
D em ocrat coalition to upset
m ore N e w D eal apple carts when
congress m eets next January— all
these are spurring Franklin D.
R oosevelt to develop a new theme.
C all it new rabbits from new hats, if
you like, but w hat the President
needs is som ething to bring about
three things:
1.— M ake the adm inistration the
lea der in the im provem ent o f business—
in other w ords, get the credit,
thus upsetting the picture now
that the im provem ent is in spite of
the N ew Deal.
2.—D ive rt C apitol H ill from its
co n servative course tow’ard undoing
N ew D eal reform s by givin g congress
som ething new to fight o ver
— but—not at the risk of another
m a jo r defeat on the ev e of the national
conventions and the election
cam paign.
3 .—W ork out some b ig g er and better
w a y o f handling the fa rm surplus
and low fa rm price situation.
N ot necessarily, fo r exam ple, letting
prices slide a w a y down to encourage
consumption and exports,
and com pensating the fa rm ers direc
tly by A A A checks, but som ething
as rad ical as that.
I f R oosevelt can produce form u las
fo r these three problem s, he
m a y h ave the political bear by a
nose-ring instead o f by the tail next
w inter.
Watch fo r Another Fireside
Chat or B ig Set Speech
So when the President gets round
to another fireside chat, or has to
m ake a big set speech on some occasion
this fa ll, it w ill probably be
the m ost interesting of anything he
has e v e r m ade, and this is no reflection
w h atever on the im portance
o f m any o f his fo rm e r speeches and
fireside chats. In the v e ry nature
o f things the President, being distinctly
on the defensive at the m oment,
is alm ost sure to follow old
m ilita ry strategy and take the o ffensive.
But he must take it so
spectacu larly that he w ill get the
country talking about w hat's new,
rather than what happened a little
w hile back.
Th ere is another difficulty in his
problem , which would be plenty
hard without it. The additional hurdle
is that R oosevelt is a ve ry stubborn
m an, a man who hates to adm
it defeat, as evidenced by his recent
referen ce to the Supreme court
packing battle.
So R oosevelt w ill find h im elf anxious
to inject into his new theme,
w h atever fo rm it m a y take, some
tyin g in with the old battles. He
wants vindication on his advocacy
o f the spend-lend bill that congress
rejected. H e wants vindication on
the neutrality program that he dem
anded and that congress turned
down.
R eg ard in g this last, everyth ing
depends upon what happens in Europe.
It m ay easily be that events
in Eu rope w ill convince the country,
long before congress m eets again,
that the President w as right.
tBell Syndicate—W N U S c r v ic c .)
WHO’S
NEWS
THIS
WEEK
B y L E M U E L F. P A R T O N
■ ^ E W Y O R K .— W ith E dw ard R.
' Stettinius Jr. as chairm an, the
newly announced w ar resources
board can be expected to function
W ar Board Chief s w iftly a n d
sm oothly. The
Runs Days on chairm an of
Belt Conveyor f t . I n states
Steel corporation goes from
his hom e at 21 East Seventy-Ninth
street to his office at B roadw ay and
R ector by subway to save moments.
H e eats no lunch to sa ve m ore tim e.
He cuts through fo rm a lities with
his m any business ca llers and saves
m ore.
Stettinius is that reputed rarity,
a rich m an's son who has
m ade good. Ilis father becam e
an industrial leader in St. Louis,
and w as invited to becom e a
M organ partner. The son lost
little tim e a fter his graduation
from the U niversity of V irgin ia
in beginning his business ca reer,
not because he had to, but
because he wanted to w ork. He
w as 24 yea rs old when he went
into G en eral M otors in 1924 , 31
when he becam e vice president,
34 w hen he was m ade vic e ch airm
an o f the finance com m ittee
o f U. S. Steel and 31 when he
took the top job as chairm an of
the board.
M odern ity stands out in the strong
lines o f his figure, his crisp speech,
and his attitude toward problem s of
politics and business. T h ey say he
nearly fain ted when he first saw the
office furniture o f the 21 floors of
the Steel Corporation building after
he becam e chairm an. T h e rolltop
desks and sim ila r item s w ere unchanged
since the days o f Judge
G ary. Th e refurnishing began im m
ed iately under Stettinius and was
thorough.
M r. Stettinius plays neither bridge
nor g o lf; he takes his exercise on
the bedroom floor, and occasionally
goes out to his 500-acre fa rm in V irginia.
---- ♦ ---- OW E N A . T O M L IN S O N , the man
w ho forb ad e the building of
an 11-foot mound on the top o f Mt.
R a in ier so that it m ight retain its
• i > • >Holds Nro Hi ,o nor lhaiugrheelsst asm tohuirnd_
Lies in A rtificial tain in the
Addin—g of Cubits w^as‘t edonnnSc‘ea tesa’
captain in the Ph ilippine scouts under
Gen. J. G. Harbord. B efore
that he w as a buck p riv a te in the
United States arm y, in which, a ltogether,
he served 14 years, participating
in the F ilipino insurrection.
H e w as born in Whitestown, Ind., 57
yea rs ago, and in 1923, a fter lea ving
the a rm y, he w as appointed superintendent
of the R a in ier N ational
park.
When Tom linson, sorrow fully,
refused to perm it Uie Tacom a
ch am ber of com m erce to pile,
as it w ere. Pelion on Ossa, thus
bringing R a in ier a foot higher
than M assive o f Colorado, he
underwent some o f the tribulations
that used to be his when,
as lieutenant-governor of the
sub-province of Ifu gao in the
Ph ilippines, he had som e 130,000
head-hunting savages to handle.
H ow ever, report has it that public
clam or is dyiftg down, a
tribute to Captain Tom linson's
persu asive tact in convincing his
fe llo w statesm en that little
o f the genuine honor lies in the
artificial adding o f cubits to
stature.
tAsk Me Jlnother
0 A General Quiz
1. Why w as the site o f Washington,
D. C., chosen fo r the national
capital?
2. What w as the heaviest oneday
rain fa ll in history?
3. What a pproxim a te portion o f
the earth ’s su rface is co vered w ith
trees?
4. Can fish hear?
5. What does pantheon mean?
6. W hat ch ara cter o f G reek
m ythology fe ll in lo v e with his own
reflection and w as m etam orphosed
into a flower?
7. Can you translate the follow ing
into a fa m ilia r p roverb : Too
g rea t a num ber o f cu linary assistants
m a y im p a ir the flavor o f the
consom m e?
The Answert
1. It w as at that tim e the center
o f population.
2. Th e heaviest one-day rain fa ll
occurred in B aguio, Ph ilippin e islands,
on July 14-15, 1911, w-hen 46
inches o f w a ter fell in 24 hours.
3. About one-fifth, an area
roughly 8,000,000 squ are m iles.
4. Scientists rep ort fish cannot
hear and a re affected only by
sounds that cause vibrations in the
w ater.
5. A tem ple o f all the gods.
6. Narcissus.
7. T o o m an y cooks spoil the
broth.
By burning 25% i f t m r than th*
average a f th * IS other o l tb *
largest-sellin g brands tested—
slower than any of them-CAMELS
give snokars tha equivalent a f
• I *
GE N . J U A N Y A G U E is named by
G eneralissim o Francisco F ran co
as m inister o f air in the new
j cabinet he has form ed and of which
mm a i i >i he has named
M ora l: Talk U p h im self as pre-
To D ictator— if m ier. So fa r as
You Know How ^ v i e e s f ro m
Spain are concerned.
this is the m ost favorable
! news concerning Y agu e heard since
| the fa ll o f Toledo.
Outspoken alw ays, he is the
m an who, in prelim in ary m a neuvers
o f the advance upon
L erid a , accused F ranco of sanctioning
the bombing o f open
cities and of sounding off too eloquently
in praise of G erm an and
Ita lia n contingents in the R ebel
a rm y . F o r this contum acy, report
had him behind bars and
la te r a suicide— both, to quote
M a rk Tw ain, grea tly ex a g g era ted.
L a te r, when he w as rem oved from
comm and of his Moroccan corps, a
personal disaster, specifically, the
garrote, w as reported to aw aiting
him.
And so what? Nothing short of
bestowal of the a erial portfolio and
the consequent strengthening o f the
falange as the backbone of post-war
Spain.
(C o n s o lid a te d F e a tu r e * — W N U S e r v ic e .)
Ex p e n s i v e T 0 B A C C 0 S -y e t»
inexpensive to smoke. Recent impartial
laboratory tests o f 16 o f the
largest-selling brands show;
1 CAMELS were found to contain
MORE TOBACCO 11Y W E IG H T
tlun the average for the IS other of
the largest-selling brands.
2 C AM E LS B U R N E D S L O W E R
T H A N A N Y O TH E R B R A N D
TESTED - 2 5 % SLOWER T H A N
TH E AVERAGE TIM E OF THE 15
O THER OF TH E LARGEST-SELLIN
G BRANDS! By burning 25%
slower, on the average, Camels give
smokers the equivalent o f S E X TR A
SMOKES PER PA C K!
3 In the same tests. CAMELS HELD
T I IEIR ASH F AR L O N C E R thsn
the average time for all the other
brands.
For cooler, milder smoking. . . and
more o f it per pack. . . smoke America's
favorite—long-burning Camels.
CAMEL
TH E W ITTENBERG ENTERPRISE. WITTENBERG. WIS.
,'5‘ ‘ ^ n ■*;■ f i
V t " $ ‘ A y 0*C r, i i M
h,3 oj « O s , ^ : i . d
[ >9 * 'P » ® ® «9J -c." j A
I i ^ ■* o ^ *'i ' J l
M r * — f i
iry. S/ie pufs
pposite the
reby fixing
meaning in
righ t: Hoys
estigate the
r/iey bitihl a
office to find
letters travel
: to a
friend
s they
work,
THREE SHUTTERED HOUSES
By BEK AMES WILLIAMS
Copyright— WNU SERVICI
Education Goes ‘Gadget-y’
C H A P T E R X V I— Continued
— 15—
“ Is Rab—dead?” Lissa asked
pleadingly.
“ R a b ? ” Miss Moss echoed. “ You
m ean A s a ? ”
Lissa straightened, quick hope in
her eyes. “ No, no,” she protested.
“ Rab is m ine! Is he all righ t?”
Miss Moss tried to collect her
wits. “ Rab is hurt, but he w ill get
w e ll,” she said then, and she felt
new life flow into this girl. “ But
A sa is dead.”
“ Oh, I ’m glad ! I ’ m g la d !” Lissa
crie d ; and she demanded to know
w hat had happened. M iss Moss told
her sw iftly as much as she knew;
and having done so, she ventured a
question in her turn. So Lissa, clinging
close to the older woman,
poured out .all her story.
“ Rab and I w ere m arried over a
y e a r a go,” she confessed. “ Father
and M other knew; but we didn’t tell
anyone else, because R a b ’s people
would disown him.
“ I knew Asa too, and he uSed to
m ake love to me. So finally, to
m ake him stop, I told him Rab and
I w ere m arried. But it didn’t do
any good. H e kept a fter m e just
the sam e, and when I threatened to
tell Rab, he said if I did, he’d tell
old Mrs. Bowdon w e w ere m arried.
So I didn’ t tell R a b ; but last night
A sa kissed m e, and Rab saw him,
and was furious with me, so I had
to tell him. Then he was w ild at
A sa — ”
She broke off, for they w ere come
suddenly to the top of Kenesaw Hill,
to the Taine house. Inspector Tope
hurried across the lawn.
Miss Moss saw how tired he was,
and held him hard for a moment.
“ T h ere,” she whispered, “ dear
m a n !” And she asked: “ Where is
Clint? W here is June?”
He pointed to the Bowdon house a
little w ay off, where there was a
lighted window on the second floor.
“ T h ey ’ re asleep up there. Miss
L ea fo rd is in bed with a blanket over
h e r; Clint in a chair beside her, holding
her hand.”
T h ere was a deep exhilaration in
h er; then turning to Tope she said:
“ So it was Asa? You know, 1 picked
Rab, all the tim e.”
Tope shook his head. “ He was in
Provid en ce last night, when the fire
■tarted,” he reminded her.
“ I thought he might have gone
down there and registered, and then
com e back to set the fire, raced
back to Providen ce again. There
w as tim e .”
“ No, he’d put his car up for the
night,” Tope insisted. “ He was
there, all right.” He added awkw
a rd ly : “ I didn’t tell you, but he
had a g irl with him. Th ey registered
as man and w'ife.”
She rem em bered, suddenly, L issa
Th ayer, and turned back to the
car.
Lissa and her father w ere no longer
there; so Tope and Miss Moss
went toward the house. Th ey m et
Doctor C abler with Mrs. Taine in
the hall. Doctor C abler explained:
“ I ’m sending Mrs. Taine to bed.
She must rest.”
Mrs. Taine protested w ea rily :
“ R ab needs m e.”
“ H e’s all righ t,” the Doctor assured
her. “ His w ife is with him .”
And he and Mrs. Taine went on
upstairs.
“ His w ife ? ” Tope echoed incredulously.
-
“ O f course— Lissa. She was the
one with him in Provid en ce,” she
whispered.
Tope and Miss Moss withdrew unnoticed.
Th ey went out on the front
porch together, and Tope sat down.
H e shook his head helplessly. “ W ell,
that’s one on m e,” he confessed. “ I
guess I ’m getting old. I was sure
she was m arried to A sa .”
“ So w’as I ,” she admitted, eager
to com fort him now. “ T ill she told
m e the truth, on the w ay up r.ere
. . . N ow tell m e aboui lonight.”
And she listened while he recited
the tale. “ I blam e m yself,” he decla
red at last, “ for holding off, w aiting
to be sure?” And he said in a
som ber tone: “ Asa was mad, drunk
with killing. Ho had a ladder ready
over there. He must have meant
to com e back tonight, clim b to
June's room , kill her and old Mr.
Hurder too.” And he explained:
“ Mrs. Taine gave June milk tonight.
I think Asa had drugged that; but
I spilled it, like a clum sy fool.”
“ C abler says Rab can talk now,”
H eale told them a little later.
Rab had a twisted frown between
his eyes. Lissa bent o ver him, and
M iss Moss saw his fingers tighten
on her hand.
W here's M other? I don’ t want her
to hear.”
• “ A sleep,” Doctor C abler assured
him.
The hurt man nodded. “ W here’ s
A sa ? ” he asked then. N o one answ
ered him, but he seem ed not to
notice this neglect. “ It was about
L iss a ,” he repeated. “ You see, she
and I w ere m arried. W e kept it secret,
because Asa and June and I
w eren ’ t supposed to get m arried
without permission. It was in
Grandpa Bowdon’s will, and Grandpa
H u rder’s too, that if any of us
m arried without Grandm a Bowdon’ s
consent, w e w ere outcasts, disinher-
And he said: “ But Asa was— m aking
love to Lissa w henever he
caught her alone. I didn’ t know it,
till I saw him kiss her, last night.
She’d been in Providen ce with me.
We used to go aw ay together whenev
er I had business out of town.”
H e looked up at the g irl beside
him with a deep fondness. “ I saw
him kiss h er,” he explained. “ And
she slipped aw'ay, and I found her
crying, in the woods behind the
barn. H e’d hurt her, his hands on
her arm s. So she told m e how he’d
persecuted her for months, and I
cam e back to— do something to
him .”
His eyes m et Inspector H ea le’ s.
“ And then you told m e someone
had killed Aunt K itty, and set that
fire, and I fo rgot about Asa for a
T o arouse Clint and June.
while. But tonight I m eant to have
it out with him. So on the w ay
home, I m ade him stop, and we
w ent into the gara ge, out o f the
rain.
“ I told him he’d got to lea ve Lissa
alone, and he laughed at m e, said
if I m ade a row , he’d tell the folks
we w ere m a rried .”
H e hesitated, continued g rim ly :
“ But I found out, last week, that
Asa had been stealing trust-funds
in the office. I told Grandpa Bowdon
about it, the day he died. It
upset him terrib ly, m ay have killed
him. But I told Asa last night that
I knew about that, and that if he
didn’t lea ve Lissa alone, I ’d send
him to ja il.”
He grinned ruefully. “ Asa didn’t
say anything. I thought I ’d stumped
him ; and I was fool enough to turn
m y back on him , and the next thing
I knew, m y light went out. This
cra ck on the head . . . Th at’ s all
I rem em b er. What does he have
to sa y?”
Inspector H eale was about to
speak, but Tope touched his arm
quickly, restraining him ; and Doctor
C abler said g ra v ely :
“ Y ou ’ ve talked enough, Rab. Get
som e rest now.”
H e cleared the others briskly out
o f the room. Tope and H eale moved
on through the hall to the front
veran d a; and as they em erged
there. Tope said briskly:
“ I ’ve had m y eye on Asa ever
since he produced that bottle What
reason had he to go looking for it in
the cellar, in the laundry-chute?
Th e answer is. there wasn’t any reason,
unless he had some other business
in the c e lla r.”
“ You think he did find the bottle
th ere?” H eale asked.
Tope said ex p licitly : “ Yes. Justus
Taine dropped it down the chute.
He left the Hurder front door unbolted
that night, slipped back over
there to get some o f Mrs. L ea fo rd ’s
sleeping-tablets. Th ere w ere only
two in the bottle, so he took them,
and dropped the bottle out of sight
in the handiest place. With so few
tablets in the bottle, she’d miss
them in the m orning; but if the
whole bottle was gone, she’d just
think it was m islaid.” H e added
honestly: “ P a rt of this is guessing;
part I know.”
And he went on: “ So here’s
w hat w e ’ ve got: Asa Taine was a
th ief; and he needed money. You
heard w hat Rab said, that if any
o f the young ones m arried, they
w ere to be disinherited. Well, Rab
was m arried and Asa knew it; and
Asa bought June new clothes, encouraged
her to m arry Clint. If
she did, with the old gentleman
dead, and K itty Lea ford dead, and
June m a rried —or dead— and Rab
m arried and so disqualified under
the w ill, A sa ’d have all Bowdon’s
money, and H u rder’s too.”
H eale listened g rim ly , and Tope
w ent on:
“ Th ere are three elem ents in e v ery
m u rd er,” he said: “ M otive, and
opportunity, and capacity.
“ Money was m otive enough for
Asa. As for opportunity, he had
plenty o f chances to steal some of
K itty L e a fo rd ’s pills, and he h*d a
chance to drop some of them into
her m ilk that night, when he went
to the kitchen for a glass of water.
“ And he had a chance to dope the
m ilk the Hurders drank, too. He
cam e for a cup o f tea, in the kitchen,
that night— got him self some
m ilk out of the bottle, could have
drugged the m ilk then.
“ I don’ t know w hether he did that
or not. It doesn’t m atter. But I
know he started fhe fire. He was
alone on the ground floor o f the
Bowdon house, his m other and Mrs.
Bowdon upstairs. He slipped out
and cam e o ver here. Th ere’ s an
electric light above the Tain es’
back door. Y ou ’ll find the bulb is
broken and the edge of the socket
is fused. Asa m ade a short-circuit
there, and then he raced back and
got into the Bowdon dining-room
again before Mrs. Taine cam e downstairs.
“ And he proved tonight that he
w as insanely ready to kill, that he
had m urder in him. He tried to
kill Rab. and he’d m ade his plans
to kill June and M r. Hurder too.
Asa convicted h im self tonight.” He
added sternly: “ And—executed him self
too. Saved you the trouble,
H eale.”
H eale stood silent aw hile; the day
brightened, and the sun began to
burn aw ay the clouds. The man
said at last: “ You know, I kind of
hate this. I ’m sorry for these folks
up here. Four o f them dead, in
less than a month. T h ey ’ve had
about enough, it looks to m e.”
Tope sm iled faintly. “ Y e s ,” he
a gre ed ; and he said g ra v ely : “ Outside
o f a few people who won’t
talk, this thing tonight m ight pass
as an accident, Inspector. Cars
have smashed into trees before.”
As H eale considered this. Tope
added: “ Y ou ’ ve never charged Mr.
Lea ford , have you? Nothing in the
newspapers?”
“ No, just held him ,” H eale replied.
“ He w’as w illin g to stand for
that, W’ait till something happened.”
Tope nodded: and then he looked
toward the road and chuckled. A
car had stopped in front o f the
house; young Doctor D errie swung
to the ground and cam e briskly tow
ard them across the lawn.
The M edical E xam iner greeted
them cheerfully.
“ W hat’s wrong, H ea le?” he asked.
“ M ore trouble up h ere?”
H eale hesitated. "W h y , they had
a smash-up— car piled into a tre e,”
he explained. “ Asa T a in e’s dead,
and Rab got a crack in the head.”
D errie nodded. “ Bad,” he said
gravely. Then he looked at Tope
and grinned. “ I suppose you’ re try ing
to m ake a murder out of this
too,” he suggested in amused derision.
But Tope shook his head. “ Why,
no, D oc,” he said m ildly. No, it was
an accident, I gu ess. Matter of
fa ct,” he added, “ I ’ve com e around
to youc w ay o f thinking on Mrs.
Leaford too. Guess you w ere right.
Guess it was an accident, just the
w ay you said.”
The young doctor chuckled.
“ Sure,” he agreed triumphantly.
“ I told you so. Y ou ’ve been seeing
goblins in the dark, old man.” He
said: “ W ell, I ’ll go in and take a
look at them .”
He turned into the house, and
Inspector H eale looked at Tope.
“ What do you aim to do now ?”
H eale asked; and Tope hesitated,
but Miss Moss said ch eerfully:
“ Why, I think w e’ ll wake Clint
and June, and go down and get her
father out of your ja il, and go
home.”
H eale chuckled. “ I ’ ll telephone
dow'n, fix that for you about Mr.
L ea ford ,” he agreed. He went into
the house to do so.
Tope stood still, suddenly tired.
But Miss Moss hugged tight to his
arm , and she sm iled proudly up at
him, and her eyes w ere shining.
* “ You know, m y dear,” she said,
“ you’ re a grand m a n !”
He grinned uncom fortably, w’iped
his mouth with his hand; and she
rose on tiptoe to kiss him. Then
they went together across the lawn
to rouse Clint and June.
T H E E N D
i A cousin o f the fa m iliar peai
flower, called Tephrosia, is used in
the West Indies and Polynesia for
I a ve ry unsportsmanlike form o f an-
I gling. The crushed leaves and
I stem s are thrown into the river,
w here the fish are quickly stupefied
and easily caught.
Another West Indian, the hog gum
tree, is so called because wounded
hogs rub the injured parts against
the tree to sm ear them selves w’ith
the abundant resin it exudes, which
heals their wounds. This resin is
so powerful that the natives make
torches of the branches. Another
light-giving plant is the candleberry
tree, a native of Polynesia related
to our common spurge, notes a w riter
in London Tit-B its m agazine. The
kernels of the walnut-like fru it are
so rich in oil that they are stuck
on reeds and used as candles.
C ertain of the F iji islanders never
use forks except when they eat their
neighbors. They m ake these forks
o f Casuarina, a tree that looks like
a huge specimen of our common
horse-tail. Each fork bears a name,
and is handed down as an heirloom
from generation to generation.
f l P E M N G o f the
^ school year
methods o f teachin
r o llin g eyes, hand.'
ears . . . otherwise,
ing by doing. Above
Chicago youngster i
reader dictionary. Sh
the word oppositt
drawing, thereby
spelling and
her mind. A t
and girls inv
world. H ere they b
m iniature postoffice, i
out just how letters
from mail box miles away. As they keep a written r
O dd Uses for Plants and Trees in Distant Lands
Th e cow-tree, a n ative of South
Am erica corresponding to the fa m
iliar bread-fruit, yields a m ilk
p ra ctica lly indistinguishable from
ordinary co w ’s m ilk in chem ical
composition and nourishing qualities,
from which excellent cream
and cheese are m ade.
Linnaeus, the fam ous Eighteenthcentury
Swedish botanist, m ade a
sort o f floral clock. The dial consisted
of names o f flowers, arranged
in the order o f their opening and
closing hour by hour. The dandelion,
for exam ple, opens about 5
a m. and closes about 9 p. m.
G rea ter accuracy is obtained from
a Japanese form of m agnolia. The
watchm en use the powdered bark
for burning in graduated tubes, to
m ark the tim e by the regu lar com bustion
o f the powder.
Perhaps the lim it o f queer uses
o f plants is reached in the case of
plumbago, related to thrift and seapink.
Th e fresh-root is a powerful
blistering agent, and the beggars
o f San Domingo use it to raise ulcers
on their bodies in the hope of
exciting the sym pathy o f the
passers-by.
B e g i n n i n g N e x t I s s u e ■
EHSIawIUEST
B y T A L B O T M U N D Y
• Lynn Harding, a beautiful American girl. U vacationing
in India a« th* guest oi the Maharanee and
Maharajah oi Kadur. Two men enter her Uie: Carl
Norwood, a level-headed officer oi the British army,
and charming, unscrupulous Prince Rundhia. heir to
Kadur's throne.
In the inevitable conflict between the age-old
customs oi the East and the conventions oi the West
—made even more exciting by Norwood's eiiorts to
settle a boundary dispute among the natives—
Prince Rundhia pits all the craft and gvile oi Oriental
philosophy against Norwood's Western code.
Lynn, attracted by something diiierent in both men.
watches breathlessly as the battle of wits and brawn
works itseli out to an overwhelming climax aa
dramatic as anything Mundy has ever written.
"East and West" is one oi the truly great adventure
stories oi the Far East You'll enioy every
chapter oi this glamorous, thrilling yarn by one ol
the world's best writers. Begin reading it next Issue!
‘ - R E A D E V E R Y I N S T A L I M E N H
Radio is becoming in creasingly
im portant in
Am erican education work.
M usic and current events
subjects are taught with
this instrument as well as
w ith p h o n o g r a ph s and
newspapers. Radio often
p ro v e s valuable d u r in g
stormy weather, epidemics
and other times o f stress
when children cannot get
to school. This picture
shows a mother in an epidem
ic-bound city helping
her children with lessons
broadcast from the local
radio station. F or this purpose
studies in all grades
must be standardized in
the broadest version.
Ideas are bu ilt up in
ste p-by-ste p seq uence wi t It
this book of thin cellulose
sheets superimposed upon
each other to form a
composite whole. It was
invented by Dr. Theodore
Jonas, a dentist, who got
the idea while studying
medicine.
C L A S S I F I E D
D E P A R T M E N T
S T O V E R E P A IR S
R E P nA ,I,R, WS .faU M .kt.a.JK .
O rd e r through y o u r Dealer o r w rit* u t
THE S PE IC H C O M P A N Y
Established IS M
R EM E D Y
PILES - E X A M IN A T IO N F R E E -
F IS S U R E . F IS T U L A . A B
O th er R E C T A L T R O U B L E S
•n d Varicose Veins C orrected
NO D A N C E *
I f S u fferin g — Wrxte Today It W ill Pay Yam D r.G.F. MESSER J£ £ £ ! 
Sew a B ag to Keep
Your Ball of Twine In
By K I TH W Y E T H S P K A R S
A I / H E N you want to w rap a
* * package do you alw ays know
w here to find twine? A ball o f it
in a bag like this one hung o v er
the kitchen table w ill be ready fo r
use. A fter tryin g this you are
sure to want to make som e of
these twine bags to sell at the next
bazaar or to use as gifts.
Scraps from your piece bag m ay
be used in this w ay. Th e bag is
just big enough to co ver the ball
loosely and is m ade of a straight
A bove: This C alifornia
shorthand instructor not
only takes his class out o f
doors but demonstrates
symbols with huge placards.
L e ft: Elementary
school pupils study about
nature, tending their crops
o f beans, oats and clover
to learn sources o f thc
joods they eat.
piece o f goods with the ends
seam ed together with a French
seam . The top and bottom are
bound with prepared bias binding.
A single cord is run through the
binding at the bottom. It is drawn
up to lea ve a sm all opening and
the ends are tied and sewn securely.
T w o cords are run
through the top with a loop of
each cord left on the outside so
that the bag m ay be drawn up by
pulling them. The ball o f twine
is placed inside w'ith the end running
through the bottom opening
ready for use.
Did you see the good news in the
paper last w eek? About the new
Sewing Book No. 3, which is now
ready for m ailin g. It contains 32
useful ideas for home decoratin g;
and things to use as gifts, and to
sell at bazaars. You w ill be delighted
with it. The price o f
this new book is only 10 cents
postpaid. Send coin with nam e
and address to Mrs. Spears, 210 S.
De: plaines St., Chicago, 111.
f ------------------------------------ N
To Check Constipation
Get at Its Cause!
I f con stipation haa you down so
you f e d heavy, tired an d dopey.
It's tim e you did som eth in g about
It. A n d som eth in g m ore th an Just
ta k in g a ph ysic! Y o u should get
at th e cause o f th o trouble.
I f you e a t th e sa p er-refln cd
fo o d m ost people eat, th c chances
a re th e d ifficu lty is s lm p le -y o u
don’t get en ough " b u lk ." A n d
“ bulk” doesn’t m ean h e a v y food.
It 's a kind o f food th a t isn 't con sumed
tn th o body, but leaves a
s o ft *■ bulky” mass In th c Intestines.
I f th is com m on fo rm o f cons
t ip a t io n Is y o u r tr o u b le , e a t
K e llo g g ’s A ll-B r a n fo r breakfast
every d a y an d chink p len ty o f
w ater. A ll-B ra n Isn ’t a m edicine
- I t 's a crunchy, toasted, nutritious
cereal. A m ' it w ill help you
n ot on ly to get regular but to keep
regular, day a fU 'r day. M ade by
Kellogg’s in B attle C reek. Sold
by every grocer.
Open Avenue to Glory
Literatu re is an avenue to glory,
ev er open for those ingenious men
who are deprived of honors or o f
w ealth.— Isa ac Disraeli.
NERVOUS?
D o you fe d so D trvnoi you want to srream?
A re you croaa and irritable? D o you scold
those deareet to you?
If your nervea are on edge and you feel
C»u need a good general system tonic, try
ydia K. Pinkham ’a Vegetable Compound,
mad*- tujmnnUy for tcorntn.
For over «0 y**ara one woman has told another
how to go "sm ilin * thru” with reliable
Pinkham’s Compound. I t helpa nature build
i up more physical resistance and thua help*
eatm quivering nerve* and lesaen discomfort*
from annoying sym ptom * which often accompany
female functional disorders.
W h y not g ivr it a chance to help Y O U ?
O ver one million women have written in
reporting wonderful benefits from Pinkham ■
Compound.
B u r e a u o f S t a n d a r d s
A BUSINESS organ ization
which wants to get the
most for the money sets up
standards by which to judge
what is offered to it, just as in
W ashington the governm ent
maintains a Bureau o f Standards.
• You can have your own Bureau
o f Standards, too. Just consult
the advertising columns o f your
newspaper. Th ey safeguard
your purchasing power every
day o f every year.
PAGE FOUR THE WITTENBERG ENTERPRISE, WITTENBERG, WIS. Thursday, August 31, 1939
The
Wittenberg Enterprise
JOHN E N G LU N D , Editor
I’ ublixhed Every Week On Thurxdaj
$2.00 l*«r Year. C »»h In Advance.
Telephone 63-2
National Advertising Representative
AM ER IC A N ’ PRESS A S S O C IA T IO N
Member Wisconsin Press Association
Entered as matter o f the second class
at the Wittenberg, Wis., postofflce
November 23, 1893.
State Capital Letter
(Run-over from first page.)
past under a joint resolution introduced
by two Republican, one Democrat,
and one Progressive assembly
man. which would limit sessions to
five months.
The measure, sponsored by Assemblymen
Robert H. Burns and Otto
Toepfer. Republicans; Alex L. Nichol,
Progressive; and Albert D. Shimek
Democrat; would have sessions begin
the second Wednesday in January and
end the third Wednesday in June of
odd numbered years.
The present legislature has been in
session for eight months. Other notably
long sessions in the past include
the 1935 and 1929 session, both of
which lasted almost nine months, and
the 1915 session, which sat until
August 24 o f that year.
Back to School
With the new scholastic year about
to get under way again University o f
Wisconsin officials are preparing for a
total enrollment o f almost 11.500
students, approximately the same
number enrolled last year for the first
semester.
But Wisconsin students at the U niversity
must come with a slightly
fuller pocketbook, fo r incidental fees
have been raised five dollars a semes
ter, and w ill now total $65 for the en
tire school year instead o f $55. Non
resident tuition stays at $100 a semes
ter.Regular increases in enrollment for
the past three years, says Curtis Merriman,
registrar, have been due to a
marked growth in the graduate school
and more students entering in their
junior year after having served their
first two years at other colleges and
schools. Freshman registration for
the period has remained at about *2,500
students a year.
Present record enrollment fo r the
first semester is the 1938 figure o f
11,416. Ten years ago the total enrollment
for the first half o f the school
year was 9,468.
‘Oz ’i 'era' 'antrihutni Rt/ 'Spnd
Nominally Labor Day is a holiday.
But for a vast arm y o f men and
women, old, middle-aj?ed, and young it
is the day their labors fo r another
year commence. For a vaster army
o f boys and girls it marks the end o f
play time and the beginning of nine
months o f confinement to books and
hard work.
Since there is no public institution on possible roads for Shawano in the
which wields a greater influence over] future. We cannot let towns nearby
activities; but we are not in fa vo r o f
so many that teachers and pupils are
alike overtaxed. W e would like a
happy balance in our school with emphasis
on the school studies where
that emphasis righ tly belongs.
W e welcome back our fine staff of
old teachers and welcome to W ittenberg
the new. W e wish you and the
students a happy and successful year!
U. S. 45 Cost Shawano
Much Tourist Trade
(Editorial in Shawano Leader.)
During the past 10 years we have
heard much of the H ighw ay 26 club
and the H ighw ay 45 club, organizations
promoting old state highway 26
and new federal highway 45 running
from the south throutrh Shawano county
and on to Eagle River.
Undoubtedly many of you have
wondered w hy all the excitement about
a highway. Last Saturday we had occasion
to drive federal highway 45
from Clintonville to Oshkosh, and
upon seeing so many foreign cars,—
mostly Illinois,— we decided to jot
down on paper the number o f Illinois
cars and the number o f Wisconsin cars
which we either met or passed on the
way. We started this counting at the
triangle corners about three miles
south o f New London and counted until
we reached the city o f Oshkosh.
Farm trucks and larger trucks were
not counted in the tabulation.
Here is what we found o f the 127
cars we either met or passed: 65 were
foreign cars and 62 were Wisconsin
cars. Think o f that, more than 50
per cent of the passengers traveling
on highway 45 were out-of-state
tourist traffic guided up highway 45
through the years of effort o f advertising
the road and developing it.
And who knows how many o f the W isconsin
cars we met were guided up
that road by honest and intelligent
propaganda spread by our neighboring
towns. I f you will remember
neighboring towns fought the move all
the way to keep highway 45 out of
Shawano and no effort was made to
guide this traffic through this citv and
the beautiful Menominee Indian Reservation.
The Highway 45 club has arterialized
the traffic of the south to Eagle
River in such a way that about all the
traffic we get now that goes to the
popular vacation land is stragglers
who have been told to drive 47 to see
the great and beautiful timber lands
o f the north.— the land owned by the
Menominee Indians. We have known
more than one instance the past summer
in which a tourist in returning
from the north was told by Eagle
River and Rhinelander lodge owner*
to drive back 47 if they really wished
a treat.
Getting a federal highway thrjugh
your town these days is just like g e tting
a railroad into your town a
hundred years ago. Now. the people
travel by automobiles and traffic lanes
have turned from steel to concrete.
Conditions have wot changed as to the
need o f traveling and people coming
through and passing through a town.
Traffic and people are important and
if Shawano is going to grow with the
other towns in this section of the
;tate, we must keep at least one eye
the citizens o f the United States than
the Public Schools, it behooves us as
adults, whether parents or no, to cooperate
with the teachers whom the
School Board which we elected have
hired. Some of the teachers w ill be
outsmart us but we must fight for
good through roads the same as they
havp. This does not mean that we
must take 45 away from them, but it
does m*'an that we should make an
effort to guide at least some o f the
town— never seems satisfield with
what she has and has no scruples
about grow ing in importance at the
expense o f sister towns. She did not
seem to care that by having Highw ay
45 relocated over 22— not a feasible
proposition in the first place— she was
depriving all the villages but one in
this end o f the county o f their only
arterial and their best chances fo r an
all-the-year connecting highway.
W e do not like to think o f Shawano
as a selfish town but we will soon have
■to do so if any more confessions like
the foregoing one appear in the public
print.
(F irst pub. Aug. 31; last Sept. 14).
N O TIC E O F H E A R fN G ON F IN A L
S E T T L E M E N T A N D D E T E R M IN A
TIO N OF IN H E R IT A N C E T A X
State o f Wisconsin, County Court,
Shawano County.
In the matter o f the estate o f George
Gjermundson, Sr., deceased.
Notice is hereby given that at a
term of said Court to be held
on Tuesday, the 26th day o f September,
1939, at 10 o’clock in the forenoon
of said day, at the office of the County
Judge, in the V illage of Wittenberg, in
said County, there will be heard and i
cons:dered:
The application o f George W.|
Gjermundson, administrator o f the
estate of George Gjermundson, Sr.,
deceased, late o f the Town o f Morris,
in said County, fo r the examination
and allowance o f his final account,
which account is now on file in said
Court, and for the allowance o f debts
or claims paid in good faith without
filing or allowance as required by law,
and fo r the assignment of the residue
o f the estate o f said deceased to such
persons as are by law entitled thereto;
and for the determination and adjudication
o f the inheritance tax, if any,
payable in said estate.
Dated August 25th, 1939.
Bv Order o f the Court,
H E L E N M L U D O LPH .
Register in Probate.
W . D. H A S E L T IN E . Attorney.
repainted. W ith the remodeling that I
has been done in the old barn, the
capacity has been increased about |
fo rty per cent.
Last year marked a major change
when the “ Township Booths" were replaced
by the Agricultural Booths.
The Township Booth merely showed
good farm produce while the “ Educational”
booth was conceived and applied
to show better farm practices.
The smaller booths met with public
fa vo r and w ere praised by Judges o f
the Fair.
N E W L IB R A R Y SC H E D U LE
Wednesday*
Saturdays—
i— 2:00 to 5:00 and
7:00 to 9:00.
2:00 to 5:00 and
7:00 to 9:00.
C.  N . W . T IM E T A B L E
I)R . A B. S C H U LT Z . O PT O M E TR IS T ,
C O M IN G S A T U R D A Y E V E N IN G
at Gauerke’s Jew elry Store, W ittenberg,
from 7 to 9 p. m. Eyes tested
and glasses fitted.
I f you wish to keep milk sweet, put
it in the cold part of the ice box or
refrigera tor where the temperature is
about 45 degrees Fahrenheit.
Southbound
Train A rrives
No. 108 ( d a i l y ) ................. 5:16 a. m.
No. 116 (d a ily ex. Sunday) 12:50 p. m.
Northbound
No. 117 (da ily ex. Sunday) 10:13 a. m.
No. 109 (d a ily )................... 9:53 p. m.
Southbound Flambeau leaves Eland
(d a ily ) 3:50 p. m.
Northbound Flambeau arrives at
Eland (d a ily ) 6:15 p. m.
Rosholt Free Fair
September 2, 3, 4
Plans fo r the County Fair are going
forward at Rosholt for the three-day
Fair and exposition to be held or
September 2, 3 and 4* coming to e
close on the evening o f Labor Day. A
fa irly favorable growing season
should make 1939 a record entry year.
Saturdav afternoon being entry day.
the Fair will officially open that evening
with Free Acts and talking pictures
on the outdoor stage. A splenfid
nrogram has been arranged with
the Hagen booking agency for Sunday
afternoon and evening. Arch Adrian
and his “ men of note” will furnish
music for the dance Monday night,
and also will appear on the stage in
the afternoon in addition to other Free
Acts and entertainment. In also engaging
Dorothea and M argaret Widmer,
the yodeling girls from Monroe
Wis., the Fair management has lined
up the best talent to be seen here in
years.
4-H Club Work Steadily Growing
Under the leadership o f County
Agent H. R. Noble and Miss Irene
Skutley, County Home Ec. Agent, 4-H
Club work has been on the increase
for the past number of years.
Because of increased enrollment in
4-H C alf Club work, it has been necessary
to enlarge the C alf barn to make
room for over 60 calves. Th irty six
new poultry pens have been built and
strangers in Wittenberg. Let us make' traffic we used to get through the city
them happy that they will live in such! of Shawano. Highway 45 now gets
a friendly town. Some o f the teachers j traffic old 26 always got. and we bewill
be returning fo r another year. I t ! lieve that a large portion o f the traffic
would be well to let them know we are that 47 and 55 form erly got is now
happy to have them back. going up U. S. highway 45.
We realize that there is a tendency | I t '» to say that towns the size
to be enthusiastic over young teacher* J Shawano on 45 draws business from
just out of college and brimming overj ovpr 200 cars a day over week-ends,
with enthusiasm and new ideas and: Estimate that for yourself, Mr.j
untried theories. Their pep and en-j Shawano merrhant. and you w il rea-|
thusiasm are infectious, and school j that Clintonville, New Ixtndon and |
board member and parent alike are in
clined to be too greatly impressed by
clever little numbers the young teacher
trains her youngsters to give.
One does not put up green saplings
for winter fuel. When one fires with
green wood one gets much smoke but
very little heat. One wants his basement
full o f seasoned wood which
gives the maximum heat with the
minimum of smoke, and it’s from the
glow ing coals that the most intense
heat comes.
So it is with our teachers. The
young peptomists just out of college
supply the smoke and fanfare; but the
seasoned teachers who have tried out
their theories and tested their methods
are the most valuable members o f the
school faculty. They supply the even
balance and give stability to the school
system. It would be well not to undervalue
their work because it is not
spectacular.
L et us remember that a school is
a place where children learn to think,
to read, to write, and to figure. The
first function of the teachers is to
teach; and to be able to do a food job " tw s fn d and that
of teaching, they cannot be loaded
down with all sorts of extra curricular!
programs. I f we demand that a|
teacher carrying a full teaching load
put on plays, operettas, nnd coach
declamatory, his teaching will necessarily
suffer.
It would be a fine thing for the
community if the teachers were allow ed
to teach and the students were
allowed o study and have a little spare
time to spend at home in their church’s
activities.
We are in favor of extra curricular
ral small towns talked you out of
quite a nice little jack pot each week-1
end. ,
C O M M EN TS
That’s a brazen statement in the
foregoing editorial taken from last
Friday's Shawano Evening Leader—
that “ neighboring towns fought the
move all the way to keep highway 45
I out o f Shawano,” as if Shaw'ano at |
1 any time had any claim whatsoever on
1 that h’ghwa.v. As every one knows,
those “ neighboring towns” — Clintonville,
Marion. Tigerton. Wittenberg,
Kland. Birnamwood and Aniwa -were
• only seeking to keep what rightfully
belonged to them out o f the grasping)
and greedy hands of Shawano. And
| » very one knows that if it had not
been for the effective work done by
! the Highway 26 and Highw ay 45
clubs, Shawano might have succeeded |
;n her unneighborly move to have
: Highway 45 rerouted over 22 into
Shawano and away from this end of
the county. Everyone in western
| Shawano county has strongly suspect-
1 all ii >ng Shawano’s secret scheming
confession of
this scheming now appears in the
Shawano daily is indeed surprising.
Equally surprising is the fact that
Shawano, having four state highways
— 29, 55, 47 and 22— besides the many
advantages accruing to a county seat
For
H E A L T H . A C C ID E N T , M F E .
A N D A U T O M O B IL E
INSURANCE
See
JOE TURECEK
W IT T E N B E R G . W IS.
DRY C LEANING
I f you have any Dry ( leaning to be
done notify Kusserow’s store, our
local station.
HOWARD YOUNG
Apent for P A N T O R IU M DRY
C LE \ N E R 8 . of Shawano.
Specials!
FOR T H E W E E K
W A SH T IE S 15c. 30c and 25c
values @ 9c. 15c an d............19c
C O M PLE TE L IN E O F
SCHOOL S t'P P M E S
25c
w I). HASELTINE
Atto rn ey -A t-Law
Office in Rank Building
W IT T E N B E R C , W IS C O N S IN
8x12x1" O V E R N IG H T
C ASE S ..........................
R IN G S M IT H ’S
Ben Franklin
Store
Wisconsin’s Best Free F a ir!
Rosholt
Free
Fair
P O R T A G E C O l'N T Y ’S
A G R IC U L T U R A L E X P O S IT IO N
E X T E N S IV E F ARM A N I)
4-H C L l'B E X H IB IT S
SEPT. 2-3-4
S P E C IA L D A IL Y F E A T U R E S !
F R E E A C TS!
R U S T Y H A G E N T R O U P E
R O L L E R SK \ T IN fi
C O M E D Y A C R O B ATS
C O N T O R T IO N IS T
HOOP H O LLE R S M \GIC1ANS
H IL L B IL L IE S Y O D E LE R S
T A L K IN G PIC TU R E S
A R C H A D R IA N B A N D
With Special Features
B A S E B A L I. G A M E S !
S O F T B A I.I. ( JAMES
K A A R U P ’S RIDES
C L E A N M ID W A Y \ T T R A C T IO N
D A N C E on LA BO R D A Y
Land o’ I.akes Bus Co.
B US SC H E D U LE
Daily
Southbound—8:08 a. m. and 5:08 p. m.
Connects Madison, Janesville, and
Chicago.
Northbound— 11:15 a. m. and 8:50
p. m. to A n tigo and Rhinelander.
Wau»au-Green Bay Bus
Daily
Eust Bounnd— 8:50 a. m.; 3:20 p. m.
W est Bound— 11:55 a. m.; 4:25 p. m.
C A L L
The N e w SfreoV
GEHL
SILO FILLER BETTER BUILT, Bia
CAPACITY, LOW
NEW MODEL
Improved
to the Minute
Big. wide, low feed table; large •elffeeding
beater roll; unbreakable
fly w heel; o il enclosed gears; h eavy d u ty
ball-bearing m ain and jack shafts. Easychangeable
length o f cut. T hrow s green
corn 4S fe et high w ith aa little as 5 hp.
m otor, 500 rpm . A "T h o ro b red " is known
b y hia record. T h e N e w G E H L , with
h a y cutting attachm ent, IS a T H O R O -
B R E D . B efore you b u y an y cutter, call
and aee the latest from the old reliable
Houac o f Q E H L .
C i t i e s S e r v i c e G a r a g e
Elderon, Wis.
IN SIG N $ 1 . 2 9 J!L POCKET a n d WRIST W ATCHES
* 1 .0 0 t o *3 .9 5
A L A R M C L O C K S
1.00 t o *2 .9 5
LOOK FOR -gs-Mer ON THE DI Al
“C h eap ” h o u se
p a in t is a lu x u ry
for the rich man only
I f yoa have loads of money . . . If you can afford
to buy twice as many gallons . . . if yoa
can pay the cost o f burning or scraping off the
old paint every two years or so—and the
added cost of frequent repainting . . . then
you are rich enough to use a “ cheap,” low
p ric e house paint.
But if you want to make every dollar count
—to get value for your money—then you’d
better buy the best house paint money can
buy —SWP. It costs no more in the beginning
— and much less in the end.
Come in and let us tell you the truth i
tbe exorbitant coat of “ cheap” paint.
S e e “ P a i n t H e a d q u a r t e r s * *
G .  M . H a r d w a r e
Back-to-School
SALE
N E W SH O ES N E W S W E A T E R S N E W D RESSES
N E W M E N ’S A N I ) B O Y S ’ P A N T S N E W S H IR T S
N E W M E N ’S H A T S N E W S K IR T S A N I ) B LO U SE S
EV E R Y T H IN G N E W FO R F A L L A N D W IN T E R
A T V E R Y L O W P R IC E S
Y O U C A N DO B E T T E R A T
F a rm e r s O u tle t S to re
W H E R E Y O U R D O L L A R S GO F A R T H E R
W IT T E N B E R G , W IS . N E X T TO C A SH W A Y STO R E
In Paying Final Tribute
to your loved ones, you expect the
best we can give, and it is our aim
to measure up to your expectations.
S M I T H ’ S
F U R N IT U R E and U N D E R T A K IN G
Phone 32
SEPT. 1 THRU 7
Cash W a y leads in low priced, high
quality groceries for the thrifty
SUGAR 10 c£* 50c
PICNICS L . . » 15c
CAKE FLOOR -re -- 16c
Peanut Butter Ss? 2 S; 20c
Northern Tissueu-"“- *•" 5c
FRI. IT'S A PEACH OF A TIM E TO C A N
PEACHES A N D PEARS SAT.
PEACHES
Michigan Elbertas
L a r g e s i z e B i . 1 .8 5
M e d . s i z e B i . 1 .4 9
Colorado, b o x ........... 95c
PEARS
L a r g e s i z e B o . 2 . 0 9
M e d . s i z e . . . $ 1 . 6 9
Michigan Bartletts
FRESH PRUNES £ C Lug 85c
BLUE GRAPES ^ 4 22c
COOKIES
Fresh Coconut
M aca ro o n s ........... Ib. 15c
Lemon Cake . . 2 lbs. 25c
Lemon Creams . . Ib. 15c
C A N D Y SPECIAL
O ld
Fashion Gums 2 lbs. 15c
Chocolate
Butter S ta rs .........Ib. 15c
Harvest M i x .........Ib. 19c
PURE COCOA
SOUP . .
OVALTINE
OXYDOL
Nicolet
The Swiss
Food Drink
New High
Test
15c
25c
33c
2 b«« 39c
lb.
__ can
22 os.
cans
6 ox.
Can
WITTENBERG. WIS.
SCHOOL SUPPLIES
P E N C IL S ........... 2 for 5c
Regular 5c Vnlue,
With thc B ig Rubber
T A B L E T S .........3 for 10c
Fillers, N ote Book*, Composition
Books, T yp ew riter Paper,
Scratch Pads.
Ib. 19c
NBC Crinkle M M
SA N D W IC H . . .
Pride Assorted
COOKIES . . . Ib. box 23c
Nicolet Colossal 20 Oz.
SWEET PEAS. 2 cons 29c
B A B - O .........2 cons 25c
Just sprinkle on cloth and
w ipe off. Ask us about special
book offer by Em ily Post. p a s i f | f « y r o o o a r o m
Thursday, August 31, 1939 THE WITTENBERG ENTERPRISE, WITTENBERG, WIS. PAGE FIVE
LOCAL NEWS NOTES
Miss Esther Gunderson was in A ntigo
Wednesday.
Joe Komp visited with a brother in
Milwaukee from Sunday until Tuesday.
G. A. Meisner, Ernest Sickler and
Jerry Coyle spent Sunday at Stone
lake.
Roland Jesse and W alter Schwertfe
g e r spent Sunday at Huntington
lake.
M arilyn Mech o f Green Bay is
spending the week at the Thoreson
home
Jimmy Liesch is spending several
days in the Robert Brown home in
Antigo.
Mrs. Frank Ripple, and son, Victor,
o f Waukegan, 111., visited in the Ed.
Maahs home.
Miss Dora Haupt, o f Shawano, spent
Sunday with her parents, Mr. and Mrs.
Louis Haupt.
Miss Marcella Bloecher is visit?ng
with relatives and friends in Milwaukee
this week.
Mr. and Mrs. R. Oestreich and
daughters, Doris and Mary, spent the
week-end at Wausau.
N orval Solvang, o f Chicago, was a
visitor this week in the home o f his
cousin, Lester Carlson.
Herman Schmidt is enjoying a
vacation this week from his duties at
the K raft-Phenix plant.
Mr. and Mrs. Raymond Schulz and
daughter Ruth, o f Wausau, were W ittenberg
visitors on Friday.
Miss Ruth Thoreson left Sunday a fternoon
fo r Mattoon, where she will
teach the Lake M ay school.
Mr. and Mrs. Ervin Laude and
daughter. Karen, visited at the Frank
Kolpack home at Bowler Sunday.
Paul Johnson, o f Camp Rjb Mountain,
snent the week-end with his parents,
Mr. and Mrs. Peter Johnson.
Miss May Krause returned to A th ens
Sunday a fter being employed at
the H. Gauerke home several months.
Mrs. W illiam Sense and children, of
Marquette, Michigan, and Mrs. Cleve
Guerin w ere Wausau visitors Thursday.
W
. S. F. Smith, o f Mazomanie. arrived
Tuesday for a few days’ visit in
the home o f his nephew, W . D. H aseltine.
Dr. and Mrs. Wm. Sihler returned
to Decorah last Tuesday. Mrs. F. Palladeau
traveled with them as fa r as
Tomah.
Rant, Edwin and John Ellingson and
son, Russell, and G. J. Jenson, o f W'ausau,
visited at the John Peterson home
Sunday.
Mrs. Eldrt»d Hull and fam ily are
this week enjoying a visit by her parents,
Mr. and Mrs. Emil Harning, o f
Waupaca.
Miss Sylvia Westlund returned Sunday
from Wausau Memorial hospital
where she underwent an eye operation
a week ago.
Mr. and Mrs. Francis Bossette and
children, Blanche. Arnold. Roger and
Yvonne, o f Oshkosh, visited relatives
here Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Elmer Werth andj
fam ily, o f Hartford, w ere week-end
visitors in the home of her fa th er,!
August Korth.
Joe Bolster, o f Clintonville, and
Marvin and Marilyn Mech. of Green
Bay, spent the week-end at the C. A.
Thoreson home.
Mrs. Melvin Bessette took her 16-
months-old son. Ronald, to Madison
Wednesday where the baby w ill undergo
observation and treatment at the
Wisconsin General Hospital.
Mr. and Mrs. Oscar Falstad and Mr.
and Mrs. Carl Mathison motored to
Madison Sunday, returning with the
form er’s baby daughter, who had been
receiving treatments at the Wisconsin
General Hospital.
ENTERPRISE WANT
AD DEPARTMENT
G IR L W A N T E D — for housework, at
the H. Gauerke home, Wittenberg.
FO R S A L E — 5 gallons aluminum exterior
paint in original container.
$10 cash. E. W. Sihler, Bethany
Indian Mission. 42-1 t f
H A V E ROOM A N D B O AR D for two
boys or two girls for coming school
year. Inquire at Enterprise iffice.
41-1 tc
W A N T E D Old standing and disabled
horses. Arnold Heistad, Route 1.
W ittenberg. Phone 50B-R10. 89-4t
FOR S A L E — Dressed poultry. Inquire
o f Emil Schrank, Route 2. 38-tf
FOR S A L E — We have a good assortment
o f grain and corn binders and
other machinery as well, and Mr. car
or truck buyer, we believe we are in
a position to supply your wants right
here at home on cars or on tires or
what else you may have in mind.
Don’t fo rg e t to see us before you buy.
Gust Norrbom. Elderon. .'{fi-tf
S E L L your old horses direct to a fur
farm er and get higher prices. We
also buy cows lost through freshening,
accidents, etc. Graves Mink Ranch.
Eland, W is. 4K-eow
A N T IG O RENDERING W O R K S—
w ill call fo r your dead and disabled
horses and cattl* free o f charge (w ith
hides on ). Telephone A ntigo 744
W e pay telephone charges.
W A N T E D —OM arul diftftbled h o it n
fo r mink feed. Arthur Larson, W it
tenberg. 24-tf
Mr. and Mrs. Bernhard Plagemann!
and daughter Bernice and Miss Ella |
Z eitler took a trip to Abbotsford and
U nity last Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Sam Levine spent
from Sunday until Tuesday in Miwaukee,
where they attended to business
matters and also visited relatives.
Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Martin and
children, Junior and Gordon, o f Ringle,
visited at the Conrad Verpoorten home
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Joe Kuptick and son
Chester, o f Milwaukee, arrived during
the week-end fo r a visit in the Deruchowski
home.
Mr. and Mrs. Leland Bloecher and
son Douglas and George Bloecher
were week-end visitors with Oscar
Bloecher at Tomahawk.
William Jorgenson, a resident o f the
Homme Home fo r the Aged, returned
here Saturday a fter a week’s visit
with relatives in A ntigo.
Dr. Doolittle, who took care o f Dr.
Evenson’s practice here while the
latter was on his vacation, has returned
to his home in Madison.
Mr. and Mrs. Eldred Hull and four
children have moved here from Bowler
and are livin g in the Utech house just
vacated by the Sutheimer fam ily.
Carl Sutheimer and fam ily this
week moved to N iagara, where they
w ill make their future home, a fter
several years’ residence in Wittenberg.
Marvin Midtsjo and a friend, John
Gavin, o f Maywood, 111., called briefly
on friends in W ittenberg on Friday
while enroute home from an outing up I
north.
Miss Leona Schwertfeger returned]
today from Woodruff, where she spent,
several davs in the home o f heri
brother, W illiam Schwertfeger, andj
fam ily.
Mr. and Mrs. Lew is A. Liesch and
children, Jimmy and Doris, spent the
week-end at H artford with Harry
Liesch and fam ily and also visited in
Milwaukee.
Frank Koenig, Mr. and Mrs. Louis
Peters and Mr. and Mrs. H arry Krahn,
all of Milwaukee, arrived Saturday fo r
a visit until next Tuesday in the Otto
Schrank home.
. Mrs. Henrv Ringstad and children,
Shirley and Howard, o f Milwaukee,
have been spending several weeks here
with her parents, Mr. and Mrs. John
Laude.
Mr. and Mrs. Paul Glaubitz and Mr.
and Mrs. W alter Glaubitz. o f Milwaukee,
made a brief call at the Mrs. Ida
Glaubitz home S*turdav evening while
on their w ay to the Glaubitz cottage at
Pel’ can Lake.
A .A. Grimstad returned Saturday
from a five weeks’ visit with his
daughters, Mrs. William Farrell, at
Waukegan, and Miss Nina Grimstad,
at W ilm ette, 111.
M 'fs Kathleen Stone who has been
emnloved at Winnetka. 111., fo r several (
months, vs visitin g friends here before!
resuming her studies at Stevens Point
teachers’ college.
Mr. and Mrs. H. E. Kersten and;
^nueMer. MHItta. returned Monday j
from Milwaukee. Mrs. Raymond Lieg
and daughter. Mary, returned with;
them to visit here.
Mr. and Mrs. Val Meckes, Miss
Mildred Gilbert and Miss Ellenora L o berg
visited the Gateway Inn Sundav.j
They also stopped at K raftw ood Gardens
on Enterprise Lake.
I .oui.* Gardner and son Thomas Louis,
o f Chicago, are spending a few days
in this village. Mr. Gardner being here
on duty as an inspector o f dairy farms
for the Chicago board o f health.
The Rev. and Mrs. Ernest Gander
who have been visitin g in the A.
Mathes and Wm. Rosenthal home the
past several days, returned to their
home at Dundee. Illinois, Wednesday.
Mr. and Mrs. H. R. Cappel and sons.
Robert. Donald and Darrell, Mr. and
Mrs. Charles Huebner and daughter
Lynn and Mr. and Mrs. Otto Fredrick
spent Sunday at Rib Mountain park.
F ire in the Mike W alters home in
the town o f N orrie yesterday did damage
to the extent o f about $30. F ire
started on the roof from a chimney
spark and was quickly extinguished.
Mrs. T illie Halverson departed for
Wauwatosa on Friday a fter a stay o f
ter weeks with friends in W ittenberg
and vicinity. On leaving she expressed
appreciation o f their kindness to her.
Mr. and Mrs. Alvin Laude and son
John. Mrs. Henry Ringstad and children.
Shirley and Howard, and John
Laude spent Sunday at Pickerel lake.
Saturday they visited Mrs. Lapinski at
Brvent.
Sunday night visitors in thc Ed.
Schoepke home were Mr. and Mrs.
Chas. Schoening, o f Rhinelander, Mrs.
Aug. H oeft and son, of Tigerton, Mrs.
Wrill Schoepke, o f Crandon, and Mr.
and Mrs. August Wendler and son
Rolland.
Mr. and Mrs. W illiam Spargo and
W ill Wiseman made a trip to Argonne
last week. Returning, they were ac
companied by Mrs. Andrew Baken.
who made a visit with relatives and
friends near here. Wiseman says one
night up there was so cold that the
water froze in a bucket.
fcGINIA G m
(ONC€ A STAND-IN F O * FLORENCE SIC£
AND MADuE EVANS) DIDN'T HAVE TO LEAVE
HOME TO GET IN THE M O V IE S ... SHE WAS
* 0 * N ASOUT 10 MINUTES DRIVE F tQ M THE M-G-M STUMPS'.____________
New York, N. Y .—“ I T ’S T R U E ! that Lew Ayres was once
told by a fortune teller that he would never amount to anything,
that he would die broke and that no one would ever know his
name!” says Wiley Padan .. . “ Ian Hunter, British-born leading
man, plays Ayres’ rival in M G -M ’s ‘Broadway Serenade’ . . .
Jeanette MacDonald’s nephew, Earl Wallace, just back from
service with the Marines in China, was an interested visitor on
the ‘ Broadway Serenade’ set.’*
Miss Ledah Van Gilder motored to!
Manitowish last Saturday and her
sister, Miss Marion, who has been em ployed
up there returned home with
her Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Herman Bloechl and
children, Delores and LeRoy, of Sheboygan,
are making a visit with relatives
at this place, Mr. and Mrs. Albert
Hartleben and Mr. and Mrs. George
Vollmer.
Mr. and Mrs. Herbert Lasch, of,
Duluth, and Mr. and Mrs. Fred Vohs, 1
o f N ew London, spent several days
last week at the home o f their sister
and daughter, Mrs. Henry Jannusch, j
and fam ily.
Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Wandschneider,
o f Milwaukee, arrived S atu rday1
for a visit in the Chester Bloecher |
home. While here they also enjoyed .
an outing at the Bloecher cottage on
Bestul lake.
Mrs. Hertha Murdock and G e o rg e 1
Natzke, o f Shawano, visited at the
Claus Schaar home Sunday. Kent
and Donald Murdock returned with
them a fter visiting at the Schaar home
several months.
W’ illiam Palladeau went to Chicago
last Wednesday night. Mr. and Mrs.
Ferdinand Palladeau drove down Saturdav
pfternnon and returned Sunday
with Wm. Palladeau and his sister,
Mrs. M. Krause.
Mr. and Mrs. E. Westphal and
daughter, Anita, o f Pella, and Mr. and
Mrs. Carl Damrau, o f Tigerton visited
at the John Laude home Sunday. Visitors
there Saturday were Mr. and
Mrs. John Nachts and son and Mrs.
Augusta Sedrell, o f Tilleda.
Stanley Feuerpfeil and fam ily, o f
New Richmond, were Saturday visitors
here. Mrs. Florence Turecek and
children returned here with them after
spending several weeks in N ew Richmond,
while Mr. and Mrs. Stanley
Feuerpfeil attended the N ew York
fair.
Mrs. Arthur Gray (the form er
Gladys W’ ilson), o f Cincinnati, Ohio,
was a brief caller in W ittenberg on
Saturday. Mr. and Mrs. Gray have
been camping at Shawano Lake during
part o f this month and also spent
a little while at the Thiede cottage at
Pike Lake.
August Matz returned home Sunday
a fter a two weeks’ visit with his
daughter (M rs. Frank Schenk) and
fam ily at Rush Lake west o f Oshkosh.
Mr. Schenk is running a farm at that
place for the Buckstaff interests. Mr.
Matz was taken home by Mr. and
Mrs. Schenk, who lingered fo r a brief
visit with relatives and friends near
Shepley.
A schafskopf club of 22 members,
a fter playing together for the past ten
years, form ally organized Sunday evening
when they met at the home o f
Mrs. Lorena Hempel. They now call
themselves the “ Jolly Time Club” and
will meet every third Friday. Prizes
went to John Hartleben. Emil Schrank,
Mrs. John Hartleben and Mrs. Albert
Hartleben. Mrs. Albert Hartleben received
the floatin g prize.
Dr. and Mrs. Frank E. Ross, o f
W illiam s Bay and Los Angeles, were
dinner guests in the editor’s home last
Friday, coming here from Wisconsin
D ills. Mrs. Ross w ill be remembered
as the form er Anna Lee of Milwaukee,
who made frequent visits here. An
account of her recent marriage, which
appeared in the Milwaukee Sentinel
last week, -will be found elsewhere in
this issue. A fte r spending several
days at Green Lake they went to M ilwaukee.
On September 10th they will
leave fo r their home in the California
metropolis, where Dr. Ross is on the
staff at Mt. Wilson observatory.
Mr. and Mrs. E. C. Maahs motored
to Appleton fo r a visit in the Milo
Welch and Rud. Maahs homes. Renona
Welch, who visited with her grandparents
the past two weeks, returned
to Appleton with them. They were
also accompanied by Emma Welder,
who visited in the Maahs home the
past week. While in Appleton Mr. and
Mrs. Maahs were pleasantly surprised
at a picnic dinn« r given in honor of
their 44th wedding anniversary.
The W illiam Feuerpfeil fam ily observed
a fam ily reunion at the A. W.
Kuehlman home at N ew London last
Sunday. Among those present were
Mr. and Mr*. W illiam Feuerpfeil, Mrs.
Florence Turecek and children, Peggy,
Delores and Junior, o f W ittenberg;
Mr. and Mrs. Stanley Feuerpfeil and
children, Jacqueline, Kent and Frederic,
o f New Richmond; Mr. and Mrs.
Eugene Feuerpfeil and daughter, Nancy,
o f Shiocton, and Mr. and Mrs. Alois
Kuehlman and children, June and
James, o f New London.
H E L L O , W O R L D !
Born to Mr. and Mrs. Joe Wanta, in
Bevent, on August 22, a son.
Born to Dr. and Mrs. Wendell Marsden,
in Madison, on August 21, a
daughter, M argaret Jeannette. Mrs.
Marsden is the form er Esther Wang.
DR. A. B. SC H U LTZ . O P T O M E T R IS T
CO M IN G S A T U R D A Y E V E N IN G
at Gauerke’s Jewelry Store, W ittenberg,
from 7 to 9 p. m. Eyes tested
and glasses fitted.
Hoy Scouts
Monday night is Charter N ight and
all parents are being invited to be with
us. The boys are planning a demonstration
program. Come on, dad, and
bring mother with you this time,
(liv e your son some moral support by
showing your interest in Scouting.
R. W. Hawkins, Scoutmaster.
Want Something?
A d v e r t is e
for it in
ihese columns
For Mutual Insurance
F IR E . W IN D . A C C ID E N T .
A U T O M O B IL E
W rite or Call
H OW ARD ERICKSON
Phone 2652 Tigerton, R. 1
Automobile Repairing
H aving leased the Feuerpfeil garage, I wish to announce that
on September 1 I w ill be ready to do
GENER AL AUTOMOBILE REPAIR WORK
Guaranteeing all work — and that I am taking on the complete
line o f C IT IE S S E R V IC E PRODUCTS.
Such as gasoline, oils, tires, spark plugs, batteries, fan belts,
etc. Y ou r patronage is solicited.
Mr. Feuerpfeil will continue his agency for the Chevrolet
cars and trucks in the same location.
Eldred Hull, Wittenberg
H A V E YOIJK C H IL D R E N ’S
, E Y E S E X A M IN E D B Y .
DR. A. B. SCHULTZ
OITOMKTRIST
O f Wausau
A T W IT T E N B E R O . F IR S T
S A T U R D A Y O F E A C H M O NTH
Office at Gauerke's
Hours: 7 to !) I*. M.
D A N C E !
MAYFLOWER LAKE
SU N D A Y  M O NDAY—SEPT. 3  4
------------ M USIC B Y ------------
B O B M A L C O L M
A D M IS S IO N : 10c and 25c.
5th A N N U A L CATHOLIC PARISH PICNIC
M AYFLOW ER LAK E
SU N D AY, SEPTEMBER 3
Where Tn Q o . . .
F R E E W E D D IN G D A N C E A T
W O O D L A N D IN N
There w ill be a free wedding dance
at Erbrecht’s W'oodland Inn on Sept. 2
fo r Philip Kohn and Elsabeth Britzke.
Everybody is welcome.
F R E E W E D D IN G D A N C E A T J. D s
Saturday, Sept. 2, on highway 29, four
miles west o f Wittenberg, in honor of
Ann Bruski and John Kaminski. Music
by A ugie W o lf and his W hite Coons.
Everybody welcome.
A xel Jacobson was a dinner guest
at the home o f Rev. Sihler last Sunday.
St. Paul’s ladies aid society met in
the church parlors this afternoon.
Hostesses were Mesdames Henry Jannusch,
Charles Koeppen, Otto Draeger
and Otto Frederick.
Mr. and Mrs. A very Vose were
dinner guests Saturday evening at the
home o f J. L. K ra ft, president o f the
K raft-Phenix Cheese Corporation, at
his summer home at Enterprise Lake.
Mr. and Mrs. E. R. Dobbert and
children were supper guests in the
Con Verpoorten home Monday night,
in celebration of the anniversaries o f
the Dobbert children, D nna, Darlene
and Jon, whose birthdays are in
August.
ERST
M I D
WEST
8 y TALBOT M U N D Y
• The story oi a beautiful
American girl vacationing
In India, and oi tbe two
men In love with her—
one a cool-headed British
army ofiicer, the other an
Indian Prince.
Through the story oi
their fight to win Lynn
Harding run* a thread oi
Intrigue that adds excitement
to every chapter.
"East and West" Is one
oi Talbot Mundy's most
exciting, glamorous stories.
SERIALLY
IN THIS PAPER
W IT T E N B E R fi S N E W H O T E L
H o t e l M o d e r n e
Joe Deruchowski, Proprietor
C O M P L E T E L Y N E W
TH R O U G H O U T
Meals Lodging
Refreshments
D O W N T O W N W IT T B N B E R t.
Shawano County
SEPT. F A IR 5-6-7
ENTRY DAY, SEITEM BER 5th
W L S N a t i o n a l B a r n D a n c e S h o w
Featuring L U L U BELLE and S K Y LA N D SCOTTY
l‘ R A I Rl E S W E E T H E A RTS
MISS P A U L IN E
GEORG IE G O E B E L H A Y L O F T F ID D L E R S
R A L I 'I I A N D H E L E N S T E R N A R I)
H u g e F a r m E x h i b i t s . R i d e s  A m u s e m e n t s
B a s e b a l l
W E D N E S D A Y , S E P T . 6— S H A W A N O vs. G R E H A M
T IL L E D A vs. K R A K O W
T H U R S D A Y , SEI*T. 7 — S E Y M O U R vs. C L IN T O N V IL L E
C H A M P IO N S H IP K IT T E N B A L L T O U R N A M E N T O F S H A W A N O C O U N T Y
R a c i n g
2:21 TR O T
W E D N E S D A Y (2:15 PA C E
(2:14 T R O T
2:22 PA C E
T H U R S D A Y (2:1K T R O T
(2:0!1 P A C E
7 R i g V a u d e v i l l e A c t s o n t h e P l a t f o r m
H A P P Y H A R R IS O N ’S C IR C U S S A S C A T R IO — S E N O R PED RO
S T U A R T R O B E R TS T R IO F E N W IC K K COOK
T H E F A R M H A N D S — Wednesday Evening, September fi
W itte n b e rg C on cert B a n d S h a w a n o H . S. B a n d
D a n c i n g
T U E S D A Y N IT E , S E P T . 5— L A W R E N C E Dl ( HOW A N D H IS R E D R A V E N S
W E D N E S D A Y , S K IT , fi— T H E F A R M H A N D S
T H U R S D A Y . S E PT. 7— BOB M A LC O LM A N D H IS O R C H E S TR A
T h e G reat S h a w a n o C o u n ty F a ir Sept. 5 r 6, 7
LO U IS W. C A T T A U . Secretary ( HAS. P IE H L . President
PAGE FOUR THE WITTENBERG ENTERPRISE. WITTENBERG, WIS.
The
Wittenberg Enterprise
JOHN E N G LU N D , Editor
Published Every Week On Thursday
$2.00 Per Year. Cask In Advance.
Telephone 63-2
N »tional Advertising Representative
A M E R IC A N PR ESS A S S O C IA T IO N
Member Wisconsin Press Association
Entered as matter o f the second class
at the Wittenberg, Wis., postoffice
November 23, 1893.
State Capital Letter
(Run-over from first page.)
past under a joint resolution introduced
by two Republican, one Democrat,
and one Progressive assemblyman,
which would limit sessions to
five months.
The measure, sponsored by Assemblymen
Robert H. Burns and Otto
Toepfer, Republicans; A lex L. Nichol
Progressive; and Albert P . Shimek,
Democrat; would have sessions begin
the second Wednesday in January and
end the third Wednesday in June of
odd numbered years.
The present legislature has been in
session for eight months. Other notably
long sessions in the past include
the 1935 and 1929 session, both of
which lasted almost nine months, and
the 1915 session, which sat until
August 24 o f that year.
Bark to School
With the new scholastic year about
to get under way again U niversity o f
Wisconsin officials are preparing for a
total enrollment o f almost 11.500
students, approximately the same
number enrolled last year for the first
semester.
But Wisconsin students at the U niversity
must come with a slightly
fu ller pocketbook, for incidental fees
have been raised five dollars a semes
ter, and w ill now total $65 fo r the en
tire school year instead o f $55. Non
resident tuition stays at $100 a semes
ter.Regular increases in enrollment for
the past three years, says Curtis Mer
riman. registrar, have heen due to a
marked growth in the graduate school
and more students entering in their
junior year a fter having served their
first two years at other colleges and
schools. Freshman registration for
the period has remained at about 2,500
students a year.
Present record enrollment fo r the
first semester is the 1938 figure o f
11,416. Ten years ago the total enrollment
fo r the first half o f the school
year was 9.468.
'o n w no n trib u tfd Rtf 'S/trtrf
activities; but we are not in fa vo r o f
so many that teachers and pupils are
alike overtaxed. W e would like a
happy balance in our school with emphasis
on the school studies, where
that emphasis righ tly belongs.
W e welcome back our fine staff of
old teachers and welcome to W itten berg
the new. W e wish you and the
students a happy and successful year!
Nom inally Labor Day is a holiday.
But for a vast arm y o f men and
women, old, middle-aged, and young it
is the day their labors fo r another
year commence. For a vaster army
o f boys and girls it marks the end of
play time and the beginning o f nine
months o f confinement to books and
hard work.
Since there is no public institution
which wields a greater influence over
the citizens o f the United States than
the Public Schools, it behooves us as
adults, whether parents or no. to cooperate
with the teachers whom the
School Board which we elected have
hired. Some of the teachers w ill be
strangers in Wittenberg. Let us make
them happy that they will live in such
a friendly town. Some of the teachers
w ill be returning fo r another year. It
would be well to let them know we are
happy to have them back.
We realize that there is a tendency
to be enthusiastic over young teachers
just out of college and brimming over
with enthusiasm and new ideas and
untried theories. Their pep and enthusiasm
are infectious, and school
board member and parent alike are in-!
clined to be too greatly impressed by s
clever little numbers the young teacher
trains her youngsters to give.
One does not put up green saplings
fo r winter fuel. When one fires with
green wood one gets much smoke but j
very little heat. One wants his basement
full o f seasoned wood which
gives the maximum heat with the
minimum of “moke, and it’s from the
glow ing coals that the most intense
heat comes.
So it is with our teachers. The]
young peptomista just out o f college
supply the smoke and fanfare; but the
seasoned teachers who have tried out
their theories and tested their methods
are the most valuable members o f the)
school faculty. They supply the even
balance and give stability to the school j
system. It would be well not to under-1
value their work because it is not
spectacular.
L et us remember that a school is
a place where children learn to think,!
to read, to write, and to figure. The
first function of the teachers is to
teach; and to be able to do a good job
o f teaching, they cannot be loaded j
down w'ith all sorts o f extra curricular j
programs. I f we demand that a
teacher carrying a full teaching load
put on plays, operettas, and coach
declamatory, his teaching w ill necessarily
suffer.
It would be a fine thing for the;
community if the teachers w ere allow ed
to teach and the students were
allowed o study and have a little spare
time to spend at home in their church’s
activities.
We are in favor of extra curricular
U. S. 45 Cost Shawano
Much Tourist Trade
(Editorial in Shawano Leader.)
During the past 10 years we have
heard much o f the H ighw ay 26 club
and the Highway 45 club, organizations
promoting old state highway 26
and new federal highway 45 running
from the south through Shawano county
and on to Eagle River.
Undoubtedly many of you have
wondered why all the excitement about
a highway. Last Saturday we had occasion
to drive federal highway 45
from Clintonville to Oshkosh, and
upon seeing so many foreign cars,—
mostly Illinois,— we decided to jot
down on paper the number o f Illinois
cars and the number of Wisconsin cars
which we either met or passed on the
way. W e started this counting at the
triangle corners about three miles
south o f New London and counted until
we reached the city of Oshkosh.
Farm trucks and larger trucks were
I not counted in the tabulation.
Here is what we found of the 127
cars we either met or passed: 65 were
foreign cars and 62 were Wisconsin
cars. Think o f that, more than 50
per cent o f the passengers traveling
on highway 45 were out-of-state
tourist traffic guided up highwav 45
through the years o f effort o f advertising
the road and developing it.
And who knows how many o f the W isconsin
cars we met were guide1 up
that road by honest and intelligent
propaganda spread by our neighboring
towns. I f you w ill remember
neighboring towns fought the move all
the way to keep highway 45 out of
Shawano and no effort was made to
guide this traffic through this citv and
the beautiful Menominee Indian Reser
vation.
The Highw ay 45 club has arterialized
the traffic of the south to Eagle
River in such a way that about all the
traffic we get now that goes to the
popular vacation land is stragglers
who have been told to drive 47 to see
the great and beautiful timber lands
o f the north,— the land owned by the
Menominee Indians. We have known
more than one instance the past summer
in which a tourist in returning
f»*om the north was told by Eagle
River and Rhinelander lodge owners
to drive back 47 if they really wished
a treat.
G etting a federal highway thrm gh
your town these days is just like g e tting
a railroad into your town a
hundred years ago. Now, the people
travel by automobiles and traffic lanes
have turned from steel to concrete.
Conditions have not changed as to the
need o f traveling and people coming
through and passing through a town.
Traffic and people are important and
i f Shawano is going to grow with the
>ther towns in this section o f the
state, we must keep at least ->ne eye
on possible roads for Shawano in the
future, W'e cannot let towns nearby
outsmart us but we must fight for
good through roads the same as they
have. This does not mean that we'
must take 45 away from them, but it
ioes mean that we should make an
*‘ff rt to guide at least some o f the
traffic we used to get through the city
of Shawano. H ighw ay 45 now gets
traffic old 26 always got, and we believe
that a large portion o f the traffic
that 47 and 55 form erly got is now
going up U. S. highway 45.
It is safe to say that towns the size,
o f Shawano on 45 draws business from
over 200 cars a day over week-ends.
Estimate that for yourself, Mr.
Shawano merchant, and you w ill realize
that Clintonville, New l^ondon and
several small towns talked you out of
quite a nice little jack pot each w eekend.
C O M M EN TS
Th at’s a brazen statement in the
foregoing editorial taken from last
Friday’s Shawano Evening Leader—
that “ neighboring towns fought the
move all the way to keep highway 45
out of Shawano,” as if Shawano at
any time had any claim whatsoever on
that h’ ghway. As every one knows,!
those “ neighboring towns” Clintonville.
Marion, Tiverton, Wittenberg.
Eland, Birnamwood and Aniwa were
only seeking to keep what rightfully
belonged to them out o f the grasping
and greedy hands of Shawano. And
every one knows that if it had not
heen for the effective work done by
the Highway 26 and Highway 45
clubs, Shawano might have succeeded
*n her unneighborly move to have
H ighw ay 45 rerouted over 22 into
Shawano and away from this end o f
the county. Everyone in western
Shawano county has strongly suspected
all along Shawano’s secret scheming
to this end and that a confession of
this scheming now appears in the
Shawano daily is indeed surprising.
Equally surprising is the fact that
Sha wan •. having four state highways
— 29, 55, 47 and 22—-besides the many
advantages accruing to a county seat
Thursday, August 31, 1939
town— never seems satisfield with
what she has and has no scruples
about grow ing in importance at the
expense o f sister towns. She did not
seem to care that by having Highway
45 relocated over 22— not a feasible
proposition in the first place— she was
depriving all the villages but one in
this end o f the county o f their only
arterial and their best chances fo r an
all-the-year connecting highway.
W e do not like to think o f Shawano
as a selfish town but we will soon have
to do so if any more confessions like
the foregoing one appear in the public
print.
(F irst pub, Aug. 31; last Sept. 14).
N O T IC E OF IIE A R rN C . ON F IN A L
S E T T L E M E N T A N I ) D E T E R M IN A
T IO N OF IN H E R IT A N C E T A X
State o f Wisconsin, County Court,
Shawano County.
In the matter o f the estate of George
Gjermundson, Sr., deceased.
Notice is hereby given that at a
term o f said Court to be held
on Tuesday, the 26th day of September.
1939, at 10 o’clock in the forenoon
of said day, at the office of the County
Judge, in the V illage o f Wittenberg, in
said County, there will be heard and j
cons'dered:
The application o f George W .
Gjermundson, administrator o f the]
estate of George Gjermundson, Sr.,
deceased, late o f the Town o f Morris,
in said County, fo r the examination
and allowance of his final account,
which account is now on file in said
Court, and for the allowance o f debts
or claims paid in good faith without
filing or allowance as required by law,
and fo r the assignment o f the residue
of the estate o f said deceased to such
persons as are by law entitled thereto;
and for the determination and adjudication
o f the inheritance tax, if any,
payable in said estate.
Dated August 25th, 1939.
Bv Order o f the Court,
H E L E N M L U D O LPH ,
Register in Probate.
W. D. H A S E L T IN E , Attorney.
Rosholt Free Fair
September 2, 3, 4
Plans for the County F air are going
forward at Rosholt fo r the three-day
F air and exposition to be held or
September 2, 3 and -If coming to p
close on the evening o f Labor Day. A
fairly favorable grow ing season
should make 1939 a record entry year.
Saturdav afternoon being entry day.
the Fair w ill officially open that evening
with Free Acts and talking pictures
on the outdoor stage. A splendid
nrogram has been arranged with
the Hagen booking agency for Sunday
afternoon and evening. Arch Adrian
and his “ men of note” w ill furnish
music for the dance Monday night,
and also w ill appear on the stage in
the afternoon in addition to other Free
Acts and entertainment. In also engaging
Dorothea and M argaret Widmer,
the yodeling girls from Monroe
Wis., the F air management has lined
up the best talent to be seen here in
years.
4-H Club Work Steadily Growing
Under the leadership o f County
Agent II. R. Noble and Miss Irene
Skutley, County Home Ec. Agent, 4-H
Club work has been on the increase
for the past number o f years.
Because of increased enrollment in
4-H C alf d u b work, it has been necessary
to enlarge the C alf barn to make
room for over 60 calves. Thirty six
new poultry pens have been built and
repainted. W ith the remodeling that
has been done in the old barn, the
capacity has been increased about
fo rty per cent.
Last year marked a major change
when the ‘Tow nship Booths” were replaced
by the Agricultural Booths.
The Township Booth merely showed
good farm produce while thc “ Educational”
booth was conceived and applied
to show better farm practices.
The smaller booths met with public
favor and w ere praised by Judges o f
the Fair.
I)R. A B. S C H U LT Z . O lT O M E T R IS T .
C O M IN G S A T U R D A Y E V E N IN G
at Gauerke’s Jew elry Store, W ittenberg,
from 7 to 9 p. m. Eyes tested
and glasses fitted.
I f you wish to keep milk sweet, put
it in the cold part of the ice box or
refrigera tor where the temperature is
about 45 degrees Fahrenheit.
N E W L IB R A R Y SC H E D U LE
Wednesdays— 2:00 to 5:00 and
7:00 to 9:00.
Saturdays— 2:00 to 5:00 and
7:00 to 9:00.
C.  N . W . T IM E T A B L E
Southbound
Train A rrives
No. 108 ( d a i l y ) ................. 5:16 a. m. j
No. 116 (da ily ex. Sunday) 12:50 p. m.J
Northbound
No. 117 (d a ily ex. Sunday) 10:13 a. m.
No. 109 (d a ily )................... 9:53 p. m.
Southbound Flambeau leaves Eland
(d a ily ) 3:50 p. m.
Northbound Flambeau arrives at |
Eland (d a ily ) 6:15 p. m.
For
H E A L T H . A C C ID E N T . L IF E ,
A N D A U T O M O B IL E
INSURANCE
See
JOE TURECEK
V M T TE N B E B Ii, WIS.
DRY CLEANING
I f you have any Dry Cleaning to hi*
done notify Kusserow'n store, our
lH'al station.
HOW ARD YO UNG
Arcnt for P A N T O R II’ M DRY
C L E A N K ItS . of Shawano.
W. I). HASELTINE
A ttorn ey-A t-Law
Office in Bank Ruitding
W IT T E N B E R G , W IS C O N S IN
Specials!
FOR T H E W E E K
\\ ASH T IE S 15c, 30c and 25c
values @ !lc, 15c a n d ............19c
C O M P L E T E L IN E OF
SCHOOL S U P P L IE S
8x12x4" O V E R N IG H T Q C A
C A S E S ........................ Z O C
R IN G S M IT H ’S
Ben fran klin
Store
Wisconsin’s Best Free F air!
Rosholt
Free
Fair
P O R T A G E C O U N T Y 'S
A G R IC U L T U R A L E X P O S IT IO N
E X T E N S IV E F ARM A N I)
4-H C L U B E X H IB IT S
SEPT. 2-3-4
S P E C IA L D A IL Y F E A T U R E S !
F R E E A C TS !
R U S T Y H A G E N T R O U P E
R O L L E R SK \TIN G
C O M E D Y A C R O B ATS
C O N T O R T IO N IS T
HOOP R O L L E R S M V G IC IA N S
H IL L B IL L IE S Y O D E LE R S
T A L K IN G PIC T U R E S
A R C H A D R IA N B A N D
W ith Special Features
B A S E B A L I. G A M E S !
S O F T B A L L G A M E S
K A A R U P 'S RID E S
C L E A N M ID W A Y \ T T Ii VCTION
D A N C E on LA B O R D A Y
Land o’ Lakes Bus Co.
BUS SC H E D U LE
Daily
Southbound— 8:08 a. m. and 5:08 p. m.
Connects Madison, Janesville, and
Chicago.
Northbound— 11:15 a. m. and 8:50
p. m. to A n tig o and Rhinelander.
Wausau-Green Hay Bus
Daily
East Bounnd— 8:50 a. m.; 3:20 p. m.
West Bound— 11:55 a. m.; 4:25 p. m.
C A L L S E E
The N e w S tr e a m -L in e d |
T U f f t
SILO FILLER ftrrra built, bio
CAPACITY, LOW COST
NEW MODEL
improved
to the M in uU
Big, wide, low feed table; large •elffeeding
beater roll; unbreakable
fly wheel; oil enclosed gear*; h eavy d u ty
ball-bearing main and jack shafts. Easychangeable
length o f cut. Throw s green
corn 45-feet high w ith as little as 5 hp.
m otor, 500 rpm . A '*T h orob red ’'is known
b y his record. T h e N e w G E H L . with
hay cutting attachm ent. I S a T H O R O -
B R B D . B efore you buy an y cutter, call
and see th e latest from thc old reliable
House o f G E H L .
C i t i e s S e r v i c e G a r a g e
Elderon, Wis.
IN S IO N $ 1 .2 9
e Z T n q e k d
POCKET a n d WRIST WATCHES
*1.00 to *3.95
A L A R M C L O C K S
1.00 to 2.95
L O O K F O R O N THE DIAL
“C h eap ” h o u se
p a in t is a lu x u ry
jor tine rich man only
If yoa have loads o f money . . . if you can afford
to buy twice as many gallons . . . if you
can pay the cost of burning or scraping off the
old paint every two years or so— and the
added cost of frequent repainting . . . then
you are rich enough to use a “ cheap,” low
price bouse paint.
But if you want to make every dollar count
— to get value for your money— then you’d
better buy the best house paint money can
buy S W P . It costs no more in the beginning
- and much less in the end.
Come in and let us tell you the truth a
the exorbitant coot of “ cheap” paint.
S e e “ P a i n t H e a d q u a r t e r s ”
G a  M . H a r d w a r e
Back-to-Schoo]
SALE
N E W SHOES N E W S W E A T E R S
N EW M E N ’S A N I ) B O YS ’ P A N T S
N E W DRESSES
N E W S H IR T S
N E W M E N ’S H A T S N E W S K IR T S A N D B LO U SES
E V E R Y T H IN G N E W FO R F A M , A N D W IN T E R
A T V E R Y L O W P R IC E S
Y O U C A N DO B E T T E R A T
F a rm e rs O u tlet S to re
W H E R E Y O U R D O L L A R S GO F A R T H E R
W IT T E N B E R G , W IS . N E X T TO C A S H W A Y STO RE
SEPT. 1 THRU 7
Cosh W a y leads in low priced, high
quolity groceries for the thrifty
SUGAR 10
PICNICS >..
CAKE FLOOR
Peanut Butter es? 2
Northern Tissue
u>.
Cloth
Bog
Nicolet
2 % ft. box
Lb.
Jar
Linenixed Roll
50c
15c
16c
20c
5c
FRI. IT'S A PEACH OP A TIM E TO C A N
PEACHES A N D PEARS SAT.
PEACHES
Michigan Elbertas
L a r g e s i z e B o . 1 .8 5
M e d . s i z e B a . 1 .4 8
Colorado, b o x ........... 95c
PEARS
L a r g e s i z e B a . 2 . 0 9
M e d . s i z e . . . $ 1 . 6 9
Michigan Bartletts
FRESH PRUNES Eating Lug 85c
BLUE GRAPES c”“”' 4 £2 22c
COOKIES
Fresh Coconut
M acaroon s........... ft. 15c
Lemon Cake . . 2 fts. 25c
Lemon Creams . . ft. 15c
C A N D Y SPECIAL
Old
Fashion Gums 2 lbs. 15c
Chocolate
Butter S ta r s .........Ib. 15c
Horvest M i x .........Ib. 19c
PURE COCOA x - 2
SOUP . . . 3
OVALTINE
OXYDOL
ib.
can
Tbe Swiss
Food Drink
New High
Test
15c
25c
33c
2 .o’.', 39c
22 ox.
cans
6 os.
Can
SCHOOL SUPPLIES
I P E N C IL S ...........2 for 5c
Regular 6c Value,
With the B ig Rubber
T A B L E T S .........3 for 10c
Fillers, Note Books, Composition
Books, Typ ew riter Paper,
Scratch Pads.
N B C C rinkle M M
SA N D W IC H . . . . Ib. 19c
Pride Assorted
COOKIES . . . ft. box 23c
Nicolet Colossal 20 Oz.
SWEET PEAS. 2 cons 29c
B A B - O .........2 cons 25c
Just sprinkle on cloth and
w ipe off. Ask us about special
book offer by Emily Post.
A
WITTENBERG, WIS.
Thursday, August 31, 1939 THE WITTENBERG ENTERPRISE. WITTENBERG, WIS. PAGE FIVE
LOCAL NEWS NOTES
Miss Esther Gunderson was in A n tigo
Wednesday.
Joe Komp visited with a brother in
Milwaukee from Sunday until Tuesday.
G. A. Meisner, Ernest Sickler and
Jerry C oyle spent Sunday at Stone
lake.
Roland Jesse and W a lter Schwertfe
g er spent Sunday at Huntington
lake.
Marilyn Meeh o f Green Bay is
spending the week at the Thoreson
home
Jimmy Liesch is spending several
days in the Robert Brown home in
A ntigo.
Mrs. Frank Ripple, and son, Victor,
of Waukegan, 111., visited in the Ed.
Maahs home.
Miss Dora Haupt, o f Shawano, spent
Sunday with her parents, Mr. and Mrs.
Louis Haupt.
Miss Marcella Bloecher is visit*ng
with relatives and friends in Milwaukee
this week.
Mr. and Mrs. R. Oestreich and
daughters, Doris and Mary, spent the
week-end at Wausau.
N orval Solvang, o f Chicago, was a
visitor this week in the home o f his
cousin, Lester Carlson.
Herman Schmidt is enjoying a
vacation this week from his duties at
the K raft-Phenix plant.
Mr. and Mrs. Raymond Schulz and
daughter Ruth, o f Wausau, were W ittenberg
visitors on Friday.
Miss Rirth Thoreson le ft Sunday a fternoon
fo r Mattoon, where she will
teach the Lake M ay school.
Mr. and Mrs. Ervin Laude and
daughter, Karen, visited at the Frank
Kolpack home at Bow ler Sunday.
Paul Johnson, o f Camp Rib Mountain,
snent the week-end with his parents,
Mr. and Mrs. Peter Johnson.
Miss May Krause returned to A th ens
Sunday a fter being employed at
the H. Gauerke home several months.
Mrs. William Sense and children, of
Marquette, Michigan, and Mrs. Cleve
Guerin were Wausau visitors Thursday.
W
. S. F. Smith, o f Mazomanie. a rrived
Tuesday fo r a few days’ visit in
the home o f his nephew, W. D. H aseltine.
Dr. and Mrs. Wm. Sihler returned
to Decorah last Tuesday. Mrs. F. Palladeau
traveled with them as fa r as
Tomah.
Rant, Edwin and John Ellingson and
son, Russell, and G. J. Jenson. o f W ausau,
visited at the John Peterson home
Sunday.
Mrs. Eldred Hull and fam ily are
this week enjoying a visit by her parents,
Mr. and Mrs. Emil Harning, of
Waupaca.
Miss Sylvia Westlund returned Sunday
from Wausau Memorial hospital
where she underwent an eye operation
a week ago.
Mr. and Mrs. Francis Bessette an'?
children, Blanche, Arnold, Roger and
Yvonne, o f Oshkosh, visited relatives
here Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Elm er Werth andj
fam ily, o f Hartford, were week-end i
visitors in the home of her father,!
August Korth.
Joe Bolster, o f Clintonville, and
Marvin and Marilyn Mech. o f Green ■
Bay, spent the week-end at the C. A.
Thoreson home.
Mrs. Melvin Bessette took her IBmonths-
old son. Ronald, to Madison
Wednesday where the baby will undergo
observation and treatment at the
Wisconsin General Hospital.
Mr. and Mrs. Oscar Falstad and Mr.
and Mrs. Carl Mathison motored to
Madison Sunday, returning with the
form er’s baby daughter, who had been
receiving treatments at the Wisconsin
General Hospital.
ENTERPRISE WANT
AD DEPARTMENT
G I R L W A N T E D — for housework, at
the H. Gauerke home, Wittenberg.
FOR S A L E — 5 gallons aluminum exterior
paint in original container.
$10 cash. E. W . Sihler, Bethany
Indian Mission. 42-1 t f
H A V E ROOM A N D BO ARD for two
boys or two girls for coming school
year. Inquire at Enterprise office.
___________________ 41 -1 tc
W A N T E D Old standing and disabled
horses. Arnold Heistad, Route 1.
Wittenberg. Phone 6Q5-R10. 894t
FOR S A L E — Dressed poultry. Inquire
of Emil Schrank, Route 2. 38-tf
FOR S A L E — W e have a good assortment
o f grain and corn binders and
other machinery as well, and Mr. car
or truck buyer, we believe we are in
a position to supply your wants right
here at home on cars or on tires or
what else you may have in mind.
Don’t forget to see us before you buy.
Gust Norrbom, Elderon. 36-tf
S E L L your old horses direct to a fur
farm er and get higher prices. We
also buy cows lost through freshening,
accidents, etc. Graves Mink Ranch.
Eland. Wis._____ ___________ W
ANTIGO RENDERING WORKS—
will call fo r your dead and disabled
Horses and cattle free o f charge (w ith
hides on). Telephone A ntigo 744.
W e pay telephone charges.
W A N T E D — Old and disabled horses
for mink feed. Arthur Larson, W ittenberg.
24*tf
Mr. and Mrs. Bernhard Plagemann
and daughter Bernice and Miss Ella
Zeitler took a trip to Abbotsford and
U nity last Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Sam Levine spent
from Sunday until Tuesday in Miwaukee,
where they attended to business
matters and also visited relatives.
Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Martin andj
children, Junior and Gordon, o f Ringle, j
visited at the Conrad Verpoorten home!
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Joe Kupsick and son|
Chester, o f Milwaukee, arrived during
the week-end fo r a visit in the Deruchowski
home.
Mr. and Mrs. Leland Bloecher and
son Douglas and George Bloecher
were week-end visitors with Oscar
Bloecher at Tomahawk.
William Jorgenson, a resident o f the
Homme Home for the Aged, returned
here Saturday a fter a week’s visit
with relatives in Antigo.
Dr. Doolittle, who took care o f Dr.
Evenson’s practice here while the
latter was on his vacation, has returned
to his home in Madison.
Mr. and Mrs. Eldred Hull and four
children have moved here from Bowler
and are living in the Utech house just
vacated by the Sutheimer fam ily.
Carl Sutheimer and fam ily this
week moved to N iagara, where they
w ill make their future home, a fter
several years’ residence in Wittenberg.
Marvin Midtsjo and a friend, John
Gavin, of Maywood, 111., called briefly
on friends in W ittenberg on Friday
while enroute home from an outing up
north.
Miss Ix*ona Schwertfeger returned
today from Woodruff, where she spent
several davs in the home o f her
brother, W illiam Schwertfeger, andj
family.
Mr. and Mrs. Lewis A. Liesch andl
children, Jimmy and Doris, spent the
week-end at H artford with H arry
Liesch and fam ily and also visited in
Milwaukee.
Frank Koenig, Mr. and Mrs. Louis
Peters and Mr. and Mrs. H arry Krahn,
all of Milwaukee, arrived Saturday fo r
a visit until next Tuesday in the Otto
Schrank home.
. Mrs. Henrv Ringstad and children,
Shirley and Howard, o f Milwaukee,
have been spending several weeks here
with her parents, Mr. and Mrs. John
Laude.
Mr. and Mrs. Paul Glaubitz and Mr.
and Mrs. W alter Glaubitz. of Milwau-
Vee, made a brief call at the Mrs. Ida
Glaubitz homo Saturdav evenimr while
on their w ay to the Glaubitz cottage at
Pel’can Lake.
A .A. Grimstad returned Saturday
from a five weeks’ visit with his
daughters, Mrs. William Farrell, at
Waukegan, and Miss Nina Grimstad,
at Wilm ette, 111.
M 5ss Kathleen Stone who has been
employed at Winnetka, 111., fo r several,
months, is vis itir? friends here before'
resuming her studies at Stevens Point
teachers’ college.
Mr. and Mrs. H. E. Kersten and|
^aueh^or. Melitta. returned Monday |
from Milwaukee. Mrs. Raymond Lieg
and daughter. Mary, returned w ith !
them to visit here.
Mr. and Mrs. Val Meckes, Miss
Mildred Gilbert and Miss Ellenora Loherg
visited the Gateway Inn Sunday.!
They also stopped at K raftw ood Gardens
on Enterprise Lake.
T Gardner and son Thomas Louis,
o f Chicago, are spending a few days
in this village. Mr. Gardner being here
on duty as an inspector of dairy farms
fo r the Chicago board o f health.
The Rev. and Mrs. Ernest Gander
who have been visitin g in the A.
Mathes and Wm. Rosenthal home thej
past several days, returned to their;
home at Dundee. Illinois, Wednesday.
Mr. and Mrs. H. R. Cappel and sons.,
Robert. Donald and Darrell, Mr. and
Mrs. Charles Huebner and daughter
Lynn and Mr. and Mrs. Otto Fredrick
spent Sunday at Rib Mountain park.
Fire in the Mike W alters home in
the town o f N orrie yesterday did damage
to the extent o f about $30. F ire
started on the roof from a chimney
spark and was quickly extinguished.
Mrs. Tillie Halverson departed for
Wauwatosa on Friday a fter a stay o f
ter weeks with friends in W ittenberg
and vicinity. On leaving she expressed
appreciation o f their kindness to her.
Mr. and Mrs. A lvin Laude and son
John. Mrs. Henry Ringstad and children.
Shirley and Howard, and John
Laude spent Sunday at Pickerel lake.
Saturday they visited Mrs. Lapinski at
B( vent.
Sunday night visitors in the Ed.
Schoepke home were Mr. and Mrs.
Chas. Schoening, o f Rhinelander, Mrs.
Auer. H oeft and son, o f Tigerton, Mrs.
W ill Schoepke, o f Crandon, and Mr.
and Mrs. August Wendler and son
Rolland.
Mr. and Mrs. W illiam Spargo and
W ill Wiseman made a trip to Argonne
last week. Returning, they were accompanied
by Mrs. Andrew Baken.
who made a visit with relatives and
friends near here. Wiseman says one
night up there was so cold that the
water froze in a bucket.
kginia 6 h ly
(ONC€ A STAND-IN FOfc FLORENCE RICE
AND MAD6E EVANS) DIDN'T HAVE TO LEAVE
HOME TO GET IN THE MOVIES... SHE WAS
SQE>N AEOUT 10 MINUTES DRIVE PROM T*E M-G-M STUDIOS ?________
New York, N. Y .— “ I T ’S T R U E ! that Lew Ayres was once
told b y a fortune teller that he would never amount to anything,
that he would die broke and that no one would ever know his
name!” says Wiley Padan.. . “ Ian Hunter, British-born leading
man, plays Ayres’ rival in M -G -M ’s ‘Broadway Serenade’ . . .
Jeanette MacDonald’s nephew, Earl Wallace, just back from
service with the Marines in China, was an interested visito r on
the ‘Broadway Serenade’ set.”
Miss Ledah Van Gilder motored t o !
Manitowish last Saturday and her
sister, Miss Marion, who has been em ployed
up there returned home with
her Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. Herman Bloechl and
children, Delores and LeRoy, o f Sheboygan,
are making a visit with relatives
at this place, Mr. and Mrs. A lbeit
Hartleben and Mr. and Mrs. George
Vollmer.
Mr. and Mrs. Herbert Lasch. of
Duluth, and Mr. and Mrs. Fred Vohs,
of New London, spent several days
last week at the home o f their sister
and daughter, Mrs. Henry Jannusch, 1
and fam ily.
Mr. and Mrs. Clarence Wandschncider,
o f Milwaukee, arrived Saturday
for a visit in the Chester Bloecher |
home. While here they also enjoyed ,
an outing at the Bloecher cottage on 1
Bestul lake.
Mrs. Hertha Murdock and George!
Natzke, o f Shawano, visited at the
Claus Schaar home Sunday. Kent
and Donald Murdock returned with
them a fter visiting at the Schaar home
several months.
William Palladeau went to Chicago
last Wednesday night. Mr. and Mrs.
Ferdinand Palladeau drove down Saturday
afternoon and returned Sunday
with Wm. Palladeau and his sister,
Mrs. M. Krause.
Mr. and Mrs. E. Westphal and
daughter, Anita, o f Pella, and Mr. and
Mrs. Carl Damrau, of Tigerton visited
at the John Laude home Sunday. V isitors
there Saturday were Mr. and
Mrs. John Nachts and son and Mrs.
Augusta Sedrell, o f Tilleda.
Stanley Feuerpfeil and fam ily, o f
New Richmond, were Saturday visitors
here. Mrs. Florence Turecek and
children returned here with them after
spending several weeks in New Richmond,
while Mr. and Mrs. Stanley
Feuerpfeil attended the New York
fair.
Mrs. Arthur Gray (the form er
Gladys W ilson), o f Cincinnati, Ohio,
was a brief caller in W ittenberg on
Saturday. Mr. and Mrs. Gray have
been camping at Shawano Lake during
part o f this month and also spent
a little while at the Thiede cottage at
Pike Lake.
August Matz returned home Sunday
a fter a two weeks’ visit with his
daughter (M rs. Frank Schenk) and
fam ily at Rush Lake west o f Oshkosh.
Mr. Schenk is running a farm at that
place fo r the Buckstaff interests. Mr.
Matz was taken home by Mr. and
Mrs. Schenk, who lingered fo r a brief
visit with relatives and friends near
Shepley.
A schafskopf club o f 22 members,
a fter playing together for the past ten
years, form ally organized Sunday evening
when they met at the home o f
Mrs. Lorena Hempel. They now call
themselves the “ Jolly Tim e Club” and
will meet every third Friday. Prizes
went to John Hartleben. Emil Schrank,
Mrs. John Hartleben and Mrs. Albert
Hartleben. Mrs. Albert Hartleben received
the floating prize.
Dr. and Mrs. Frank E. Ross, o f
William s Bay and Los Angeles, were
dinner guests in the editor’s home last
Friday, coming here from Wisconsin
Dells. Mrs. Ross will be remembered
as the form er Anna Lee of Milwaukee,
who made frequent visits here. An
account of her recent marriage, which
appeared in the Milwaukee Sentinel
last w eek,-will be found elsewhere in
this issue. A fte r spending several
days at Green Lake they went to M ilwaukee.
On September 10th they will
leave fo r their home in the California
metropolis, where Dr. Ross is on the
staff at Mt. Wilson observatory.
Mr. and Mrs. E. C. Maahs motored
to Appleton fo r a visit in the Milo
Welch and Rud. Maahs homes. Renona
Welch, who visited with her grandparents
the past two weeks, returned
to Appleton with them. They were
also accompanied by Emma Welder,
who visited in the Maahs home the
past week. While in Appleton Mr. and
Mrs. Maahs were pleasantly surprised
a t a picnic dinner given in honor of
their 44th wedding anniversary.
The William Feuerpfeil fam ily observed
a fam ily reunion at the A. W.
Kuehlman home at N ew London last
Sunday. Among those present were
Mr. and Mr*. William Feuerpfeil, Mrs.
Florence Turecek and children, Peggy,
Delores and Junior, of W ittenberg;
Mr. and Mrs. Stanley Feuerpfeil and
children, Jacqueline, Kent and Frederic,
o f New Richmond; Mr. and Mrs.
Eugene Feuerpfeil and daughter, Nancy,
o f Shiocton, and Mr. and Mrs. Alois
Kuehlman and children, June and
James, o f New London.
H E L L O , W O R L D !
Boy Scouts
Monday night is Charter N ight and
all parents are being invited to be with
us. The boys are planning a demonstration
program. Come on, dad, and
bring mother with you this time.
Give your son some moral support by
showing your interest in Scouting.
R. W. Hawkins, Scoutmaster.
Want Something?
A d v e r t is e
for it in
these columns
Born to Mr. and Mrs. Joe Wanta, in
Bevent, on August 22, a son.
Born to Dr. and Mrs. Wendell Marsden,
in Madison, on August 21, a
daughter, M argaret Jeannette. Mrs.
Marsden is the form er Esther Wang.
DR. A. B. SC H U LTZ , O P T O M E T R IS T
C OM IN G S A T U R D A Y E V E N IN G
at Gauerke’s Jew elry Store, W ittenberg,
from 7 to 9 p. m. Eyes tested
and glasses fitted.
For Mutual Insurance
F IR E , W IN D , A C C ID E N T .
A U T O M O B IL E
W rite or Call
H OW ARD ERICKSON
l*hone 2652 Tigerton, R. ]
Automobile Repairing
H aving leased the Feuerpfeil garage, 1 wish to announce that
on September 1 I will be ready to do
G ENERAL AUTOMOBILE REPAIR WORK
Guaranteeing all work — and that I am taking on the complete
line o f C IT IE S S E R V IC E PRODUCTS.
Such as gasoline, oils, tires, spark plugs, batteries, fan belts,
etc. Your patronage is solicited.
Mr. Feu erpfeil will continue his agency fo r the Chevrolet
ears and trucks in the same location.
Eldred Hull, Wittenberg
H A V E Y O U R C H IL D R E N ’S
. E Y E S E X A M IN E D H Y .
DR. A. B. SCHULTZ
0IT0M K TRIST
O f Wausau
A T W IT T E N H E R C . F IR S T
S A T U R D A Y O F EAC H M O NTH
Office al Gauerke's
Hours: 7 to !• I’ . M.
D A N C E !
MAYFLOWER LAKE
SU N D A Y  M O N D AY—SEPT. 3  4
------------ M U SIC B Y ------------
B O B M A L C O L M
A D M IS S IO N : 40c and 25c.
5th A N N U A L CATHOLIC PARISH PICNIC
M AYFLO W ER LAK E
SU N D AY, SEPTEMBER 3
Where To Q o.
F R E E W E D D IN G D A N C E A T
W O O D L A N D IN N
There will bp a fre e wedding dance
at Erbrecht’s Woodland Inn on Sept. 2
fo r Philip Kohn and Elsabeth Britzke.
Everybody is welcome.
F R E E W E D D IN G D A N C E A T J. D s
Saturday, Sept. 2, on highway 29, four
miles west o f W’ ittenberg, in honor of
Ann Bruski and John Kaminski. Music
by Augie W o lf and his W hite Coons.
Everybody welcome.
A xel Jacobson was a dinner guest
at the home of Rev. Sihler last Sunday.
St. Paul’s ladies aid society met in
the church parlors this afternoon.
Hostesses were Mesdames Henry Jannusch,
Charles Koeppen, Otto Draeger
and Otto Frederick.
Mr. and Mrs. A very Vose were
dinner guests Saturday evening at thr
home o f J. L. K ra ft, president o f the
Kraft-Phenix Cheese Corporation, at
his summer home at Enterprise Lake.
Mr. and Mrs. E. R. Dobbert and
children were supper guests in th*
Con Verpoorten home Monday night,
in celebration of the anniversaries of
the Dobbert children, D nna, Darlene
and Jon, whose birthdays are in
August.
EAST
P H D
WEST
Hy TALBO T M U N D Y
• The itory ol a beautiful
American (jirl vacationing
in India, and oi the two
men In love with her—
one a cool-headed British
army officer, the other an
Indian Prince.
Through the story oi
their fight to win Lynn
Harding runs a thread of
intrigue that adds excitement
to every chapter.
"East and West" Is one
ol Talbot Mundy's most
exciting, glamorous stories.
SERIALLY
IN THIS PAPER
W IT T E N B E R G 'S N E W H O TE L
H o t e l M o d e r n e
Joe I>trachow»ki, Proprietor
C O M P L E T E L Y N EW
T H R O U G H O U T
Meals Lodging
Refreshm ents
D O W N TO W N W IT T E N B E H f.
Shawano County
SEPT. F A I R 5-6-7
ENTRY DAY, SEITEM BER 5th
W L S N a t i o n a l B a r n D a n c e S h o w
Featuring LU LU BELLE and S K Y L A N D SCOTTY
I'K A IR IE S W E E T H E A R T S C E O R G IE (SO E IIE L H A Y L O F T F ID D L E R S
MISS P A U L IN E R A L P H A M ) H E L E N S T E R N A R I)
H u g e F a r m E x h i b i t s . R i d e s  A m u s e m e n t s
B a s e b a l l
W E D N E S D A Y . S E PT. fi— S H A W A N O vs. C R E H A M
T il.I.E D A v h . K R A K O W
T H U R S D A Y , K E PT. 7 —S E Y M O U R v s . C L IN T O N V IL L E
C H A M P IO N S H IP K IT T E N B A L L T O U R N A M E N T O F S H A W A N O C O U N T Y
R a c i n g
(2:24 TR O T
W E D N E S D A Y (2:15 PA C E
(2:11 T R O T
2:22 P A C E
T H U R S D A Y (2:1H T R O T
(2:0> P A C E
7 B i g V a u d e v i l l e A c t s o n t h e P l a t f o r m
I I A P P Y H A R R IS O N 'S C IRC U S S A S C A T R IO — SE N O R PE D RO
S T U A R T RO B ERTS T R IO F E N W IC K H COOK
T H E F A R M H A N D S— Wednesday Evening, September fi
W itte n b e rg C on cert B a n d S h a w a n o H . S. B a n d
D a n c i n g
T U E S D A Y N IT E , S E PT. 5— L A W R E N C E DIJCHOW A N D HIS R E D R A V E N S
W E D N E S D A Y , S E PT. fi— TH E F A R M H A N D S
T H U R S D A Y . S E PT. 7— HOB M A IjCOLM A N D H IS O R C H E S TR A
T h e G reat S h a w a n o C o u n ty F a ir Sept. 5, 6, 7
L O U IS W . C A T T A U . Secretary C H AS. P IE H L , President
TH E W ITTENBERG ENTERPRISE. W ITTENBERG. WIS.
Brighten Tea Towel
Set With Bluebirds
O U R C O M I C S E C T I O N
"L u c k y you—to be em b roidering
us on a set o f tea tow els! ”
say these cross stitch bluebirds.
W e’ re in sim plest stitchery and
colorfu l floss— so you 're sure o f a
grand result! Pattern 1983 contains
a transfer pattern of 7 m otifs
a vera g in g 5 by 7*4 inches; m aterials
required; illustrations o f
stitches; color schem es.
Send 15 cents in coins for this
pattern to The Sewing C ircle,
N ee d lcc ra ft Dept., 82 Eighth A ve.,
N ew Y ork, N. Y.
m
“Evarp kid'* Mom
■ honi d know
about DWIN*—
th* fragrant inMrf
killer — will not
taint foods or xpol
tinsst fabr.cs.
“Dwnr
Saeqertown. Ps>
Esteem ed Self
A m an must be ex cessively stupid,
as w e ll as uncharitable, who
believes there is no virtu e but on
his own side.— Addison.
FLORIDA
• Of Its Fresh Water and Deep
Sea Fishing
• Of the Bountifulness of Its Game
• Of Its Year Round Sports
• Its Climate
• Its Truck Farming Opportunities
A ll covered thoroughly in the
new and delightfully written book
//
M
S O T H I S I S
F L O R I D A
• y Frank Parker Stockbntfg* and
John H ollid ay Parry
Over 300 pages
63 full page illustrations
beautifully bound
S »n d $ 1 .0 0 to
Box 600, Jacksonville, Florida
W N U —S 35— 39 J t S T T H K T H IN G
BARGAINS
—-that w ill save you many a
d o lla r w ill escape vou if
you fail to read carefully and
regu larly the advertising o f
local merchants * » »
IN THIS PAPER
T om m y Fish— I ’ m hungry, M a!
Ma Kish—A ll right M l lix you
Some bread and je lly fish.
F oolin g Bossy
A N ebraska fa rm er was troubled
with his cow s craw lin g through an
ordin ary barbed w ire fence, so he
put up a single strand and charged
it with ele ctricity.
T h e cows cam e In contact with
the w ire severa l tim es, then refused
even to go near the fence.
‘ ‘ I turned off the juice, and the
cows h aven't found it out.” he says.
" I guess it w ill work until I get
another herd.”
D O ES N O T H IN G B I T P L A Y
A ®
T-toyd
A D V E N T U R E R S ’ C L U B
H E A D L I N E S P R O M T H E L I V E S
O F P E O P L E L I K E Y O U R S E L F I
----— ■ ■■ ' ......... —
“ Tteo Kinds o f Death”
He l l o e v e r y b o d y . -
This is the story o f a man who had a choice to m ake—
— a choice betw een two kinds o f death.
One of those deaths was certain— and unpleasant. I f he chose
the other, he’ d at least have a chance.
But he chose the death that was unpleasant—and certain!
Anthony A . H ensler is his nam e, and he lives in N ew Y ork
City. Tony is an aviator, and one day in the latter part o f July,
1927, he had a call from Andy Andrews, who was then senior
pilot at Curtis field out in M ineola.
Andy wanted to g et hold of somebody who could take a
blim p up in the a ir and put it through test flights. There
w ere few m en availab le in the East, at that time, who knew
enough to test fly a blimp, and Tony Hensler was one of
them. A ndy asked him if he would do the job.
Tony said It was all right with him, and Andy took him
to m eet a fellow nam ed H am za who owned the blimp. The arrangem
ents w ere m ade and Tony went to w ork. He did a little
tinkering with the m achinery and finally had the big gas bag
whipped into shape for a first hop.
Th e departm en t o f com m erce lays down certain rules by which va*
rious types o f a irc ra ft are tested, and the rule in regard to blim ps was
that the first hop had to be a fixed flight. That m eans that the blim p is
sent aloft with a line attached to the ground, so that if anything goes
w rong it can't get aw ay, float over the city and kill somebody or dam age
property in com ing down,
Tony D ecides on a Second Fixed Flight.
Tony m ad e that fixed flight. H e adjusted the controls and centered
fhe stabilization. But just to m ake sure everyth ing w as in good shape
he decided to m ake a second fixed flight a few days la ter w hile he
checked those controls o ver again. And three days later, on the third of
August, he did m ake that fixed flight. And it nearly fixed Tony fo r good.
Tony clim bed into the blim p all set for what he thought was
going to be just another routine test in a captive balloon firm ly
anchored to the ground by a land line. But the trouble w asn't long
in starting. N o sooner w as the blim p in the a ir than the land line
snapped and the big gas bag started shooting upward.
“ She went up to 6.000 feet before I got the m otor started,” Tony
says, "bu t the m otor, a two-cylinder, high-speed m otorcycle engine, finally
began to turn over, and for a w hile everyth ing went swell. But not for
long. I was just o ver Manhattan, with m y spirits as high as m y ship,
New F a ll Patterns
A re So Flattering
A T I N Y basque w aistline, rem -
* * iniscent o f the 1890s, flirta tious
little bows down the fron t
and a w —e, circu la r skirt, put N o.
1800 in the fo re fron t o f fa ll fashions,
and flatter you ou trageously!
Be am ong the first to w ea r this
enchanting frock, in fa ille, flat
crep e or thin w ool. *
D esigned to Slenderixe.
Suave, sophisticated lines, shirring
and gathers to g ive an uplifted
bustline, a slim paneled skirt
and sm all w aist, m ake this dress
Th ey w ere creating a wind of their own that was slowly turning the
blim p ’s nose around.
when things began to happen. And what I mean, everyth in g happened
at once. M y controls began to go sour. The big bag began to hog badly.
And to m ake m atters w orse, a la rge hole appeared in the nose o f the
ship.
“ I shut off the m otor for fe a r o f an explosion. I had carried 15,000
cubic feet o f hydrogen when I left the airport, and if a m otor spark ev e r
got into any o f that leaking gas it would blow m e and the blim p to bits.”
The ship was losing altitude fast. Th e city seem ed a long w ay
down, but it w as getting closer with alarm ing speed. And then
Tony took a desperate chance—did the only thing he could
to save h im self and avoid crashing on a tall building or in a
crowded N ew Y ork street. He clim bed out on the narrow catwalk
and pulled on the forem ost suspension cords, doubling the
cloth o v er the hole in the bag’ s nose to prevent any m ore hydrogen
leaking out o f the balloon.
The B lim p W allow ed H elplessly in M id-air.
" A f t e r securing those ropes,” he says, " I felt a little better, for I
then knew that the ship wouldn’ t crash in the crow ded city. But I still
didn’ t dare start the m otor, and the blim p was w allow ing helplessly in
m id air. And what was w orse still, the wind was carryin g m e out to sea.”
And right there was w here Tony had to make his choice—his choice
between two kinds of death. Th ere w as a slim chance that he m ight
bring that big bag down sa fely in crowded N ew York. On the other side
of the picture w as the prospect o f blowing fa r out to sea and drowning
in the Atlantic. D row ning w asn’t a pleasant thought. It would be much
better to try and m ake a landing in N ew Y o rk—fo r Tony. But what
about those other people down there—those scurrying humans that looked
like ants as they craw led along the crow ded streets? I f Tony landed
among them there was a pretty good chance that a lot of them would
be killed.
So T o n y m a d e his c h o ic e, and he ch ose the su re, u n p leasan t
dea th ra th e r than ta k in g a fig h tin g ch a n ce and p erh a p s k illin g
som eo n e els e , l i e sat still and did n oth in g w h ile th e w in d c a rr ie d
h im out to s e a !
Tony Kccognizes a W om an Pilot.
Out across N ew Y ork harbor he floated— out toward Sandy Hook
and the ocean— and his doom ! And then, from o ver toward the Jersey
shore Tony saw two planes com ing in his direction: A s they neared him,
he recognized one. It w as the plane o f Thea Rasch the famous G erm an
woman pilot.
The tw o planes cam e closer and closer. They couldn't take
Tony off that blim p in m id-air. In fact, it didn’ t look as though
there was much they could do but stand by, or return to the a irport
from which they had com e, and send help. But Tony wasn’ t
counting on the ingenuity of Thea Rasch. She headed straight for
the blim p until Tony thought she was going to crash into it— until
he could feel the wind of the plane as it dived under him. The
other plane follow ed suit. Th ey w ere creating a wind of their own
that was slow ly turning the blim p's nose around—pointing it
back to land.
About that tim e, too, the wind that w as blowing him out to sea
shifted to another quarter. Aided by that, and by the two planes, Tony
finally landed at C ollege Point, L. I., and there he was m et by a crowd
that would pack the Y an kee stadium, including the C ollege Point police
reserves.
"N o p e , I w asn’ t locked up,” says Tony. "B u t if it hadn't been for
the backwash of those two planes I ’d have blown out to sea and never
found again.”
(R e le a s e d by W e s te rn N e w s p a p e r U n ion .)
(1716) as slenderizing as ft is
sm art. M ake it o f rayon jers ey ,
flat crepe, silk sheers or thin
wool, and w ea r it not only for runabout
but for in form a l afternoons
as w ell.
The Pattern s.
No. 1800 is designed for sizes 12,
14, 16, 18 and 20. Size 14 requires
43s y a rd s o f 39 inch m ateria l w ith
short sle ev es; 5 yard s with long
sleeves. 2% y a rd s ribbon fo r
bows.
No. 1716 is designed for sizes 36,
38, 40, 42, 44, 46, 48, 50 and 52.
Size 38 requires 5 yard s of 39 inch
m a teria l with short sleeves; 5Vi
yard s with long s le ev es; % yard s
o f trim m ing.
Send your order to The Sew ing
C ircle Pa ttern D ept., Room 1324,
211 W. W ack er Dr., Chicago, 111.
P ric e o f patterns, 15 cents (in
coins) each.
« B e ll S y n d ic a te— W N U S e r v ic e .!
GIRLS! 8E TOUR OWN BOSS.
EARN GOOD INCOME
IN THIS FASCINATING.
GLAMOROUS PROFESSION
F ree yourselffrom du llundram atic jobs. Beauty
c u ltu re , s c ie n t if ic a lly ta u g h t b y H a r p e r
Method, is a pleasant, profitable career Free
nation wide em ploym ent service. .'•00 H arper
M ethod Shops. Financial help to graduates
starting shops. Ix>w tuition and living expense.
W r ite tor F R E E catalog.
T0EBE ACADEMY *,0•'
HARPER METHOD TRAINING CENTER
N O W W R E C K I N G
D u p o n t P la n t
C A R R O L L V I L L E . W I S .
5.000.000 Brick
1.000.000 ft. Lumber
P ip e , I-b e a m s . h o t w a t e r ra d ia to rs ,
sash, d o o rs , p lu m b in g , p a rtitio n s , s te e l
sash, v a lv e s , m o to rs , s w itc h e s , e le v
a to r s . fir e d o o rs , ta n k s, m a c h in e ry ,
v a u lt d o o rs , lin o le u m an d hu nd red s >if
o th e r ite m s a t m o n e y -s a v in g p ric e s
S a l e s m e n o n P r e m i s e s
NATIONAL LUMBER  WRECKING CO.
C a r r o llv ille . W is .
In L O S A N G E L E S
"W h at a trifler that musician is !”
Y es, he does nothing but p la y .’ 1
Earth’s Motion Interferes
I f you m ake a deep hole in the
earth you can’ t drop anything to the
bottom, because the earth m oves on
and the side o f the hole stops the
fallin g object. This has been proved
by experim ents in the deep shafts
of the A m erican copper mines. Tools
dropped from the mouth o f a shaft
w ere not found at the bottom but
wedged against the side of the shaft,
and this led the Michigan college of
mines to m ake experim ents. The
W ith the I.aw of Gravity
object being to discover how fa r the
earth's motion interfered with the
usual effect of the laws of gravity.
The tests em ployed included suspending
m arbles by threads just below
the mouth of the shaft, the
threads w ere then burnt by the
flam e of a candle and the m arbles
allowed to fall. Investigations
showed that after dropping some SOO
(eet the m arbles in all cases cam e
to rest on the cast w all of the mine
It ’s
H O T E L
C L A R K
N earest d ow n tow n hotel
t o H O L L Y W O O D
\ 1 T 1 T H the m ovie capital o f the world
Y and western Am erica * radio city
within th e b o r d e r s o f L o s A n g e le s ,
entertainm ent reaches its renith. G ay
nights, laughter and life ; sunny days
filled w ith thrills and excitem ent. In
the center o f e v e r y th in * is situated
th e H O T E L C L A R K at F i f t h and
H ill Streets. A hotel where you w ill enjo
y hospitality to its fullest e x te n t; where
you w ill find your e v e r y wish anticipated.
W h ether you stay in L os Angeles for a
few days or a m onth, ehoose H otel Clark,
dow ntow n in the heart o f things.
555 Rooms Witk Baths tn>,m$U»
Personal M anagem en t
o f P. G . B M orris*
THE WTTTENBERG ENTERPRISE. WITTENBERG. WIS
M A N Y V A R IE T IE S O F CO O KIES
(S ee R ecipes B elow )
Household News
cH /^ O cm orr
Jiws
Disobedience
Often Sign of
Forgetfulness
• I M P U L S I V E A C T S O F
c h i l d a r e m a d e w i t h o u t
t h o u g h t e i t h e r o f b e i n g o b e d i e
n t o r d i s o b e d i e n t . H e l p i n
r e m e m b e r i n g o f t e n m u c h
m o r e n e c e s s a r y t h a n a n y
f o r m o f p u n i s h m e n t .
i
Wisconsin News
« Briefly Told
is a s a a s a o u
C ookies in the C upboard
What cookies do folks like best to
eat?
A cookie that’s rich, and spicy and
sweet?
A soft, thick cookie with fru ity flavor,
O r the thin, crisp w a fer the tea
drinkers savor?
A chncolate cookie that’s m oist and
^ i c h ,
O r a tasty tidbit with nutmeats,
which
M a y be flavored with honey, m olasses
or spice?
A ny kind o f a cookie is pretty nice!
T h ere are as m any varieties of
cookies as there are occasions for
s e r v i n g them.
And what satisfying
morsels they
are for the school
lunch box, for
afternoon tea, or
fo r a fam ily m eal
at home. Y ou ’ ll
find among the
tested cookie recipes below one for
any such occasion ranging from
dainty tea cookies to thick, soft, m olasses
cookies for an after-school or
bedtim e snack. T h ey ’re all grand
recipes for the G irl Scout cookie sale
you m ay be planning, or fo r the
next m eeting o f the church guild.
Soft Molasses Cookies.
(M akes about 7 dozen cookies.)
1 cup shortening
1 cup sugar
2 eggs
1 cup N ew Orleans molasses
2 teaspoons soda
1 cup butterm ilk
6 cups flour
1 teaspoon baking powder
1 teaspoon cinnamon
1 teaspoon gin ger
C ream shortening, and add sugar
gradually. B eat in the eggs and
m olasses. D issolve the soda in the
butterm ilk. Sift flour, baking powd
er and spices together and add to
the first m ixture alternately with
the butterm ilk. Drop from teaspoon
onto a greased baking sheet. Dip
the bottom of a tum bler in cold w ater,
and press down gently on each
cookie. Sprinkle with sugar. Bake
in a hot oven (425 degrees) for about
8 minutes.
Even on Sunday evenings hungry
fam ilies demand good food.
I t ’s sim ple enough to provide a
m eal that is tem ptingly different
with suggestions such as those
E leanor How e w ill g ive you in
her column next week. Be sure
to look for her article “ Sunday
N ight Suppers” !
Butterscotch Brownies.
(M akes 2 dozen sm all cookies.)
4 tablespoons butter
1 cup brown sugar
1 eg g (sligh tly beaten)
*/a cup flour
1 teaspoon baking powder
Vz teaspoon vanilla
Va cup nut m eats (cut fine)
M elt the butter in a sm all saucepan.
Add sugar
j . slow ly, and cook
f or 2 minutes.
R e m o v e from
flame, and add
rem aining ingredients.
M ix w ell.
Pour into shallow
greased pan and
bake in a slow
oven (300 degrees Fah renheit) for
about 18 minutes. Cut in squares.
Chocolate Applesauce Cookies.
(M a kes 3 dozen cookies.)
Vz cup shortening
1 cup sugar
2 V a cups flour
1 teaspoon soda
Vz teaspoon salt
2 teaspoons cinnamon
Vz teaspoon cloves
Vz teaspoon ginger
4 teaspoons cocoa
m cups applesauce (unsweetened)
Cream shortening, add sugar and
beat w ell. Sift together the flour,
soda, salt, spices, and cocoa and
add altern ately with the applesauce.
B eat thoroughly. Drop by teaspoonfuls
on greased cookie sheet and
bake in a m oderate oven (350 degrees
Fahrenheit) fo r approxim ately
15 minutes.
Orange Ice Box Cookies.
(M a kes 5 dozen cookies.)
1 cup shortening
Vz cup brown sugar
Vz cup white sugar
1 egg
2 tablespoons orange juice
1 tablespoon orange rind (g ra ted )
2% cups general purpose flour
Va teaspoon salt
Va teaspoon soda
Vz cup pecan nut m eats (broken)
C ream shortening and add sugars
slow ly, while beating constantly.
Add eg g (w e ll beaten ), orange juice
and orange rind. M ix and sift flour,
salt, and soda together and add to
the cream ed m ixture, together with
the broken nut m eats. F orm in
rolls in w ax paper and chill o vernight
in refrig era tor. Slice thin,
place on greased baking sheet and
bake in m oderately hot oven (375
d e g re es ) 12-15 minutes.
G randm other’ s Sugar Cookies.
(M akes 5 dozen cookies.)
Mi cup shortening
1 cup sugar
1 egg, and 1 eg g yolk
^ cup sour cream
Mi teaspoon vanilla extract
Vz teaspoon lemon extract
3 cups flour#
1 teaspoon baking powder
Vz teaspoon salt
Vz teaspoon soda
1 teaspoon nutmeg
Cream shortening, and add sugar
gradually. Add the egg and beat
until fluffy. Combine sour cream
with flavoring extracts, and add to
the cream ed m ixture alternately
w'ith the sifted dry ingredients. Chill
for about Vz hour. R oll out and cut.
P la ce on greased cookie sheet.
Brush tops o f cookies with unbeaten
eg g white and sprinkle generously
with sugar. Bake in a m oderately
hot oven (425 d eg rees) for about 9
minutes.
Pineapple Cream Tarts.
P A R T I —T a rt Cases.
Mi cup butter
Vz cup granulated sugar
1 eg g yolk (beaten )
1 teaspoon lem on extract
l 3/4 cups cake flour
Cream butter thoroughly and add
sugar slowly w hile beating constantly.
Add the
beaten egg yolk
and lemon e x tract.
Then add
the flour. D ivide
dough into 12
even pieces. Then
lay one piece at
a tim e in the left
palm ; press with the right hand until
dough is la rg e enough to fit a
muffin tin. Then fit each piece into
the muffin tin and prick w ell with a
fork. Bake approxim ately 20 minutes
in a hot oven. F ill with Pineapple
Filling.
P A R T I I — Pin eapple Cream F il^
ing.
3 tablespoons cornstarch
3 tablespoons sugar
Va teaspoon salt
1 whole eg g (w e ll beaten)
lVz cups m ilk (scalded)
1 teaspoon lemon extract
1 No. 2 can shredded pineapple
1 cup whipping cream (w hipped)
M ix cornstarch, sugar and salt.
Add the egg (w ell beaten) and m ix
thoroughly. Pou r on the m ilk (scalded
). Return to a double boiler and
cook until thick. R em ove from
flam e, add lemon extract, and a llow
to corfl. F ill tart shells and
just before servin g place one spoonful
of crushed pineapple (drained)
on top of the cream filling.
By G E O R G IA L O T T S E L T E R
« A H , W H Y need children be quite
so heedless and disobedient?"
sighed M ary Lance w earily.
“ I w onder if they rea lly are,” answ
ered her neighbor, Mrs. Jaynes,
com fortably. ‘ ‘They behave as they
do because they are children. They
usually act on impulse, without any
thought either of being obedient or
disobedient. You must expect such
conduct until they begin to acquire
the knowledge \hat experience
brings.
‘ ‘I am convinced that children
need real help in rem em bering
much m ore frequently than they
need punishment. This belief is
based partly on m y own never-to-beforgotten
childish experience with a
detested red apron. My aunt, with
whom I lived, m ade me a big red
apron from one of her old house
dresses and said: ‘Lucy, you are to : rangements for the event
A u to Junk Yards Out— Gov. Heil
figned a bill designed to beautify
Wisconsin landscape by regulating
outdoor storage of junked automobiles.
Fish Die in Lake Winnebago— Fish
w ere dying by the thousands as a
heavy scum of algae formed over
the F ox river, the government canal
and- the north end of Lake Winnebago.
Board to Inspect Coal Mines— The
Kenosha county board, which is purchasing
10,000 tons of coal for relie
f clients this winter, w ill go to
southern Illinois to inspect coal
mines there.
Knights o f Pythias Pick M ilw aukeean—
Th e annual conclave of ttfe
Knights o f Pythias at Fond du Lac
named Laurence H. G revc as grand
chancellor and chose Appleton as the
1940 convention site.
A grees on Car License B ill— The
senate concurred in the Schlabach
bill to set up a new system o f autom
obile registration under which licenses
would be issued by county
clerks instead of the state.
Farmers to Discuss M ilk Prices—
D airy farm ers have been invited by
the Wisconsin milk pool to attend a
state-wide meeting at Battle Creek,
Wis., Aug. 27, to discuss m ilk prices.
Ray C. Retzlaft is in charge of ar-
‘Swing Style” Reading Not New;
The Greeks Had a Word for It
E v e ry now and then, the news-1
papers report a “ brand new ” id e a j
or a “ brand new” discovery.
Take, for instance, the report
about “ swing reading.” A cco rd ing
to recent headlines, “ swing
reading” is the latest thing im aginable—
the invention of two sm art
eye doctors in Los Angeles.
A s the papers say, the doctors
disclosed their “ idea” a short tim e
ago at a national convention o f the
A m erican Optom etric association.
A dvocating a new system o f printing
in “ swing style,” the doctors
said they had something that
would help the eyes. In short,
they urged this type of thing:
Many of the convention delegate$
a rof snoisse* dennuhx yadretsey
day on the golf course. The ueath-
.enif saw re
This little excerpt must be read
by swinging the eyes left to right
along one line, then right to left
along the next, and so on.
W ell, we don’t like to make ourselves
seem scholarly, but the doctors
have unwittingly dug up
something pretty old. As a m atter
o f fact, the ancient G reeks
had a word for it, used the system
and gave it up. Th ey called it
boustrophedon, and you can find
the w’ord in a good dictionary even
to this day. Pronounced boo-strofee-
don, with the accent on the
third syllable, it means literally
“ turning like oxen in plow ing.”
It is a compound o f two Greek
w ords— bous, m eaning ox, and
strephein, m eaning to turn.
P. S. Incidentally, the excerpt
quoted above reads norm ally this
w a y : “ Many of the convention
delegates yesterday shunned sessions
for a day on the golf course.
Th e w eather w as fine.”
Anybody else got a new idea?—
Pathfinder.
F i n a l l y A u m p H a s O . K .
T l w u t i h !\>t b u t ' K ’
A gentlem an had completed his
purchases, and the clerk, in filling
out the sales slip, asked:
“ What is the name, please?”
“ Jepson,” replied our hero. “ Sixteen
twenty-one West— ”
“ Your first initial, please.”
“ Oh, K .”
“ O. K. Jepson.”
“ 1 said ‘Oh.’ ”
“ O. Jepson.”
“ No. Rub out the O .”
The clerk began to look hag-
“ Your initials again, please?’*
“ I said K .’ **
“ Pardon, you said ‘O. K.* ”
“ I said ‘Oh’ —”
“ Just now you said ‘ K .’ "
“ 1 said ‘Oh,’ because I didn't
understand what you w ere asking
me. I didn’ t mean it was my initial.
M y name is K irb y Jepson."
“ Oh.”
“ No. Not O, but K. Here, g ive
m e the pencil and I ’ ll w rite it m yself.
Th ere, I guess it’s O. 1C
now.” —Annapolis Log.
put this apron on o ver your school
dress each morning until your work
is done.’ I had no objection to that,
but several times each w eek I
rushed heedlessly away to school,
flaunting the apron’s faded ugliness
for all to see. M y aunt always sent
a m essage by an older girl who
w as our neighbor, rem inding m e to
rem ove the apron. And no reproof
w as e v e r considered com plete until
these episodes of the red apron
w ere held up to m e as evidence of
m y disobedience!
“ I ’v e never forgotten the unhappiness
and em barrassm ent they incurred.
Y e t how easily m y aunt
m ight have prevented them. She
could have said, ‘ A lw ays com e to
m e before you start to school to be
sure you look nice.’ Or, ‘A lw ays kiss
m e good-by, Lu cy.’ M y love-hungry
little heart would never have allow
ed m e to forget to do that, you
m ay be sure! And there would have
been no hurting apron episode.”
“ But H enry’s case is different,”
said Mrs. Lance. “ He is a boy and
should learn to take responsibility.
Y e t he never rem em bers his chores
or his errands.”
“ A ppreciation Lightens L a b or.”
“ H e just needs the help of a little
rem in d er,” insisted Mrs. Jaynes.
“ Suppose you mention it casually
before his father each tim e he does
his work w ell and without being reminded?
Even w e older folks find
that appreciation lightens labor.
“ T r y to m ake work pleasant. N e v er
use it as a punishment.
“ L e t work lead naturally to suitable
rewards. I f Henry helps you
with the dishes and tidies the house,
it would be quite evident that you
would have m ore time. Perhaps
you could both go to the m ovies or
for a ride. When he has learned
to prepare food he can have picnics
and parties. I f he keeps his room in
order, let him know how restful you
find it when you go in to spend a
fe w moments with him. I f he takes
good care of his clothes, brushing
them and hanging them up neatly,
he would be happy indeed if Mother
should buy for F ather and him two
articles just alike.
“ I f Henry is apt to forget his duties,
do not credit it to disobedience
but study how you m ay m ake
it interesting and profitable for him
to rem em ber. Children dread to
w'ork alone, so m ake his duties, so
fa r as you reasonably can, som ething
that you can share. Do not
expect results beyond the ability of
his years. Pra ise him when he does
w ell. R ew ard him in a natural and
sensible way. H elp him rem em b er
for he honestly needs your help.
“ And presently you w ill have the
satisfaction of seeing that he has ac-
Ban on Working W ife — Married
women, w ith the exception o f teachers
protected by the tenure law, no
longer can hold a city job in Green
Bay. The council passed a resolution
which provides that any women em ploye
o f the city who marries w ill
be discharged within 30 days.
Wisconsin Invaded by Crickets —
Southern Wisconsin has been invaded
by house crickets and are causing
housewives and merchants no end of
trouble. Th e crickets, apparently
hatched from eggs during the recent
hot spell, have heen swarming by
thousands at night w herever there
are bright lights.
Arsonist in Marathon County—
Farmers engaged in harvest w ere
alarmed by the activities of an unidentified
arsonist operating in the
town o f Wausau. F ive fires broke
out in a threshing machine operated
on the farms of Philip G rzyw acz a n i
Joseph N ovak Although no damage
was done the fires w ere unexplained.
State A ge Pension A pension of
$40 a month for all Wisconsin residents
o ver 60 was asked by the
Home Owners and Tax Payers’ C ivic
lub in a petition to the legislature.
Collections on t'pgrade The public
service commission said its collections
o f utility securities fees and
motor carrier fees for the fiscal year
mded July 1 w ere $171,360 higher
han the previous year.
Deaths Low er in June— The state
x>ard o f health reported that deaths
.n June totaled 2.287, 78 less than the
six-year average. Only heart disease
and cancer showed increases. The
board cited substantial reductions for
ihe month in deaths of infants,
leaths from puerperal causes, from
accidents, pneumonia, nerhritis and
uberculosis.
State Helps Farm Co-ops -Eleven
jo-operatives have been organized
ind five dairy corporations have
jeen converted into co-operatives in
the last six months, W. L. Witte,
marketing division chief of the state
department o f agriculture, reported.
The co-operative movement is sup-
•x>rted by the department because of
arms groups’ requests.
Doctors to Meet Soon Doctors of
he state w ill converge in M ilw aukee
Sept 13 to 15 for the annual
meeting of the State Medical Society
of Wisconsin. Tho society w ill
be commemorating its ninety-eighth
anniversary. General and group
meetings w ill be held in the auditorium,
which also w ill be the place
af 37 technical and 30 scientific e x hibits.
Medical Plan Offered -A trial plan
or the prepayment of medical care
A'ill be placed into immediate opera-
Send for Copy of 'B etter Baking/
O f course you’d like to be able to
m ake a feath ery angel food cake,
lemon pie that m elts in your mouth,
and crusty delicious rolls. You can
m ake all these and many m ore
tem pting dishes with Eleanor
H ow e’ s cookbook, “ B etter Baking,”
to guide you. Send 10 cents in coin
to “ Better B aking,” care of Eleanor
Howe, 919 North Michigan Avenue.
Chicago, Illinois, fo r your copy of
this valuable book.
(R e le a s e d by W e s te rn N ew sp a p e r U n ion.)
Ben Jonson Burial
Tradition says that Ben Jonson
w as buried in a sitting position because
the plot provided (or him on
the north side o f the nave in W estm
inster abbey was not la rge
enough (or the body to be placed
in the grave in a horizontal position.
According to a legend. King
Charles I personally promised Jonson
that he should be interred in the
abbey in any spot that he m ight
choose. A fter his death August 6.
1637, it w as found that the space he
had selected for burial was already
occupied except about “ eighteen
inches of square ground." Charles
kept his prom ise and Jonson was
buried with his head toward the sky,
the only occupant of the abbey to
be so honored. Thc famous inscription,
“ O R a re Ben Jonson," was
cut in the slab over his grave. Many
yea rs later a portrait bust to his
m em ory was placed in the P o et’s
corner.
quired the habit of reliability and i Iltin by the Rock county Medical Soaccepts
work as a pleasant and ! iety Subscriber* w ill make regunecessary
part of norm al liv in g ." )ar Monthly payments to the medical
iociety for which they w ill receive
medical and surgical care from their
fam ily physician. The premiums
would be $36 a year per fam ily regardless
o f size.
Former Kland G irl K illed A fo r mer
Wisconsin girl, now of Chicago,
was one of those killed in the wreck
of the str ?m liner C ity of San Francisco
near Carlin, Nev. Six other
Wisconsin residents, two o f them
from Milwaukee, suffered minor injuries.
The fa tality was M yrtle K o hasky,
24, a stenographer for the
Illinois Bell Telephone Co., in Chicago.
She was a daughtei o f Mr.
and Mrs. E. B. Kohasky of EL’ nd,
in Shawano county.
Grain, Hay Crop* Are Down
Crop prospects have declined son.ewhat
during the last month. Grain
and hay production w ill be generally
low er than a year ago. The latest
estimates for Wisconsin are: corn
crop 81.252,000 bushels, about 10 per
cent low er; oats estimated at 71,*
488.000 bushels, 6 per cent less than
a year ago; the barley crop at 21.-
835.000 bushels, 10 per cent under
last year. H ay crops in the state,
w hile above the average, are under
a year ago Th e total tome hay production
in the state is estimated 8t
5.685.000 tons, about 12 per cent under
the big crop of last year.
Many V iolate I.aw
It is against the law in the United
States and Canada to open a pock
of cigarettes from the bottom ; hundreds
of thousands daily break the
federal ciga rette law by failin g to
destroy the tax stamp on every
pack of cigarettes consumed.
F i r e s t o n e s t a n d a r d
SIZE Price For
Tkt 1*1 Tire
Not Tire
50A Ditcown!
Pik. Fof
t II...
YOU
SAVE
4.40 21 (
4.50 21 S $7.20 $3.40 $10.80 $3.40
4.75 19 f
5.00 19 ( 7.45 3.73 11. l t 3.72
4.50 20 (
5.00 20 ( 7.40 3.10 11.40 3.80 |
5.25-171
5.50-17( 9.50 4.75 14.25 4.75 j
5.25 18 1
5.50 18 (
6 00 16
l i S
10.35 '
4.33
5.11
12.98
15.53
4.32 I I
5.17 K
Above Prices include Ymt OK lire Ottier Slut Prtportlonililr ltt. |]
A $ 0 % D IS C O U N T A I S O A P P I I I S T O T H I P U R C H A S I
O F T H I I n d T I a C O N T H I I 0 U 0 W I N 6 :
T i n t t o n e C H A M P I O N
J SIZE
f ®P*r tTc.k *
Tin
N.it
TV.
Dl«co."t
Price
For
t Tire*
ro u
SAVE SIZE
Me.
F o. Th.
I* Tin
Neat
Tire 50%
Discount
Price
For
1 l i f t
YOU
SAVE
5.50-16
5 25 17{
5.50 17 {
5.25 18 1
5.50 18 (
6.0016
6.0017
$14.15
14.45
13.35
15.95
14.50
$7.08
7.33
4.48
7.98
8.25
$21.23
21.98
20.03
23.93
24.75
$7.07
7.32
4.47
7.97
8.25
6.00 18
6.25-16
6.50-16
7.00-15
7.00-16
7.50-16
$17.15
17.95
19.35
21.35
21.95
27.80
$8.58
8.98
9.48
10.48
10.98
13.90
$25.73
24.93
29.03
32.03
32.93
41.70
$8.57
8.97
9.47
10.47
10.97
13.90
A IO V E PRICES INCLUDE TOUR OLD TIRE — OTHER SIZES P R O P O R T IO N A T E L T LO W .
‘F i r e s t o n e h i g h s p e e d ri r e $ t o n e c  3 N V O > r
» ze
Price
For The
lit Tire
Ne«t
Tire 50%
Discount
Price
For
« Tire*
TOU
SAVE SIZE
Price
For Tho
1st Tire
N . . i
Tlr. 50%
Discount
Price
For
t Tire*
YOU
SAVE
4.75-191
5.00-19(
5.25 17
5.50 17 (
5.25 18 (
5.50 18»
6 00 16
6.25-16'
6.50 16(
$10.30
13.20
12.00
14.35
17.40
$5.15
4.40
4.00
7.1*
8.70
$15.45
19.80
18.00
21.53
24.10
$5.15
4.40
4.00
7.17
8.70
4.40 21 (
4.50-21 (
4.75-19/
5.00-19 \
5.25-17
5.50 17 (
5.25-18/
5.50 18 (
1.00-16
$8.35
8.40
11.00
10.00
11.95
$4.18
4.30
5.50
S.00
5.98
$12.53
12.90
14.50
15.00
17.93
$4.17
4.30
5.50
5.00
5.97
A IO V E PRICES INCLUDE TOUR OLD TIRE — OTHER SIZES P R O P O R T IO N A T E L T LO W .
F O R C R I A T H T SAFETY A N D E C O N O M Y PUT A N I W T U B i IH EVERY N I W T H E
LIFETIME GUARANTEE • NO TIME OR MILEAGE LIMIT
S E E Y O U R N E A R E S T F I R E S T O N E D E A L E R O R
F I R E S T O N E A U T O S U P P L Y A N D S E R V I C E S T O R E
See F irn tn n e T i m made in the F irrtto n e Factory and
J'jthi fat ion B u ild in g at N n o York W o rld ’* F a ir.
A l i o t i n t t h r FireB tone I r h ilu t a t th r (io ld r n
(t a u In tem a tu m a l l.tp n u tio n at Sun Fra ncitco.
L i m to the V o ice o f Firestone w ith Richard C rook *
M argarrt Speaks and the F irrtto n e Symphony
t h r h r ttr a . u n drr direction n f A lfrrd R ’ul/rn«nn,
Moniiuy rvem ri#* N ation w id e N . II. C . Ret I S etuxnk.
PAGE EIGHT THE WITTENBERG ENTERPRISE. WITTENBERG, WIS.
E L A N D
Mr. and Mrs. S. A. Smith o f Oakfield
were quests at the W. E. Schoepke
home a few days last week.
Mr. and Mrs. Felix Konkol and
jfuests, Mr. and Mrs. Richard Post and
children o f Chicago spent Sunday at
the Eau Claire Dells.
Mrs. Edith Wadhams o f Huron,
South Dakota, is visiting at the home
o f her daughter, Mrs. Howard Cronnoble.
Mrs. Raymond W arning spent a few
days at Milwaukee visiting her husband
who is emnloved there.
Miss Rosalie Bohlman left Wednesday
fo r Viroqua for an indefinite stay
at the home o f an aunt, Mrs. Bertha
Overjjard.
Mr. and Mrs. W. C. Pickerinsr and
the T. E. Kinney fam ily attended the
weddinjr o f Miss Meryl Pickering1 and
Frank Stone at Black Earth Saturday.
Mr. and Mrs. Joe Mosier o f Clintonville
and Mrs. Anne Pribbernow went
to W'ocdruff Sundav to see Mrs. A.
Engel who is with her daughter, Mrs.
Fred Piehl, who is quite ill.
Mr. and Mrs. M cKeiffer and fam ily
and daughter and fam ily o f Anpleton
and Mr. and Mrs. Joe Stoltz of Ringle
spent Sunday in the Otto Meyer home.
Mr. and Mrs. Chas. Westfahl and
fam ily were at A ntigo Saturday .
Mr. and Mrs Frank Murphy of In ternational
Falls. Minn., came to see
her father, Mr. Hulehan, and took him
to Wausau.
Mr. and Mrs. R. Schultz’s little «on
David was seriously ill Sunday. They
took him to Memorial h-ospital at
W’ ausau fo r treatment.
Mr. and Mrs. Matt Fox drove to
Marathon C ity Saturday to visit an
invalid sister.
Mrs. Ward Leach o f Elcho is visiting
at the Philip Guelle home this
week.
Alex Schrieber and his bride of M ilwaukee
w ere on their honeymoon trip
in the North to visit different lakes
and called on Eland friends Friday on
their way to Madison where they expected
to spend a few days with Mrs.
Schrieber’s parents.
Mrs. Bert B igford spent a few days
with her aunt at Antigo. returning on
Thursday.
Mrs. H. Cronnoble and children
were at A ntigo Wednesday.
Mrs. H arry Walters and her uncle.
Henry Feidler. o f Green Bay called,
on Eland friends Sunday.
Mrs. John Byrnes and children o fj
Janesville are visiting her parents,
Mr. and Mrs. Geo. Brunner.
Miss A lta Brown returned to her
home Thursday from Eagle River
where she spent the summer.
H. S. Franklin and children. Tom
and Sally o f Wauwatosa spent several
davs in the Franklin home last week.
Mr. and Mrs. Lyle Cannon o f A ntigo
v:*'ted friends in Eland Saturday
night.
Mr. and Mrs. Lagest were in Chicago
over the week-end.
Jimmy Baird o f Marshfield was in!
Eland Sunday and Monday.
Mr. and Mrs. W. P. Burke and Bob
drove to Green Bay on business Satur-1
day.Mr. and Mrs. Dale Van Doren left]
fo r Bismarck, North Dakota. Thursday
morning.
Mrs. Chas. Fox visited her daughter,
Mrs. Howard Kusserow, at Green Bay
last week.
children spent Sunday at Marathon
Park in Wausau.
The Morris choir held their weekly
practice at the Earl Cowles home last
Friday evening. Gordon Cowles was
presented with a “ going-aw ay” g ift.
The school interior has been greatly
improved by the installation o f Masonite
over the plastered areas and the
repainting o f all woodwork a light
color.
Orlen Cowles and the Edwin Cowles
fam ily visited the Luther M oore’s near
Galloway.
The number o f pupils enrolled in
school this year is 28. Gordon Glick
and Marjorie Roper are back again.
The follow ing pupils attended Wayside
last year: Peter, Carol and Roger
Kaufman, Leonard Kutchenriter and
Patricia are the two new first graders.
Mrs. Earl Cowles, Eileen Jorgensen,
Mary B riggs. Phyllis and Carolyn
Dumdie visited in Rosholt on Sunday
afternoon.
FAST REID SCHOOL
Hubert Ostrowski left fo r W'illard
Washington, where he will be employed.
Bernice Oatrowski returned to her
homo in the Town o f Elderon after
spending two weeks at the Paul Esker
home.
On Sunday, September 3, St. Florian’s
church o f Hatley will have
chicken dinner. Bingo will be played
in the afternoon.
Mr. and Mrs. Stanley Jachowicz o f
Milwaukee have been visiting at the
home o f Mrs. Kate Jachowicz.
Mr. and Mrs. Leo K in g called on
Mr. and Mrs. Leo Zoromski o f thi
Town o f Ringle Sunday evening.
Miss Jean Jachowicz returned to
Milwaukee Monday.
Mr. and Mrs. John Adamski of
Stevens Point, Mf. and Mrs. Ernest
Platta of Hatley, Mr. and Mrs. Am brose
Sinski of the Town of Elderon
and Mr. and Mrs. I^awrence Day spent
Sunday afternoon at the home o f Mr.
and Mrs. Leo King.
Mrs. Kate Jachowicz returned home
Inst week a fter an extended visit in
Milwaukee with relatives.
Mary Ann Ostrowski and Junior Ostrowski
o f the Town o f Elderon left
for their homes afN?r visiting at the
G. J. Buss and A. F. Morien homes.*
Mr. and Mrs. William Berna and
Mr. and Mrs. A lfred Bema and daughter
Barbara and son Richard o f W'ausau
were caller* o f Mrs. Augusta
Marks Sunday afternoon.
Visitors at the home o f Mrs. Frank
Letarski Sunday were Mr. and Mr
Joe Sowinski and son Chester, Mr. and
Mrs. Alvin Sowinski. Mr. and Mrs. Joe
Barnish and daughter, Mr. and Mrs.
Henry Fischer and sons and Missr*
Leona Letarski and Irene Wendler o f
Wausau.
Th** East Reid School commenced
last Monday with an enrollment of 22
pupils.
Friday afternoon the East Reid
English Club held an election of
officers. President is Bernard Ostrowski.
vice president is Esther Jachowicz.
and the secretary is Angeline Trzebiatowski.
L ittle Marilyn Breske has been absent
a week because o f illness.
The first and second grades enioyed
dramatizing the story o f the Three
Bears. A Mother Goose booklet is
beincr made in the study o f nursery
stories.
This year the prim ary grades have
a reading table and chairs.
Some now interesting books h**ve
been purchased fo r the school this
year and are being enjoyed.
NORRIE
Mrs. Cora Lee and son Robert o f
Aniwa called at the home of Mrs. Minnie
Bucknam Monday evening.
Frank Suick and Mrs. L. Stengle
visited at the Mrs. O. H. Paulson
home last week.
Gilbert Bulson and fam ily o f Eagle
River visited Mrs. M. Bucknam last
week.
Congregational Sunday school picnic
was held last Fridav afternoon at
the home o f Mrs. M. Bucknam. A
large crowd attended.
Mr. and Mrs. Joe Hoffman of Milwaukee
are spending the week-end at
the Androw Christenson home. Mr.
Christenson, who was visiting at Milwaukee
the past week, returned home
Thursday.
Mrs. Gust Spitzer spent W'ednesday
at W’ ausau.
Mrs. Charles Paulson and Mrs.
Gambleyard of Minneapolis visited at
the O. H. Paulson home the past week.
Mrs. R. Jashman visited her
daughter. Mrs. Ritchie, at Milwaukee
the past week.
Rubert Gowell visited friends at
W’ ittenberg Tuesday.
Miss Ruth Spitzer visited at T ig e rton
Sunday.
Mr. and Mrs. C. B. Hall o f Davison,
Michigan, spent several days at the
R. E. Bruce home this week.
WHITCOMB
School reopened Monday with Mrs.
Evelyn Berirlund again the teacher.
We again bid her welcome.
Mrs. Jackson McConley and Mrs.
Melvin Rice are on the sick list. Mrs.
Rice has been staying with her daughter.
Mrs. Charles Krolow, at Tigerton.
Miss Edeline Liesch returned home
Sunday from Menasha where she has
been visiting relatives fo r some time.
Mr. and Mrs. Mason Buck went to
Madison last Tuesday.
Mr. and Mrs. Fred Blaese and Marjorie
K riegel were Sunday visitors at
tho Eric K riegel home in Germania.
Mr. and Mrs. Jesse Low and son
Robert were visitors in the Paul Bublitz
home Tuesday evening.
FOREST VIEW
Juanita Vandenberg spent the weekend
at Caroline.
Mr. and Mrs. Roland Hangarten and!
sons, Ronald and Jerry, o f W'aukon.
Iowa, spent Friday afternoon at the
Cleve Guerin home.
Orlen Cowles is visiting at the
Edwin Cowles home.
Mrs. Evelyn Hermanson and Mrs.
C. O. Lekve, o f BeLtrami, Minnesota,
are visitors in the Earl Cowles and
Edwin Cowles homes.
Mr. and Mrs. Stanley W’ estgor and
S
Bt SIN ESS D IR E C T O R Y OF
Wittenberg
[ B e n is a list " f tho business and
! professional places in Wittenberg.
| They are here to serve the people
| of Wittenberg and the sum unding
( territory in the very b» t manner
J possible. Give them a try!
Furniture Store Bid#. Supply Co.
2 Barber Shops Tw o .r»c-$l Store*
Bottling Works 2 Ice Dealers
3 Food Stores 4 Filling Stations
1 Hdw. Stores Shoe Store
Hotel Drue Store
3 Restaurant* 2 Harness Shops
3 Dwtors Jewelry Store
Apparel Shop Gi ft Shoo
ft Garages 2 Dentist;*
Printing Office Beauty Parlor
Clothing Store 2 Ins. Agencys
Greenhouse Electric Shop
Movie Theatre Chirk Hatchery
2 Meat Markets Hank
Dairy Cold Storage
8 Taverns Opera lla ll
Bakery 2 Feed Stores
3 General Stores Telephone Co.
Tailor Shop Millinery Shop
2 Blacksmiths Dray Line
Law yer 2 Sales Stables
2 Morticians Auto Parts Shop
Veterinarian 4 Bulk Stations
W IN N E B A G O IN D IA N ITE M S
(B y Bertha W’ abshagain.)
Mr. and Mrs. James McKinnis from
Delafield, W’ is.. are here visiting her
folks at the Settlement.
Bill Decorah and fam ily are visiting
at Mauston, Wis.
Mrs. Alice Clouds father, Jim Standing
W'ater, died last week at Mauston.
Mr. and Mrs. Eli W’hite Wing, also
children George, Katherine and Caroline
returned to the Settlement from
Sturgeon Bay.
Herman W’ abshagain and Mr. and
Mrs. Sam Little George also returned
from Sturgeon Bay last W’ ednesday.
Quite a few Indians went to visit
Keshena Fair Sunday.
Ray W’ hite W’ ing and fam ily returned
a fter picking blueberries,
j Oscar Pigeon and his mother are
paying a visit to Sarah Johnson at
Crandon, W’ is.
Mr. and Mrs. John C. Decorah are
spending their vacation at Star Lake.
Win.
Fred Sam is back in the Settlement
a fter staying in St. Paul, Minn., during
the winter.
PLEASANT V IE W
Mr. and Mrs. Guy Shaddock and
daughter lone o f Clintonville visited
in the Wilbur Thayer home Sunday.
A large crowd attended the farew ell
at B ill’s and Ma’s Saturday night.
The new proprietors, Mr. and Mrs.
Roland Schoenike of Shawano moved
in and will begin business for them selves
Sept. 1.
Jack Thayer is helping his uncle,
W. L. Thayer, in town o f Elderon the
balance >-f this week filling silo.
Mrs. Herman Buettner and Kenneth
Matson o f Tilleda visited Wm. Werth
and fam ily Saturday evening.
Albert Peppenberg and fam ily and (
Mrs. Annie Peppenberg and Charles
Breaker all of Neenah were Sunday
guests at the Wm. W’ erth home.
“ 81111)” and M argaret Hanson were
business visitors in Shawano Monday.
BADGER
T H E A T R E
W IT T E N B E R G . W IS C O N S IN
Showing every niirht at 7:15 and 9:15
A D M IS S IO N 25c-15t-10t
FRI.  S A T.
t O f l S E
R A IN E R
S E P T . 1-2
P A U L E T T E
G O D D A R I)
“ Dramatic School”
Henry Stephenson
Alan Marshall
Lana Turner
Ann Rutherford
Factory girl who fights to win fame
in theatre— o f yearning youth who
say “ I was born to be an actress.”
A lso
Misses M argaret, Jessie and Josie
Kading have gone to C alifornia where
they will v is it the Fair and other
places o f interest.
Miss Mildred Stewart o f W ittenberg
spent Sunday with her parents, Mr.
and Mrs. James Stewart.
Mr. and Mrs. Otto Bredendick,
Elaine and Esther Bredendick, Chester
Hieble o f Neenah visited at the
John Liesch home Sunday. Miss Edeline
Liesch, who spent ten days in
Oshkosh and Neenah, returned home
with them.
Gary Low, Shirley and Beverly Stai,
B etty and Bobby Stewart Lois Jean.
Dale and Duane Joubert helped A v a nelle
Joubert celebrate her fourth
birthday Tuesday afternoon,
Mr. and Mrs. A ml re w Peterson entertained
relatives in honor o f their
son A rthu r’s birthday Friday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. John Liesch and fam ily
visited at the Leonard Hoffman
home Tuesday evening and at the Leo
Buser home Sunday evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Milton Krolow and baby
and Marcell Rohlinger o f Tigerton
and Beatrice Joubert were visitors at
the Russell Joubert home Tuesday
evening.
Mr. and Mrs. James Stew art and
children visited at the Bert M cLaughlin
home Thursday evening.
Mrs. T illie Halverson returned to
Wauwatosa Friday a fter visiting
friends here.
George Fischer, Mrs. Clara H itz,
and Mr. and Mrs. Daniel H itz o f Oshkosh
drove up Tuesday to spend the
day in the John Peterson and Mrs.
H arriet Becker homes, bringing along
their cousin, Mrs. Dora Jones, who enjoyed
visiting her friends here. They
all returned to Oshkosh the same day.
F ou r-Year Term s
The terms o f the state’s five highest
elective officers would be increased
from two to four years, but the g o ve rnor
and lieutenant governor would be
prevented from serving consecutive
terms in a joint resolution introduced
in the senate by Otto Mueller and
Fred Fisher, both Republicans.
The measure allows four year terms
for the governor, lieutenant governor,
secretary o f state, attorney general
and the state treasurer. Preven ting
the governor and lieutenant governor
from serving consecutive terms would
considerably lessen their chances to
return to the tw o positions because the
proposed law would keep them out of
the running and political prominence
fo r four years at a time.
Under the present two year term
with no restriction on the number o f
terms that may be served four men in
the history o f the '*ate have held
office for three term '. They are “ old
Bob” La Follette, Emanuel Philip,
John J. Blaine, and Philip F. La F ollette,
who w'as defeated by Governor
Heil last fall when he sought his
foUrth term.
The resolution also provides fo r a
state wide referendum in 1940 on
whether all appointed state officers
should end their term o f office at the
end o f the term of the governor who
appointed them. This would g ive each
governor the power to fill all appointive
positions.— Madison N ew s Letter.
(F ir s t pub. Aug. 17; last Sep. 21.)
Lega l N otice
State o f Wisconsin, in Circuit Court
Branch o f County Court fo r Shawano
County.
The Federal Farm M ortgage Corporation,
a corporation. Plaintiff,
vs.
A ugust Schroeder (also known as
August J. Schroeder) and Jessie
Schroeder, his w ife, Joseph Steiner
and Bertha Steiner, his w ife, W illiam
F. Schultz and Carlton W.
Schultz, Defendants.
Notice is hereby given, that under
and by virtue o f a judgment o f fo re closure
and sale made in the above entitled
action on the 29th day o f July,
1938, the undersigned, Sheriff of
Shawano County, State o f W'isconsin,
w'ill sell at the sheriff’s office in the
Courthouse, in the city o f Shawano,
Shawano County, Wisconsin, on the
7th day o f October, 1939, at 10:00
o’clock in the forenoon o f that day,
the real estate and m ortgaged prem ises
directed by said judgment to be
sold therein described as follow s:
The South H a lf o f N orthest Quarter
(S V iN E * 4 ) o f Section Six ( 6 ),
Tow nship Twenty-seven (2 7 ), N orth
o f Range Fifteen (1 5 ) East; containing
E ighty (80 ) acres, more or
less, in Shawano County, Wisconsin.
Term s o f Sale: Cash.
Dated this 11th day o f August, 1939.
A ik, Kresky  Cohen, Attorneys,
Green Bay, Wisconsin.
C A R L D R U C K R E Y , Sheriff of
Shawano County, Wisconsin.
— Enterprise Ads Bring Results.
I N D I G E S T I O N
Senutiona! Re.icf from Indigestion
„ . snd One Dose Pro*e* It
I f the Urn iIqm* of this i>e»>*nt-u«ttng little
hlMfc tablet doesn't brlnt 700 th* fattett and B u t
complete relief you hav* expert ei>cet! tend bottle
b*cfc to ua and gei OOUBUS MONEY BACK. Thia
Bell-ana tablet help# the jtomacto dlgeat food.
a :
the axceaa itomach fluid* harm I aaa aiu
it the nourlthlng foods you need. For heartftefc
headache and upseta ao often canted by
a M all oeer— _ __________
apeedy relief. Sic e»erywhere.
DR. E. E. EVENSON
Physician and Surgeon
A ll Calls Prom ptly Answered
Office in Bank Building
W IT T E N B E R G , W IS C O N S IN
M. C. C R ANE
Physician and Surgeon
O ffice O ver Gamble Store
Eyes Tested — Glasses F itted
W IT T E N B E R G , W IS.
2nd BIG H IT :
GEORC.E H A Y E S (W in d y )
“ Fighting
Thoroughbreds”
with
M ary Carlisle. Ralph Bird
Robert Allen
Thrills, Famous Horses, Southern
Pride.
HAY FEVER
Tart Thia Quick Ballet
T ry on * doa* "D r P la tt'* H I N E X P r w e H p -
Uon.” R e lie f usually b «*in a ln a f « w m lnutea.
A physician's in tern a l m edicine in conven
ien t eapaulea. ta*t«l«*»-— a boon f o r suffe
re rs fro m H• / T * »e r , R*»ee Fever. H ead
Cold* Catarrh. Aathma H o t h a b lt-fo rm in *.
f a c e t in g , w h eelin g, itch in g eye*, ru nn ing
Dos* quickly relieved. S a tisfa ction w ith in S
fe w hour* guaranteed o r m oney bach. I « * r
riruveist reeotnmenda R IN E X , $1.00.
Larson’s Barber Shop
l Tp-to-I)ate Tonsorial Parlor
E xpert W'ork Guaranteed to Both
Men and Women Customers
W IT T E N B E R G . W IS.
Thursday, August 31, 1939
yA
O FF TO ELMER f i
, CAR {bargains/
F O R D D u k r i’ Nation-wide Used Car
Clearance Sale now going full blast. Many can carry the
“ R ft G” Ug, which ia good newa for every buyer. For R
meana Renewed where neceaaary to certain specification*.
G meana Guaranteed under a money-back plan.
’38 F O R I) C O U PE— An R  G
C ar; clean inside and ou t;
has hot a ir heater;
N ow
O n ly ........
’37 F O R D TU D O R
R  G specifications, looks
like new; good tires, radio;
heater; wheel shields.
Priced Low
A t ............
$489.00
*439.00
36 F O R I) TU D O R
Car has been checked; good
tire s; heater: good paint.
$319.00
'35 FO RD C O U PE
A real honest-to-goodness
$239.00
•34 C H E V R O L E T S E D A N
V ery economical transporta-
£ $265.00
•33 C H E V R O L E T COACH
N ew paint, re-upholstered.
A real
buy. $24900
’37 Z E P H Y R S E D A N
Com pletely reconditioned,
very clean: radio; overdrive;
££... $745.00
'37 C H E V . T O W N S E D A N
Thoroughly reconditioned —
thousands o f unused miles;
very good tir e s ; hot water
$479.00
•36 DODGE S E D A N
Reconditioned ear; will give
good service fo r miles and
S£U.. $419.00
’35 F O R D T U D O R
Completely overhauled.
N ow
O n ly .
$269.00
‘34 FO RD TU D O R
Refinished and clean.
N ow
O n ly . $259.00
'33 F O R D TU D O R
Clean and refinished,
guarantee
O n ly ........
A 50-50
$229.00
A N D M A N Y M ORE M A K E S A N D M O D E LS A L L P R IC E D
A N D R E C O N D IT IO N E D FO R IM M E D IA T E S A L E !
A ll Makes and Models o f Trucks. Farm Machinery.
BUY NOW
I n t h i a
Clearance Sale
YOUR "SHIP WILL
COME IN” Sooner
By the A id o f N ew ipaper
ADVERTISING - A
J f i a
Marlon Motor Co.
Call U s!
SU N .  MON. S E P T . 3-4
Heart throb romance in muscial drama
J E A N E T T E M cD O N A L D
“ BROADWAY
SERENADE”
with
Lew A Y R E S Frank M O R G A N
lan H U N T E R
S E LE C TE D SH O R TS N E W S
F O R S A L E
COZY HOME located at ELDERON, WIS.
(Known as the Fish dwelling)
Kids wanted nn this home to close trust fund
o f Coloma State Bank
TR U S T E E S — W illiam W ichner, W . E. Perkins, A lb ert U h er
Send All Fiids to Wm. Wichner, Coloma, Wis.
M A R IO N . W IS. P H O N E 21 I
P A R AM O l'N T W E E K
TU E S.. W ED ., TH U R S..
S E P T . 5-6-7
Paramount presents drama with
locale in Swiss Alps
IK SAY DIE’
S C H L Y T T E R
I N S U R A N C E A G E N C Y
W IT T E N H E R G , W IS C O N S IN
gJW/ immmuimmiimmiim— iim m i imi I ml immmiim— iimmlimmmu*
W E H AVE N E W SHIPM ENT OK
Sisal-Kraft
Paper
FOR TEM PORARY
Silos
with
BOB H O PE
Th irty days to live, so he marries
M A R T H A R A Y E
and the fun begins!
Andy Devinr Alan Mowbray
--------------------- Also ---------------------
2nd BIG H IT :
V IR G IN IA W E ID L E R
Starring in
“ FIXER DllGAN”
Thrills of circus lift* and ‘The F ix er’
who had to smooth out all jams a j
tomboy w a if jjot into.
______ j
O f G r e a t I m p o r t a n c e . . . I
IT IS MORE IM P O R T A N T T O K N O W W H E R E T O B U Y "
T H A N T O K N O W W H A T T O B U Y . j
W H E N YO U B U Y IN S U R A N C E FRO M T H IS A G E N C Y , |
Y O U R P R O T E C T IO N IS A L W A Y S R IG H T . f
K ENNETH S. SCHLYTTER. Agent.
W E H A V E T H E B E S T
A T T H E R IG H T P R IC E S !
JOHNSON-BURT
LUMBER CO.
A R T H l'R O LS E N . M A N A G E R
§ W IT T E N B E R G , W IS. P H O N E NO. 41 §
i//«5</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
